Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on Native Image Tool from VMM.
So far we've looked at the default toolchain of different platforms because those are the prerequisites
of compiling a Java application to a native binary using native image tool.
And then we saw also how to install crawl VM, how to download it, install it, and then use the Google
Updater to install Native Image tool on different platforms Mac OS, Linux and Windows.
And now I'm going to just bring up a few notes from the official website of the Native Image Tool,
and there is also a very interesting website, medium.com grad beam using quad beam and native image
on windows and it again walks you through the steps that I also mentioned.
So if you want to learn more or details, then you can also always visit this image, this online website,
some notes from the official Native Image website.
This is from the Google VM website prerequisites for using Native Image on Windows.
So to start using native image on Windows, install Visual Studio and Microsoft Visual Compiler, right?
MSK and Visa.
I showed you how to do it.
Now the thing here is that the native image, especially on Windows, only works for the default toolchain
of the Windows platform, which is MSK.
So really you really don't have much option of using other open source compilers like GCP at this point,
I'm not really sure that it's even possible to use those.
For example, GCP build toolchain with native image on windows, but for now the easiest thing to do
is SVC.
And when you run native image on Windows which I will show you, it searches for CL or command line
command select x, which is the MSC compiler and terminal.
And I showed you that you have to ensure that when you run the terminal and run the native image in
the terminal, the path environment variable already sets up so that all the all the directories that
are from MSC are already on the path so that the compiler has no problem finding, for example, the
header files or other build tools required to compile a application.
Right.
And I told you that it's best to define a few environment variables on on Windows so that you can quickly
set up the path and then call the native image from terminal.
So there are two installation options for the native image on Windows.
Install the Visual Studio, build tools with the Windows ten SDK.
And this is what I showed you.
Install Visual Studio with the Windows ten SDK.
So this is basically the full IDE, the full IDE, and that's what I downloaded.
But you don't really need to also install the ID, you can only use the bell tools.
And that's very similar to Mac OS.
Right.
We said that Xcode, you can download the entire application, it's like ten gigabytes.
It's a very large application.
It has a full, full featured ID, but you don't really need that on macOS.
You just can install the command line tools, which are the build tools for the Mac OS.
Same with Windows.
You can also just download and install Visual Studio build tools, right?
So you can use Visual Studio 2017 version 15.9 or later.
And in my tutorial, I use the Visual Studio Community Edition 2022.
Right?
So I'm going to write down a community edition because that's the free edition.
And obviously every platform must provide its own free build tools, otherwise nobody would be able
to write, write applications.
And so lastly on Windows, the native image builder will only work when it is executed from the x 64
Native Tool Command.
And we saw that in order to do that, you want to go back and set up the path environment variable.
You go to the MSI.
AVC Right, Microsoft Visual Studio Community VC, which is the Visual Compiler Auxiliary and in the
bell directory.
And there are different command line scripts that you can execute them in terminal, and then it correctly
sets up the path environment variable for the build that you want to do.
And we said that we see was 64 is the one that we want to use on a 64 bit platform and it correctly
sets up the, the environment variables.
And I also show you that it's best to actually define an environment variable that points to this file.
And then whenever you type that environment variable and hit enter in terminal, it automatically executes
the script and sets up the path environment variable.
All right.
So.
These are the nodes on the native image.
And again, your main option on windows is to use use the default toolchain, which is the RMS we see.
So native image only mainly searches for this compiler.
Select the command for initiating and 64 Native Tools Command prompt is different if you only have the
Visual Studio tools to install versus if you have the full voice studio installed.
Check this link for a step by step instructions.
And this link is basically pointing to this website medium.com called VM using grab VM and native image
on Windows.
Right.
So you can check this out.
And again, but again, it's I showed you all the steps you have to go ahead and download the Visual
Studio and then you have to set up the past environment where we're correctly by executing one of these
scripts and it automatically adds a lot of directories to the path so that the command clicked exit
can work fine on your terminal, and after that you can go ahead and create a hello world application
and then execute it to make sure that the native image works fine on your Windows platform.
And that's what I'm going to show you next.
So basically so far we've set up the default tool chains of different platforms.
We download it and install the native image.
We made sure that it works fine on all three platforms and now we want to start learning about Native
Image.
What is it so or essentially what is Native Image?
As I mentioned before, it's a compiler.
It's a tool that compiles your Java application to a native executable binary that includes actually
having a compiled version of the JVM, a very compact version of the JVM garbage collector.
All the pieces that the Java application requires to successfully run, right?
But because everything gets compiled to a native binary using using a static compilation instead of
instead of running on JVM, right?
With the operating system takes full control or full responsibility of running your application after
the compilation because there is no JVM, right?
So VM native image building tool, this tool can be used to generate an image that contains ahead of
time compiled Java code.
Now Ahead of Time compilation is a fancy word for saying that we are aesthetically compiling to the
native executable binary.
Right.
And again, to refresh your memory Java compilation or the Java, the job of the Java compiler is to
compile to an intermediate level binary.
It's a binary that the CPU doesn't understand, the operating system doesn't understand, but the Java
understands that.
So when you launch your Java application using Java, JVM loads the class files, which are the binaries
that the JVM understands.
And then after JVM understands your class files, it tells the operating system what to do.
So the Java sits between you and the operating system, and the operating system sits between you and
the hardware, right?
There are some tasks that you want to ask the harbour to do in your job application, and there are
some other tasks that you're not concerned with the hardware.
You just want to talk to the operating system, for example, terminal.
If you want to bring something to the terminal, you don't talk to the hardware, right?
You don't care about the hard disk or the RAM or anything, right?
And it's not an IO operation.
It's just telling the terminal, hey, turning the operating system, hey, print this line to the terminal.
Right?
So whenever you launch an application in in your operating system, the operating system has to allocate
some OS resources or operating system resources.
Right.
And one of the resources is always terminal.
So your application always has IO streams like input streams so that the user can give some feedback
or the commands to your application.
And again, the output stream is when the application can print something to the console, right?
These are not directly related to the hardware.
These are just some resources that the operating system has and it allocates to your application.
And how do we use this native command?
And again, when you open up a terminal, we said that you can either a.
You can either add graph LLVM being directory to the path environment variable so you can just type
native image.
But I didn't do that on Mac or on my on my Mac OS because I want to make sure that when I type Java,
it comes from my JDK 17 that I downloaded from Oracle.
Right?
So if you append a bean environment being directory of the VM to the to the path, the Java comes from
that because Google Beam also includes a JDK, which is an open JDK build.
So I didn't want to do that.
So I define the crawl home and then bean and then a native image, right hyphen, hyphen version.
And we installed the latest version as of this day, which is 20 2.1.0, and it's built based on the
open JDK 17.
And as I mentioned in the Bing directory, there is a Java or Java.
See these are the open JDK versions, right?
Open JDK 17.
But I want on my command line to have the Oracle JDK as my Java application, right?
So just be careful which Java you use.
I always recommend whenever you want to execute Java C or Java first check the version.
So say Java C, hyphen, hyphen version and it tells me Java 17 and Java hyphen hyphen version.
It tells you which JDK it's using, right?
Which JDK the terminal is finding on the path environment.
So you're saying native image options just like any other executable application, any application by
application, take some options or command line arguments and then the name of the class that has the
main method, right?
The class that is entry point to your application and again it's the class file and then you don't include
the dart class extension, you just tell the name of the class.
If it's inside a package, then you have to provide the fully qualified name.
So this class is actually the fully qualified name.
And then you want to tell a native what should be the name of the output binary.
And we know that when we compile a C++ application, we can say hyphen o, which is which means and
then some name, right?
And then the output is going to be named this name that you specify for the compiler.
Same with native image.
You can after you tell it, which class file is the entry point to your application, then you can tell
it the first of all, what's the name of the output is?
And this name can actually be a full path or relative path to the output, which means you can say native
image, right?
And then my main class.
Right, and then you can say for example, put it in a directory called test a relative to this current
working directory and then name it my underscore app.
Right.
So what this does is that if this directory doesn't exist, then the native image actually creates this
directory and then it compiles your main class and puts it.
And then the name of the application is going to be whatever you specify here.
My underscore app in this case and after the compilation Native Image creates this directory and puts
this the application with this name inside this directory.
Right.
So if the directory doesn't exist, native image creates that.
Now, one of the main options here for the native image, as I mentioned, is the class path.
That's the most important parameter when you deal with any job application.
Same with native image.
Native image in order to compile the main class.
Obviously, if your main class has some dependencies on other classes other types, then native image
should be able to find all those classes.
Right.
Remember, Native Image is not a java compiler.
It's a compiler that takes all the class files necessary for your running your job application and builds
a native image and native executable binary.
Now later, we will see that you can actually also create libraries like static or dynamic libraries
that you can then, for example, use in other applications.
So it's not necessarily a it's not you don't have to just create an executable binary, but that's the
most useful way of using native image, right?
You write your job application.
Developing, compiling and maintaining a Java application is much easier and much faster than developing
a C++ application, especially in a huge project, a C plus.
Compiling a C++ application will take a long time.
And the reason is that you might not be familiar with how C++ compiler works, but every CP file has
to include all the other files.
Right?
Let's say if you write a CP just helloworld and then include EOS Stream, the preprocessor copies all
those code in the iOS stream into your current CP and then the compiler compiles the entire thing right.
And then if you have a lot of these includes, then it takes a very long time and resources write CPU
resources to compile.
Whereas in Java we know that import statements have virtually no effect on your class files.
Right?
Every class in Java gets compiled to a class file.
Import statements are not basically written in the class files.
They they don't include any extra code.
Instead, they get translated into the fully qualified name of your types.
And then at runtime the gvm has to be able to locate those fully qualified.
Same with native image.
Right.
Again, import the statements in your class files.
Doesn't do anything but then native image and relies on the class path argument to find all the dependencies
of your application.
Right.
So not only you can compile a main class that has the main method, you can also entire a jar file.
You can compile a jar file using hyphen jar arguments and then jar file.
And you have to be careful that this jar file has to be executable.
And in order to make a jar file executable, you have to have the manifest dot inside of it.
And then the manifest that MAF has, the information about which class is the main class, which class
has the main method or which class is the entry point to your job application.
And I will have examples in the future lectures on how to make a jar file or how to make an executable
jar, and then how to compile it with a native image.
Right.
All right.
So what are these options?
So we have two options here.
One of them is in orange.
One of them is green.
For now, I'm going to look at a few.
This is not the all the options here, but a few of the orange options, options that you give to the
native image.
When you're compiling the application, obviously you can tell that the most important one is the class
path, which you can type it in three ways hyphen XRP, hyphen class path hyphen, hyphen class hyphen
path.
Right.
So if you want to keep this hyphen, you have to use two double hyphens here so that the native image
understands that.
I mean, my favorite is Hyphen XRP.
It's very concise.
And then the class path separator is a colon on any platforms.
Windows, Mac, OS, Linux doesn't matter.
Java always uses a colon for the class path separator.
What this means is that you can have multiple directories on your class path and you separate them with
call it, right?
So any of these can be used with a colon seperated list of directories, jar files, so you can even
point to the jar files because jars are like a compressed archive and the JVM or the native image,
they know how to and archive these, decompress it and access all the class files inside of it.
So not only directory is jar files or even zip archives, the compress archives like zip.
It also works fine.
Native Image knows how to access the class files inside that note that this zip archive shouldn't include
Java source code.
It should include classifies or a compiled java source code.
Right.
Native image works with the class files just like the java works with the class files and then hyphen
D name equal value a set of system properties.
We've already seen these and these are the system properties that is that basically past.
The JV team write again when Native Image compiles your application, it actually has a compiled version
of the JVM.
It's a compact version, hyphen j flag pass a flag directory to the JV team so directly to the JV and
running image generators.
So these flags are like we know that, for example, you can set how much memory is the initial memory,
right?
So hyphen x x flags or for example, hyphen a boolean flag is like print GC, for example.
This is something that you can see the details of the GC.
So these are JV flags and I believe you can pass them with this argument.
We will look at this later and see if this works or not, but for now, hyphen X or hyphen x, these
are usually the JV and flags that you use.
Hyphen oh is the optimisation level.
As I mentioned, the native image does a static compilation and if you say hyphen o zero, it means
no optimization and one means a basic optimization default, right?
So usually in C++ you can also have these flags, for example, GC, G Plus, plus, and then the name
of your CP and then a hyphen or for example, three.
I believe the C++ compilers have three levels of optimisation, zero hyphen or zero hyphen oh one,
hyphen oh two and hyphen oh three and same here.
Here you only have two choices hyphen o zero, hyphen or one, which is the default.
So if you don't specify any optimization level, the native image already uses the most optimized version.
Right hyphen hyphen verbose, enable, verbose output, hyphen, hyphen, virgin print, product version
and x ID.
And that's what we've been using, right?
So if we say crawl VM, crawl home, bing, and then native image and then in for this orange option,
I'm going to tell it hyphen, hyphen, version.
This prints the version and then exits the application.
It doesn't continue.
So grow.
LLVM 20 2.1.0 Java 17 come into edition and then we exit the application, right?
We go back to the terminal.
All right.
So a hello world, a native image in window in MapQuest.
We've already seen this many times, but now let's have a closer look.
You create a Helloworld Java compiler, compiler with any Java See compiler, which is version 17 because
we're using LLVM 17, you have to use a compiler that is at least 17, I believe.
I mean it's best to have the exact match so you can either use the Java Sea that comes with the LLVM
or you can use the Java Sea that comes with the Oracle JDK 17.
They are compatible run native image tool and the class file and then you omit the class, right?
Just like when you launch a Java application using JVM.
So don't use the don't use the DOT class extension.
So here's a quick example.
So public class helloworld and public say vote main is the string args.
System.out.println helloworld from native image.
This is our java source code.
And then here in my terminal I use the Java Sea from google vm growler home being java c helloworld
java.
Note that I'm in the same directory that this Java source code is, so I don't need to specify hyphen
CPP and give it the directories for the class path and then a girl home being Java C hyphen version.
I'm using Java C 17 and after I compile to the class file.
Hello world class.
I just tell it.
Crawl home being native image.
Hello world.
And I'm omitting the dot class extension and the compilation goes through and then it creates the Hello
World application.
Note that I'm not specifying the name of the output file and then by default, if you don't specify
the name of the output application output executable, it's going to use the name of your class main
class, the class that has made.
But all the letters are lowercase.
That's why you see that the output application is Hello world.
All the letters are lowercase.
So let's, for example, head to Eclipse.
We've already done this many times and even our Hello World application had more complexity.
It had dependencies, but I'm going to create a new directory here.
Let's say hello app or just app.
Right, let's close this and here we're going to new instead of direct.
So we're going to create a new directory or file, let's call it Hello World dot Java.
And we're going to say public, public class again, this is for refreshing your memory and then showing
you that now that we've installed the default toolchain and then we've installed VMM and a native image
is set up, how we go ahead and create a simple hello world application.
So hello world and then public static void main string args and then let's do a see out system that
add print line.
Hello world from Java in a native image and an exclamation mark.
Right.
So this is our Java application.
We open up a terminal at here.
So where our source code is exactly in our current working directory.
And then I can say Google Home and then being a Java C and then hell of all the java I'm using the Java
compiler from LLVM.
If I do an LS, you see that?
Now I have the hello world class which also shows up here.
And finally, now that the class file is ready.
First of all, I can check that my Java application is correct by running it on a JVM.
Hello world.
Right.
So you use the Java command line application and then pass it the class file.
That is, your main class has the main method.
And now, as you can see, my application works fine.
Let's see.
Oh, okay.
So the reason is that right now it's I had another hello world in my test directory and this was part
of the my global environment variable class path.
So that's why now Java, this Java is picking up the class path and executing that application.
So in order to avoid this, I have to explicitly override this class path variable.
And the way we do it, we explicitly provide the hyphen CPP here, which means only look into the current
working directory and now it's correctly picking up.
Okay, we have a one here, so let's remove this and then let's quickly compile our Java application
again.
All right.
So if you've already set up your class path environment variable, you have to be careful.
You can always override the class path environment variable by by explicitly providing this hyphen CPP
to the Java.
You can even append it.
So I can tell you the first look into the current directory.
Append right with the colon.
That's our class path separator.
And then provide a class path in double code, which means.
So what this does, I believe.
Let's see if this works.
Or, um.
Okay, so we made a mistake.
Yeah.
So let's clean up.
So hyphen seep first.
So the dot goes first, and then a class path.
And then double quote, right?
So what this does, it is still ranks correctly, despite the fact that I have to hell of all classes
that are on my class path.
But when you give the current working directory as the first directory in the class path, Java tries
to search a class called Hello World in the current directory.
First, if you cannot find it, then it goes into the directory that the class path specifies.
Now, if you if I change the order, I tell it first, search the class path environment variable and
then use the search the current directory you see.
Now it uses or finds this hello world class because that's the class that comes up in the first directories
which are in the class path.
Right.
So you can explicitly override the class path by just providing all the directories using hyphen CPP.
Or you can also append the class path to the directory that you are specifying.
Right.
So we're going to compile the class file now with the native image.
So Google Home being a native image, I'm going to tell it hyphen.
This current working directory, the name of the class file is Hello World and then I'm going to tell
it.
The name of my application is going to be my app, so it's going to compile my job application.
The entry point is this class hello world.
It's not inside the package.
If it were inside the package, we have to provide the fully qualified name.
Of the class that has the main method and then the output is going to my app is going to create this
native binary and puts it in the current working directory.
So let's go ahead and run this generating my app and that's executable.
So it's telling us that it's creating a native executable.
We're using a version 17 of Java CC, Apple Clang compiler and then Garbage Collector is going to be
serial GC.
So compiling methods looks like everything works fine.
Almost done creating image.
Now it's and it's finished.
So everything went fine.
And then, um, project artifacts, it's my app, which is executable and then build artifact.
The build artifact is a text file that tells you what kind of file you generated executable and what's
the path or the.
To this application which is my app.
Right.
So let's go ahead and obviously we want to check that the compilation work fine so dot forward slash
which means from the current directory execute my app and hello fold from Java in native image.
So we successfully created a binary native executable binary for our Java application, which was a
simple hello world.
And the other thing that I'm going to point out here, we saw already the command line arguments, right?
And those are passed.
If your application requires some, you can pass them here.
But we saw that also we can use the system like get property and give it the name and then this returns
a string, right?
A string, val or value.
And then I'm going to say that see out name, arrow, arrow and then a plus value.
So if this system property is not set, we're going to get null.
So what I'm going to do is let's run our application with the Java or first of all, we have to compile
it.
So let's compile with Java C and then HELLOWORLD Java.
It works fine.
And then now we can run it with Java a specifying that use this current directory and then name becomes
null.
And then we know that after hyphen CPP we can tell java hyphen DX variables name equals bob and now
this system property is set and what we can do now also use the native image hyphen CPP here and before
specifying the main class, we're going to give it hyphen DX name equals bar.
So let's compile again.
So let's see if this works or not.
If this doesn't work, then after the native executable binary is generated, we can also pass these
at the time that we run the application.
But if this works, then by default this parameter is going to pass to our native executable binary.
Every time you run the application.
So compiling the methods.
And after that, it's going to generate creating the image.
Let's see if this works.
Everything seems to work fine.
And then if I said that my underscore app and now name is NULL.
So that hyphen DX parameter did not work as expected.
But then now we can pass it here hyphen dynamical bar and now this works, right?
So and we saw this before that not only you can pass arguments to this string array, you can also pass
or set the system properties using hyphen DX and the native image differentiates between the parameters
that you pass.
For example, these two strings are passed to this string array, but this hyphen, the name equal Bob,
is passed to as the system property.
So they are this this argument is not passed to this string array.
Just I want you to understand this very clearly, that there is a difference in that.
Right?
So but then let's go back and see if we can actually put this hyphen DX name.
So let's see if we can pass it to the options here.
Hyphen name equals bar.
Let's see if this works or not.
So initializing performing analysis.
So almost done.
And in in lining methods, compiling methods.
And then finally creating the executable file or the image.
So the compilation was, okay, so let's see if we run my app.
What do we get?
Name is still comes as null.
So it looks like we can't really set the system property directly when we compiling them.
But as I mentioned, you can always pass them at the runtime when you run your application, right?
So I hope you enjoy this lecture.
Obviously in the future lectures we're going to go into more depth about all the details of Native Image.
So please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.