Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on Native Image.
So far we've learned how to set it up, how to compile a simple application, how to take advantage
of the power that the Eclipse external tool provides.
And now let's look at the details of most most important flags or options that the native image has.
And we saw that previously some of the important options.
And we said that generally if you want to run the native image from terminal, this is the general usage,
native image.
Obviously you have to point it to the being directory of the VM and then the options that Native image
accepts and then the name of the class or and then we will also discuss that.
You can also give it a jar file, a jar that has a is basically executable.
And then the image name, the name of the output file that will be generated, the native executable
binary and then the options here.
Right.
And I believe these are mostly for the JVM itself.
And we said that the most important one is hyphen CLASSPASS Hyphen oh is also important.
No optimisation.
One is basic optimization.
And in the most recent version of when they actually added hyphen or B, so zero one and B and you can
probably guess that if we turn off the optimisation, then the compilation goes faster, right?
And then not only this, they also added this hyphen or B, right, zero one.
So basically the lowercase B, which basically does doesn't do a deep optimization.
So hyphen or B is more or less something between zero and one.
Right?
Full optimisation.
No optimisation.
All right.
So let's look at the class path.
If the main class has dependencies, we need to provide the path for native image tool.
And we see that it's very similar to how you set it up for JVM.
And again, the way the native image works is that actually VM comes with the JDK.
So first when you try to compile an application, it actually runs your Java application background
and runs, for example, garbage collection a few times because it has to figure out the optimized size
of your Java heap when your application is running.
And then.
And then basically try to come up with a very small size heap when it compiles because it creates a
static image of your heap.
Right.
So you can either use hyphen, CP, hyphen class path or hyphen hyphen class hyphen path.
And obviously because there is a dash here between class and path, you have to use two hyphens here.
And the class path operator is always calling on all operating systems.
We already know that on Mac OS and Linux, the path separator right is also call it.
But on Windows, the path separator is semicolon.
But don't confuse it with the class path separator for Java because Java is independent of the operating
systems, it always follows the same convention in an all operating system.
That's why the class path separator is the same on all platform and it's just calling, right?
Even if you're on windows, you use call it.
So Native Image Tool operates on class files and we said that you give it a again, you give it a fully
qualified name of the class.
It needs to find all all of the necessary class files at the compile time.
In fact, in the most recent I mean previously in the older versions, it would fail the compilation
if some of the classes were not available.
But but now it can compile.
But then at runtime it throws a class not found error or something like that.
Right.
We there is an option actually one of the flags that we will see later that you can tell the native
image to fail on in the compile phase if some of the classes are not found on a class path, said the
working directory to the bean folder of your Eclipse project.
Or we discussed that, for example, every ID compiles the application has its own build tool and we
said that we can.
People prefer Maven build tool because it's the same for everything.
And IDs usually have support for Maven and it ensures that all the IDs, if they build the MAVEN project,
the basically the directory hierarchy where the class files are there all the same.
Right, said the hyphen hyphen class path I prefer to always use hyphen CPP is much easier to use hyphen
class path argument of native image to like this.
So usually if you are already in your working directory, it's already where your main classes.
So we append a dot which is the current working directory, right.
And usually this is if you're in, if you are inside eclipse IDE, this is usually the being directory
of your current project and then path, the other being directories that have the class files.
And remember, when we say class files, it means the package hierarchy.
If your class belongs to a package, it means on the hard disk there is a directory with the name of
that package and your compiled class file is inside that directory pass to another being directory.
If there is a jar file or zip file, then you give the path to that jar file.
Right.
The name of the jar file or the zip file should also be included.
The next one is how to find all the dependence of the Java class main class.
Let's say you are inside your ID and you have a main method.
So you have a class that has a main method.
You want to run it and you can successfully run it in ID.
Right now, let's say you have a lot of dependencies, you've added them, your ID is managing the dependencies,
but now you want to run the native image on your terminal to compile your main class into executable
binary.
And you want to figure out what are all the dependencies that are on the class path.
In fact, in your main class, in your main method, you can ask JVM to tell you what directories are
on a class.
But because remember, if you are in the ID and you can successfully run your Java application, it
means the class path is correctly set up and you can use a system property called gate property, java
dot class dot path.
So the class path operator is calling and this returns a string, a single string.
Remember it doesn't return a string array.
Right, but then you can split it from the, based on the token column to get all the directories or
you can directly print it right and then you can print it to the terminal and after that you can copy
and paste the entire string using the hyphen CP or hyphen hyphen class hyphen path.
Right?
The result is a string containing a column separated list of the path that include all of the class
files necessary to your to run your job application.
In Eclipse ID we saw that eclipse has internal environment variables which are very powerful.
One of them is project hyphen class path because when you run your job application inside the eclipse
ID it, it is already aware of what's going on, right?
If you can successfully run your application, run the main method, it means the class path is correctly
set up.
Use this string to set the hyphen CP or hyphen hyphen class hyphen path of the native image.
So here's an.
Dampen.
Let me zoom in a little bit.
So I ran this code in my eclipse ID and then it tells it prints a string, which is the class path of
my main method, my main class, and then grow a home being native image, hyphen or hyphen, hyphen,
class, hyphen path.
I copy and paste that string, make sure I put it in the double code because there might be a string,
a spaces or something between and in the fully qualified name of the class, which is the package hierarchy
and in the class name, fully qualified name.
And then where I'm right now, I'm this in this test one directory.
That's my working directory, right?
That's where I'm launching the native image from.
And I can tell you where to put the output file.
I'm telling you, go one level up, another level up, go to the native directory and create a executable
file called my app and it starts compiling.
Right now in this case because we are giving the native image the full class path, the working directory
doesn't have to be like being directory of your Eclipse project or any other specific directory.
You can be anywhere because native image searches in the class path or the directory that are on the
class path.
And remember that the class path separator is calling.
All right.
So let's head to Eclipse and try to have a quick look.
So let's say let's see.
We have this hello world and.
Okay.
Uh, native.
Let's see this one.
So this is the old one that we had.
So let's look at this.
This is a simple class, right?
So.
And then what we're going to do, let's remove these.
Yeah, it's just print something to the console and obviously I can actually run this, right?
So this is successfully run.
And then what I can do, I can say a string class path is system dot get property.
And just one thing to note that the reason I can successfully run this because this is configured as
an Eclipse project, right?
So previously we were having like Java files inside directories, but they were not part of the Eclipse
project, so we were manually compile them with the Java Sea.
But now I have a CRC directory.
Right?
I create a Java image as RC, create a eclipse package and then create my source files.
Eclipse compiles them and puts them in a bing directory which is a mirror of CRC and it has all the
dot class wise.
So Eclipse, if you set up a Eclipse project, put your stuff packages and classes in this CRC.
Eclipse is aware of all the dependencies and now you can run it successfully in your right.
Now we're getting an error here.
So let's say java dot class dot path and then cis out class path, right?
So this tells me what's going on.
So right now there is only one directory on my project which is the being directory of the current project.
There's one directory in my class path because my application doesn't have any dependencies.
Right.
So I can just run this so I can.
This is my class file and then.
Basically what I can do, I can actually open up a terminal here.
Right now we don't see the beam directory here, but then we can go in there and then there is really
no reason to go in into being directory.
Right.
So let me just close this or let's open this.
We are at the top level directory of our Java project.
Now let's go to the native directory and clean up these previous bills.
All right.
So what we're going to do, I'm going to copy this.
This is my class path.
Right.
And then.
I'm going to open up a terminal.
We already opened up the terminal here at the top level and I'm going to try to compile this.
So we're going to say growl home, forward, slash being forward, slash native image and then hyphen
CP double coat and then copy and paste our class path.
Right.
And after that, we're going to give it the name of our binary, which is a Java underscore native image.
This is our top level package, the test class, right?
And this is the name of the class file.
And again, we're not in the directory.
This class file doesn't exist in this directory, but doesn't matter.
Native image searches in the class path that you provide.
And then we're going to say that go to native directory and create my app.
So let's run this.
So generating the alternative my app.
Initializing and then Virgin Info Group album 22.1 C compiler.
It's the Apple Clang Garbage Collector Serial GC.
So it's trying to perform analysis and then go ahead and compile.
So the analysis is done, parsing methods in lining methods and the final step is compiling methods.
And after the compilation the linker kicks in and then puts everything together and creates a one native
executable file.
So that's it, that's done.
So it took us about 35 seconds.
So if I go to the native and then my app.
So hello world from Java and external to an eclipse ID and you see the second one which is printing
out the class path is gone.
Right it's empty because this is a native executable.
So there is no concept of class path there anymore.
Right.
But it still works fine.
Now let's make it more complicated.
For example, I have a jar file here
or before that in eclipse ID you may have multiple projects right now in a working set.
If I deselect working said you see I have also other projects.
For example, this dev underscore Java.
There are some classes there now in Eclipse you can actually your one project can depend on the other
classes in other projects inside your Eclipse ID, which is a very nice feature that allows you to build
separate projects and basically build a project on top of another project, right?
Eventually each project you package them as a jar or something, but before going to packaging, you
can just directly give a dependency of a Java project on another project.
And basically what happens is that because Eclipse knows for every project where the classifiers are,
the compile files are there in the being directory.
So when you tell this project that it has a dependency on another Eclipse project or project, it just
adds the beam directory to the class path.
So we can go ahead and build path, configure, build path and then select the class path and add one
of the projects in the workspace which is Dev Java.
So yeah, now if I run this again, again the run is going to be successful.
And you see now I have two directories on my class path.
What I can do now.
I can, actually.
Let's see.
There is a class called Car in that project.
Right.
I can import a car.
Car, a new car.
And then we give it a price.
Let's say 1000 and then see out car.
So the two string method is not overloaded or overridden, but the car has class, has some aesthetic,
initialize it and instance initially which are called and in the class path right now if I go ahead
and try to compile my this class file again now the compilation is probably not going to fail.
The reason is that I believe they.
So the native image in the most recent version doesn't fail on the compile phase if some of the classes
are not found, but then it probably is going to fail on at runtime so we can see.
So let's see.
I believe the compilation is going to succeed.
But then at runtime, yeah, it's succeeded.
It's trying to create the image.
Let's see it.
So it worked fine.
But now if we go ahead and try to run the app, it says exceptional thread main no class.
They found error.
So it says I cannot find this car class.
I mean some people I personally doesn't prefer this because I want to make sure that when I compile
my project it's going to run
fine.
So everything so and I believe there is an option there.
So let's see.
Crawl VM a.
It's clean this up.
So if I say hyphen help, hyphen, hyphen help.
And in native compiler option.
Let's see how to file back.
Okay.
Class path module, path, FLAC version or the fallback.
Features force fallback.
Uh, native compiler path shared a static target.
I believe there is a, uh, uh, flag that allows you.
So let's see.
Help.
Extra.
Okay.
And then what I'm going to do.
Let's see.
GREP fail.
Or.
Let's see.
No.
Fall back.
All right.
For now, we're going to.
So right now, the default behavior is that it's going to succeed in the compilation phase.
But then at runtime, you get a runtime exception for not being able to find these, um, this, this
class.
So if all I have to do is now copy this class path, which now also has a dependency on another Java
project, and then go back here and update my class path.
And again, the beauty of this approach to manually setting up the class path is that then you really
don't care about where you launch your job application from because native image searches, searches
inside the let's see, searches inside all the directors of the class path to find your main class and
then also all the dependencies.
So hopefully this should work fine.
So we have two dependencies on our class path and then there is a column that separates them.
Let's see.
This should succeed.
Performing analysis.
Parsing methods in lining methods.
Compiling methods.
As I mentioned before, the compilation is very smart.
It only compiles the classes that your application absolutely needs to run, right?
So if I say native, my app and now our car class works fine.
You can see even the default to a string.
It works fine.
But we don't have the Java class path system property anymore because it doesn't make sense.
This is the native image.
The last thing the last thing that I want to show you is the flag hyphen.
Oh.
So if you want to quickly just compile, you're in the development phase so you don't care about the
optimization that the aesthetic compiler does from the native image.
You just want to check the compilation is fast enough.
So hyphen or B, let's see if this works.
You enable hyphen obi for this image build.
This will configure some optimization to reduce image build time so it means that it reduces the amount
of aesthetic optimization.
This feature should only be used during development and never for deployment.
Right?
Because once you want to deploy, you want to compile with the.
With the fast with the most optimize case.
Right.
But then it takes more time to compile.
Right now, the compilation was relatively fast and it took us about 29.
I mean, not much difference.
Previously we were having like 35 or 32 and this is now 29, right?
And again, if I run this, it's going to run just fine, right.
The last thing that I want to show you, obviously, we can also have other types of dependencies in
our eclipse.
So let me go back and activate my working set.
So I have a jar here.
Let's call it my and actually not this one.
Let's say in the app, in the lib there is one is util for j.
I want to right click again.
We are in the Eclipse project so I can just right click go to build path and add to Build Path and eclipse
automatically creates these reference libraries.
And now if I look at the class path again, again as long as I can successfully run my main method in
eclipse ID, it means the class path is set up correctly.
And now I have three directories.
Right.
So remember jar is a compressed or zipped directory.
So you have to also include the name of the jar file in the in the class path.
So my class path now has three dependencies.
And again, what, what I can do now is, for example this util for j in the it has, for example,
in the let's say math class, it has a or in the complex class it has complex numbers.
So I can say complex and eclipse knows where it is on the class path.
Z One is a complex of or of rect 1.1 and 2.2, and I can do az1.
So if I run this, this is going to succeed.
Yes.
And now I can copy this class path which I enquired in my Java source code and then yeah, I can go
back and run my native image.
Let's remove these hyphen o b option four.
Now and then we're going to.
Delete this old class path and give it a new class path, which now has three dependencies.
All right, so double code and then copy paste.
Yeah, it looks good.
We're going to run this.
Okay.
It's running.
Performing analysis done building universe parsing method in learning methods.
Compiling methods.
Creating image.
That's the final step.
And okay, so let's clear and run my app.
And now as you can see, the dependency, this complex number that we had from that jar file is now
compiled to the native binary and our native application has no problem running it.
Right.
So I hope you enjoy this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.