Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
In this tutorial I'm going to continue the discussion on Native Image and we're going to look at a very
important discussion, which is how to design our job application and later compile it to native executable
binary.
And in such a way that our application is a command line application and it accepts some command line
arguments and you know that whenever you have some command line application, usually it accepts flags
with a hyphen, hyphen, some word or hyphen some letter.
For example, if I open up a.
Basically a terminal here and then say, for example, Java and then hyphen, hyphen version, right?
So this is a command line argument and it doesn't accept any parameter for these particular arguments.
Right?
So if we say Java, hyphen, hyphen version, this application, which is Java, which is a binary application,
understands this flag.
And then if we say Java, hyphen, hyphen help, it lists all the flags, right?
That this Java application accepts.
And some of the flags start with hyphen and a single letter.
Some of the one is start with hyphen and usually abbreviations, for example, hyphen, XRP or hyphen
class path.
If we want to introduce a hyphen in between the name of the flag, we normally use two hyphens hyphen,
hyphen and in class hyphen path or single hyphen CP or single hyphen class path.
So usually single hyphen is used with letters and abbreviations and hyphen hyphen is used with the words
that have more than one part.
So module dash path or hyphen path, we use a hyphen hyphen, right?
So hyphen, hyphen, dri, hyphen, round or hyphen.
So this is the convention.
You don't have to necessarily follow these, but that's a good practice to follow this convention.
For example, instead of saying Java, hyphen, hyphen help, we can say Java hyphen H, that's also
the abbreviation.
So you can either use hyphen, hyphen help or hyphen etch, right?
So this is how we can set up our basically.
Commando agreements.
So now you can do the same thing even with the Java application which runs on the Java.
So command line arguments are passed to the Java application during the launch of the game and we've
seen this before that that's the string array args that the main method has, right?
JVM knows which class has the main method and the main method accepts a array of strings.
Right.
If you don't specify any arguments after the name of the main class on the command line when you run
the Java, then it means the string area arg is empty.
There is nothing there.
Right.
We can use a command line parser framework that already is available.
Now the question basically is when somebody passes a command line arguments right to your job application,
how do we grab those and transform them into the objects?
Remember your Java, your Java code.
Java is object oriented, so we have to kind of transform those command lines into objects or create
objects, set some of the fields or properties of those objects based on the command line arguments.
Now, the naive thing to do is to write, if else, a statements or a switch statement and go through
all the strings in that string array args.
And we manually write the parser somehow we manually write the logic down and then based on the command
lines we decide what kind of objects to create.
And that's that's possible.
But nobody does that right.
It's better to stick with a framework that has already been tested, and it provides a lot of nice and
flexible features.
Now, the framework that I recommend is called J Commander.
The source code is on the GitHub, you can just go to GitHub dot com slash CB USD and then DJ Commander
and then the online documentation is DJ Commander's org.
It has a very, very nice documentation.
That's also one of the reasons that I'm recommending this framework because it's documentation, it's
very nice.
It's also available on Maven, Grader or any other build tool that you use.
I personally use Maven.
It's very easy to group ID is com.
The abused artifact ID is j commander and the version you can just set it as latest version as of today
it's 1.82.
And basically the way this works is that you create empty objects and then you pass them.
And the commander has a static builder pattern which uses reflection to build the objects, or basically
it doesn't call the constructor.
You create empty objects and then you pass it to the commander, you pass the command line arguments
and the commander sets the the fields or the state of those objects.
Using reflection, it has a pass method to parse the string array arcs.
It uses reflection to accomplish parsing.
And then obviously the first question that you're going to ask is how does it know which fields to parse
or set values based on the command line arguments?
And it provides a very nice annotation feature which I will show you.
But first, let's look at the features.
Why am I recommending this commander?
Obviously, one of them is it has very nice documentation, very detailed, very nice examples, but
it's very easy and intuitive to use.
All complexity is hidden from the user.
You literally don't need to do anything.
It can pass multiple objects at the same time.
Let's say based on the command line arguments, you want to parse multiple objects, parameters that
are not set on the command line, get default values.
That's one of the nice features and I believe most of the frameworks that work in different programming
languages like Python, C++ or this one in Java, they have this feature that what if somebody what
if you have lots of parameters but somebody doesn't provide some values for some of the parameters.
So it makes sense that to design the this framework for Python parsing command line in such a way that
if, if one of the parameters is not set on the command line, it gets a default value, right?
Each Java field can get multiple names under command line.
As I mentioned, for example, Java, we can use either hyphen, hyphen help or hyphen H, right?
That's usually the convention we use.
And both of these hyphen, hyphen, help and hyphen should do the same thing.
So they map to the same command, right?
It has a rich online documentation, as I mentioned, and it works with Java collection as well, which
means you can even set a flag on the command line to say and give multiple values.
And then internally the commander can map all those value and build a list, release or a set or something,
which is the field of an object.
Now, a very simple example is here.
First of all, as I mentioned, the builder pattern that the commander follows.
It doesn't really directly call any constructor, so you kind of use it mainly for data classes or pogos
plain old Java objects.
So you just want to set some fields, right?
So you create an empty object and then basically pass it to the J commander and it parses the command
line arguments and then sets the values of the fields.
Right?
So create a class with an int field called value and then I'm going to assign it to command line flags
to for setting up this value.
The user can either give hyphen V and then a space and then the value or hyphen hyphen value.
I want both these commands or flags to map, to basically parse, to set the this int field value,
int field called value in an object.
So the first thing you do, obviously you add your j commander to the build path and we'll use Maven.
So it's very easy.
You just add the maven to the maven coordinates the dependency to your point file and after that you
create your class as usual, but then you annotate it with add parameter.
This is the nice annotation that the the the J commander framework provides and it has a list or array
of strings called names and then you can directly initialize it in with this nice syntax.
Right?
So this is an area of a string.
You can provide as many strings as you want or as many flags as you want so that they all map to the
same field.
Right.
A step to create an empty object.
I called my class test class.
It it it has an empty or default constructive, which doesn't do anything.
So you have to create this object.
And then you use the j commander.
Get the base.
They're ADD object and obviously you can add multiple objects, that's fine.
And then you call the build and then when you call the bell, it uses the reflection to basically figure
out what fields have been annotated, etc. So this build is mandatory and after that pass and you pass
the a string array arcs of the main method to it, and then after that it already has figured out which
fields have been annotated.
So it goes through the a string area arcs and then maps, all those command line or all those flags
to the to set the right values right.
And then once after that, if we say object that value this object, you will see that it's been properly
set.
So and then obviously we're going to run our job application on top of the JVM first to make sure everything
works fine, and then we'll figure out how to compile our job application with this capability into
a native executable binary so that when we launch that native binary, all these flags are still available.
We've already seen that how to include dependencies, because right now, in order to use this framework,
our job application is going to have a dependency, which is the commander we've seen.
We've gone into details how to work with Maven, when we want to compile to native executable, how
to handle the dependencies and eclipse ID basically takes care of everything.
So let's head to Eclipse and try to go through this example and have a good understanding of what's
going on.
So here's Eclipse.
I have this Maven project and in my file, if you look at the dependencies, I've already added a J
Commander version 1.82.
You just basically copy and paste this one, right?
J commander.
And after that maven grabs the repository, complete views.
And then in the j commander we have converters, default provider internals, partial validators and
lots of classes, right?
For integer parsing strings, other parameters.
This is the main annotation that we use parameter a string array names and then a string.
You can also add description whether it's required or not.
And this means that it has to, if you set it to be required, means that the user has to set it as
a flag on the command line.
It's not possible to give it a default value description.
Key default array or default entity is minus one.
Entity means usually you have one, which means when you set the flag, you only pass one parameter
or you can set it to have multiple values, whether it's a password or not.
And then you can also define your own converters how to convert the string that is passed to the command
line, to the actual value of the field, and then a lot of other capabilities.
I will have a full course on J.
Commander to go into the details.
But for now, we're just going to start with a very simple example.
All right.
So we have this test class.
It has a Field eight value.
And I want to parse these arguments such that essentially the user provides a flag, let's say.
So I want the user to provide hyphen, hyphen value and some value, let's say ten or hyphen V and some
value like 20, right?
Usually there is at least one space here.
Multiple spaces are fine.
It's not going to break the code.
But for now, I want to do this right.
So first, the very first thing that I do is create a test class here, right?
And then if I do a six out on object value, obviously it gets the default value because it hasn't been
initialized.
JVM will initialize it to zero.
So if I run this, I will get zero, right?
And I'm printing this one also.
So I will get zero.
And then if I want to run this using eclipse and pass command line arguments.
So what I need to do is go here and here, hyphen, hyphen, value ten.
Right?
So if I run this, I still don't get because right now I'm not parsing it.
So what I can do manually is say.
Basically I can write a for loop.
Um.
For ain't.
For example, I equals zero.
Less than that length.
Plus.
Plus I.
I can say if basically if args at index are equals equals hyphen hyphen value or args at index i equals
equals.
Actually this should be double code, not a single code, hyphen, hyphen, value or args at index i
is hyphen v.
Then we're going to say that object that value equals or basically integer dot parse int.
And then args add index I plus one.
Right?
So and then let's run this and now we still get zero.
Um.
Okay, let's see.
Let's run this.
Let's go back to our own configuration.
Hyphen, hyphen, value ten.
We're running this.
So let's do a six out on the ark.
So let's see.
Let's see what kind of command line arguments are past.
A string array.
Maybe we also print these so called args at index i.
So we have hyphen, hyphen value.
Uh, and so actually we shouldn't use double e quality equals this one or args equals hyphen hyphen.
So for string equality we have to use equals.
And now we get ten, right?
So this is how you can manually pass this error.
You have to kind of loop through this.
And then you you write a general for loop and then you write a lot of, if else, statements to figure
out at Index II which flags are passed.
And then once you find a flag, then you can figure out what to do.
You you want to parse it or somehow convert it to some sort of integer value or some other things,
right?
So run this and then this works fine.
But this is tedious and as if you have many, many objects, this, this for loop and if else statements
can become very long.
So we don't want to do this.
So then the question, how do we do that?
We're going to use a framework, right?
So use a J command framework.
So we are creating our empty objects and we want to set its field.
The very first thing that we're going to say, do this, we're going to annotate it with add parameter
and we're going to use the names, which is a string array, and then we're going to initialize it with
the flags, hyphen, hyphen value or hyphen V, right?
And then that's it.
That's all it takes.
And then here we're just going to say that J commander, new builder.
So J Commander only already only has this a new builder which uses the inner class builder that the
J commander has.
And after this we're going to say that basically add object.
And we're going to add our OBJ class.
So we are only going to build one object from this string.
RS And then after that we're going to build it returns the builder, right?
So the new builder builder and then add object returns the builder and in build returns the j commander.
So basically this is a fluent builder interface, fluent builder interface.
And then after we build it, we just tell it.
Now go ahead and pass it.
ARGs Right, that's it.
And so until this build the builder goes through all the objects that we add and then figures out which
ones have this annotation so that it knows which parameters to parse and after that utility now go ahead
and pass it.
So it loops basically it's more or less the same idea.
It just hidden from you.
So if we run this.
We still get ten, right?
And if I go ahead and change this to, let's say -25 and run it, I get -25.
So everything is working fine.
J Commander is a very nice syntax.
You don't need to manually do any.
And if I add a new parameter, let's say double
basically some basically let's say double x, right?
And all I have to do I can do add parameter and then names and then let's say a hyphen, hyphen x.
So if I go ahead and basically so object X, if I run this right now, we're not setting it.
So it gets the default value that the JVM says, but we can also give it a default, right?
So description, hidden order password requires.
So if you look at the parameter again, it has description at arity converter, hidden echo input help.
It does have the help.
Right.
If true, this parameter is for help.
If such a parameter is specified, requirements are no longer checked for their presence and order.
Right.
So these are all the details.
So we said this with the hyphen hyphen x and then pretty much we don't do anything else.
That's it.
You don't.
So if you manually write your own for loop, then if you add more parameters for parsing, you have
to go ahead and add more lines of code for if else statement and check for the flags.
Whereas in Commander, you could just add this annotation, your code doesn't change.
So if I go ahead and.
Into arguments, say hyphen hyphen X is 2.5 and then running it and my ex now gets 2.5.
It's very easy to use.
All right.
So then the question is, now we're using these.
How do we go about and converting it or compiling it to native executable binary?
So if I try to select this and run my native image.
If I compile this, this is most likely not going to work.
The reason is that we've we've said this before.
Right now, the native compiler doesn't know what's going on behind the scenes in the GE Command.
And we know that this uses reflection, uses reflection to figure out.
So let's see what error was given.
So it's it's pretty much giving us error that there are some reflections going on, which I don't know
about.
So it tries to do a fallback.
Now it tries to do a fall back as a rapper.
Right.
So so it uses refraction to figure out the annotations.
And then after that, it uses reflection again to set up basically the values.
Right.
All the parameters.
To access the parameters of all the objects that we register.
If I open up a terminal here, the native image is already telling me it's a fallback which requires
a JDK for execution.
So if I try to run the binary test class with, let's say, hyphen, hyphen, value 25, I could not
find our load.
So we know that when the fallback happens, we can't really run this.
So.
Let's delete this.
So what's the solution?
We know.
We've already seen how to deal with reflection.
We have to tell native image and create those configuration files.
And the way we do it, we run our application.
We the Java Trace, right?
But then because our application accepts command line arguments, we kind of need to go here.
So we are running the Java or Java from the VM and activating the agent lib for the native image.
And we are manually setting the class path and then Java type name.
This is our main class and we're passing some parameters, let's say hyphen, hyphen, value ten and
hyphen hyphen x 2.5.
So you only need to do this once because the tracing agent needs to know and you don't really need to
pass all of them.
Let's say let's only pass value and we will see that basically the compilation will work, right?
So.
So let's run this and our test class right now.
We didn't pass any value for X, so it says to the default.
And if you look at the matter in native image and then reflect config, you see that a lot of the j
commander classes I registered and then we have a name int and then Java and then our main class is
also registered for reflection.
So now if we go ahead and compile to native executable, remember the meta is our is on the class path
of the native image that we use.
Right.
So it's going to pick up on the meta inf.
So let's close these, select our class and then run our native image so it will automatically pick
up this matter.
INF And is a reflection config and hopefully it's going to work fine.
So let's wait for it to finish compilation.
No, that what we needed to do was to also pass some command line arguments because if you don't pass
when you run the job or tracing agent, we know that reflections happen in two places, one at the time
of the build and the other one at a time of passing.
So when we run our Java Trace agent, if we don't pass any command line arguments, we don't get all
the configurations.
So let's open up a terminal here.
So let's say hyphen hyphen value 25.
It works fine.
X gets the default value zero and then hyphen hyphen x 2.5.
And this doesn't work.
Right?
So the reason this doesn't work because we didn't register this hyphen hyphen x, so you really have
to run this with all the parameters.
And then so that in the configuration we know everything about it.
So let's go back and terminate.
So I'm going to delete the matter INF And then I'm going to also delete this binary.
And now what I'm going to do, I'm going to run my Java Trace agent.
But then also add hyphen, hyphen X, let's say -11.5, something to invoke this reflection that happens
for the X as well.
So let's run this and everything works fine.
And now if we look at the meta inf and then reflect config, we have two reflection fields.
One is double, the other one is eight.
Right?
So you have to register all these fields a little bit tedious.
It kind of defeats the purpose.
But if you just want to run your application on top of Gvm, obviously you don't care.
It's very easy.
But if you want to compile to a native executable, you have to tell a native compiler about all these
parameters and that use reflection.
And for that you have to run your application with a Java Trace agent at least one time and then pass
all the flags that your application will accept so that that configuration file, the reflect config
picks up on all the parameters that will be set or can be set on the command line.
So if we now select our class and then run our native image, this time everything should work fine.
We accept only two command line parameters hyphen, hyphen value or hyphen V equivalently, and then
hyphen hyphen X and then the native image has information about all these two parameters.
So let's wait until this finishes up.
And then.
We will test the result.
Almost done.
Done.
So let's look at let's open a terminal here.
And then let's run this.
So hyphen value 25, hyphen x 2.5.
Everything works fine.
We don't get any exception now for x because it's already in it was already in the configuration file
for reflection.
The other thing is now we can also test the other option hyphen hyphen, hyphen v still works fine,
right?
If we pass a different flag, let's say hyphen P, it's not going to work.
So we get an exception.
But no main parameter was defined in your class.
Right.
So that's kind of exception happens.
I believe we can configure it to kind of ignore that flag.
But for now and the other thing that you might already know, that the order of the flags don't matter,
hyphen, hyphen X, if we don't pass it, we get zero.
We can't set the required flag.
So if here we say that required equal to then and then we go ahead and compile.
We already have the basically metal.
So we just go ahead and compile.
Quickly.
Let's see what happens if we set the required to true.
But then we don't pass this flag at the right at the time we run our binary file.
Almost done.
All right, Don, let's refresh this.
We get the binary, let's open up our terminal.
And now let's see what happens if we don't set it exception.
The following option is required hyphen hyphen value or hyphen v.
Now it says that you have to have to pass it.
So we have to say hyphen v 12.
It works.
What if we pass a float?
It's going to give us exception saying that couldn't convert 12.5 to an integer.
So what's it saying?
That you have to make sure that this is all
this is all set.
Right.
So I hope you enjoyed this lecture and now have a good understanding how to easily use this command
and framework to set up flags for your Java application and then what to do when you want to compile
it to native executable binary.
You have to run it with the JVM using the tracing agent so that you you create the configuration file
for all the reflections that happen in the command there, and then the rest is very easy.
You just compile your application and all the flags stay the same.
I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.