Hello and welcome to these series of lectures on Grand VM Java Native Image.
This is one of the exciting topics for me personally because that allows you to write your Java application,
develop it very quickly.
Developing a Java application is much faster than developing, for example, a C++ application.
And then with the press of one button, you compile your Java application to an executable native binary
of your platform, like 64 bit CPU architecture and macOS or Windows and Linux, right?
So this is very exciting.
You get all the benefits of the Java, all the benefits that the Java programming provides, and then
eventually your runtime becomes as fast as a C++ program because you compile to native binary.
Now there are some pros and cons.
Obviously the pros for me personally are much better than the cons.
One of the cons you probably can guess if you're familiar with how Java works is that Java emphasizes
on the the dynamic compilation of your program, which means when you launch your job application,
the GVM or the Java virtual machine runs in an interpreted mode, which means each line of code gets
executed one by one, right?
And then after a while the gvm and the runtime analyzes your code, how it behaves, and which methods
are called more often than others.
And if some methods really do call to some methods, that passes a particular threshold which you can
configure at runtime when you launch your Java, then that method, that particular piece of code gets
compiled to the native binary, which is optimized for your platform.
Whereas in this case we're trying to directly compile your Java application to a native executable,
which means we don't get the benefit of dynamic compilation.
So all the compilation, all the analysis of the code appears at compile time instead of at runtime.
So this means you end up with something called a static compilation instead of dynamic compilation.
So I'm going to write it down here.
It's more like a static compilation of your code.
And then what happens then is that, you know, that Java provides some dynamic class loading in Java
reflection, which means intersecting your classes objects at runtime.
So then the question is usually this kind of stuff like reflection.
They're not very compatible with a static compilation because they rely on some sort of extra meta information
at runtime.
That's why the Java, when you launch your job application on Java, it has a particular piece of memory
called the meta space, which is reserved for basically storing information, meta information about
your classes and objects so that you can retrospect or basically use the reflection to see what properties
a class has or not.
Right.
But again, we will see that what we aim at at the current point of time, it's reached a very good
maturity with the release of Java 17, which was a long time support to support.
They also released a VM version that supports Java 17, and in this course I'm going to basically focus
on the Native Image tool that comes with the VM for Java 17.
I've tested it.
It's really working fine.
We will look at all the details, how to compile your job application, for example, if it has dependencies
on some other Java files on some other libraries, what if you have dependence?
What if your application actually uses Java Reflection API?
Is it supported or not?
What if you're using Java Native Interface?
Your classes have some native methods.
I will show you how to basically do that eventually.
The goal is we were going to write our job application developer application in Java instead of C++
and then we don't worry about memory management whether or not use raw point is a smart port and pointers
Java doesn't have any any of those concepts and you can kind of guess what happens with this kind of
static compilation is that the way the VM works in a general sense is that they provide something called
SVM, subsystem VM or subsystem virtual machine.
It's a dense version of the GM Java virtual machine.
And what they do is that not only they compile your application to the native binary, it also provides
a dense or compact compilation of their, for example, the garbage collector that comes with the JVM
and then or for example, the JVM itself.
It has components like class loaders, right?
So everything gets compiled and the sub sub VM, the SVM provides that infrastructure so that eventually
your code gets compiled.
One drawback you will see that is if you write the same application in C++ and in Java, write in C++,
you directly write your application, compile it to the executable binary.
In Java, you write your application and then compile it with native image and it creates an executive
executable binary.
You see, you will see that the difference in the size of the files in C++ executable is very small,
right?
It could be just a few kilobytes.
But in Java, when you use a native image, it becomes, let's say, at least ten megabytes or so.
Now obviously ten megabytes these days is basically nothing.
So compiling your application to native binary is very well worth it, right?
Ten megabytes compared to a few kilobytes.
Both of them are still very much acceptable.
Right.
And the reason for Java native image.
The reason it becomes large is because not only it has to compile your application, it has to provide
the infrastructure, which is the JVM itself in the binary, the garbage collector or the class loader,
all this stuff, right?
But one thing that we will see is that once you compile your application to native image, the startup
of your application becomes very fast.
Why?
Because now there is really no we know that when you launch your JVM, there is a warmup period.
When you launch your JVM, JVM has to first load all the class files that come by default with the JDK,
right?
Because your application might depend on them.
So JVM has to load all those class files into memory.
That takes time.
That's why sometimes people say that the JVM has a slow start up time, and then obviously the next
step is warm up time, whether or not the compiler dynamic compilation happens or not.
So in general, a static compilation allows your application to start up much faster.
And in the course of these lectures, I'm going to focus on developing command line applications, which
means you write your Java classes.
The entry point to your job application is the main method of a class, and then that main method accepts
some arguments and a string array of args.
And then those are the command line parameters that you pass to your application when you launch your
application.
So we will set when we will see that when you launch your when you compile two native executable binaries,
those command line API arguments become very useful.
Now they are the way that you interact or pass parameters your to your native executable binary.
Now let's start with first of all, how do we run a normal Java application?
Now obviously in order to develop a Java application, you have to write source files and then compile
them to the class files.
Class files are basically a compact version of your source file.
Those are the binaries that the Java virtual machine understands and converting the.
In order to do that, first you have to get a development kit or Java development kit, right.
So this is different from Java runtime.
Java runtime is basically the Java virtual machine.
So Java virtual machine is the runtime, which means once you develop your application now you want
to run it.
In order to run it, you have to load those class files into memory because class files are the blueprint
of how you're organizing the data.
Right.
So you're going to need a JDK or Java development kit.
And then right now I recommend you download JDK 17.
I believe Java 18 was also released, but it's not a long term support, so it's best to develop your
application, especially if it's a large application with a long time support version, right?
So JDK 17 is an Ltsc version and then you can use it.
And I believe they change the licensing also.
So that from JDK 17, you can in fact use it in your commercial production.
But the goal of these lectures that I'm presenting are not about commercial use.
It's just for spreading the knowledge of knowledge of Java.
All right.
So first you need a JDK and in the JDK, Java development kit comes with some applications and those
are applications are called the command line binaries or executable binaries.
So on Mac OS, here's a screenshot.
You, you install the JDK, you get a folder JDK, some version 17.
And inside that there is a folder called contents.
And then home.
This folder home is usually referred to as the Java home.
And inside the home directory there's always a directory being means binary, which means there are
command line applications that are the form of binary.
These are executable files.
All right.
And then you see there are a lot of command line tools or executable binaries that come with JDK.
They allow you to Java C is the Java compiler.
It allows you to compile your source file, which is a dot Java file into a class file, which is what
your JVM or runtime understands.
And then we also have the Java Virtual Machine or Java command line.
And this is basically what actually loads your class files into memory and launches your job application.
I will show you an example of how to actually write a class that has a main method and then how to launch
your Java application using this binary executable binary, which is Java.
So if you want to launch your Java application, you have to have an entry point.
So again, if you're familiar with Java, you know that you can develop your job application in two
ways.
One is an application that has a main method, which means it's an executable application.
You can run it or you package your project into a library.
It becomes it acts as a library.
It just has a it's a basically collection of class files that are just some that act as a library.
So you add them to other projects and you build upon them, right?
And as you can see in the bean directory there is a executable binary called Jar Jar means it allows
you to basically package your library as a archive file, which is a compressed version.
It has only the class files.
It usually doesn't include the source files.
And then a jar stands for Java Archive, which means it's a compressed version.
So Java Archive or Java file is a format of the zip file.
So it's very compressed.
The size is very small and we know that the Java is platform independence.
That's why you can use jar file on one platform to another and that's a very nice benefit on Java.
Right.
And by the way, when you use a static compilation and compile your job application to a native executable,
obviously these executables are not compatible on different platforms, which means if you compile for
the MAC OS, you cannot run it on Windows.
That's why I'm going to have separate lectures on how to compile your application on macros, how to
set up your tools in Windows, and then compile your Java application to the native binary in Windows.
Same with Linux.
Mac OS and Linux are much easier to deal with because they have a much nicer terminal interface.
Windows is a little bit tricky.
You have to do more work, but I will show you how to automate the process.
All right.
So you can launch your Java application if you want to build a basically executable Java application.
And the entry point is the main method of a class.
And we know that the main method is a static method, which means that the JV team has to be able to
access and run this method without even instantiating an object of your class.
That's the meaning of a static method, right?
And then the way you run, the way you compile your source file into or basically the way you compile
your source file into a class file so that you will be able to load them into JVM and launch your application
is using the Java compiler.
And then the way you launch your Java application is with this command line.
So you have the Java binary tool that comes with your JDK hyphen.
CPP means class path.
You have to provide the directories that include all the classes necessary for your application to perform.
If your classes have dependencies on other classes, you have to provide all these into a variable called
the class path.
And therefore the JVM is know basically is aware of which directory to search if it needs to load a
particular type.
Because each type, when the Java compiler compiles your source files, each type gets compile to a
separate class file.
And those are the blueprints for the JV team to understand what you're talking about.
And then you have to specify the main method of a class or basically the fully qualified name of a class,
that fully qualified name of the class that has a main method.
Right?
And then the Java JVM looks at these class searches in the class path in these directories to see if
we can find a classify that has this name.
If it does, JVM looks at it to see if it has the main method.
If it does, then it starts by running that main method and then continuing executing all the lines
of code in the main method of your class.
So you see in the binary failure of the JDK 17, there are lots of different basically binaries.
One of them, for example, JDB, is the Java debugger.
It helps you debug your code, scan it, it scans your application to see if it uses any deprecated
API jobs.
It also scans your application, tells you whether you're using what kind of modules you're using because
from Java nine JDK became modular, so they introduced the module system.
So if you want to see what kind of dependencies you have, JFR Java Flight Recorder, it's more like
inspecting the internals of the gvm to see what happens when your application launches.
Obviously when you compile to native executed binary, you don't have any of this, right?
There is no concept of the Java runtime, it's just binaries, operating system executes them and then
that binary only contains the CPU instructions.
Right.
That's how you compile to native binaries.
J package allows you to kind of package your Java applications in nicer format.
JS Shell is an interactive shell that they introduced from JDK nine, and it's more like a rappelle.
Read a print, evaluate something like that.
And then there are lots of other things.
I will have separate lectures to go into the depth about each one of these tools and how to use them.
In this series of lectures, we're going to just look at Java, C, Java, and again, at some point
we will switch to an ID and IDs, hide a lot of the details of the compilation, organizing your codes,
class path, etc. So you don't need to worry about things.
But right now I'm showing you this is JDK 17.
In order to get the Native Image tool, we have to download the graph LLVM, which it also provides
all the tools that come with the JDK right?
Your Java Java C, but Gradle VM comes with additional tools like the sub VM, SVM and the native image
tool.
So Grow VM is a separate thing that we need to download.
Now what happens when you launch your JV team or Java application through the Java binary tool, which
means you are creating a virtual machine, a runtime, and then that runtime already manages the memory
and then how to allocate the allocate object, etc. so you don't worry about those in the step one June
1st loads all the g class files.
These are the basically the API, the Java API that comes with the JDK.
So I'm going to type JDK API.
Right.
These are and the reason the JVM has to load all these into memory because your application may use
any of the classes that are in the API.
So JVM has to load all of them into memory.
And that's why some people say that the JVM has a slow start up time.
Obviously in the recent releases, with every release of JDK, they improve the performance of the Java
or the JVM Java virtual machine.
So the startup becomes faster, the classes become more compact, they have less footprint, the gvm
has a consumes much less memory.
And we will see that when you.
Compile your Java application to native executable binary.
The memory footprint becomes significantly smaller, which means now your native bind, your java application
in the format of the native binary consumes much less memory.
That's another complaint that people usually have when compare, for example, C++ applications to Java
application.
They usually say that job applications are a memory consumer, which means the Java applications consume
more memory than an equivalent C++.
But that's the way that but with the memory, you can always configure your Java.
So when the JVM loads the class files from JDK into memory, JVM compiles some of the classes.
So it's not just loading them into memory.
JVM has a year of compilation and because obviously running all loading them and in executing all of
these JDK APIs, the classes in the interpreted mode is not very efficient.
That's why Java as as soon as it loads them into memory, it also tries to compile a few of them, not
a full optimised way, but in a in one of the tiers of compilation so that it's easier to work with
is faster.
And clearly these compilations and loading of all these JDK API takes time, hence a slow start of time.
I'm going to put this low in the double code, which means it depends on which version of the JDK you
use, right?
So the newer version of the JDK is everything improves, the performance improves, the application
becomes faster.
So once the JVM is done with all the JDK classes and then it just reaches your application class files,
so JVM loads them, let's say the class file from your application that has the main method.
And then launches it.
It starts executing all the codes in the main method and after a while the JV team profiles your application.
So JVM comes with a profiler that looks at your code and see which parts of the code are executed or
called more frequently than another.
And if there is a threshold and some of some pieces of the code in your application, pass that threshold.
Then the JIT compiler Java just in time compiler, which is basically dynamic compiler, may compile
some of the classes and there is a flag actually at runtime that you can pass to your JVM that shows
which methods are getting compiled.
So this still also takes time, right?
This is called Dynamic Compilation and it takes time.
This depends on how long the application is running.
So again, it goes into the warm up period of your application because the JVM profiler has to look
at your code for some time.
Right, to decide which parts of the code are being executed more frequently, and therefore to decide
whether or not to compile them to a native executable.
But then if we say that, okay, so this is great, Java is great because its API is much easier than
C++.
You don't need to worry about memory management, any of those.
But then the problem is the slowest startup time.
And then, um, and then one way to solve that is to execute compile your application to a native binary
and that completely solves the as low as startup time because everything has been already compiled.
There is no extra compilation at runtime, everything has already been compiled to native binary.
You just launch your application after it's been compiled and then the operating system and the hardware
just runs your code, right?
So this called a static compilation and I hope in these series of lectures you learn very well how to
how to do this.
So I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
Please stay tuned.
I'll see the next one.