Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We are going to continue our discussion on compiling Java applications using a VM native image.
And so far we've looked at the fundamentals of Java applications, how we launch them.
Using the Java runtime, which is a Java command.
A prerequisite is that you have to compile your source files into the class files because those are
the binary files that the Java or the Java tool understands.
And then we said we said that eventually the goal is with the native image to transition from launching
our Java application on top of a JVM, which is a virtual machine to directly compile it to the native
executable that runs by the operating system.
And then we discuss a very important topic which was command line arguments and we said that there is
a subtle difference between command and command line arguments for C++ binary applications when you
write your application in C++ and the Java.
And we said that the similarities are both require a main method in C++ or C by convention.
The return type of A main is INT.
But in C++ or in modern C++, you are not really required to return zero.
But then in Java it's void because it doesn't make sense to basically return anything from Main.
And then we said that the main difference is the command line arguments that you pass to a C++ application
or a binary or executable binary that has been compiled that had a C++ source and compile to Native
and Java.
And we said that the main difference here is that Java, when you launch your application with the JVM
or the Java Command Line tool, right, there are three types of arguments that you can pass.
One is your application arguments is this string array.
The other one is system applications.
Those are the parameters that you pass to the JVM.
We're using hyphen de key equals value, right?
And then the third one is just the global environment variables that are available for your terminal.
Basically, you launch your Java application inside a terminal, right?
Terminal is the application you use is what's what you use to communicate with the operating system.
Now let's head back here.
And previously we saw that we developed this application.
It has a hello it's a hello world class has two dependencies and inside our bash RC basically we defined
a class path and added all these to the class path.
Test.
Test two.
Test three.
So that we don't need to specify the class path each time, each time that we want to recompile the
application.
And we said that when you launch your application in the terminal, if this global environment variable
called class path and all caps, remember these global environment variables are all caps.
If these is defined for your terminal, the Java compiler and the Gvm or the Java command line tool,
both can pick it up and also add these to the list of directories that they can search into.
And then we said that.
One.
One point that I didn't directly mention is that when everything is available on your path or class
path, then if you need to compile this helloworld java, which has a dependency on car and machine,
then if you just run the Java Sea Command on this helloworld Java, the Java compiler tries to basically
compile all the dependencies first.
So what I mean is that if I delete this car, that class and this machine class and then this helloworld
class, right?
Right now I only have the source files and let's make sure that we have access to this class path.
Yes, it is.
And now we are inside this test directory, let's say Java C and then.
Hello World Java and it's able to compile this because it also is aware of the class path environment
variable and not only it compiles the Helloworld Java, but before that it also searches for the dependencies
which are the car type and the machine type.
And those are also available on the class path, right?
Those source files are available so that the Java compiler automatically compiles them first and then
compile the the main Java class.
So basically what I'm trying to say is that it's not actually you don't need to go one by one and compile
your Java files and then eventually get to the class that has the main method.
You just make all those Java files available on the class path and then once you run the Java compiler
Java Command on your on your main class, the class that has the main method, it automatically picks
up or searches for the types, the dependencies of your particular class and then compiles all the dependencies
first and then comes back and compiles the main class.
So it's relatively easy.
It's not that complicated, right?
Obviously, you can go ahead and individually compile the car and machine and that's what we do.
We did previously, but it's not necessary.
The Java compiler has become very smart in terms of automatically picking up on all your dependencies
and then and then compiling all the dependencies first.
Now, now that we have this, we saw that we have three types of arguments.
So a string args and then a system properties which is hyphen D key call value.
And then you pass these application arguments after typing, writing the name of the main class.
These hyphen dx key call value are passed to the Java application or the JVM.
So these are the you type these before typing the name of the main class.
And then there are global environment variables.
These are the global environment variables that are available to the terminal at the time that you run
your basically a Java application.
Now if I say Java and then Hello World, it's going to work fine because I don't need to specify the
class path because I've already specified the directories that my application needs inside this class
path environment variable and Java is aware of that.
So it picks up any and note that.
So let's do this one more time and we're going to pass ARG one, ARG two and then as you can see, basically
it says that our count is two anything that you type after the name of the main class and there is a
space there, then it counts as an argument to your job application part of this string array.
And basically.
But then anything that comes.
But then you can also pass a system environment.
So know that here in the source code we're trying to find if a system property called name is said.
And because right now we didn't set it.
Therefore it comes as null.
But then we also check for an environment where we're called later home and if we find it, then we
try to look at the version of this PDF later, which resides inside the later home directory.
Right?
And we get the execute that command in terminal.
We hook it up back to basically the JV team and in JVM can print it back to Gemini.
So let's look at this.
So Java hyphen D name equals a bob and then the name of the main class.
Hello world.
And then arg one, arg two.
And as you can see now, the name is System Property.
Is that all right?
Now, previously I mentioned that what happens?
The question is what happens to these system properties when you compile your Java application to native
binaries, right?
Because when you compile your application, then you don't use the Java application anymore, you just
directly launch it.
And I've already done this.
I've already compiled the this application to a binary native executable binary called Hello Helloworld.
Obviously in the future lectures we will see how to do it.
But then right now I'm in this test directory.
So if I say hello world arg one or two and as you see it still works.
It tells me that these command line arguments, we have two command line arguments.
The first one is ARG one, the second one is ARG two.
But this name comes out as null, right?
And then it is still searches for this global environment variable later home.
It finds it and then it looks at the version of the PDF later.
Everything works fine.
So our Java application now it's a native executable binary.
We can directly launch this application.
The question is what happens to those system argument hyphen D key value.
Now we can test it if I say hello world and then pass a command line argument that starts with hyphen
de name equals bar.
And as you can see now, this is very interesting that the way this native executable binary works,
that it actually differentiates between the command line arguments that start with hyphen DX and the
other ones, then don't start with hyphen de.
As you can see, it is still tells me that I have two command line arguments or basically two arguments
inside this string array, which are the arguments to my Java application.
But the interesting name was Bob, which means now this, this is passed as the system property.
So even if you compile your Java application to native executable binary, it is still recognized as
system properties and you can specify them directly as command line arguments when you launch this executable
binary, but then it automatically differentiates between these system properties that start with hyphen
DX and the others that don't start with hyphen dx.
Right?
So it automatically understands this.
So nothing gets messed up in your process of compiling your job application into native executable binary.
You can still see it set this system properties and they will behave as system properties that you pass
to your JVM.
Right now.
This is obviously different from a C++ application in C++.
They don't understand this hyphen.
DX So it just means you have three command line arguments.
But here, because your native executable binary inside of it, it has a compact version of Java.
So it can differentiate between hyphen DX parameters and then regular parameters that you pass your
application.
All right.
Now finally, we want to now start with the default tool.
And obviously, in order to compile a Java application to native binary, we have to have a compiler
and that's a platform compiler or which is called a default toolchain.
Every operating system comes with its own compiler vendors usually.
So these compilers are either proprietary, which means that people who develop the operating system
provide these compilers, or this could be open source.
For example, in case of an open source operating system like Linux, there are open source compilers
that can compile applications for the Linux operating system.
So let's start with Mac OS default toolchain.
So Platform Toolchain are compilers that compile source code to binaries for CPU and usually they're
developed for C or C++ application.
Obviously, older programming languages like Pascal or those ones also have their own compilers.
In general, there is no restriction on what kind of programming language you use as long as there is
a compiler for that programming language that can compile to native binaries for the CPU.
So not only the operating system is important, but the architecture of the CPU is important because
different CPUs use different basically instruction sets, right?
For example, arm CPUs have a different architecture than x86 or x 64 Intel or AMD CPUs.
Therefore, the kind of instruction sets that they use is also different.
For example, you might have heard that x 64 CPUs like AMD and Intel, they use a six card architecture,
which is a complex instruction set, whereas arm CPUs use a simplified version of the instruction sets
called the risk or reduced instruction set, which means arm instruction sets are much easier, but
complex instruction sets in the Intel or AMD CPUs means we want instructions.
You can execute more complicated tasks, but it requires more complicated circuitry.
So more power consumption.
That's why arm CPUs have basically much lower power consumption, for example.
Right?
So right now we're just not we don't focus on the hardware for now.
Let's just assume you typically have a CPU, which is X 64 architecture.
If you have any other CPU like ARM, then you have to find a compiler that allows you to compile your
source code to native binary.
And every platform, every operating system has to provide some sort of default tool change so that
people can develop applications for that platform, for that operating system.
And the reason that different operating systems have different compilers because the kernel that they
use are different kernels, are basically a very a group of files.
So let's say operating system, they all also developed with C or C++ and they provide an API for others
some functions, right, for the developers so that the developers can use those functions to call some
basically to perform some hardware operations, reading from the disk, for example.
So for example, in C++, if you just use a file input, a stream or FS stream or output file stream,
something like that, those have calls to the kernel files right in Windows or MAC OS.
The kernel API is different.
Therefore you cannot when you come.
While your application on different operating systems, the binaries are different.
That's why the binaries are not compatible.
So Mac OS, you can just go ahead into App Store, install Xcode.
It's a very big application.
I think it's about 12 gigabytes or so.
But in fact for just trying to compile applications, you don't need to install the entire Xcode because
part, part of the code is just gooey that comes with it and it provides a lot of tools for developing
applications for different hardware like iPhone, iPad, etc. But we're just interested in getting the
compiler that allows us to compile for Mac OS.
Right?
So you can just use the toolchain that comes with the Xcode and it's called command line tools, right?
So either go ahead and install the Xcode app from App Store or just open up a terminal and type Xcode
hyphen select hyphen hyphen install.
So if we go, let's go back to the PowerPoint, let's open up a new terminal.
And if we just say Xcode, select, hyphen, hyphen, install, it gives me an error saying that the
command line tools are already installed so there is no update for it.
If you want to update something, go to the software update to install updates.
But right now I've obviously I've already installed the command line tools and therefore there is basically
no reason to install it the first time.
If you have not installed it, you can either use this command or just open up a terminal in macOS and
type, for example, C++.
If you haven't install it again, the terminal recognizes that you're trying to use the command line
tools, a compiler, the platform compiler.
So it opens up a prompt and asks you whether you want to install the command line tools and you just
say, yes, it downloads some stuff.
All right.
So by default, this command line tools comes with Apple Clang compiler and then when you install it,
it actually creates aliases.
So we know some people prefer a C++ command on the terminal to compile their applications.
Some people prefer C++ to compile their C++ application.
Some people prefer GC to type GC to basically compile their C applications or clang to basically compile
their C applications.
And you see all of these commands when you install it, all of these commands become a symbolic reference
to the same thing, to the same X code, ab contents, developer, user, and then basically the same
thing.
So these are not different things.
You're just using the apple clang.
These are just aliases depending on what you want to do, right?
So and G plus, plus, as you can see, it goes to library developer command line tools SDK, Mac OS
user includes C++.
So this is the directory that has all the header files for the C++ compiler that comes with Apple Clang.
And this is a proprietary, so it's not open source and then it's in the being directory of the Xcode,
right?
Xcode app contents, developer tool chains and then XY toolchain user bean.
So if you run C++, it just points to the same directory being directory and same header files.
Right.
So the same thing.
JCC and then.
Same thing.
And then Klang also same thing points the same day.
So all of these are the same.
And these aliases get generated when you are when you install your application.
And if you want to check that your application is successfully installed, right?
Command line tools are installing applications.
Xcode App Contents Developer And there is the inside the developer there is a tool change and then Xcode
default dot xy toolchain.
This is a directory you can open it right click view the package contents and then there is a directory
there that you can check.
So if you install it and you want to double check, you just type for example, G plus plus hyphen,
hyphen virgin.
And if it shows you that G plus plus is available, the directory is being directory of the code.
Everything is set up correctly.
And previously we also actually we wrote a C++ application which prints something to the command line
and also picks up on the basically on the command line arguments.
We also had a class a user defined type called car.
We overloaded the output stream operator so that we can push it directly to the console.
And this was equivalent to basically overwriting the two string method in Java, right?
We said that in C++ classes don't implicitly inherit from a master class like object or something.
So they by default they don't have any insertion operator or to a string operator.
So you have to overload them as global functions.
And then we saw that basically let's go back here, let's go one level up.
So one level up and then go into the example.
And then we saw that if we say G plus plus example, dot CP and then we want to name the output file
something else.
So hyphen oh and then my app.
And if this doesn't give us any error, it means the compiler is compiling fine all the included header
files like our iOS HTML is available to us and then we are able to.
And then my app and then we saw that you can pass command line arguments.
Everything works fine for a C++ application.
It doesn't matter if your command line argument starts with hyphen DX, it just treats it as a regular
argument.
Right?
Whereas we saw that for the Java application, this will get treated differently because there is an
underlying JVM that also accepts the system properties instead of command line properties.
All right.
So this was the introduction to the macros default toolchain.
In the next lecture, I will show you the basically the Linux and Windows default tool change.
I'll show you how to install them, especially Windows, Mac, OS and Linux are much easier to deal
with in terms of developing applications because they either by default come with their compilers or
it's very easy to install the Mac OS.
It's very easy.
Linux usually comes by default with the compiler, especially if you install a popular distribution
like Ubuntu, which is also my favorite.
It definitely comes with the GCC, which is default toolchain for Linux.
You can also for example, install clang on Linux because it's open source, but you cannot install
for example, Apple clang for Linux because Apple clang, first of all, it's not compatible.
Second of all, it's not open source.
So I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see you in the next one.