Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We are going to finish our discussion on how to use JNI when we are compiling our job application to
native executable binary.
And we saw that the way to do it is to add the compiler to input our resource, which is a dynamic library
that has bindings to basically Java native methods and then put it on the class path and make sure that
we load it in a platform independent way using the class loader.
So we asked class loader, hey, search for a system resource.
And then we said that once we get this, we can open a platform independent, a stream to read the binary
contents of that, right?
And then we set that unfortunately system that load the method doesn't accept a binary stream, so we
have to give it a file that already exists on the host operating system, the file system.
So we kind of need to grab all those binaries that the native image already includes in the final file
and then copy the or basically extract them out using the copy method that the files provides and then
put them back as a new file.
Right?
And then after that we can just get the absolute path of that and then load it.
And this approach worked and we set it optionally.
We can also ask the JV team to delete that on exit and we said that this is not very efficient.
If every time the user runs the program we extract the binaries, create a new file, and then after
the program terminates, we delete it.
This is not definitely not a efficient way.
So if I go back to my eclipse, what we did eventually was to first create an abstract file here and
then check if it's already exists, which means the very first time that the user runs the application,
we want to grab the binaries and extract it.
And then the second time or the later times when the application is run, we check that if this file
already has been extracted means it's already been cached.
So we don't need to like extract the binaries again.
We just go ahead and use the cached version which has been already extracted.
Right.
And we said that this approach works even in the Java.
If you run your application with JVM, it still works fine just because it just grabs the binary.
It's here on my I just have to be careful about the working directory when I run it inside eclipse.
The working directory is the project folder.
That's why it extracts this file.
My leave the die lib here and then the second time it just checks if the file already exists in my working
directory and the name of the file my lib that w if it is it just goes ahead and load.
Get the absolute path and load it.
This JVM loads that dynamic library and then our native method, this dynamic library has already binding
so and then the native method works just fine.
Now one thing that I would like to mention is that usually when we develop, we have dynamic libraries
that provide bindings for native methods to C++ functions.
The extension is, first of all, the extension doesn't matter because it's just the JVM only cares
about the binary actual binaries of this file which instructs the CPU what to do.
Right?
So normally the convention is to rename or set the extension to JNI lib.
So that's the convention for JNI dynamic libraries.
Obviously Platforms Macros prefers the convention of that DI lib Linux prefix, the convention of that.
So and Windows prefers the convention of that DLL.
But at the end of the day for JNI, JVM doesn't care about that because it just cares about the binary
content of this file.
And normally when you look at the professional Java projects that use JNI bindings, you see that there
are some dynamic libraries that are called JNI lib.
So that's one convention.
So I'm going to rename this and then obviously we want to also rename this file and maybe we can also
rename this.
Okay.
Again, the code works fine because whatever this file is, we ask it to get us the absolute path and
let's delete the previous file that we extracted.
If we run this, this is still going to work.
Fine.
The first time we call it, it's going to extract the JNI dynamic library.
My lib jane lib.
The second time that we run it is going to realize that it's already been cached extracted.
So we're not going to go through the copying again and just we use the cache version.
And then the last thing that I would like to mention is that as I mentioned, typically we don't want
to we we don't want to cache.
In the current working directory, we want to cash in a very specific location.
That's because if we compile our application to native binary, which we already did right.
This one, let's let me open up a terminal here.
And if we run the application.
Last time we ran it, it extracted the binaries in this current working directory so it realises that
the file already exists and just loads them into memory.
But then the problem is that if somebody moves this executable file to another directory and the operating
system, then because the file doesn't exist in that particular directory, then we have to extract
the file again.
So this is not an ideal case and what we prefer to do is to cache it for a particular directory and
that's a user's home directory.
User's home directory, right.
And normally on Mac OS and UNIX, the caching happens in hidden directories.
Usually they start with dot something.
So if I open up my home directory on my mac OS, you see these are non hidden folders.
If I show up there, if I show the hidden directories, you see there are a lot of directories related
to the applications that are installed.
For example, Anaconda for Python management, Eclipse also has some caching going on or some log files,
etc. is stability.
For example, as you can see, this is for stability.
We programming Java and you see it has obviously a stability has some platform dependent um calls right.
Because it's a window tool, gooey right graphical interface and you see the way they extract it in
this hidden directory stability.
But then cache or extract is JNI libs which are basically dynamic leaves that have the bindings to the
native methods that stability uses and they use this convention lib and then the name of the platform,
what's the architecture?
And then eventually the name which ends with and I'll write again.
The extension generally doesn't really matter for JVM as long as this is a binary that has been properly
compiled for this platform and for this CPU architecture.
So we're going to use the same convention.
So we're going to use the same convention, and our convention is going to be we're going to say Dot
my Java app, right?
And then inside of this, we're going to have Lib directory.
And inside of this we're going to have basically.
Basically our platform or OS.
And inside of this we're going to have a CPU architecture and then inside of this we're going to extract
the dynamic library.
Right?
And this applies to the current user for each user has a different home directory.
So with this approach, putting in the user home directory obviously means if multiple user is using
it, then if everyone needs to run it so that the cache happens and sometimes you don't want this,
you want to install it for all users or cache the file for all the users.
So you put it somewhere outside the home directory, more like in the root or some somewhere else for
example, being depends on the filesystem, right?
So for now we are limiting ourselves to each user and the way we're going to do this.
So we create the file.
But instead of saying working directory first, we have to we have to get the user a home directory.
Right.
How do we do it in Java?
It's very simple.
Again, it's it's a system property.
So we say a string home is a system that get property and then we're going to say user dot home.
All right.
So let's start with this.
I'm going to copy these basic commands out.
Let's do a C out, make sure that our home directory is correct.
Let's go here.
And it says users and then the name of the user.
Everything looks good.
So the name, the next thing that we want to check is the OS, right?
So we're going to say that a string OS name is or just OS is.
Um, uh, we're going to, uh, say, see to get property and we're going to say that, uh, always
start name and do excel on the OS.
Let's also check this one.
Says Mac OS.
Obviously we prefer to do it to lowercase and then we're going to remove the white spaces.
So replace all.
And we're going to say any white space, replace it with underscore.
So let's run this again and Mac OS.
So now this works fine.
And then a.
The other thing is the next one is the architecture, right?
So a string architecture is systems that get property.
And the property we're going to look at and look at is a believe OS dot arch.
So let's see out arch.
And he says 86, 64.
Right.
So now we have all these three properties and what we're going to do, we're going to create the directory
hierarchy.
My, my Java app, Lieb OCP architecture and none of this, my java app doesn't exist.
LEAP Directory doesn't exist.
The OS name CPU architecture.
So we're going to say path path.
We're going to use Java IO and we're going to say paths, use the paths, the utility class and get.
And in the gate we're going to say that it's going to be percent s and then
basically.
We can say that.
We can either put them with forward slash or use past that file separator.
So let's say a string CEP is file dot separator.
Let's get it.
And then we're going to say that person is for home percent as for separator and then um, or we can
just say, um, home plus CIP plus, um, OS plus plus, uh, arch.
Uh, we actually need to have the lib also there.
So lib plus CEP plus something like that.
So this happens and then we're going to create all these things.
So first of all, let me look at the home directory right now.
I don't, uh, so let's, uh, remove this previous one here.
So right now I don't have any my job app here.
So let's, uh, do a see out on P and then we're going to say files, this is a utility class and then
create directories and we don't want, we want to use the default attributes.
And here we're going to just put p so this and this throws IO exception obviously.
So we have these and note that we cannot throw this IO exception in a static block declaration.
We cannot say a static and throw something.
So we kind of need to handle it here directly.
And then so we create directories and if already exists, if already exists, it doesn't do anything.
It doesn't do anything, which is good.
I mean, if we don't need to check if these directories exist, if they exist, this just doesn't do
anything right.
It doesn't delete them and then recreate them.
So if you run this, hopefully everything goes fine.
So we're creating these directories, lib macros and then x 84, 86, 64 in the user home.
Okay.
Actually, we made a mistake.
We want to say, um, um, uh, home and then dot my Java app.
Okay, my Java app, for example or my, my app, something like that or my Java app and then plus zip
plus lib plus plus OS plus app.
So now this grace is hidden directory.
So let's run these.
And this is our directory that we are created.
If I look at my home directory, I should see a my Java app here.
Yes, lib is there mac os x x 8664 and this is fully automatic.
If I compile my application, give it to somebody else, they run it on Windows, for example.
This changes to Windows.
Maybe they may run it on a some other machine, linux machine that has arm then
then they have to basically this directory hierarchy will change know that obviously the problem is
that because we are compiling to native executable then then obviously we have to compile on each separate
platform.
So I'm right now compiling a mac OS, I cannot give it to somebody to run it on Linux, for example.
So that thing, this has to happen basically on decomposition has to happen on separate platforms,
but the Java code remains the same, this code remains the same.
We just grab it and compile it on different platforms.
So after we create these directories, we kind of go through a basically all the other stuff.
Right now we need to cache the.
I'm casetify.
So when you file.
But then now the name of the file.
We already have this path, right?
We just say maybe P.
Plus we just and then we already have the separator separator plus.
So this should work fine.
This is the name of the file.
And then hopefully everything works fine.
So let's run this and.
So we run into this exception because we forgot to change the file here.
So obviously we has to change.
We have to change it.
We just say delete the gate, absolute path.
That's it.
So we grab it.
We create the file based on that path that we created that directory hierarchy in the user home directory.
And then we give the name that we want to extract.
And then we're saying that if it doesn't exist, then we go ahead and open a stream binary stream from
our native file, native image and to this path which is the user home directory all the way to this
file name.
Remember, this path has to include the name of the file also.
And then if it does, if already exists, we don't do anything, we just try to load it into memory.
So if you run this.
Everything works fine.
And he says extracting the Jrny dynamic library, which means it didn't exist and we extracted it and
now we're going to run it one more time.
Now it says Using cache to generate dynamic library.
All right, now what I'm going to do, I'm going to obviously delete the previous ones that we compiled
and then we're going to also delete this one.
And what we're going to do is I'm going to select these and let's also delete our metal and quickly
run with Java Trace agent to recreate everything.
It looks fine.
And then what I'm going to do is just compile to the native binary for my platform for macros and then
we're going to run it.
The other thing is we're going to try to do after we compile, we run it and then we move it to different
directories.
We run it again to make sure that regardless of which working directory we run our application, it
always grabs the same cache file which is in the user's home directory.
So the compilation is going quickly.
It probably ends very in a few seconds.
And what I'm going to do.
I'm going to go back to my home directory and I'm going to delete this directory hierarchy that we already
created.
And this is our application.
Let's see if there was an auto.
No, there is no terminal.
So you open a terminal here.
All right.
And let's run our application.
Everything works fine.
It detects our CPU.
Now it says AMD 64.
Right.
And then it actually don't.
When we run with JVM, it the naming was Xe 8664.
But when we run with a native image which uses JVM, it uses this naming.
AMD 64 and then extract the JNI Dynamic Library and then Hello World from C++.
So everything worked fine.
If we look at our home directory, we have this my Java app dot my Java app live Mac OS X and then AMD
64 and then my leap generally.
So if I run this again it now it's using the cache dynamic library which is this one from the home directory.
Right.
That my Java app live mac OS AMD Mail.
Now what I'm going to do, I'm going to actually let's move this to another directory.
Let's say move it to this example directory.
All right.
And then let's go back to our terminal and then we do see the and n example.
So we have our executable right here and in Java.
Now previously before caching in the user home directory, we were caching the dynamic library in the
current working directive, which means if we move the application from one directory to another, a
new copy of that dynamic library would have been generated.
But now if we run this, it is still says using cache change dynamic library because we cached it in
a place that is kind of like a central place.
Regardless when the user logs in they have their home directory.
And regardless of where they run our Java app or compiled application from it, the cached file, the
cache dynamic library is always in the home directory, so pretty much only the very first time they
run the application from some directory, it gets cached in the user home directory and after that basically
the cached version is used.
Now sometimes you're developing application, obviously the newer versions, then you have to update
maybe the dynamic library, you add more native methods to your job application.
So the question is how do we deal with that, right?
Because right now we we assume that if the file exists, then we're not going to extract the file again.
Right?
So what we can do, we can simply put a flag or something for checking the version, like a static flag
in our application.
And then every time we release a new version, not only we check if the file exists, we also check
whether the the application version has changed.
If it hasn't, then basically we don't need to extract the dynamic library again.
So I hope you enjoyed this lecture and now have a really solid understanding what actually happens.
We compiled a native binary.
We write a platform independent code in such a way that we can extract the binaries from our native
file and cache the dynamic library somewhere so that wherever the user runs, the application from that
cached file is accessible.
And then eventually we have to get the path to that cache file and pass it to system that load to be
able to successfully load that dynamic library.
And the JVM can use those to binding use those bindings for native methods.
So please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.