Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We saw how to download Growl VM native image and now let's look at more details about VM native image.
Now we saw that native image doesn't by default come with the growl VM and we saw that growl beam is
built on top of a JDK, usually open JDK.
And what it means is that it has the JDK, all the command line tools that come with the JDK also built
in the graph VM, but then it has some extra command line tools like Juju, which was the growl updater,
and we use that with the install command to install the native image.
And the native image is an executable binary from being a folder inside lib kvm.
So when you install Java VM here, I installed for example, VM Community Edition version 11.
The most recent version is 17.
So I recommend you install VM 17.
And then in the contents home there is a lib directory and inside that there is a SVM which is called
the substrate VM.
And then inside there is a bing directory and then native image is there.
Now we saw that in the actual being directory, which is inside the home directory, there is a symbolic
link to the actual executable file which is native image and to the operating system or to the terminal,
the executable binary and it's symbolic links their equivalent, right?
So usually you create you put your executable file somewhere and you can create a symbolic links to
them and put them in, put them in different directories.
So the native image compiles your executable class, a class that has the main method and we have already
seen this in the previous lectures.
It can also compile the required Java modules and also the garbage collector.
So basically when it compiles your Java application to a native executable binary, it actually there
is a JVM already compiled to native binary and also it has all the necessary components like garbage
collectors, etc..
So you are still sure that if your Java application that was running on top of the JVM didn't have any
memory leak or resource leak, once you compile it to native binaries, it will not have a memory leak
as well.
However, I will show you what happens when you compile to native binary and the memory usage of your
native binary after you compile.
Your application is much smaller than when you run your application on a JVM.
That's just because how JVM requests memory from the operating system, right?
So the memory footprint becomes a small error, but and then the execution time or the start time becomes
much faster.
But then the question is, what's the benefit of the JVM?
And we saw that previously there are some benefits on running your Java application on top of a JVM,
right?
When you when you compare it with the with the native execution.
And the main benefit is the JIT compilation, which means first of all, JVM is lazy loading.
It does lazy loading.
If you if you have lots of classes on your class path but you never use them, JVM doesn't load them
into memory.
That's one thing.
And then the Git compilation, which is a dynamic compilation, happens at runtime, and it only happens
for the methods that you mostly use, you mostly call, right?
So a lot of methods in reality, they don't need to be compiled to exit to native code.
But then when you compile your entire application to native code, obviously everything has to be aesthetically
compiled.
So at the end it can create a native executable binary which has a much faster startup time.
So it's very cool, right?
Clearly it has some limitations.
One of the there are a couple of limitations.
We know that currently Gravel VM supports Java 17, which is very good.
It works great for simple Java applications, especially the Java applications that you develop based
on like trying to develop a command line tool.
The final executable binary is much larger than a jar file, which we already know that because the
jar file is just the class files from your source code.
The JDK class files are not included in your Java, but when the VM native image compiles your application,
it also includes everything all the class files from the JDK and even a JVM itself.
Right?
A very compact version of the Gvm and Garbage Collector.
So when you compile your application, your native image could be 11 megabytes.
Whereas if you just package your Java application as a jar or executable jar, it could be just a few
kilobytes, right?
So the size is different.
But then the fact that even ten megabytes of a size these days is very small file size, you really
don't need to worry about the fact that native compilation causes a larger size.
And in general, the native image at the moment has a very weak support or kind of non-existing support
for the graphical tools that the Java provides, like the swing or Java effects.
So pretty much all the Java frameworks at the moment are not supported, which means if you develop
a swing application, there is a high chance that it's not going to work after you compile it to native
image.
But again, for the command line applications, it works very well.
If your Java application has a main method and take some arguments from the user and then it does some
stuff, you can definitely compile it to native binary and it's going to work much better, much faster
with consuming less memory for our simple Java projects, Native Image is a good tool for creating a
native executable.
Make sure that your file has a declaration of the main class inside its manifest.
That file.
So this is a topic.
We will come back and later look at it.
But the idea is that so far we've tried to basically give the native image, the class path and then
also specify the main.
That declares that has the main method, right?
So we run the native image on the main class, but you can also run the native image on a jar file.
So you package your project as a jar file and then run the native image on the jar file.
And in order to make it executable, you want to make sure that the jar file actually has a manifest
file inside of it.
And usually in the manifest file there is a line that tells the whatever runtime that's running this
jar file, which class is the has the main method or where is the entry point to the Java application?
Right.
So jar is like an archive file, but then there is a file manifest that MF inside of it that tells the
that says which class has the main method.
Right.
So you can also run native image on a jar file that has a main, has a manifest that points to the main
class or main method, and then it can be compiled to a native executable binary.
All right.
So we saw that how to install the default toolchain for Mac OS and other platforms.
And then after that we saw that you go ahead and download and install Crawl VM on Mac OS.
You have to make sure that in the recent version of the macOS Catalina and the later versions, you
need to make sure that you tell the operating system to not quarantine these global VM directories.
So you have to remove that by removing the attributes recursively and in this home directory of the
VM.
Right, just execute this command and give it the path to the VM directory.
And then after that you run the Google Updater juju with the install command and tell it native dash
image saw this and if you have already installed and there is no newer version available, they grow
vm or gio update.
Juju just tells you that you already have installed the latest version and then you can add the being
director of VM to the past environment variable.
And remember that the Bing directory already includes a JDK open JDK itself.
Right.
But my recommendation is that you always create a environment variable for the home directories.
Like I have created an environment variable called Google home.
So you say export Google home equals the path to the home directory of the VM.
And also I've created another environment variable Java home.
Which points to the JDK 17, for example, Home Directory.
Right.
And then after that, what you can do, you can access the native image from Google Home for where it's
been.
So let me just quickly show you that.
So if I open up a terminal and tell it echo Google home, it tells me that it's set for the terminal
to this path.
Right?
The home directory of the album JDK 17.
And if I say Echo Java Home, it tells me that it's set to the home directory at JDK 17.
If I want to run Java or Java compiler or Java from JDK 17, I say Java Home slash bean slash Java,
right?
And then I can look at the version and it tells me that it's Oracle Hot Spot.
If I look at if I want to launch my job application with the JVM that comes with the VM instead of telling
your Java home slash bean slash Java, I tell it Google home, slash bean slash Java.
And you will see that this is the JVM that that is built based on the open JDK 17 instead of Hotspot.
Right.
So what is?
What is the Oracle LLVM?
Open JDK is the community version of this.
The open source version.
And then.
But again, in the past environment variable, if I obviously if I type java hyphen hyphen version,
my terminal can also find a Java.
And if you look at my path environment variable, you see that, um, basically the JDK 17 is the first
that comes in the path, which means if I just type Java, it's going to pick up on this version Java
Home, which is JDK 17 being Java, right?
So you can decide which JDK you want to use that.
The open JDK 17 is basically compatible with Oracle JDK 17.
So if you compile your Java application with the Java compiler that comes with the Oracle JDK, then
you can compile that application to the Native Image tool that comes with with the LLVM JDK, right?
So these are compatible as long as for both of them you use 17, for example, which is my recommendation.
Now finally we can also look at how we can execute.
LLVM So you say Galois home a slash bean and then a native hyphen image.
That's the and then we can say hyphen, hyphen version and it is able to execute this native image from
the bean directory of the Google home.
And then it tells me that LLVM Java 17 Community Edition and then everything works fine.
Right now if you want to compile you have to tell it basically native image and here you're going to
tell native image the class path, right that your application needs in order to date the native.
So native image also needs to know where all the classifiers are for your application.
So you also specify the class path and then after that you specify the main class of your application.
And after that you can give it the name of.
So you see the class name and then the image name so I can tell it.
Let's actually go back to our eclipse and then try to compile our native image again.
So let's terminate this, go back to our eclipse.
So we previously compiled our hello class, but we put it we run it from this directory.
So right now we are in this test directory.
If I just run the native image on the hello vault without giving it the name for the output image it's
going to create hello world and put it in the same directory.
But I'm not going to do it.
So let's go one level up.
All right, now we are in the super directory, so or directory.
So I'm going to run the native image.
So I growl home native image and then hyphen CP which is the class path, right.
And then the name of the main class.
But then you can specify the name of the output file and actually you give it the full name.
Right.
So right now this hello world class is going to be found by the native image because a native image
searches the class path right now that this helloworld that class is not inside the current working
directory that I have in a terminal, but it doesn't matter because it searches all the directories
or specify in the class path.
And after that I'm going to tell it.
For example, go to test two and create an image called my app or my Java app or my underscore Java
underscore app, right?
What it does, it compiles your Java application and then puts the native image or the native binary
inside the test.
Two And the name of the executable binary is going to be my Java underscore app.
But then there are also other parameters like the options.
So there are options that come in between your native image and the main class and those are the options
that you pass to the native image tool, namely just mainly it's just the class path right after your
main class and the name of the output executable, you have some other options and these options are
the ones that usually are passed to the JV team.
So we can also try that.
For example, at the moment our hello world class accepts some system arguments, right?
So we can see if we can set them here so we can say hyphen DX Name equals Bob.
Right?
So let's see if this works.
So we are passing some parameters or options to the native image and then we are passing some parameters
that to our hello world class, right?
The main method of our Java application.
And if this works, then every time we run our native executable application, these parameters are
going to be by default passed to that application.
Right?
So if you know that you always run your job, your native executable binary you and you require that
some system properties are be set by default all the time, then you can give them at the time of compilation.
At the moment it didn't work right.
So there was an error linking the native image and let's see what the error was.
Uh.
Let's see.
So let's try to remove that and then see if this works.
So let's see if this works.
So right now we're not specifying any options.
And in the future lectures, I will show you what options are allowed here and what options are allowed
here.
So these are all in the documentations of the native image, and we will look at all the options and
all the details.
For now, we're trying to make sure that everything works fine.
We can compile our application or Java application, and then we can also specify where to put the result
of the compilation and what the name of the output file is going to be.
Right.
And it worked fine.
And I just can see the compilation is pretty fast just because it, it uses multithreading, therefore
it uses all the CPU power that your computer provides.
So it's very fast.
So right now if I say LS Test two OC so we actually put it in test three I believe.
No.
So let's, let's refresh.
All right, so?
So it created a directory.
Okay, so we made a typo here.
Yeah.
So let's go back.
Let's delete this.
Yeah.
Test two.
So, yeah, so we made a typo here.
That's why if this directory doesn't exist, native image actually creates the directory and puts the
compiled the result of the compilation there.
Right.
So it's good.
And then right now we're telling it, hey, compile this class, file this Java application that has
this main class and then put it inside this directory.
And the name of the executable is going to be my Java app.
And again, it's using all the CPU power of my computer, all the cores.
That's why the compilation goes pretty fast because so basically it mostly compiles the JDK and because
my application only has three class files, so it's pretty fast.
Now if we try to say LS test two and as you can see, I have my native executable and it's already named
my Java app.
So if I say test two and then my Java app, it's going to work fine.
And again, we saw that in the past that we can pass parameters, the command line arguments, let's
say hyphen, the name equals bob.
And as you can see, this system property said, we're not passing any command line arguments, but
we can do that as well.
Hello.
And then we have one command line arguments.
And then one system property.
And these are some other stuff that our Java application runs.
So I hope you enjoy this lecture in the future lectures we will look at all the details of the native
image, so please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.