Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion with the native image options and one of them is trying to compile
a jar file.
So we saw that first of all, the class path is the most important parameter or flag because the native
image tool, just like the Java JVM, needs to know where all the class files are.
And then after that we said that some of the dependencies could be in the format of a jar file.
Remember, jar is just a compressed directory or a compressed archive.
Right jar stands for Java Archive.
So you typically give the path on your class path, you have the separator which is colon and then give
the path to the directories that contain the patches, packages and class ones.
But then you can also give the full path to the jar files.
Remember, you should also include the name of the jar file and the class path.
Right?
Not the directory that includes the java.
So when you add the jar file to your class path, the name of the jar file must be also included.
Right.
And then this is basically what Maven build tool does.
So whenever you specify a dependency in your POM file for Maven, Maven just adds that jar file to the
class path.
It downloads jar files and add them to the class path.
If the JAR file obviously already has been downloaded and is available on your local repository, which
is the dot m folder in your home directory, then maven doesn't download it right unless you request
a different version.
For example, this Helloworld Java has a dependency on this jar file util for dash 1.0.
This is the version.
And let's say I have this app app directory that has a helloworld java in it and then there is a lib
directory that I put all my jar files and then add them to the class path right where I try to compile
or run this application.
Note that path.
The Jar file must include the name of the jar file as well.
Right.
Remember, this is very important because JAR is already a compressed directory.
So it's a directory.
So you have to also include the name of that jar file.
Remember jar first are compressed directories and the class files and packages are inside the jar file.
I will show you what inside a jar file would look like.
But then here we're just using this complex which we also use in the previous lecture and then this
complex class, complex number class is inside this forge.
Now, the other thing that you can do is we've seen that you can either run the negative image and give
it a class that has the main method, or you can give the native image a jar, file a complete, complete
jar file.
But then in order to create a executable file from compiling that file, you have to tell the native
image that this jar file, first of all, you have to tell the, Hey, I want to compile this jar file.
So hyphen jar and then the name of the jar file, right?
But then you have to make sure that this jar file is executable, which means it has a manifest file
inside of it, which can at that point the runtime to the main class.
Right.
The class that has the main method and the easiest thing to do to you can usually if you're using Maven,
you can create an executable jar with Maven.
I will show you in the next lecture.
But in this lecture I'm going to just show you how to use your ID.
For example, eclipse ID.
So native image can also compile a jar file.
It must be executable, which means it has a manifest.
If you if you export or create an executable jar with your from your ID, this is an inside the disk
jar file I've created.
I've installed applying for my eclipse ID that allows me to look inside the compressed or zip directories.
Remember jar is just a compressed format, so I recommend you also install this plugin if you're using
eclipse ID.
And inside that you see I have my packages, I have my class files and there is a meter dash enough
and inside that there is a manifest that EMF right.
And inside that it tells me obviously what the version is, what the class path is from the top of this
jar file.
Remember jar is just a directory.
And when you create a jar file with Eclipse, it tells the runtime that hey class path is dot, which
means anything, any directory inside this jar file is a package.
So for example, this class third class as is actually belongs to a package and that package is Java
native image for example.
Right.
And in the main class is Java native image.
This is my package and dirt test class and this is basically the fully qualified name of the class that
has the executable or basically that has the main method.
Right.
And we already know that you can even run a executable jar using the Java Command or the Gvm and I will
show you.
So it's very easy.
And Eclipse ID, you select your Java project, right click and select the export on the Java project.
And then you know that whenever you run a Java class that has a main method, eclipse creates a launch
configuration or run configuration.
So you want to select one of them.
And the properties of that run configuration, the JVM flags, everything is you've already set them
up in that run configuration.
So here you just point this jar utility.
Remember, you have to select the run jar so you can create two types of jars in Eclipse.
One is just a jar file, jar archive or a jar.
When you select the eclipse to create a reasonable jar, it asks you which launch configuration you
want to select, and when you select, whatever that you select, Eclipse knows that class has a main
method, so it belongs to whatever project and Eclipse already avails of everything, already aware
of the class path that is required to run that main class and export destination.
Remember that first of all, you cannot use eclipse internal variables here like project location is
kind of stuff that we saw before.
And then there is a hint here that the export destination will be relative to your workspace.
Remember not the project, the workspace.
So if the project name is java native image I'm using dot, you don't really need to use dot or forward
slash.
Doesn't matter.
It always is relative to your workspace.
So I'm going to set from DOT, which is my workspace, go inside this Java Native Image project, go
inside the jar directory and create a file called My App Jar.
And then the other thing is that because Eclipse is aware of dependencies or the class path, it tells
you what you want to do about library handling or the dependencies.
Obviously, if you want to create a self contained jar or Java archive, which is executable when you
execute it, you have to also have those dependencies on the class path and Eclipse gives you three
options extract required libraries into generate a jar.
So any class that is on a class path from other projects, they will be copied inside your jar file.
So everything, all the dependencies are there and sometimes you don't have the license for the other
libraries, right?
So you have to be careful about licensing this kind of stuff.
Package record labels into the JAR file, which means it doesn't extract the class files, it just copies
the entire project, the entire package.
Let's say there is a package from another jar file and other project that you're only using one of the
classes it doesn't copy only that class.
It copies the entire package.
Everything, right?
Copy record libraries into a sub folder next to generate a jar.
So if there is a jar file, there is a library that you don't have license to use those files to extract
them and put them in your jar.
You have to extract them as separate libraries and then distribute them because you don't own the binaries.
So you have to be careful, right?
So the third option copy required libraries into a sub folder next to generate a jar is a good idea.
Again, if you don't have the license to the binaries so you can't really incorporate them directly
inside your jar file.
So you have to basically you have to basically extract them as the separate jars and eclipse does that
for you.
Now save as anti script.
This is not really necessary.
You don't need to worry about that.
And then you hit finish eclipse creates the jar file and then you can execute it and see everything
works fine.
So let's head to Eclipse.
I'll give you a quick demo of this.
So here we have this Java Native Image project.
There's a package here, test class and we wrote this.
This is something to the standard output.
And then we look at the class path.
We have a dependency on another Java project inside the Eclipse workspace and we have a dependency here
complex on a on a on this jar file util forge and eclipse has a nice view reference dependencies that
tells you which external jars are on your class path.
Right, which is a very nice feature to have.
So what we want to do, we want to first of all, I can run it when I run this, I can successfully
run this.
And whenever you run something, eclipse creates a run configuration.
So if you go here, this test class is what I just used to run.
And for example, it tells you what the main classes arguments you can provide.
Um, basically JVM arguments and Eclipse already provides two arguments here.
Jerry we're using the project executable environment, which is Java C 17 dependencies.
Everything is on the class path.
We have one project and a class path, one jar and also the system libraries on a class path source.
Our source is just the basically the default which is all the Java projects and the Java is from system
environment variables if you need to manually define it, environment variables, the common allocate
console.
These are not really necessary because this is something that only attributes to the console environment
inside eclipse prototype.
This is also not that important for now.
For now, what's important is that you can configure this run configuration by going here, selecting
that run, because every time you run a class eclipse creates a new or basically a run configuration
for that.
And now if I select my project or maybe the package or the Java file doesn't matter, it doesn't matter
where you click, right click and then export.
And in the Java there is a jar file jar file with aspect j support.
This is not important.
That's I have this option because I also installed this aspect but there's jar file and run a jar file.
So if you just want to create a library which is not running but you just want to distribute your class
words, you can use Java, but if you want to create a reasonable jar file, which means a jar file
that can be directly run on the VM gvm.
You have to select this option.
Run a jar file.
And it already recognized this.
This is the last one, this class, which I just ran.
Right?
This is the last configuration.
And it tells me that this export destination, you can browse this.
Right.
And then this has to be with respect or relative to your workspace, right?
So I can say DOT for example, if you want to export Java native image to eclipse recognizes that I
am putting a relative path and when you use a relative path it means relative to the workspace.
So I usually what I do my convention is that to create a directory called jar in the top level of my
Java project and then tell it, let's say my app dot jar, right?
And right now I have some dependencies.
So let's see what each of these options does as extract the library required libraries into the Java
generated jar.
Let's see what happens.
So he'd finish this operation requests repack the reference library.
So Eclipse is giving us a warning.
Please review the licenses associated with libraries you wish to reference to make sure that you are
able to repack them using this application.
What this does is it actually grabs all those class files that inside are the libraries or dependencies
and copies them into our jar file.
It repackages them.
And again, if you don't have the license to them, you have to be careful.
And Eclipse is also warning us.
I have all the licenses jar creation failed a class size and class was not found.
Okay, so let's go.
I think the other project has some compilation issues, so I'm going to remove this car.
All right, let's just run this right now on our class path.
There is being directory here.
I'm going to also go ahead in the build path, configure build path, and I'm going to remove this dependency
on the other project.
So let's run these.
And now we only have a.
So we have a jar file on our class path and it being director of the current project.
So let's delete this privacy jar.
Let's right click export around a jar next and then everything is said.
Java native image.
Remember export destination will be relative to your workspace.
Obviously you can select this browse and choose a absolute path on your file system.
Here.
I want to put it in the work in the work space in my Java project.
So you give it a relative path.
So finish.
Okay.
And then now the jar file was successful.
I have installed this zip archive application, so let me go show you the plugin.
Let's go to the install tab.
So I recommend that if you're using Eclipse, definitely install this plugin Eclipse Zip editor because
it's a very nice thing inside Eclipse, you just double click and opens it up and you can actually edit
anything, right?
For example, this kit ignore, I don't need it, so I just delete it and then save my zip file.
So that's it.
I edited my zip file and then you see, this is our Java project.
Everything else comes from that util forge.
It has some native libraries and then there is a manifest and then Maven or Science Forge.
These are from the dependencies, the files of the other project util forge but there is a manifest
emf and I can actually look at it without even a unzipping.
This this this zip editor plugin for the eclipse is very nice.
All right, so what does this mean?
First of all, this is now a reasonable jar because I have the manifest INF and then manifest EMF tells
the runtime what is the main class?
This this line is very important.
And what is the class path relative to this jar file.
Right.
Which means all these directories java, native image and util forge.
These are the top level packages that the class files are inside.
For example, this array math is actually a type that is part of this array package, which is part
of this forge package.
So the fully qualified name of this type, for example, has two packages and we can see that.
So if I right click open with class file viewer.
Okay, so we cannot we have to basically right now it decompile it so it belongs to this package util
forge array, right?
So the manifest mef, when you export with eclipse, it also gives this option class path so that the
runtime knows which directories are actually the packages.
So if I open up a terminal here, I can actually directly run this jar file and the command is java
hyphen jar and in my app jar.
Right.
So everything works fine.
Hello.
Full from java external tool.
This is this line, the class path.
And again when you run this command hyphen jar, my app jar, what the Java runtime does, it actually
becomes equivalent to Java hyphen C.P.
Right.
And then my app jar.
Now the jar file is on the class path.
Right.
And then we give it the fully qualified name of the main class which is a Java native image dot test
class.
And this is still works, right?
So this Java hyphen jar, my app, the jar is a syntactic sugar.
What happens is this Java Command replaces it with this line.
And we know that in the the reason that this hyphen jar my app jar works because there is a manifest
file inside this jar file which points the Java or the runtime to the fully qualified name of the main
class, the class that has the main method.
But actually when you do this, the jar file is appended added to the class path.
That's why when I'm looking at the class path, obviously it tells me that my app jar is on the class
path.
Right.
And then Java native image, the test test class.
So this java hyphen jar, my app jar gets translated into Java hyphen, keep my app jar, right.
But then the main because there is a manifest that also has the information about the main class, we
can directly run the jar file.
All right.
I just want you to understand what's going on.
All right?
Now, how do we compile this to a native executable binary?
Because this Java is executable, I can compile a native image hyphen c.p dot.
So again, two options.
Either I put the jar file on my class path and then give the fully qualified name of the main class
inside that jar file.
Or I use the hyphen jar flag my app dot jar and then let's go, let's call it my app underscore native.
So what I'm telling you, the class path is here, but I'm compiling a jar, my jar, and then this
jar has to be executable, which means it should have a manifest file inside of it that tells a which
class is the main class, which class has the main method.
So this way you don't really need to worry about.
I can also basically remove this hyphen zip dot because I'm already inside this jar directory inside
of this jar folder.
Right.
So it makes the, makes the command very simple.
You just tell it, hey, I have a jar file this one and then create a application executable file called
whatever my native image.
So hopefully this works fine because we have the manifest all the dependencies of this class, which
is another jar David directly extracted into this.
So this jar should be self contained.
Again, the reason is that I was able to do it because I had this util forge something that I developed
myself.
So I have the ABC, the licenses and I can repackage it.
So let's look at it.
Everything worked fine so far.
It's compiling and it's going to basically convert our executable jar to a native executable binary.
So let's just quickly check that we can execute this and everything works fine.
Again, we know that when you compile two native executable binaries, there is no concept of class
path.
That's why we're returning nothing.
And then this is the dependency that we had.
It's already contained and we can look at our, for example, the complex number here.
So this is the way that you can directly compile your file like for example, with Maven.
We know that eventually when you build or the artifact is jarred, so then you can directly pass that
jar file to native image in other ways, which we saw was to set up an external tool and then configure
it in a way that a native image gets all the dependencies there.
Right.
So that's the whole idea of the jar files.
It's it's relatively convenient.
You have to make sure that all your jar file is executable and native image has access to all the dependencies.
So I want to do right now, when I exported that jar file, I selected the first option extract required
libraries in to generate a jar.
Let's select the second option package required library into the generated jar and let's look at the
inside.
Now you see that util for j is the entire jar was copied and then the eclipse is eclipse has to add
its own jar loader.
Basically what the eclipse does is it includes its own jar loader and then copies the entire jar.
Now this is a seal.
Okay, so even if you don't have license for this util forge binaries, it's fine.
You can directly copy it into your jar and then that's fine.
So that doesn't violate any licensing because you're not unpacking or accessing the binaries, you just
copying the entire jar.
Right.
And then manifest mfw and now things have changed a little bit because what the eclipse has to do or
tell the runtime, let's say JVM or native image, whatever application that can run executable jar
is that things are a little bit different.
So you have to tell it, this is my package Java native image and this is my main class.
So the first thing is domain class, right?
And in the class path, the top of the jar file, which means everything here has to be on the class
path.
This jar file must be added to the class path.
This directory is a is a directory which is a package because it's on the class path.
Right.
And then what is eclipse also has to add the extra instructions to the manifest so that the runtime
knows that this util forge jar has to be loaded.
And the way it works is that eclipse changes actually the internal main class.
So now this my class test class has been renamed to resource main class and the main class is actually
eclipse's internal jar loader.
So what happens when you run this jar?
It first runs this class, it adds this forward dot from the class path, right for voiceless util for
j.
It adds this entire jar to the class path.
Remember a directory that containing the class path that contains the jar file.
It shouldn't be on the class path at the directory forward slash the jar file the entire the full path
to the jar file, including the name of the jar file should be on the class path.
That's why this main class just makes sure that the current the working directory which is the class
path forward slash util for jar jar is on the class path and then it goes ahead and invokes this main
method, the main or this main class.
Right.
So just eclipse changes a little bit if you copy the entire jar files dependencies into the your extracted
executable jar just because it has to do some stuff behind the scenes.
But let's open a terminal here, make sure that we can actually run this.
So Java hyphen jar, my app jar as you can see it is still works fine and nothing has changed.
So my app jar is still on the class path and then the dependency is there.
But now we didn't actually extract the binaries.
Let's say we didn't have the license for this jar file.
So we can we are we cannot we are not allowed to look inside this Java, but we are still allowed to
copy the entire jar into this for Jar Jar, which is a dependency into our jar and eclipse behind the
scenes changes the manifest EMF to make sure that everything works fine.
But the question is if we do this because right now inside this manifest manifest MFW things have changed.
So the main class is not our test class, right?
It's the eclipses internal jar loaded class.
So does it make a issue for let's close this for the native image.
That's the question.
So let's test it being a native image hyphen jar my app jar and let's see if this works.
So so far, so good.
All right, let's see if everything goes fine.
Remember, the difference here is that the main class is not our class.
It's the eclipses jar.
Loder class.
And so warning reflection method in so this jaw loaded class does some reflection stuff.
Aborting a stand alone image bill due to reflection use without configuration.
So what happens right now is it ran into an issue saying that this jar jar loaded this main class uses
reflection.
And in order to be able to allow reflections for native image to be correct, successfully compiled,
you have to do some other stuff, right?
So as you can see now, the main compilation failed, but then Native Image went into a fallback compilation
which creates an image which requires a JDK to be available on your past environment variable.
So warning image.
My app native is a fallback image that requires a JDK for execution.
If you pass the node fallback, then it should have failed at this line and no other thing would have
happened to suppress fallback image generation and print more details about why fallback image was necessary.
So what happens here is that if I now execute this binary, it is still works.
But now the class path also shows up.
Because what happens behind the scenes, this binary, it actually requires a JDK.
If you don't have a JDK and it's not a standalone binary, it is still used it internally.
This app actually executes the Java hyphen, DHCP, whatever, and then the name of it.
Internally, it does this.
This is not a fully native compilation.
It's called a fallback method, right?
Or a fallback situation.
So in the next lecture, I will show you how to deal with it.
In general, I will have a more detailed lecture on how to deal with reflections, because what this
class, main class, your resource loader uses Java reflection to configure a stuff and it has to call
the main method of this and it does it reflectively.
You know that using Java reflection at runtime you can access the main method, for example, of this
class and invoke it from another class.
Right?
So I will show you how this works and hopefully we will be able to resolve this issue and basically
create a executable file whenever we package the Java files.
Now, the last thing that I want to show you is let's let's try the third option.
Remember, the third option in Eclipse is that instead of packaging everything inside our jar, we just
copied the required dependencies into a directory that the Java is created.
So let's do this.
And now you see it creates my app lib, which means these are the libraries or the dependencies that
this jar file requires.
So now if I open a terminal.
And if I say Java hyphen jar, my app jar, it's going to to succeed.
Right.
And let's see, look at the manifest EMF.
Now manifest that EMF actually changes the class path.
And now there are two directories on the class path.
The current directory, which is the jar inside the jar file.
Right.
This is my package of my application.
But then there is also another directory on my class path which is my app lib.
Obviously from the current working directory and util for jar jar.
So that jar file goes on a class path.
So this is a nicer way.
And now hopefully when this happens, hopefully this now this compilation works.
So let's see, let's see if this works because now inside the manifest that the class path is already
configured.
So hopefully there will be no problem.
Remember, the main class now is still the differences that now the main class is our actual class.
But the class path has two dependencies, right?
The current directory, which is inside the jar file and the other external directory which has all
the dependencies that we might not have the license to it.
And so far the native image is going fine.
And then again, native image when you look, when you do the hyphen jar, my app, the jar, it looks
inside the manifest at MFW and looks at this class path option and then automatically configures the
class path.
So everything worked fine.
We didn't get any message that there was a reflection or something because this main class is exactly
our own main class.
So my app dot native OC my app dot native and it works fine.
There is no class path because this image is a fully is a true native image.
It's not a fallback image which requires a JDK and everything works fine.
Remember when you compile, if you have other dependencies, everything gets compiled.
So you have to see I don't know how the license works because right now the complex class inside, inside
the util forge is fully compiled to native binaries and it's included in our application.
Right.
So I hope you really enjoyed this lecture.
Now have a very solid understanding of how to export a reliable jar in your eclipse ID and then how
to compile it.
I recommend this third option, which is again is it extracts all the dependencies and creates a subdirectory
here which all the jar files there because native image has no problem understanding that because inside
the manifest mfw the class path is already given.
The problem is that you have to make sure you run the native image from exactly where this jar file
is because this class path is relative to where this jar file is.
Right?
And then this dependencies directory is also relative to where this jar file is.
So you have to be careful with the relative path in comparison to the absolute path in this case.
So please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.