Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on VM Native Image and how to compile our job application to
Native Executable binaries.
And I mentioned that in the first step, we're just going to look at how generally we launch a Java
application, right?
And if you're using IDE, most of the details are hidden from you, but then it's good, it's a good
practice to really know how to do it.
And we know that in general it's the terminal or the command line of the operating system that is the
interface between the user, the human and the hardware.
Right.
You talk to the operating system through the terminal, through the command line, and then operating
system understands what you're trying to do and then it instructs the hardware to do it.
And then the CPU does, for example, some calculations and returns the result back to the operating
system and then the operating system returns.
The result back to you and terminal is available in all platforms Linux, Linux, Mac, OS and Windows.
Although I personally prefer Mac OS and Linux terminals that Windows is the command line that comes
by default is not that great.
From Windows ten, I believe they introduced a new shell which is called PowerShell and there are also
some standalone applications that you can install in Windows.
They provide their own terminals, same with Mac OS, for example, the default terminal that comes
with Mac OS.
I'm going to open it up.
You can add the customization to it.
Right now I'm running an application on top of the terminal called Fish.
Fish is a basically friendly interactive shell.
So if you want to install it, which I highly recommend, you just go to Internet and search for fish.
Let's say let's go to Google, for example, and then search for download fish and then it's the fish
shell.
So finally a command line shell for the night.
So this is a very nice interactive shell.
It has a lot of nice features like Autocomplete, and then it has highlighting.
For example, if I want to see which version of fish you use, it already has nice intelligence suggestions.
I just hit tab.
It tells me what options are available.
You can use the arrow up and down to switch between them.
I'm going to just say hit fish, dash dash and then hit tab.
It gives me lots of new suggestions.
I can, for example, just select version and it tells me which version of fish I use, right?
So fish basically a command line application or a basically
basically an executable binary.
And if you want to know where an application is, so basically whenever you type the name of an application,
let's say Java, write what you want to do this the operating system tries to understand this and when
you say Java, it means you're telling the operating system.
Remember, you talk to the operating system via the terminal and terminal is a fully text based interface,
right?
There is no like other applications like this PowerPoint.
It has a lot of nice interactive features, but terminals, usually they're just text based, right.
So so you might think that terminals are actually not an easy thing to use, but then once you get accustomed
to them, you realize that using terminals is very good for automating stuff.
So because terminals also understand scripts, right?
You can write shell scripts.
They're sometimes called shell script and they usually have that as edge extension on Mac OS and Linux.
And then you can write very long shell scripts and execute them to automate a lot of stuff.
So a lot of boring stuff terminals, if you just manually want to enter them in terminals, they're
very tedious.
But then because terminals or command lines also understand scripts, you can have a very large script
and then run it and terminal.
It spends a lot of time executing them.
You don't need to manually enter every line of code, right?
So again, Java, when you type Java, it means you're telling the operating system to launch this binary,
this executable application in Java, which we know that it comes from the bean folder of the Java JDK.
Right.
And then in order for the operating system to understand these, it has to first be able to locate a
binary somewhere on your hard disk called Java.
Right.
And we know that this exists, right?
If you want to know if the operating system or the terminal is able to locate a binary and executable
application, there is a command called which and it comes, I believe, by default with with macOS
Terminal and Linux for Windows.
Again, these commands are very different because Windows is not Unix based.
We know that Mac OS and Linux are UNIX based, so they follow the same pattern.
It's the same commands so which Java and it tells me that it can find an application and executable
binary called Java which is in my from the root of my hard disk.
It goes to library folder.
Java folder.
Java Virtual Machine JDK 17 Contents Home Being Java.
So it says that basically when you type Java, the operating system or the terminal, when it tells
the operating system what to do, it actually replace this Java with this line, right?
Because operating system only understands the fully qualified full name of the application there is.
A and the reason that you are able to do this simplification, remember, this is just a simplification
for the human eye because it's very tedious to every time you have to type these, let's say I want
to know which version of the Java I'm using.
You have to type this whole name library.
You give it the full path and then on hyphen, hyphen version and it tells me that I'm using Java 17
Ltz, which is the Oracle hot spot, right?
This is not the open JDK version, for example, but because this is very tedious, especially if you
have lots of directories and then your binary application is there, what the operating systems allow
you to do is predefined these paths.
So this this library, home being all this, this is called a path, right?
Or a directory that some executable binaries can be found in this Bing directory.
And the operating systems provide a feature called the environment variable.
So environment variables and every terminal you can define environment variables for them.
In macros and Linux, you can define environment variables for the terminal.
In Windows, you kind of need to define the global environment variables for the operating system.
And again, you talk to the operating system through the terminal or the command line, but my emphasis
for these lectures is mostly on macros and Linux because they're more friendly in terms of interacting
with the terminals.
Their support for the terminals and interaction with the humans is more friendly.
But I will have lectures about windows and how to use the terminal there.
So there is a command called Echo and then this allows you to see or see the value of the global environment
variables that your terminal or currently understands.
And one of them is called PATH.
Now if I type echo path, this echo means whatever it takes that comes after these, just echo it back
to the terminal.
So it just path.
So it doesn't understand that this is not a text, I mean an environment variable.
So to differentiate between a text and a variable, you have to use a dollar sign the other path in
macOS and Linux in Windows, I believe it's a double person.
So in Windows, for example, you type these here, it doesn't understand in macOS and Linux you have
to use a dollar.
Now, as you can see now it gives me a list of directories, user locale bin and one of them is Library
Java Java Virtual Machine, JDK 17 Contents Home Bin.
What this means is that I've already added this directory to the my to my path environment variable.
And with this whenever I type Java, basically what happens is that because the terminal realizes that
this is not a path, any path it starts with either forward slash, which means from the root of the
hard disk or dot slash.
So whenever you declare a path, a path in terminal, you either start from absolute path, which means
from the root which is forward slash in macOS and Linux or dot forward.
This means this is a relative path from the current working directly, which is this folder mesa.
Right.
So this is my current if you want to know what directory you are in.
And again, this is another feature of the terminals or command line.
Whenever you talk to the operating system, it means you are running or executing an application or
a command in the terminal.
Right.
And in order to be able to do that, you have to be inside some working directory.
So there is a command called P, W de or print working directory and it tells you where you are.
For example, I can go from the current directory, I can go into my desktop folder and now I'm now
inside the desktop now usually for the home directory.
So this usually when you log into your operating system, the terminal by default is inside your home
directory, right?
And there is actually a and different users of the same computer.
They get different home directory, right?
They have separate home.
And inside the home you usually have a desktop folder, documents folder, downloads folder.
So if I go back up to my home directory and do a LS SMS list, all the files and directories see every
user gets its own library folder.
Music, movies.
I don't know.
Whatever documents, downloads, desktop, right?
So every user gets its own copy of these folders under hard disk, right?
So whenever some user logs in with their username and password, then these folders are basically the
operating system knows which folders to present.
Different folders have different home directories, right?
That's completely separate.
But the root directories are the same.
For example, forward slash library.
This is a root directory.
There is no dot here, which means this is an absolute path from the root of the hard disk, which is
the forward slash right now in obviously in windows, I believe we have to say the name of the drive,
something like this drive C or drive the in Mac OS and Linux.
Usually we don't have many partitions, there's only there's usually one partition and that's the root,
right?
And you always start from so for example all the users, they get different directories, home directories,
So their files, whatever one user puts on their own desktop is different from the files that others
put on their own desktops.
But everybody sees the same, for example, root directory, the same library directory, etc..
Now, the point I'm trying to make here is that whenever you type a basically whenever you type an application,
the terminal realizes that you're not specifying a path.
This is just a name, right?
So it tries to search for the name of that application in all the directories that are in the path directory.
And it always starts from the first one.
And usually applications come with a Bing directory, which is short for binary.
Binary means all the command line executable applications.
In the JDK we know that there is a bean that has Jar, Java, Java, C, etc. So whenever I type Java,
the operating system or the terminal, it starts from the first directory that is in the path and you
can have multiple directories in the past environment variable and then it realizes that there is no
application called Java in the Bing directory here.
So it goes to the next one.
Right.
And then it doesn't find it, it goes to the next one user, local bean, it doesn't find a Java application,
so it goes to the next one library Java Virtual Machine, JDK 17 Contents Home Bin and then it finds
a Java here and then it is sub searching and assumes that this is what you mean.
So basically if you have multiple directories so I can have JDK 17 and 16 both on my path environment
very well.
But when the terminal tries to search for this application, it starts from the first directory and
the first instance of this application that it finds it stops searching.
So if I have JDK 17 and after that it comes JDK 16, the Java that we execute or the terminal finds
is the JDK 17.
So it's first come first, right?
The very first directory that the terminal finds this application, it stops searching and assumes that
that's what you want.
So my recommendation is that whenever you try to launch Java from terminal, always check the version
first hyphen, hyphen, version, and these are hyphen hyphen stuff.
They are called the command line arguments.
We will come back to these concepts later when we try to develop a full version of a command line application
in Java and then compile it to native binary.
All the native binary applications.
The convention is that they accept command line arguments.
Usually it's either one hyphen or two hyphen.
So you can say Java hyphen version and it also works.
So this application understands both hyphen hyphen version and hyphen version.
Sometimes you don't need to write the full name, hyphen V, for example.
Now it says it doesn't recognize that.
So this is not a valid argument.
We can try hyphen hyphen v.
It also does not understand.
So you either use hyphen version or hyphen hyphen version with this particular application.
Java, right.
So that's mainly the concept of environment variables, right?
Especially path.
Path is very important.
There are two environment variables that we typically need to set up.
One is Java home, Java underscore home.
And you see all these names.
These are very similar to how we define global constants in Java applications.
Right.
All caps the names are separated with underscore the same here.
Whenever you see this kind of thing, this is a global environment variable.
So every instance of the terminal that you run, they all understand this one and this is you define
in a file called Bash.
RC So so there is a, if I say in my home directory, if I say ls hyphen a to show all the hidden files,
there is one called the bash profile, dot bash profile and then there is one called bash.
RC Right.
And then usually what happens is bash is the same the name of this terminal.
Right.
A born again shell.
So if you want to see and then usually you put define these global variables like Java home in the bash
RC or bash profile.
So for example, I've manually defined this global variable in this, right?
So we can look at the contents of the bash.
RC We're going to say less.
For example, less is a command line that prints the contents of a text file is a it's an application
that prints the context of a text file to the terminal.
So that bash.
RC for example, and you see I've defined this environment variable called the Google Home.
I have a Java home, for example.
If you want to comment a line in your bash RC, you can use the pound sign or hash sign.
So these are commented this Java home.
You see, previously I had JDK 15 as my Java and then JDK 14 and now I have JDK 17 as my Java home.
And then you can append this to the path environment variable.
And usually what you do is a Java home is the home directory and you want to add the directory that
has all the executable binaries to the path.
Right path is used to search for the name of the applications.
So it's not just Java home, Java home slash being the being directory of Java Home.
So Java Home is a convention that people use when you install JDK, Java Home points to the home directory.
Inside the home directory of the JDK, there is a bean directory, right?
You set it up.
Same with Google Home.
Once you want to download and install VM, you want to add the home directory to define it as a global
variable, right?
It's not necessary, but it's easier because instead of writing this line path down, you can just tell
the terminal crawl home and it understands what you're talking about.
So I'm going to hit queue to exit the last application and if you want to see that.
So if I type, if I want to see if Java home instead I can tell the terminal, see if there is an environment
where we call Java home which we declare with dollars on echo means.
Read the contents of these and print it to the terminal.
If you don't have an environment variable, right that's let's say Java underscore home two.
It doesn't print anything because it means there is no global environment variable called Java home
Java underscore home two, but there is a global environment variable called Java home.
And the usefulness of this is that then if you want to launch Java application and you haven't added
that to the path, you can say Java home a slash being a slash java, this works fine.
The terminal understands that you're using a dollar sign.
So you are trying to reach a the contents of a global environment where called Java home.
So the terminal actually behind the scenes replace this line of code with the contents of this environment
variable hyphen, hyphen version.
So it's the same story right now.
Google VM also comes with a its own version of the JDK, which is very similar to the, let's say,
Oracle.
So it also has a Java.
So now this tells me that this JDK is based on the open JDK.
It's not the hottest spot from Oracle Open JDK Crawl VM Community Edition.
Right?
So again, these environment variables are very easy, basically very convenient, because then you
can quickly differentiate between a Java that comes from the this JDK and one that comes from the crawl
VM Right.
So if I just type Java, the operating even, I have both.
Even if I have both the Google home being and the Java home being on my path environment variable.
The terminal only finds the Java the first instance that it finds.
Which is that the Java from the Java home being directory then it is stop searching.
Right.
So it assumes that that's what you mean.
That's why even if you have both this Java's on your path, you cannot use them with the Java world.
You have to differentiate them.
So the easiest thing to do.
Have the global environment values for the home directories and then use those which shortens this long
path that instead of using writing this, every time you just write Java Home with the dollar sign and
then the terminal understands what you're talking about.
All right.
So depending on which one of these Java home buying or Google home being are on your path environment,
whether which one comes first then then the term if you just type Java, the terminal finds one of them.
Now you can change the path environment variable using the export command in the terminal itself.
This is a life change and this only applies to the current session of terminal.
So if I say path export path equals, let's say we apply this beam from the Google home and then call
in, which is called the path separator in macOS and Linux.
You separate different directory paths in the past environment variable with call it and so we tell
it hey replace path with its old content but then put the bing directory of the Google home at the beginning.
So this comes first and this works.
And now if we go echo path, you see general VM being directory comes first.
All right.
And then what happens here is that so what happens here is that now what we do, let's clear the.
So.
So I guess now if we say rich java.
All right, so something went wrong.
Let's go back here and open the terminal again.
So echo path.
That's the that's the path.
Right.
And I think what we let's see.
So we put this command had a problem.
So let's echo path again.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I guess there is a problem with this approach and that's probably because of the this fish application
that we're using.
Let's see if we can exit it and go back to the.
Yeah.
So this is the original terminal that so the path is there.
Right.
And then if we say export path equals crawl home a slash being colon and then path itself and then echo
path and now it works, right?
So now you see the beam comes first, the being directory of the so if I now say Java hyphen hyphen
version, it says that that Java application that the terminal finds the first instance comes from the
first directory in the path which is now the LLVM Java, right, it's the JVM.
But then if I close the terminal, go back up again.
When you do the export command in the terminal itself, it only applies to the current terminal shell,
right?
If you close it and open a new window, those exports are gone.
If you want every terminal session to have read all the basically all the global variables, then you
have to define them in the bash.
RC file, right.
So in the home directory you have the bash.
RC And you see whenever you launch a terminal it loads the contents of this bash.
RC So it exports this environment variable defines them, appends these to the bash at the path and
then it also I've set it to also run the fish command line application, which is a nice interactive
terminal.
Right?
So I'm just going through these concepts so that you are aware of what we're trying to do.
All right.
Now, I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
And from the next lecture, we are going to continue to see how we actually run a Java application from
the command line to concepts such as class path.
And then we're going to see, for example, what's the difference between launching running the Java
application, using the GM or the Java Command and how we can use the Native Image compiler to compile
to the native binary and then how to execute that one, right?
Especially if your application accepts command line arguments.
We will discuss the difference between the two.
I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.