Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion with the Eclipse ID's external tool, which is a very powerful
thing to have in an ID and it allows us to run external applications and our Java files or any other
thing that you want to do.
And the goal here is to learn about these environment variables that are part of the reason that the
external tool is very basically powerful because when you run an external application through the Eclipse
ID, Eclipse ID knows a lot about the organization of your Java project and then it provides this internal
environment variables that are specific to the Eclipse ID and it allows you to write basically commands
in the external tool that change based on which files, for example, are selected in your tree view,
in the project view, for example.
Now we so far we've seen some of the most important internal variables that the Eclipse ID provides,
and some of them actually can accept arguments and you add arguments using colon.
So you still have the duller curly braces and the name of the variable.
But then if you want to add a particular argument to this specific parameter or variable you add, call
it right.
For example, project class path, we saw that if you just use it by itself, it eclipse substitutes
this variable with all the directories that are on the class path of your Java project.
And then obviously the class path separator is colon.
But if we want to just select a particular project, we can give the name of that project in Eclipse
as the as the argument to this project class path environment variable.
So you can add a project name, I believe you can only specify one particular name.
You cannot specify like two names, but if you want to select a particular project that is on the class
path, you can just provide the name of that project as argument.
If all projects are desired, you don't need to pass any arguments, right?
You just use the project class path here.
Right?
So let's go back to Eclipse ID again.
We created this project.
There are two class files here and then what we want to do, we go back and external tool I set it up
to this dummy external tool is set to just echo whatever a string that we write to the console itself
so that we actually see how this substitution works.
And we say that any external tool has to be run inside some sort of directory that's called the working
directory, because this external tool actually mimics basically the behavior of the terminal, right?
Whenever you write a call here, it means that you are running this command.
It is a binary application inside some working directory.
Right.
And then any command that you execute in terminal has to be inside some sort of working directory.
And we said that if you want to point to the class files, you have to set the working directory to
the beam of the Java project because Eclipse compiler organizes the compile the class file Snoopy now
project class path.
If we run this right now, it looks at which file is selected and it looks at the project that this
file belongs to, and then it prints the class path of that project.
All right, now let's go back and give it a an argument.
So project class path, I want to tell you, just print the path to the particular project and you specify
the name.
Let's say this, our own project, Java native image, right?
So we tell it the project class path, but we give it a name of the parameter.
So apply, right?
So let's see.
If we select these and then dummy external tool.
Yeah what's interesting that it is still prints a.
Is it okay?
No, I think it still prints the.
Yeah, that's interesting.
So let's go back here, Joe.
So that's interesting that it is still a.
Not sure if this is the SO project class path and in Java.
So let's write something that doesn't exist.
So command line could not be retrieved because this doesn't exist.
Let's go back to our one at Image Show Command OC being echo.
Oh, okay.
So that's because.
Let's see.
So it points to the being directory.
Uh.
Okay.
Let's see.
So this one works.
So so I think you cannot filter only the current project, but you can filter other projects that are
on your class path because obviously your current projects should always be there.
So I think it doesn't work on the current project, right?
The project that you're selecting applies show command line.
Now it doesn't.
So if you want to select some of the projects that are dependencies on your class path, you can basically
you can specify them as the parameter to your project class path, but you cannot just select the current
project.
It doesn't work, right?
So the argument can be basically other projects that are on your class path, not the current project.
All right.
So back here, system property.
So we know that when we run Eclipse ID, it actually runs on a gvm itself.
Right.
And if you want to see the properties of that JV team that Eclipse runs, you can use the system property
and give it some parameters like Java Home.
Right.
We know that the system properties are hyphen DX something, right?
And so let's go back to Eclipse.
So this java home shows what jr e used for running Eclipse.
I'd remember eclipse id runs on java and you can actually investigate that if you go to Eclipse.
About Eclipse and then installation details.
And then configuration.
So basically this retrieves all the information about the gvm that Eclipse ID is running on, right?
So Mac OS, hyphen OS and then Architecture 64, it has a splash show, a splash eclipse, lawnchair,
eclipse plugin, etc. and then hyphen VM.
Hyphen VM is the virtual machine and it's using an open JDK hot spot.
Jerry Fool.
So right now Eclipse ID is not running on any of the ADCs that I manually installed.
It's running on the Java that comes by default with Eclipse ID.
So I think from a few older versions like 2019, the late versions in 2019, they included a full JRI
from open JDK into so that the eclipse also comes by default with that.
But you can put it to the lib July of any JDK so you can change this.
Just you have to point these replace this argument with the lib July dot dynamically or if you're on
Linux for example, dot so on Windows it's that DLL for example and then the the the eclipse IDE runs
that particular Java eclipse home location.
Again, these are the system properties and then hyphen X used g1 GC.
So the JV that eclipse is running on is using G and GC.
Use a string deduplication at module x start on first thread or eclipse is stability.
Internal carbon is small phones, for example.
So these are all the system properties, java dot vmw, dot info, mixed mode, etc. but then in the
environment variables that the eclipse provides.
Here, for example, it has this system properties, system property.
And if you look at the description, returns the value of a system property from the Eclipse runtime.
What it means is that the Eclipse runtime is the gvm.
That eclipse is running on a system.
Property name must be specified as an argument.
So you cannot just use the system property by itself.
You have to give it an argument.
And if you look at the configure so arguments, if you don't know which arguments the system property
uses, you can select configure and it shows you all the arguments that system property of the eclipse
ID uses and we already saw those in the configuration tab in the in the about eclipse ID for example,
eclipse commands eclipse application, eclipse VM, Eclipse VM asks, for example.
So let's look at the Java Java class path.
Let's say let's, let's look at the class path that the eclipse ID uses to run the application.
And the class path is this one.
This Java file is on the class path.
Org eclipse equinox lawnchair dot jar.
Right.
And it's inside the eclipse ide application.
So that's on the class path and we can look at other configuration.
So, so let's go back to our external tool system, property system property and then let's look at
other arguments that we can pass.
For example, eclipse VM, let's say we want a new we want to know which JVM, where is the path to
the JDM that Eclipse is using for launching.
So okay.
And then apply.
Let's run it and it tells me it's an application.
Eclipse Dot App Contents.
Eclipse Plugins Open JDK Hotspot Jerry Fool Mac os dot lib July dot daily right.
So it tells me eclipse is right now it's running on its own internal Gerri not it's not using a J.D.
from the J.D. case that I have in star right and other things but as you can see some of the it's very
nice because not only you can use these variables list to tell you which variables you use, some of
them if they accept arguments.
There is a configure button here that is enabled, for example, workspace, location, configure.
Right now it doesn't have anything.
But let's look at the project class path.
Let's see, you can select all the projects in the directory and then they are passed as an argument.
So project class, path dev, java, right.
And what you're going to notice here is that if I select project class path.
And then he'd configure.
We can also select the current project Java, native image, etc. So if you don't know what arguments
you can pass, you can select and click on the configure and see which options are available, right?
And for example, environment variable.
And then let's say you want to actually this is something that it's good to talk about.
Now we know that the the terminal or applications, when you run a executable binary in a terminal,
you have your application is aware of the environment variables that are basically defined for your
terminal.
So let's say we want to print path.
Let's see if this works and.
It doesn't work and basically it's a string substitution.
Whereas in the terminal, if I tell it echo path, it's going to print the path environment variable,
right?
So the question is, is it possible to define these?
So let's see if we go to the variable and select environment where so returns the value of an environment
variable and environment variable name must be specified as an argument, right?
So environment where and then we give it an argument, call in, let's say we call it path.
So we want to do look at the value of the environment, which is path.
Uh.
Let's see, let's run this again.
And now it correctly returns the past environment variable.
Right.
So again if you want to also use a.
If you want to also use the any of the global environment variables that are defined for your operating
system, for your terminal, you use this internal eclipse environment well and then path if you just
sell it, tell it the path.
Eclipse doesn't recognize this because duller on the terminal it refers to environment variables.
But for eclipse, this dollar doesn't mean anything.
So again, and if you recall in our terminal, we define this class path environment variable, right?
And if I apply and run, I have to select something and then tell it, run it.
And you see the class path, that environment is still set, right?
So if you want to use any of those environment variables that you use in your terminal, you can use
this duller curly braces environment where and you pass the name of the environment variable variable
as an argument to this environment where basically internal eclipse, IDs, variables, right?
And in order to specify an argument for a parameter, you give it this colon.
Right after the colon you pass the arguments.
If you look at variables, again, an environment where right now it doesn't show anything because it
clips doesn't really know which environment variables you've defined.
But it's it's good to understand this.
Again.
I have to select something first and then run my eclipse ID and it correctly shows all the directories
that are that are on my path environment variable.
So arguments call in and then the argument and the most important ones are obviously environment.
There is also important project class path system property and then workspace location.
So let's say we want to specify a relative path to the workspace.
We can tell you the workspace location.
Right in the configure.
It's empty, but that's fine.
But from here we can pass.
Colin Which means we're passing an argument and let's say the name of the project Java Native Image,
some project, right?
What it does, it tells whatever the value, the string value of the workspace location is append the
rest.
So when you pass an arguments to the to this workspace location, it appends the rest to that.
So if we apply, we run.
And right now this is my workspace location and then the rest that I specified the name of the project
was appended.
So when you pass an argument to work a space location adds the relative path of the directory inside
workspace.
Right?
So you don't need to remember what the value of the workspace is.
You just use this internal environment variable, you pass it an argument which is a path, relative
path with respect to the workspace and eclipse automatically appends that.
So returns the full or absolute path to the being directory of some project.
We can specify this project being directory as an argument to the workspace location.
And again, if you want to use the global environment variables of the system, you use the env underscore
var environment variable.
I think it's it's also here so env environment variable.
But then you have to specify the name of that environment variable as a argument, as a parameter.
All right.
So finally, let's quickly also have a look.
We've seen this now.
Let's see again, have a quick look at the window for the environment external tool.
So you go and select on this new button and you create a new external tool.
You give it a name, whatever name you want, and then you location.
And this location has to be the absolute location, absolute path to the the executable file that represents
this application.
Right?
For example, native image for google vm is inside the home lieb svn substrate vm being native image.
And we know that in the bean directory, the inside home there is also being directory.
But in there there is a native image that is a symbolic link to the actual executable file which is
inside lieb svn being native image.
And when we want to configure native image, obviously you have to point it to the where the class files
is and the class files in Eclipse projects is inside the BIM directory.
So the project location, I'm using an internal environment variable and then forward slash P, right.
And then you have to give it the class path.
Right now I'm not specifying the class path, but in general you have to specify the class path.
And we already know that the project underscore class path.
That's what we do.
Java type name, native image X on X on basically a class file.
So you have to use the Java type name which returns the fully qualified name of the class file.
Right?
Even though we select a source file in the in the tree view of the eclipse ID, it returns the fully
qualified name of the class file and then you can tell it what is going to be the output name of the
project and where to put it right?
The name of the binary typically project name, right?
Or you can select it to choose, for example, the class name, etc., right?
So I hope you enjoy this lecture.
In the next lecture I'm going to finish up on this and actually give you a demo.
And next, we're going to also have to set it up for the Maven build tool, because when you use Maven
to build your Java project, the directory hierarchy is a little bit different.
So Maven doesn't put the compiled class files in the Bing directory.
So we will see how to also use the native image.
Build a external tool that works is compatible with the MAVEN builds, so please stay tuned and I'll
see the next one.