Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We are going to continue our discussion on how to download and install and correctly set up the global
VM native image.
We said that in macOS, you download it right now.
The latest version supports JDK 17, and then if you're using macOS, Catalina and later you have to
make sure that the the quarantine attribute of these files that you download for VM is not set.
So you have to remove that and then you use the updater to install the native image.
And I recommended that on macOS and Linux.
You go ahead and set up the home environment variable.
And on the Mac OS, we also looked at just quickly compiling a Helloworld Java application using Native
Image to make sure that everything works fine.
Obviously, to refresh your memory, the prerequisite is that you should have installed and correctly
set up the default toolchain of your operating system of your platform.
We saw about Mac OS, Windows and Linux.
Now in this lecture I'm going to show you how to set up the native image and make sure that it works
fine in Linux.
So again, Mac OS, we said the Google home environment variable and here's a screenshot of my backyard.
See for example, I've set up my Java home environment variable to JDK 17 Home Directory and the Google
home is pointing to the home directory of the VM 17.
Right.
And then if on Mac OS, usually the terminal loads the batch profile.
So if your terminal doesn't directly load bash RC instead of uses bash profile in your bash for point,
you can just source the bash.
RC source just means you're telling the terminal to reload the contents of this file.
Therefore, if some environment variables are defined in the bash RC when you do the source, the terminal
also goes through all the lines of code and remember that in the backyard c file the hash sign or pound
sign, it's a comment so they're not going to be read by the terminal when you run the source command,
only the lines that don't have the hash sign.
So they're pound signs or hash signs are comments.
Right.
And.
So define global environment whereas in bash or see if your terminal uses bash profile just source the
bash or in the bash bash provide which is these days Mac OS does that and the Linux the terminal directly
loads the bash.
RC So usually you don't see a bash profile and I believe in Linux what you are going to do, obviously
we saw that previously.
You have to download and install the default toolchain of the operating system for Linux.
Is GCC a new compiler collection?
And if you my recommendation is that you use Linux or Punto, obviously Linux has a lot of flavors and
various distributions.
You can choose anyone, any one of those because that's your choice.
My preference is always Linux or Ubuntu and it will come by default with the GCC, but you can go ahead
and try to see if there are any updates available for GCC.
And so let's head to my Linux.
Machine and then I'm going to open up a terminal and I am going to check whether DCC is installed and
if its installed I'll check to see which version.
So I'm going to say G Plus, Plus, Hyphen, Hyphen and Virgin.
It tells me that remember G Plus Plus is the command line tool for compiling C++ applications.
So it triggers the C++ compiler and C++ linker.
If you want to compile a C application, you have to use DCC, which triggers the C compiler and C basically
linker.
And again, as you see, I've already installed the fish tool which is sits on top of the normal terminal
and it's a very nice interactive shell.
I highly recommend you use it.
And in March, let's see whether the terminal is using bash profile or bash RC.
In my home directory, as you can see, I have a bash story and bash RC so there is no bash profile.
If you open this with editor, if you look at my SO, I have installed Anaconda for managing my python
packages.
That's why there is this line of code, this one Conda and then I have I have defined a growl home.
We will see that in the in Linux, the JVs or the JDK that you install are inside the lib directory
from the root directory, lib JVM, Java virtual machine and whatever JDK you have installed.
So in macros, it's in the library.
Java Java virtual machines in Linux is in the lib java.
So again, the naming is very similar, but in macros, it's the full name library in Linux is lib in
macros.
After lib, you go inside Java and in Java, virtual machine in Linux you go into Lib and then JVM,
Java, virtual machines and then whatever JDK you've installed.
And now I've said my Java home to actually grow all home, so I'm using the open JDK that comes with
the Agrale VM.
Right?
And then in the path I attached or I append the being directory of the Google Home or Java, remember
Java Home and Google Home are the same thing.
It's not necessary.
It doesn't have to be the case.
So I can just set it to Google Home slash pin, which explicitly says that I am using the Google Home
Bing directory, which means my Java executable or JVM or the Java compiler is also from the Google
JDK.
So let's save these.
And as I mentioned, if you are already inside the home director, you can just source the bash or C.
So there is a.
So the reason here is that basically the reason we saw an error was because it's because of the fish.
So when you load it, it first runs the loads, the batch RC and then runs the fish command, right?
Again, if you look at the batch of RC, as you can see, actually we can also look it at the terminal.
So if we say less batch RC you see at the end I have returned to run the fish and fish.
It it's better not to load the batch RC Or source the batch.
RC When you're running the fish, right?
So it's best to load the batch.
RC And then at the end run the fish and then your terminal switches to the fish, which is very nice.
I really enjoy the fish.
All right.
So again, what we want to do, everything sets up which C++ is going to tell us it's in user being
G plus plus.
And then we can say sudo apt update for example, I don't know GTC actually it's not the command we
saw previously.
What the command is for installing the essential tools for Linux build essentials.
Right.
Sudo apt install build essentials so we can copy this and go back and run it under Linux to make sure
that it's up to date.
All right.
So let's run this.
And Bill essentially is already the newest version, a zero upgrade, zero newly installed, zero to
remove.
All right.
So everything is up to date.
Our default toolchain is fully up to date.
Ready to go.
We can compile c C++ applications.
The next step is to go ahead and download the VM.
So download and install Google Vim.
And then in order to install something, you kind of need to run the Nautilus in pseudo mode.
What I mean is that basically you say pseudo and then Nautilus, right?
That's the name of the graph file manager that comes with Linux on Mac OS is, for example, finder
and Windows is file explorer.
But in order to move, remember we want to download the VM files and then unpack it or unzip it and
then move those files to the Lib JVM, which is a root directory.
So it's not related to our home directory, right?
We are really trying to manipulate the files from the root directory.
That's why we have to have administrative privileges.
And in order to do that, we run the Netflix or the file manager in the administrative mode.
Otherwise, we won't be able to change anything in the in the root directory.
Right.
Remember, when you log in with your user credentials, you are free to change anything from your home
directory, right.
So if you are basically if I open up a new window right now, I didn't open the file explorer in the
administrative mode.
So it's a regular mode.
It opens my home directory.
I'm allowed to change anything I want, but if I want to do other location and go to the root of my
file system, I'm not allowed to change anything.
Right?
So unless I run my file explorer in the sudo mode right now, obviously you can always copy files using
the pseudo mode directly in terminal, but here I'm just running the file explorer in the pseudo mode,
so I'm allowed to do any changes and we want to go to Lib.
And then GM.
Right.
JVD So right now I've installed open JDK, JDK 14 JDK, JDK 1101 JDK, Java 11, open JDK, Java eight,
open JDK VM 17 Right.
So again, the what you do is very similar.
You go to the git repository of the VM and then download the version that is for your macros or basic
for your Linux and then your platform, whether you're using an Intel AMD CPU or you're using a, for
example, arm CPU, right, download VM.
All right.
So this is the game dot org.
We want to download the community edition, which is free and it takes us to the repository.
And we saw previously we looked at the Linux.
So AMD 64 this is Intel amd x 64 platform.
If you're using Linux on a arm based CPU, then you have to download this one.
So we want to download right now I'm using an Intel 64 bit platform, so I downloaded JDK 17 version
and then there is nothing else.
You just download the file Linux AMD 64.
And we're going to save it to our downloads.
And then it's a it's about 430, so it's half a gigabyte.
So it takes some time to download.
And after that you just unpack it or unzip it or extract the files from the this is a tarball or a compressed
file.
And then since I ran an atlas in the basically pseudo mode or administrative mode, I can directly basically
move the files to my lib JVM folder.
Right?
So let's open a new window in a non administrative mode or basically a the user mode and then we go
into downloads and we just download it gradle VM 17.
Right.
And this is what we downloaded now the version I installed, let's go back to Lib and then JVM.
So the version I install is 22.02.
This newer version is 22.1.
So this is a new version.
So I'm going to let say extract two.
Or we can just extract it.
Extract here.
So the version I installed before and now the newer version has a little bit updates because it's went
from O2 to one zero.
So right now it's on zipping.
So it's a.
So I'm running this on a virtual machine.
That's why the extraction takes a little bit of time.
But after that, since this Nautilus windows is this Nautilus window is in the administrative mode,
I opened it using the pseudo command in terminal.
I should be able to drag and drop this directory to this.
And then, which means I have successfully installed the newest version of the VM Community Edition
based on the open JDK 17.
And after that I'll go to my bash RC and change the graph home environment variable.
To basically to point to the US version.
Right.
So I believe this is done.
All right.
So if we look at the inside, this global VM community edition, everything said, and then we're going
to we can either copy it or drag and drop it.
Let's copy these and then paste this here.
And I'm allowed to do that because this Nautilus window is in the pseudo mode or administrative mode,
and we are manipulating the file system not from our user account or home directory, but directly from
the root of the file system.
You are only allowed to do it if you had administrative rights or privileges, which means you have
to use the event file explorer in the administrative mode.
Right.
All right.
And now I'm going to go back to my home directory and then let's look at the hidden files and then let's
look at our bash, RC.
And open with a text editor.
And I'm going to modify my bachelor RC.
So where is that?
Here's the batch, RC.
And what I'm going to do.
This has my virtual machine has frozen.
I'm not sure why.
This works fine.
All right.
Now it's on Frozen, so 22.1.
So we're going to say 22.2.
1.0.
Right.
So grab LLVM.
So live JVM grab VMC Java 1720 2.1.0.
Right.
So we save this and enclose.
We don't need this administrative net loss anymore.
We can close the terminal again and then we're going to open it again.
And then I check if everything's set up correctly.
Remember, our JDC is now set to grow.
LLVM JDC which should be open.
JDC And we can check.
So Java, hyphen, hyphen, virgin and Open JDK 17 and then open JDK Runtime VM Community Edition 20
210.
So this is the newest version that we just installed.
Previously I had 22.01 and now it's 20 2.1.0.
Right?
So this is the new version of LLVM.
Same with Java C hyphen, hyphen version, and it's JDK 17.
And we can say because we added the being directory of the environment variable or the Google home,
then we should directly have access to Google Updater, right?
So go hyphen, hyphen version.
And it's updated 20 210, which is the correct version.
If I say native dot dash image, it's not going to find it because or I could say Google Home is slash
being a slash native image.
It's not going to basically command not found.
Right.
So what we need to do because the native image tool doesn't come by default with the Google VM.
So we have to basically say Google home, a slash been a slash g, you use the Google Updater, but
because this being directory from Google home is already under path, we could just directly type juju
or Google updated.
But here I'm going to be explicit so that you know that we're using the Google updated from the Bing
directory and then we say install and then native dash image.
Right.
And it says insufficient privileges.
The reason is that this being directory of the Google Home is not in related to my home directory.
Right.
It's related to the root file system which is in the Lib JVM.
So we kind of need to run it in pseudo mode.
Sudo and then Google home a slash being a slash juju.
Right.
I'm putting in double code to make sure that nothing goes wrong and then install a native image.
We give it the password and it's going to reach out to the git repository, download the native image
tool and then install it.
So installing new component and native image from for the version 22.106 is fully installed and now
we can check it using Google home being four slash native image hyphen hyphen version and grow LLVM
22.10 Java 17 So the native image has been successfully installed and again note that I could also directly
type native image a hyphen hyphen version because the being directory of the Google home is on my path,
right?
So let's quickly create a new basically Java file hello world and then compile it to native executable
binary to make sure that everything works fine.
So we could.
Let's go into the desktop.
And then we have this text.
Actually, we don't need.
Let's just.
Let's say touch.
Hello, world dot java.
So we're going to create a empty file here and then open it with the text editor.
Um, let's open this text editor here and open the file from our desktop, which is Java HELLOWORLD
Java.
And I'm going to try to increase the font size.
Let's see.
Preferences and then editor font.
Use the system.
Let's go.
15.
Okay.
And then we're not going to put it in any package.
So we're just going to say public class.
Public class.
Hello, world.
All right.
And then here we're going to say that public static void man a string array args.
Right.
And then here we're going to just say that system dot out dot print line.
Hello world from Java in Linux.
All right, so semicolon, everything looks good.
And then right now we are in the desktop.
So obviously first need we need to compile Java C and in the class path, we don't need to specify the
class path because our this class doesn't have any dependency and it's just one file.
So by default this class pass is the current working directory and we are already in the desktop.
So writing hyphen, CP dot is optional and then we're going to say hello World Java and it's going to
hopefully successfully compile and then we get the hello of all that class.
And after that the only thing that remains is that first of all, we can make sure that our Hello World
application works fine.
So let's see.
Hello World from Java in Linux so the JVM can successfully launch and now we type native image hyphen
cpp, hyphen CPP current directory.
And then what's the name of the class that we want to compile?
Hello.
All right, remember, you don't give the name of the Java file name, you give the name of the class.
Right.
And then we launch this.
And by default, if you don't specify the name for the output application or output executable, it's
going to have the name of the class in lowercase letters.
So it's trying to compile again, it's virtual machine.
So it's going to be a little bit slow, but this is a very simple application, so hopefully it's going
to.
Compile soon.
At See?
So great beam native image generating Halo Vault.
This is the name of the application, which is the name of the class.
All in lower letters and it's executable.
Right.
And and it also you can click on this.
It takes you to the address that gives you more build output that.
So it gives you all the details necessary that what this means.
C compiler so virgin LLVM 22 C Compiler gcc garbage collector serial GCC.
Now I will show you the in the future lectures that basically how to change this option.
Let's say you want to compile your application to use a different garbage collector, maybe.
GC Right, but note that in my case when I compiled this, it didn't show these lines just because these
lines like Virgin Info C Compiler Garbage Collector were added in the most recent version, which is
20 2.1.0.
So if I go to my Mac OS library, Java, Java virtual machines, I was using 22.02.
So I will go ahead.
And also in macros, install the latest version which is 20 2.1.0.
Later after after we are finished here.
So as you can see again, it's going slow just because it's in a virtual machine.
But the fact that in the initialization stage, it's showing me that it was able to find a graph VM
application, all the necessary tools from the global VM.
All right.
Why do we have this software update?
No, let's let's cancel that.
So it performed the analysis.
It found all the classes necessary to successfully launch our Java application, and most of them are
from four 3845 classes.
Almost all of them are from from JDK.
Right.
Our application only has one user defined class.
So building universe done parsing methods done in lining method.
So as I mentioned before, in lining is a compiler optimization and then compiling methods.
So it's compiling them.
So this is the main phase, I believe for the compilation.
And after this we are basically done and our application is going to be ready to be launched.
Right.
So again, on the Vision Machine, the compilation is taking some time.
It also depends on how many how much resources you allocate to your virtual machine, like how many
CPU cores, how much RAM.
But previously we saw that on my main operating system, right on macOS.
The compilation was very fast.
If your application is small, right?
If you have a couple of classes, it's very fast.
So let's wait for these to finish.
I am going to go back to our PowerPoints.
And again, to recap, we define the girl home live JVM girl home.
See?
So in Linux, you have to go to the root directory, you go to Lib and then JVM.
And again, the most recent version of the VM at the time of recording this lecture is 22.2 1.0.
And then the recommendation is to add the Google home as a global environment variable.
Now if you want to add the Bing directory of the Google home and then the native image is also available,
and again, you have to use the Google Updater.
After you download the Google VM, you have to use the Google updated command line tool with the install
option and separately install the native image.
Right?
And then you are all set up and as you can see, we are done with compilation here and it tells me that
it created a executable called Hello World in my desktop.
So and we are already in the desktop so we can say dot forward slash hello world.
As I mentioned before in Unix based operating system like Mac OS and Linux, the current directory is
not added to the path environment variable by default.
So if you have a executable application in the current directory, you should always tell it dot forward
slash.
Right.
So if I if you don't specify that as I mentioned, the rule in terminal inside when you type the name
the terminal assumes that this is the name of an executable binary that it has to find.
And right now it doesn't find it.
And fish is actually very intelligent.
It highlights it in red saying that I couldn't find it right.
When it can fish, when it can't find an application, it highlights in blue.
So if I say forward slash hello world fish tells me that this is OC and if I run it it says Hello World
from Java in Linux and we fully compiled our simple class file into a native executable binary for the
Linux operating system and the Intel 64 bit.
Right.
And one last thing, obviously, we can also accept a command line arguments, but I'm not going to
do it because that requires re compilation and that probably takes some time.
But you will see the idea and as I mentioned, the information is kind of is highlighted.
So for example, if we say garbage collector and click on it, let's see what happens.
Open hyperlink.
Is it going to open it in Firefox or we could just copy that hyperlink and go ahead and open that link.
I believe my virtual machine is a little bit slow, but you see the idea, you can click on this and
it's interesting that in the recent version they added this information to tell you which compiler it's
actually using to to to compile your application to Java application and which garbage collector it's
using.
Right.
So the firefights just opened up and still not that much responsive.
And that's because of my virtual machine.
So I hope you really enjoy this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.