Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on default platform tool chains.
We saw Mac OS, which uses Apple Clang, we saw Linux Ubuntu which uses GCC and we saw Windows which
uses by default Microsoft visual compiler, which you should install it and instead of the past environment
variables.
And now let's before jumping to the global VM native image, let's take a moment and discuss how we
are going to set up our C++ development environment.
And we've already saw that for a basically for a simple C++ application like one CP file, you probably
can just do it in a command line, but if you want to develop a large C++ application, then you have
to use some sort of IDE or build system.
And the idea is the same for Java because both C++ and Java are similar in the way that they are aesthetically
type languages and they have compilers that compile the source files.
And we know that in the case of C++, the source file gets compiled to the native executable binary.
In the case of Java, the source file gets compiled by the Java compiler or Java C to an intermediate
level called a basically byte code or classifiers.
Those are still binary files, but they are not.
The operating system doesn't understand them, but the GM or Java virtual machine understands them.
Now, obviously we're not.
The focus of this course is not developing C++ applications.
I will have a few lectures about native methods in Java and then once we get to the LLVM native.
So the native methods in Java require using the Java native interface.
Right.
And which means we are calling some C++ functions from Java.
So you bind a Java method to a C++ function.
In that case, you have to write the C++ code.
The bridge that allows this communication between a Java method and then C++.
In that case, I will show you an example of how to write a C++ source file and then compile it to a
dynamic library and then load it, load it back in Java and then use the native method in Java.
So first of all, we need to set up some sort of C++ development environment after getting familiar
with the default toolchain of our platform.
Right.
And we saw that the job we use the platforms toolchain or the compiler to convert source files to executable
binaries.
And when we say source files, it means C, C++ and mainly the modern C++.
That's my focus.
C++ source for the convention is that CPP headers are dot H or dot HTTP.
My convention is to use dot CP for the source files and H for the header files.
It is recommended to use an ID.
It's highly recommended.
Let's write it down.
It's highly recommended to use an ID and then in the Mac OS ID you have a couple of options.
Obviously the default ID that comes with MapQuest is Xcode.
You just install the Xcode app and you can develop that code.
BLOCK is open source vs code is open source.
I believe even Microsoft Visual Studio has a mac version and I think the community edition is still
free.
So we're going to say RMS, Visual Studio, I believe there is a mac version available.
And then my favorite is Eclipse EDT C Development Tool.
And the reason is that I'm a big fan of Eclipse ID first of all, it runs on the JVM and it's platform
independent now.
Obviously Code block and V is code and all these IDs escrow doesn't have a Windows version or Linux
version code block, I believe it has a mac OS and Linux a mac OS and Windows version.
I'm not sure if a Linux version is available and RMS Visual Studio.
I don't think there is a Linux version available, but Eclipse EDT, it's based on Java, right?
It runs on a JVM and therefore it's platform independent.
Basically, Eclipse Eclipse EDT is available for all platforms.
Not only that, but the interface is exactly the same, right?
Because the interface is designed in Java, so it's the same.
That's why I'm a big fan of Eclipse EDT You go ahead and download Eclipse ID and then you can directly
download an Eclipse ID version that already comes with the seed plugin.
If you just eclipse a download the Eclipse ID that has the Java development tool by default, then you
can just separately install the CD plugin from Eclipse Marketplace.
And after that, once once you install and restart Eclipse, you have in the prospective list, there
is a new perspective for C C++.
And then once you switch to that, all the menus immediately switch to C++ development, right?
And then you can create a C++ managed build project which so eclipse EDT by default, use it, you can
select which kind of build system you want to use.
Is it a C, make or make or just internal build the system of the eclipse?
Right.
I usually use the make system build, which is which I'm familiar with.
Recent versions of the Eclipse CD also also work with the CME.
Right?
So basically you go to Eclipse Marketplace and search for C C development tool and then you just install
it and after that you restart Eclipse and you're ready to go.
So let's head to Eclipse here and I'm going to close all these files and then help we go to Eclipse
Marketplace and in the marketplace, basically.
It's a way to second for this to load and then you can search for creat.
Obviously I've already installed it and the perspective is available and so once this start finishes
loading, we can search for the Crete.
Now there are some tabs here.
Search recent popular favorites and installed.
If you're not sure if you've installed a CDB four so you can go to the install tab and then see if Crete
is installed.
I've already installed this, right.
And then once you install and restart, you come here, this corner, this is the window that you add
perspectives, right?
I have Java perspective, C, C, C++ perspective and even Python.
So Eclipse IDE allows you to seamlessly jump between development.
You can even install a plugin for developing Fortran and so you can seamlessly jump between different
perspectives.
So this is your perspective menu and I have the option to select C++, Java or Python if you install
Fortran, for example.
And you have a perspective for for right now if you look at the main, for example, the file new Java
project package class interface.
So these are related to Java development.
If I switch to C perspective and by the way, each perspective, you can also set it to have a different
window configuration, which is very nice, right?
If I jump back to my java, you see the tabs are different, C++, the tabs are different, Python it's
different.
So it's very nice that you can seamlessly jump between different developments.
So if I jump to the C++ development and look at the files new Makefile project with existing code C++
project project, convert a C++ R to tools project.
So all the all the menus now are basically a change to C++ development, which is very nice.
Right?
So what do you do once you jump to the C++ perspective?
Right click new C++ project.
And so you see we have different options.
C management, obviously we want to create a C++.
So C++ manage build using the managed build system.
So this is the internal it's management.
Now you can select a C project, so you have to have C make install and then you configure it.
Makefile project create a new project that builds with the make build tool using this new core bell
system.
This is experimental and then you can also select this one mission project.
So I'm going to select the C++ managed build and then what it's going to do on any platform, it basically
automatically recognizes your toolchain.
A toolchain is a set of tools compiler linker assembler intended to build your project.
Additional tools like a debugger can be associated with Tuesday, so Eclipse EDT usually automatically
picks up on the or detects the the default toolchain of your operating system, which is very nice.
And usually what I do I create a executable project.
Hello world just to quickly so test CTT to quickly compile make sure everything is fine so I'm not going
to add any other I'm going to manage all my C++ files into a CRC directory next and then you can select
whether you want to compile in release and debug mode.
Right now I'm just going to show it demo, so I'm not going to compile in debug, I'm just going to
compile and release.
And the difference here is that it just passes different flags to the default toolchain to the C++ compiler,
right in release you get hyphen oh three, which means the maximum level of optimization and finish.
And now it's going to create this test CD project.
And then it automatically picks up on your default toolchain and adds all the default to include directories.
Right?
In order to develop C++ applications, you have to add all the header files necessary.
Right.
And we've seen these header files.
These are in there.
Basically, they come with the X Code app and then the X code tool and then all the header files and
then also some command line tools cards.
And so these are different libraries.
So basically based on your default toolchain eclipse, it figures out what are all the header files
that are available for your development.
Now in MapQuest and Linux, there is an extra folder per user.
It's called user locale include.
So if you've installed additional C++ libraries, for example, I've installed Boost and then all the
header files for the boost are available.
And then once you compile, you can also link to the binaries, static libraries or dynamic libraries.
So these are different libraries.
For example, boost GSL your new scientific library.
I've added I've also installed it manually on my computer, so not only it picks up on the default toolchain,
it also tries to pick up all the C++ libraries that you as a user have installed.
And this made this user local include obviously only exists for macOS and Linux on Windows.
You kind of need to figure out what to do and I'll show you how to do it maybe in the future lectures.
But for now I'm going to focus on just a quick demo based on macros, right.
So if you cannot if your ID doesn't pick up on the basically default toolchain, you can go to right
click, go to the properties of your C C++ project and you have to manually configure this build.
So right now it tells me that this build is the configuration is released, you can manage it, you
can add a debug and then build the build type is external builder and it's by default is using the make
and let's see if I have make installed on my computer.
So let's open up a new obviously in order to be able to do this make should be available on your operating
system which means the issue the terminal should be able to find it which make user being make so make
hyphen hyphen version and make right.
And I believe once you it comes with the x code.
So if you don't have Mac installed, you have to install it.
It's I believe it's an open source thing and you can use it.
You can basically switch the internal builder.
The the difference is that with the match builder it creates a makefile and then you can compile using
the make and it does that internal builder, it doesn't you use the Makefile so it doesn't create a
Makefile that you can even use it on the terminal to compile.
So for now I'm going to start with the external builder generate make false automatically expand environment
variable references, make files that's good.
And it also shows the bell directory.
Right now my configuration is released so it creates a directory called release and puts the binaries
there in the release.
All right.
And then the behavior and use a standard build arguments.
Right.
And you can even do parallel building multi core if you think you have a large project and you want
to do because the C++ compilers allow you to use multiple threads or multiple cores.
Right.
Right now we're just not going to use it.
Use custom build arguments.
These arguments will be passed to make command line arguments.
But right now we're going to use the standard build arguments, workbench build, behavior build and
resource save.
So basically the idea is that you have work in space and if you change something, for example, in
the source code, do you want to automatically rebuild the project or the default behavior is that you
want to.
So this is your build configuration, this hammer which is released and this is so when you click on
this, it builds and this is the configuration release.
So this one is the configuration.
So right now I'm compiling to a executable.
I have a main, so let's select our C project, C++ and run the build manually.
So as you can see, it runs a few terminal commands.
The first one is make all so what it does, it creates the Makefile.
So let's look at the release.
You see, we have the Makefile.
Which just tells me include this makefile that you need and then remove all the files and then include
that make source that make.
And these are all the directories that will be included.
It says that just include the Z in the make.
Right, because this Z director has our source files and then make cmd goals and then CC dependencies,
C++ dependencies, a lot of the options.
So and then eventually the target is building this executable by including all these, by executing
all these goals.
Right.
If you're not familiar with what makes this term is you can just.
Basically Google it and get familiar.
So after you create this binary, right, this is our executable binary right in the release, it also
in the source also puts the object file or hyphen or these are the binaries and D is the directories
that were used to create this object file.
Right.
So Z test also came from compiling Z test TCP.
So it tells you which CPP files were compiled to generate this object file.
Right, so that this object file test or came from compiling this C++.
So it gives you extra information.
And you can just select your source file and hit run and it automatically said, let's write something
here.
Hello.
When you do that, eclipse automatically executes the binary that it compiled.
So I changed something.
So let's build again.
It builds, and then let's run.
And he works fine.
So again, when you hit run on your source file, what happens?
Eclipse actually executes this binary.
So if I manually delete this binary and hit run.
And it says mad.
It says binary, not found.
Right.
So basically when you run the source file, I don't want you to get the wrong idea.
What actually happens is that it clips, executes that the binary that has the name right.
But right now it says, I cannot find a binary, so you have to build it again.
And now you build it and you get the binary and then it can run it.
So so when you run a source file, it doesn't mean that it keeps running the source for it just means
it keeps runs the binary that is associated with the executable binary.
Now obviously we can also open a terminal here and manually run the binary.
I've shown you how to do it.
You just in the Mac OS and Linux, the current working directory which is our release, does not by
default it does not get appended to the path you have to say DOT and then test CTT and it says hello.
All right.
So we can execute the binary just like any other native application in the terminal.
Now what we can do here is what I'm going to do.
I'm going to delete this release.
And then so let's see.
So you can also look at the outline of your application.
We're including iOS Stream.
We don't.
The best practice is to not so use the open up the entire STD namespace.
Same with this one and line.
And then you can build this write, build, release.
So you can now recompile again.
And as you can see, Eclipse actually uses the G plus plus hyphen O three, which means Eclipse just
calling the G plus plus compiler, which is our default toolchain.
And it also tells you that I found the GCC C++ compiler, the command is G plus plus and also tells
you which flags it's passing to to the compiler to compile your CP file.
Hyphen O three is maximum optimisation.
That's why we are compiling the release mode.
Hyphen W O means, show all the warning, hyphen C and then hyphen F, message length zero hyphen MD
and then which directories?
And then we're compiling this test CD2.
CP Right.
Now the question is what is the working directory when, um, when eclipse launches the compiler and
as you can see, the relative directory is one go, one level up and then Z and then tested TCP.
So basically what happens is that when you build run the build eclipse seed, it changes the current
working directory to the release directory.
Right.
And then in order to get access to the CPP, you have to go one level up and then you go into the root
of the C++ project and then go to the Z and then test CP.
Now we could actually let's delete all these files.
And then let's open a terminal here, open a terminal in the release directory.
Now we can manually compile our application because it's a very simple one.
Source file application.
C++ hyphen oh three, hyphen w all.
And then go up and we can do use double code, go up into the CRC and then test T dot CP and we can
compile again and then it puts it in the current working directory so we get a dot out.
That's because we did not specify a particular name for the output.
So we can also do that.
So let's close this one in order to give it a specific name for the output.
You say hyphen o, which means the output name and then let's say test hyphen score CTT Right.
And we compile now it puts it in the current working directory, which is this.
And then if I right click and hit run.
So let's see.
Oh, so eclipse always tries to use the Makefile.
So when you try to build with Eclipse, basically it, it cleans up all the files that are currently
in the release.
And if you look at the main file, the, the main, the first line is remove all the files that are
in the current working directory, which is the release.
Right.
So it cleans up everything, all the current, all the binaries that were already compiled and then
tries to redo.
So let's clean this up.
But right now we are directly compiling our applications.
So we're not using any make build system, right?
So when you just type G plus plus and then compile the C++ code source file to a executable binary,
you're not using a make a build system, you're just directly invoking the compiler.
Obviously, this only works for various small applications, but if the application gets large, then
then you have to use some sort of build system, otherwise it easily goes out of control.
All right.
So what we're going to do, I'm going to delete this release.
And then he bailed on our project.
And now it creates all the make files and then executes the make write.
Uh, so and again, to refresh your memory, there are two steps towards compiling a C++ source code
to the native executable.
One is compiling the CPP files, source files to object files, which are the binaries, and each CP
gets compiled to a separate binary and then linker puts or connects all these object files together
and creates one executable binary.
Right.
There are two stages and the command both for compiling and linking is the same.
It's just C++.
So based on the flags that you pass, C++ decides whether you're compiling or linking, right?
If you just say G plus plus, it tries to do the compilation first and then linking.
But if you just say hyphen C, so hyphen C is the flag that tells the G pass, hey, I just want to
compile.
Don't do the linking and I can show you by again clearing this.
So let me write this here.
So C++ by default, by default first runs the compilation and then runs a linking.
If you just want to compile, create the object files which are the binaries you have to pass the hyphen.
C So a flag hyphen c tells a g plus plus only compile don't link.
Right.
So.
So if I open a terminal again here.
So previously we use this command to directly compile to executable.
But now what we're going to say is that we're going to say G plus plus hyphen oh three, hyphen W all
hyphen C, right and then hyphen oh.
The output is going to be dot O, for example.
And if you look at the release mode, there is no release folder, there is no executable file, it's
just a binary file object file.
So if you open this up, it's just binary, right?
And then if you want to convert this binary to a executable, you have to invoke the linker again,
right?
G plus plus and then test a CD dot or a hyphen or test my app, for example.
And now if you have multiple object files, you list all of them here, and then the linker tries to
combine them together into one single binary.
And if I say my app, it's going to execute fine.
Again, I'm telling you, this stuff, these are not directly relevant to Java development or compiling
a Java application to native executable binary, but it's very helpful for you to understand what's
going on when you're compiling some source file to native executable binary.
Right?
So back to the PowerPoint.
So we can you can quickly install this C++ CD development environment and then it takes care of the
make files and everything.
You just add source files and then compile.
Everything is very automatic, very nice, and then the next step is terminal.
And I've already been using terminal quite some time in these lectures.
And terminal, just a brief introduction or quick overview.
Terminal is also known as command line console shell bash, which is born again Shell, etc. Right in
windows.
It's they call it command line or console.
In Mac OS Linux, we call it Shell and terminal is the bridge between the human and the operating system.
And it's a purely text based application, which means unlike a graphical interface, the terminal doesn't
have any button that you can click.
You basically end up typing a lot of stuff just like any other executable binary.
It's a text based application and the way it works is let's close this.
There are binary executable binary applications.
If you want to tell the operating system or terminal to do something, you type a name, which then
the operating system or the terminal interprets it as a application and executable binary.
For example, ls ls is a application executable binary and lists the or basically the directories and
the files, everything.
If you type something that the terminal cannot find, it gives you an error saying that I cannot find
it.
Obviously I'm using a interactive shell which already highlights it in red, which means a terminal
couldn't find this command.
If I say blue means the terminal is able to locate this application or for example, make right.
It's blue.
If I say make two or makes a means, it cannot find it because it becomes red.
And again, this is because I installed this fish friendly, interactive shell on top of my regular
macOS terminal.
All right.
And terminal has a buffers or streams which are either input streams or output streams or error streams.
And usually if you want to save the outputs, for example, if you if you run an application, let's
run this one more time.
So what happens here is that when you type, for example, ls this executable and the feedback that
the terminal gives you is a text based feedback, right?
Obviously this interactive shell has some highlighting etc., but it has a buffer or a character buffer
that shows to the terminal.
Now sometimes what you want to do, you want to save these.
Whenever you have characters, characters or strings, you can save them to a file.
So you can say ls on this directory and then a hyphen.
Basically, you can tell it your direct the output of this application, which is a string to one to
a file or something like this.
Arrows means this arrow means grab the output of this application, which is a string and redirected
to a file, for example, a text file or anything.
Right.
And if you want to filter some of them, there is a pipe operator instead of arrow.
You have pipe.
Pipe means when you use arrow, you are directing to a file, right?
When you pipe, when you use the pipe, you are direct redirecting the output of these to another binary
application.
For example, grep grep is for filtering something, right?
Let's say any application that any of the outputs, everything that starts with M or for example and
it says movie and this interactive shell also tells me more is red, which means it was this was fine.
So the pipe means a redirect, the output to the other application.
So if you have a application, you execute it.
And now you want to redirect the text output of this application to another application, you use the
pipe operator if you use the arrow operator.
Let's see if this works.
No, because arrow means redirect the output to a file, not another application.
Remember grep is also an application.
So you redirecting the output to a file.
No such file or directory.
Right.
With the arrows you can redirect the file.
So if you want to read the context of a file and then take them as the input to an application, you
can basically use the input as stream of the application.
Right now, the arrow, if you right, type the name of application and then the arrow it means you're
using the output buffer of the application or the terminal.
Right.
So I want you to understand this again.
These mainly these concepts mainly apply to Mac OS and Linux.
So Unix based operating systems interaction with the terminal is very important.
Advanced users prefer working with terminal.
The main reason is that terminal provides a scripting, so you can create a script that runs hundreds
of commands using terminal, right?
So you just run the script and it does a lot of things behind the scenes.
It learns runs lots and lots of commands, which is very nice because now it gives you a way of automating
a lot of routine tasks, a lot of commands, which is an application that runs in terminal and add some
enhancements.
It's available both for macOS and Linux.
I highly recommend you install it and use it.
It has a lot of highlighting features and even in my bash RC, I've set it to set by default.
Any time I run a new terminal, it immediately runs fish so that I'm always in the fish shell instead
of the original shell.
If I want to exit the fish, I type exit and I go back to the Mac OS terminal, which is a little bit
boring, it doesn't have any highlighting, etc..
So I recommend you use the fish application, right?
So I hope you really enjoy this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.