Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
Previously we saw that when using Reflection API, a static analyzer of the native image can succeed
in most of the time unless we are basically dynamically loading a class and the string or the fully
qualified name of that class, for example, is not provided at compile time.
So there is some information missing that makes it impossible for for the Native Image aesthetic analyzer
to really look at your source code and figure out what's going on.
So if it's not possible to figure out at compile time, what else can we do?
Is there a solution?
The answer is yes.
And Dancer.
Basically the solution that the graph VM in general provides for this kind of static compilation is
a tracing agent.
As I mentioned before, Google VM comes with a build of open JDK, so it already has the EVM there,
other parts of the JDK like Java, C, etc. now.
So it has the EVM, so it has the wrong time.
So which means that it has a Java Command.
So if you recall, when we run our terminal, as I mentioned, I already have installed a various JDK
and right now my job at home is looking, pointing to the JDK 17 from Oracle JDK.
Right?
So if I say Java Home Bean and in Java, which means I'm launching the JVM from this Oracle JDK, and
then let's look at hyphen hyphen version.
This is the hottest part version right now.
I've already also set up my Google home to point to the latest installation that I did right 22.1 And
if I look at the gvm that comes with this installation of Google VM, so Java hyphen hyphen version
from Google Home, now it comes from the open JDK build, right?
So open JDK 1703 And so these are two different VMs.
And the good thing about including the JVs with the VM is that they could add more capabilities to it.
And one of them is a tracing agent, some plugin to the JVM that monitors your application at runtime.
So if you go to this address, VM 2.1 reference manual, native image and then agent.
So Native Image also has an agent command, but the gvm that also comes with the beam has an agent command.
And this agent is basically tracks the interactions or basically what your application does.
And then it can log them, it can create a configuration file because last time when we compiled the
third version, native image said, Hey, I don't know what to do.
This is not possible for me to figure out at compile time.
So but if you provide me a configuration file, then I look at that and then understand what you're
trying to do.
And this tracing agent that comes with the JV team that is included in the VM, it can facilitate the
job, it can facilitate generating these configuration files.
So native images are built ahead of runtime, a static compilation, and their build relies on a static
analysis of which code will be reachable.
Right.
So retrieval means which classes are on the class path.
Not only that, but native image.
As I mentioned before, it's smart.
Realizes that if there are some classes on the class path that your application never uses, or basically
JVM never has to load those class files into memory, then there is no point of compiling those and
adding them to your application because your application doesn't use them.
Right?
So reachable code in this sense means which method of classes are called.
Sometimes you have multiple methods in the class, but then some of them are never called.
Then there is no point of compiling those methods to the executable binaries because they are never
used.
However, this analysis cannot always completely predict all usages of the Java Native Image Java Native
interface, which we will look in the future.
Java Reflection.
This is our main topic.
We saw this before Dynamic Praxis Objects and this is a more like advanced topic and we will discuss
this in the future.
Lectures and class path resources.
And again, this is something we will definitely look at when we also look at the Native Java native
interface.
So resources are like, let's say your application using some resources, there is a CSV file, a comma
separated file and it has some data that your application at runtime needs to load those data.
So the question is what happens when we compile our Java application to native executable binary?
Right.
So what happens?
Do we still need to provide those?
Those a CSV file separately or something else.
Undetected usage of these dynamic features.
And again, the keyword is dynamic, which means something that happens at runtime.
And the way that the static analyzer cannot figure out, cannot figure it out by just looking at your
source code.
So undetected usages of these dynamic features need to be provided to the native image tool in the form
of configuration files.
And that's what exactly what we saw previously that native image was telling us, Hey, for this third
version of the reflection, give me a configuration file so that I understand what's going on.
I cannot figure it out on my own configuration files in order to make preparing these configuration
files easier and more convenient.
Google Vim provides an agent that tracks all usages of dynamic features of an execution on a regular
Java VM.
So this Java VM is the one that comes with the Google VM, right?
So this agent figure is not something that is, for example, present in Oracle VM.
This is something that only was added to this JVM that comes with the VM.
It can be enabled on the command line of the VM Java command.
So if you like to use the Java Command from the Google VM, so I'm using the Google home environment
variable being.
And in Java you use this particular flag and obviously after that you provide the main class, the fully
qualified name of the class that has the has the main method.
So hyphen agent Lieb call in native image agent, which means, hey, we want to activate the agent
tracing agent for the JVM and the use case is for native image building.
Right.
And then equals config output directory.
Which means that we want to use the tracing agent that monitors all the information that is related
to building a native image.
And we want to create those configuration files.
We want the native, the agent to create those and put them in this address, in this path for this
configuration output directory.
Right.
So again, the first part, hyphen agent lib, which tells the JVM, we want to activate the agent what
kind of agent it is.
It is native image agent, right.
Which means we want to activate the agent that monitors everything that could be related to a native
image build.
And this option is config output deer.
So we want to also specify an output directory that after the execution of the JVM terminates, we want
to save all the configuration files.
And here is the path to the configuration node.
That hyphen agent lib must be specified before a jar option.
Obviously we know that we can use java hyphen jar and give it a jar file and this has to be provided
before using hyphen jar or a class name.
So this three dot means either you pass a jar or a class name that has the main method or any application
parameters in the Java command line.
So this has to come first right after the JVM or the Java Command, you have to provide it.
This has to be right after the Java Command.
Use Native Image Agent option to trace all the requirements for Native Image compiler.
So this is the key here.
Now, before going to the next slide, let's head to Eclipse and let's configure the let's run our previous
Java application which was using reflection and then enabled this tracing agent.
And again, this only works with the Java that comes with VM and then let's give it an output directory
and see what kind of configuration files it's going to generate for us.
So here's our eclipse.
I have the direct creation of this complex number and then I also have this reflective.
And if you recall, when we run this in eclipse, eclipse creates a run configuration.
So let me run this again.
And in order for the run to succeed, obviously in the run configuration of Eclipse, we have to provide
the value for this argument.
So run configuration arguments and as you can see, we are providing this argument which is passed to
the string array.
Right.
All right.
So now note that here I'm using I configured my workspace, Java workspace to by default use the JDK
17 that comes from Oracle JDK.
So how do I run?
So whenever I right click and then say Run as it's going to use the Oracle JDK, how do I run this application
with the Google VM JVM?
There are different options.
The easiest one is we want to create a external tool configuration, which we already discussed.
I have this Java trace.
And this is pointing to the being directory being Java from the VM and then working directory.
I'm setting it to the project location.
And now this is what's happening.
Hyphen CP and project class path again for JV team, we have to provide the class path first and then
hyphen agent lib.
This has to come right after that, right hyphen agent lib and we can even put it before providing the
class path.
So.
Let's put this here.
So we're telling it hyphen agent lib which agent we want to activate?
We want to activate the native image agent.
What's the parameter.
It's the config output directory that we want to set and where do we want to set it.
We want to set it on the current working directory, which is the project location.
We want to create a meta hyphen INF directory and then we want to put a native image directory inside
that and all the configuration files are going to be stored in this native image directory.
So this is the recommended way that the official documentation suggests because meta inf and the native
image to this will be automatically picked up by the native image compiler.
So you don't need to do anything extra right.
But there is no need to basically put it in the meta inf.
But I recommend to do this for now.
Maybe we can also change it.
Let's say in the current directory puts them in the native directory which we typically put our or let's
say just create a directory configuration configuration, right, put them inside this directory and
then hyphen classic path is we're using eclipse and then what is the main class is Java type name and
we are providing command line arguments.
Remember that this application requires command line arguments.
And after we said that when we launched the JVM from terminal after the name of the main class, anything
that comes after that, any string becomes the command line arguments and it's going to be passed as
to that string array.
So this all looks good.
Let's select our source in the tree and then run our Java Trace.
Now, as you can see, the execution succeeded.
We have this configuration directory and now the JV team.
Basically that comes with a growl.
VM activated the agent that is associated for creating the configuration files for a native image build.
And you see, all of these are JSON files.
JSON are object models in a textual format which are very easy to understand and interpret.
So JNI config predefined classes, config proxy config reflection config resource config and serialization
config.
And we just saw that these four were directly mentioned in the PowerPoint slide JNI config proxy config
reflect config and resource config.
Right now, right now we're not using any JNI, so it's going to by default use the main ones that are
associated with them.
We did JDK and interestingly enough, it's also registering the main method of our main class as a resource
just in case.
Right.
And then the proxy config, nothing reflect config.
We have something.
Right.
So this is where exactly it comes from.
It says util forge complex, complex number name of raid double double.
So it's telling, it's creating a configuration files.
Hey, this class is being loaded reflectively and this method is being accessed reflectively.
Resource config nothing.
Serialization config, nothing.
Right.
So the main idea here is that the.
This line of code when we run it with on the JVM that comes with the VM, we run it on the with the
native agent.
Native agent enabled tracing agent eight figures out that there is some reflection going on right now.
If we basically
if we come in this out and I'm going to clean up this directory.
And then run my application with the Java VM, JVM with VM, which has enabled the tracing agent.
So if I run it, it works fine.
But if now if we look at the reflect configuration, there is nothing there because this part is commented.
So this part doesn't use any reflections.
What about, for example, here, this version too.
Let's clean up.
We don't need to clean up because the files get overwritten.
But here I'm just going to clean it up.
So Java Trace again, it succeeds.
Let's look at the reflect config.
It is still tells the native image compiler that there is some reflection going on, but we saw that
even in this case before, without any configuration, native image compiler had no problem compiling.
So.
So I'm going to recommend these uncommon these let's run the let's clean this up.
And then.
Let's run our Java.
Basically, let's select our class and then Java trace.
All right.
It creates that.
And then now we have to feed this to a native image builder.
And the best, the recommended way is to actually create a directory.
So I'm going to delete this actually.
And then.
They recommended way is to or the default way is to create a put the configuration files in a meta inf
directory.
I close that.
This latest.
So external tool Java Trace.
Let's zoom in.
So meter dash enough and inside that native dash image.
Right and then once we put this in the matter, if the recommended way is to then make this directory
be available on the class path, this meeting directory or basically the directory that is containing
this method enough to be available and the reason they chose this convention by default because of the
JAR files, right.
Because you can also run native image on a jar file and there is always a method inside the jar file.
So that's why this is this default way is compatible with the jar files.
So what we're going to do, we're going to now select our
basically Java file that has the main method and we're going to jump to our native image.
And then here, I'm not activating any agent, but then what I'm going to do if I run this, this is
going to fail because the class path is set to the project class path and it's just pointing to the
bean directory.
Whereas my method is not in the bean directory, but because my working directory is project location,
I'm just going to append dot to my class path.
This automatically puts the project location which is this Java native image top directory and therefore
my method directory here is is also on the class path.
Now if we run this, hopefully our Native Image compilation succeeds because Native Image by default
picks up this meta native image picks up all these configuration, it has this configuration or extra
information about the reflection use in our Java code.
So native image is probably not going to complain anything and then it just by default picks up all
those configuration files from meta.
Now you don't have to create follow this convention of the meta directory and in native image inside
that.
But that's the default way.
If you do that and put it on the class path, then you don't need to add extra flags to the native image
telling it, hey, activate the agent and then this is the configuration directory.
So everything succeeded.
Native Image didn't complain about the use of reflection here because it automatically picked up all
the configuration files in this native image directory.
Remember, the requirement was that this meta inf be on the class path.
So if we open up a terminal here.
And then run our application.
So we have to basically provide that command line arguments.
Our application required that and obviously it has to be exactly this, right?
Because after we load the class, we are accessing its method.
So if it's another class, we're going to fail, but now it succeeds.
Whereas previously, when we compiled this application without the configuration files, this compilation
fail.
But now it's succeed.
Obviously, if you provide any other class, then this class, this is going to fail because we don't
have any other class with this name on the class path.
If we provide something that is already on the class path, for example, Java lang a string and then
it's going to this line of code class for name is going to succeed.
But then there is a method of rate which is obviously not available in the string, right?
So this application has a very limited use case because you have to provide an exact argument.
I suppose.
Now sometimes you want to make sure that different inputs are basically okay and in order to do that
you have to run your application with the JV that comes with LLVM multiple times so that you accumulate
configurations more and more right, depending on the inputs that the user provides to the application.
This is very important topic and we will discuss it in the future lectures.
So I hope you enjoyed this one.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.