Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We are going to continue our discussion on how to run a Java application and then look at what is the
difference between running your job application and the JV team.
Basically you launch the JV team or the Java command line tool and then you tell it where your class
file that contains the main method is.
And then what is?
What happens when we actually compile our job application to a native binary using the native image
tool that comes with grad VM?
All right.
So in the previous lecture, we saw that basically organizing your Java application and let me bring
up the terminal.
We saw that organizing your Java application.
Obviously, you don't want every job, all the Java files to be in the same directory.
Sometimes you have multiple directories and then also sometimes you want them to belong to some package,
right?
Just because if you're creating a library, you want to put your class files, you make them belong
to packages so that later on somebody else can add them to their basically class path and be able to
use those codes that already exists in their application too.
But then the problem was that compiling and running the Java application is not a trivial task because
of the way that Java Java compiler and the JVM, which is the Java command line, handle the dependencies
of your classes.
And we saw that if I have a helloworld class and a core class and each one is defined its own in its
own Java source file, and then if they're in two different directories and we saw that in this example
for simplicity, we didn't make these classes to belong to any packages.
And basically the idea was that I couldn't just directly compile the hello world because it had a dependency
on the car.
So I have to I had to first tell the Java compiler to compile the car Java to create the card that class.
Because when I run the Java compiler and the Helloworld Java, it realizes that there is a dependency
and then it needs to ensure that Java always tries to be on the safe side and ensure that if it's trying
to compile this class, there shouldn't be any error, which means all the dependencies, all other
types that this class use have to be known to the compiler.
The compiler has to ensure that at compile time the ODIs, the other class files that are associated
with these types such as CAR in this case already exist on the on the hard disk.
Right.
So we had to specify the hyphen CPO or hyphen class path write this class path parameter and this here
released all the directories that the Java compiler or the JVM can search into.
And we said this is very similar to the path environment variable that the operating system and the
terminal understand.
Right.
It's very similar.
Path is an environment variable that has or has a list of directories.
So so that when you type some in some name, the terminal assumes that this is some sort of binary executable
binary application.
So it tries to search into all the directories that are included in the path to see where it can find
an application with this name.
Right.
And we said that in Java you cannot tell it Java and then the full path or the relative path to the
class file that doesn't board in order.
Instead you have to tell JVM this hyphen CP parameter and give it a list of directories that the JVM
can search into to find all the classifiers that it needs to run your job application.
Right?
So the concept of class path is very important.
And then basically there is another thing that we can do and that's I mentioned that you can define
something called the class path environment variable.
And if you define it in your terminal, when you launch your JVM, then basically you don't really need
to specify that.
CPP.
So what I mean by that, right now I'm in the test directory, right?
So if I say Java and then Hello World, I've already compiled these, right?
It's not going to work because it cannot find this card class.
Right.
So I have to tell it Java hyphen CPP and then the current directory where my hell of all classes and
then colon which is a class path separator and I'm going to tell it, go to one level up and then go
into the Test two directory.
So I'm specifying two directories on my class path when I launch my application that have these that
have all my class files that the application needs.
And then Italy launched the Hello World Class, which means JVM launches or runs the main method of
this particular class.
And this works right now.
So if I don't specify the class path, I get an exception, right?
So the application terminates unexpectedly just because it cannot find these core class, right?
But then what I can do is I can basically open up a text file, right?
And then I'm going to open Subtree, I'm going to go and then open up this bash.
RC So this is where you can define the environment variables, right, for your terminal.
So I'm going to define another one, define or a class path, class path environment variable.
Now when you globally define these class path environment variable for your terminal, every time you
launch the terminal, those directories that the class path is pointing to or are already available
to JVM.
So we say export class path equals right and then we give it a list of directories and then the separator
is colon.
So we can say, for example.
I'm going to give you the absolute path.
So I'm going to copy the full path to the clipboard and then go back here and put it here.
All right.
Now, what this does is this is basically the full path to this test to.
Right.
Now, I can also appendix dot and then give it another path and what you can do basically export class
path again.
But here what we're going to say that we're going to give it this test.
Also the fully qualified name of this test.
I'm going to put it in double code.
If your name, the folder name has a space or something, you have to put it into inside double codes.
But I'm going to append it with the original class path variable.
So this appends.
So the class path operator is calling it reads the when you use dollar sign, it means it's an environment
variable and it's reading the value.
The original value is test two and now the test directory is also appended.
Right.
So if I save this and then go back to my terminal.
What I'm going to do.
Either you have to restart the terminal or use a command called source to that.
Reload this bash RC file.
So I'm going to say that source from home directory.
Load the bash RC file again.
Let's see.
And everything is successful.
And then if I try to read this basically class path environment, variable eco class path, you see
there are two directories on my class path.
All right.
Now let's go out.
So I'm going to let's even go to the desktop right from home direct.
I'm on my desktop.
Right.
And then what I'm going to do, I'm going to say Java Hello World.
Let's see if it's successful in running this or not.
And as you can see, it's fully successful despite the fact that I'm not even in any of these tests
or test two directories in my desktop.
But when I told JVM to find a class file called Hello World Class and execute its main method, it had
no problem because Java behind the scenes, it tries to see if there is a global environment variable
for your operating system called the class path if it finds one.
It also includes all the directories that are defined by the class path to your class path variable.
So I can still specify hyphen c p something like current directory.
Right.
And then say hello world.
And this doesn't work.
When you explicitly basically provide this hyphen CPP for the Java it overwrites, it doesn't look for
the class path environment very well again.
So what you can do is say, for example, current directory call in and then that class path environment
variable and then hello.
All right, so.
Uh, basically.
So what happens here is that the problem with this is that you I guess we should put this in double
code or do something else.
Let's see if this works.
Double code and now it works.
So that's because there are forward slashes and other things.
So put this environment variables.
If you want to read the value, put them in double code so that there is no problem.
So basically this if there are some dependencies for your classes, let's say there are some libraries
that you always use, it's better to define the directories that contain those libraries as a class
path, as an environment variable, so that whatever application and you write, you compile those directories
are available to your Java application, right?
So for example, if I,
let's say, if I, if I create a new directory, let's say test three and here I'm going to create a
class file.
Right.
And let's rename these to something else.
Let's say instead of car, let's say machine and let's open it.
And here we're going to we have to rename it to Machine because if there is a public class definition,
a source file, the name has to match.
And then we're going to say that a string type and then we're going to pass the string here and then
we're going to obviously the name of the constructor should also be machine and we're going to say that
machine and then type equals percent s and then this is going to be type.
All right.
And then we go back to the hello world and then we create a car.
Then we create also a machine.
New machine type is a printer, for example.
And then we we're saying that sys print line machine.
All right.
Now going back here.
Right now I am in my desktop directory.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to back go back to the bash RC and then try to export basically
do the same thing I'm going to.
Go back here.
Class path equals.
And then.
And I'm going to basically append the test three to my class path.
All right.
Now I'm going to source the bash RC again to reload this environment variable.
So if I say a class path now, there are three directories on my class path.
Right.
Test three and then let's see.
So we have a.
Test two and then test.
Okay.
So.
Let's see.
So I'm going to let's close these.
All right.
And then reload a new window.
And Echo Classpass.
And now we have test three, test and test two.
Right.
So there are three directories and I can say Java C and then directly compile that helloworld java.
So file not for obviously here you have to specify the full path to that basically helloworld java.
So let's say right click on this and then copy full path to clipboard and then go back to the terminal.
And then we are going to compile this and note that I'm not specifying the I didn't specify this machine,
it's not there.
But because Java C also looks at looks at an environment variable called class path.
And if your class file if your Java source for Helloworld depends on a dependency like machine class
Java C also looks at those directories that are included in the environment variable to see if it can
find a dependent file called machine class and now I can even executed hello world.
Now note the difference when you compile a file, you have to give it a path where it is on the operating
system.
When you launch a Java application, you have to tell JVM the name of the class file that has the main
method.
You don't specify the path to that class file, right?
You just tell it the name and JVM fully relies on the class path, all the directories on the class
path, and it tries to search into them.
So this works.
Why?
Because I didn't specify any class path.
I'm not even in the test directory.
I'm somewhere else.
But when I launch it in terminal, the class path environment variable is defined.
All right.
And therefore, what happens here is that the JVM just searches into all the three directories and tries
to find a class file called Hello World.
All right.
So again, for when you launch your Java application, you don't provide the fully full name of the
file all class.
That's not how it works, right?
You just provide the name of the class file or the name of the type if it belongs to a package.
You have to also specify the package hierarchy here, the type or the class that has the main method,
and JVM only searches into the directories that are specified on the class path.
Now you can manually specify the class path directories using hyphen, CPP command line argument, or
you can define them globally in a variable in an environment variable called class path, right?
And you can append multiple directories using the colon, which is the class path separator.
So I hope you understand this.
Now what I want to show you is the concept of native image.
So let's go back here.
So copy, fully qualified name, let's change the directory into that.
All right.
And then so right now what we want to do, let's see if we can basically compile this hello world.
Hello world class to the native bytes.
So I have installed the VM basically native image I will show you in the future lectures how to do it
right.
And then what I'm going to do, I'm going to tell it to compile test let's it's in the test and then
basically.
What do we want to compile?
Hello world.
Let's see if this works.
Actually, I think the class path is already defined.
So what we want to do.
We just want to compile the hello world.
I believe it will able to it will be able to find a hello world not found.
So let's see.
Tess.
Hello world.
Not found, so it's still not able to find it.
So what we can do, we can specify basically I guess the same class path argument.
So hyphen c p class path.
All right.
And then
hello world.
Now it's working, which means what it does, it searches into all the directories that are specified
in this environment variable and it is able to find a class file called Hello World Class and it starts
to compiling it to the native binary.
Obviously this class has dependencies caught on machine and both of them are specified in the class
path.
So the native image has no problem finding them and also compiling them to the native binary.
What it does eventually it creates a native image.
Now the compilation succeeded and it says that I created a executable binary, which is Hello World.
And you see, it's here.
All right.
Now let's see if we can execute it.
So the execution of the native binaries applications in terminal are different from KVM, right?
When you launch the Java, you cannot give the path to the file.
You have to specify the directories in the class path.
Whereas when you want to execute a native binary, you provide the full path.
So I'm in the Java native image.
So from the current directory hello world.
And this is a fully executable file.
It's a binary application.
It doesn't rely any under any JVM, it doesn't anything.
It's fully dead and it works pretty well.
Right?
So we compiled our Java application into a native binary.
So this helloworld is a native binary.
I can give the full qualified name of this file.
Right?
So this is the, the fully basically the path, the directory hierarchy to the name of the executable
and in terminal Wendy this works.
You can always execute a native binary by providing either a relative path to it or a full path to it.
But if I execute it, it still works fine.
Hello world from Java application.
But this is not we're not launching JVM.
We just compiled our application directly to a native binary.
All right?
And now it works fine.
It gives us the output that we expect.
And right now, the way we compile our application was to rely on this class path, which is globally
defined and native image had no problem finding our class files.
Hello all and all the dependencies that it has, which is called class and machine class.
Obviously for large programs it's not recommended to basically.
Rely on this environment variable because you have to manually add them.
So there are better ways to manage them.
But in the terminal, if there are some dependencies that you always use for all your Java application,
it's best to also define them as a global variable called class path.
And the point here was to show you that you can define this class path environment variable and the
Java Sea and Java or the JVM.
They will also look at try to search for a variable called class path that is defined or known to your
terminal.
All right.
So.
I just showed you an example, a quick example of what a native image is.
You write your application in Java using a Java ID.
It saves you a lot of time for developing a big application.
Note that what we're comparing to, we're comparing developing a Java application to a C++ application,
because once you compile your application to native binary, you essentially are equivalent.
You're getting an equivalent to a C++ application that is compile to native binary launching.
This is instantaneous.
There is no JVM, there is no loading any JDK class files into memory, nothing.
Now the main difference, you will see that the size of this native binary from Java is much larger
than if you write an equivalent C++ application the file size.
If you compile, write this application that prints something to the console.
It's just a hello world.
Some objects in C++, the final file, which is executable, it's going to be like a couple of kilobytes.
But here this helloworld is probably around.
We can look at the properties, so it's run 11 megabytes and most of these size comes from compiling
the JDK classes.
Remember, your application depends on them.
So the native image compiler has to compile also all of them, right?
So this 11 megabyte, essentially a compiled version of all the classes that come with the JDK and your
application is probably just a few kilobytes that gets added to that 11 megabyte.
All right.
But again, the benefit is that this launched instantaneously and you pretty much get the optimized
version because the native binary has a static compiler that does a lot of static optimization.
So you get more or less equivalent to a C++ optimized the compilation.
So now that you've seen the example of Native Image, I'm going to give you more details of what this
is.
So the job of operating system is to manage the applications running on your computer.
Every time you double click on an executable file, it gets executed.
Every time you type the name of a executable file, write this helloworld in executable executable file.
And when you hit enter, the operating system realizes that this is an executable file.
So basically if I do ls hyphen a and then let's see.
So you see this hello world is red and has an asterisk.
This means this is an executable file, which means if you just type the name and hit enter, the operating
system is able to execute it and give you the feedback which are the output of the application.
Right.
The other ones that end with the slash, these are directories, right.
If I say hyphen basically ls hyphen l which means a long version of the listing.
This helloworld comes out as x, so x means it's an executable file.
All right.
And we will look at these attributes later on.
But for now, we're just looking at the Native Image Compiler application to the Java application to
a native binary.
Developing a Java application is much faster.
Java has a much nicer API, much easier to do.
And then when you combine that fact with the fact that we have very, very capable IDs, you see that
a native image gives us a lot of benefit.
So what is a compiled application?
A file cabinet containing binaries?
And these files have just the instructions for the CPU.
These are directly tied to the architecture of the CPU you're using.
For example, if you're using an AMD CPU 32 bit, 64 bit, if you're using a ARM CPU.
These are different.
So the binaries are not compatible because the CPU instruction sets are not compatible and instructions
sent for the CPU is just a machine code.
And usually machine code is just zeros and ones which we humans don't understand.
So at one level, higher than machine code is assembly code, which is very simplified instruction sets.
Humans are understand that, right?
Assembly code is human readable.
But then again, one level above assembly code are like C++ or C codes.
Right.
And the compiler compiles them to assembly and then an assembly application.
Compiles the assembly code into machine code.
So binary files can be directly run if they have executable permission.
And when you compile your job application with the native image, we see that when you do.
LS Which lists all the files with the hyphen.
L It tells you that this helloworld is executable.
It has an asterisk and it has the executable permissions.
And we will look at these permissions later.
Usually you have three groups of permissions.
The owner, which in this case is mean, is me, the group and then everybody else.
So right now this application has the I have the I'm the owner of this file and I have the permission
to execute it.
So the three first letters means I can write to this file, read to this file, x means execute.
So executable permissions mean I can just say hello world type the name and the terminal and operations
and will execute it for me now I can change the permission to execute permission.
So C mod means that change the mod or the demo that these files and I can say hyphen x and then helloworld
so what this does if I do ls hyphen l as you can see now this helloworld is not doesn't have an asterisk
anymore, which means this doesn't have the executable permission anymore.
If you look at it, the third character was x, but now that X is gone for everybody, right?
So if the owner removes the executable permission, everybody else also loses that.
What this means is if I just type hello world.
It says the file helloworld is not executable by this user.
Right.
I manually remove the permission for executing that, but I can bring it back by saying that c mod.
So let's go back c mod instead of saying minus x, which means remove the x attribute plus x, add the
executable attribute.
All right.
And now if I say ls hyphen l, now this binary has the permission.
So you can have a binary that has the instructions for the CPU.
But obviously the operating system is the guard between the applications and the hardware.
Right operating system has to make sure that if somebody tries to execute a file, that file has the
permissions, write permissions.
Otherwise, it's an illegal operation right to the operating system.
So there are checks and bounds so that the operating system ensures that it's not a malicious application.
So if I say hello world now I can I I'm able to run this binary again.
So file permissions, it's separate from whether the the file is basically a binary executable or not.
The nature of this helloworld is an executable binary, but you can only execute these if you have the
execute if the file has executable permissions right now, for example, this text file, it's a text
file, right?
It is not executable.
If you look at this, you see it doesn't have an executable or X attribute just because it's not really
executable.
You cannot execute this.
You can open it and read the characters from it, but it doesn't have instructions for the CPU.
Whenever you have a executable, it has really zeros and ones that the CPU understands, but it takes
file has zeros and ones that the operating system understands.
Right.
So the text file only character encoding.
So if you look at it, these characters are UTF eight.
Each character is encoded in 8 to 8 bits or one byte.
This is not something that the CPU understands, but it's the operating system that understands it.
So when you double click on this and open it, operating system realizes that there are zeros and ones
and because it's a text file, then it knows how to correctly translate those zeros and ones to a format
that the humans understand.
Right?
So there is a difference between binaries which have instructions for the CPU and the.
For example, it takes they don't have instructions for a CPU.
Those are just character encoding.
The zeros and ones in a text file are something that the operating system understands, not the CPU.
So binary files can be run if they have executable permissions on MAC OS or Linux.
You write smart, which means change.
The mode of operation of this file plus x means add the executable attribute minus x means remove the
executable attribute on macros and Linux executable files.
Don't have any extension right now when we compile our application here.
Helloworld.
It doesn't have any extension.
It's just executable.
Write extensions are extra information for the operating system.
If a file is executable binary, there is no instruction for the operating system.
You just tell the operating system, hey, this is executable and execute it, which means this file
only has instructions for the CPU.
Write a text file, has instructions or extra information for the operating system so that it knows
that how to display the contents correctly.
But the executable file it doesn't have, you cannot display it as characters, for example, because
it's just zeros and ones that the CPU understands.
On Windows.
Executable files have dot x dot xy permission.
Right.
So Windows is always a little bit different from Mac OS X and Linux platform tool change.
As you saw in my quick example of the native image, you have to use a compiler to compile some application
to or basically some source file into a executable binaries that CPU understands.
C++ is very easy.
They always have a strong compilers that understand the C++ source code for Java.
We had a two step process.
One, use the Java compiler to compile the Java source code to Java binaries to the JVM.
Understand.
And then on top of that, after that, we use the native image compiler that understands the class files
and produces a native executable binary.
So eventually you have to need some sort of compiler and feed your files, source files or in this case
class files from Java to that compiler.
And then it understands how to translate it to the instructions that the CPU understands.
And obviously compilers are optimized or they optimize your source file source code, which means they
can provide some levels of static analysis and static basically optimization compilers that compile
source code to binary for CPU every platform, which means every operating system.
In this case, they come with their own compilers because every operating system has a different API
that allows the user to talk to the hardware.
I mean, hardware could be the same but operate different operating system, use different APIs, the
functions they use, the conventions they use, they're different.
That's why when you compile to binary for different operating systems, you have to compile on those
operating systems, right?
Or use the compilers that are specific to that operating system.
Mac OS developed by Apple, they provide their own compilers, which is Xcode.
Right?
Xcode is the tool you can basically it's a general application, provides a nice interface.
You can type your code and compile it, but if you want to judge just the compiler, you can use command
line tools, you can type, you can so you can just install the Xcode application from the App Store
and then it automatically also installs all the toolchain, all the compilers and the dependencies that
those have.
But so Xcode on Mac OS, that's the easiest way to get all the platform tool change that you need.
And when you do that, let's open up a terminal here on Mac OS.
If you when you install the Xcode, it creates some aliases on the terminal for the compiler.
So if I type C++ hyphen version, it's pointing to the apple clang.
So it's a clang, but it has an alias to C++.
If I say clang, hyphen, hyphen version, it's pointing to the clang.
Again, if I say C++ hyphen version, it's pointing to the same thing, right?
All these aliases are created so that you can use that, right?
So even GKE hyphen version, if you want to compile a C instead of C++, it's going to basically I mean,
these days we just use the again, it's also pointing to the apple clang.
So when you the easiest way on MapQuest is just install the Xcode and then the toolchain is apple clang.
So it's based on clang, it's not based on, for example, the GCC or know and this is a proprietary
compiler.
So you cannot it's not open source.
You cannot download it for free unless you are using a mac OS.
Uh, there are uh, for example, Linux obviously open source.
So there are open source compilers, GKE, compiler collection.
You can even download and install GKE on Windows, for example.
They also provide that.
And on Linux you also have the option for Clang.
Same for Windows.
You also have the option for clang and these are open source free to use on windows.
If windows when you install it, usually when you install Linux, it always comes by default with the
GCC macros you you need to install Xcode, but it's a very easy installation.
You don't really need to do anything.
Windows by default doesn't come with any toolchain.
The options.
One of them obviously is provided by the Microsoft itself, which is SVC Microsoft Visual C compiler.
And in this lecture I'm going to show you how to install this.
This is the recommended way for working with the native image in Windows, but there are also other
options like GCC clang.
These are open source.
MSC is not open source, so it's also proprietary.
And why use native image?
Because a compiled binary which is pretty much ready to execute for the Java application, it has a
very fast startup time.
All the JDK classes have already been compiled and there is nothing.
We don't launch a JVM and really it's just the operating system that loads your application and instructs
the hardware.
That's it.
There is no middle step, which in general is the JVM.
Right?
JVM has been removed from the equation.
So the, the, the execution time of your application is very fast.
So I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.