Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on Native Image.
We looked at the build output, basically all the details of the outputs that the native image prints
to the console as part of the compilation and generating the native executable binary.
But the build output also has some options and you can look at the documentations again VM dot org.
The version, the latest version is 22.1 I believe, and then reference manual native image build output
and then build output options.
So I'm going to quickly open this up in a browser and we can have a look.
And then also so Google VM, build output options, run native image, hyphen, hyphen, expert options
all.
So it shows not only the regular options that the native image can accept, also all the extra options
or flags that are considered as expert options.
And then we are pipeline.
The output of this command to the grep grep is just for filtering.
It just means a search for this particular string which is build output and only show the lines in the
output of this command that has this particular string in them.
So grep is just for filtering strings, right.
And the pipeline thing we've seen in the past, I mentioned that.
Let's see.
Where was that?
This one.
So actually, let's.
Uh, let's see.
Where was, uh, when we talked about the AI terminal.
Let's see.
Terminal, this one.
So we said that there are arrows, right?
Like the greater than sine which indicate the IO streams of the console input stream output, extremes
or error.
And these are four streams to the files.
But then.
And then the pipe lining is the streams from the output of one application directly to another application.
So if you're again not familiar with the basically with the bash terminal, so pipeline so basically
arrow operator means we are streaming the output of a particular application to a file, whereas the
pipeline or the pipe operator means we are streaming the output of one application to another application
so you can have a multiple of this pipeline and the.
So basically the idea is that, as I mentioned before, terminal is a text based application which or
a string based.
So the output of, for example, a application whatever you execute in terminal is always going to be
some sort of text.
Now obviously you can stream this, for example, to, to a file.
So if I just type the name, so let's clear and say here, but for example, stream it to a file.
So my file dot text.
So this output is stream streams the output which is just a text textual output, right?
The strings that are supposed to go to the terminal instead it redirects the output to a file, whereas
I can say pipeline the output to another application, let's say grep anything, I don't know, desktop.
Right.
I want to see if when I list all the directors in my home directory which one has a desktop.
This one has a desktop, right.
So there's only one directory, one line in the output of this command that has this word desktop in
it.
Right.
So that's how the pipeline works.
And now it tells you that.
You can look at the build output options using this by first, you can look at the native image export
options.
So let's see Google home being being a native image
and then let's first of all look at the version.
So let's see.
Google home.
Google home being a native image hyphen, hyphen version.
And we're using the 22.1 version.
And then we want to look at the output.
So let me just open up these.
Now we want to look at all the options, hyphen, hyphen, expert options.
All right.
So if I don't grab it or just look at the all the output of this command, you see, there's lots and
lots of options.
Right?
There's a huge amount.
Now, you can save these options to a file.
And later, look at them.
For example, let's redirect the output instead of to the terminal.
I'm going to redirect it to VMM expert options dot txt.
So I'm taking this redirection or the output is streaming means instead of printing the output of this
application to the terminal, redirect it to a file and now I can go ahead and go to my home directory
and open up this text file.
So let's look at it.
So you see this text file now exists.
I can open it with a text editor and you see, we redirected the output of this application using the
output stream of the terminal.
To a file instead of printing to the terminal.
Right.
So this this arrow operator means redirection.
And you see.
Let's bring back this text where you see there are lots of options.
The native image has lots and lots of options.
Literally like 1000 different options.
And obviously in the I cannot in one course, you cannot really go through all these expert options
because that takes a huge amount of time.
But I will show you some of the most useful options.
And what do they mean?
So for the build output, there are some build outputs that basically like change the behavior of what's
printing to the terminal as the native image goes, goes through the build process and creates the executable
file.
For example, build output breakdowns, show code and heap breakdowns as part of the build output.
And this is, if you recall, we said that this this part of the this extra information is in the performing
analysis and creating image.
It tells you like what size what percentage of the total size is for the code area image heap other
data, how many classes were actually compiled, how many fields and methods were actually needed for
your job application, etc. So build output breakdowns, you can set it to false and the way you do
it for the boolean or options usually you use plus minus.
So all these expert options start with hyphen edge.
So let's go back to the test.
Let's actually go back and open up this text file.
And you see there are different categories of these options.
One, it starts with hyphen edge.
Let me zoom in.
Right.
So these start with hyphen edge, the other ones.
So let me zoom back.
Yeah.
So these ones start with hyphen edge column.
The other ones start with the hyphen are.
So if I scroll down now they are hyphen R, right?
So there is a difference for the build stage.
Most flags are, most flags start with hyphen, edge and then colon.
And if it's a boolean flag, you can turn it on and off with plus or minus sign, right?
So these build output options, these are all Boolean flags because they start with a plus or minus
and then build output breakdown.
So if I tell it hyphen edge plus build output breakdowns, it shows the code and he breakdowns as part
of the build output.
And the default is plus, which means by default this is enable hyphen edge colon plus or minus build
output, colorful colorize build output and by default it's on.
But know that your terminal has to support a colorful messaging.
And we saw that, for example, if you run the fish application on top of your shell in macros or Linux,
then fish supports the colorful output.
This is the output in MapQuest, for example.
This is the output of Linux and we saw that in Windows.
It's really not that colorful.
So it doesn't matter if you turn it on or off.
If your terminal doesn't support the colorful output, then you're not going to see it right now.
For example, I can go back to my eclipse and let's delete this.
My app.
We already created this simple hello world application and so I'm going to open up a terminal here.
And then so we pass these flags to the native image.
So girl home and then bean and then native image and then a hyphen H minus.
Let's look at the flag again.
It's below the output.
Colorful.
So I'm going to copy it and then go back to my terminal and then paste this here.
So now I'm basically turning this flag off and then hyphen CP here and then the name of the main main
class is Hello World without the dot class extension and I want to generate the my app output.
So let's see what happens to the output.
And now you see the output is not colorful.
Previously it was colorful.
The first row was if you look at the previously, the first logo was colourful.
This was like a purple thing.
And then these lines are a yellow colour in Linux.
They were also the yellow colour.
But now in my case I turn this boolean flag off telling it Hey, don't print colourful.
Don't print colorful information.
So you see, it's just a just black and white.
There is no color because I passed this boolean flag to my native image compiler and then it turned
this flag off.
So if a boolean flag for the compilation or the build, it starts with hyphen, edge, colon and then
plus means enable this boolean flag minus means disabled boolean flag.
Right?
So the output is not colorful at all.
Now, obviously, as I mentioned, you can redirect the output to a to a text file.
So let me just delete this.
And that has nothing to do with the Native Image tool.
It's just the property of the bash terminal.
So instead of printing to the console, I want to say that, hey, run this, build, create my app,
but then also redirect a save the output that the native image generates to let's call it build the
underscore output dot txt.
Right?
So it's not going to print anything to the terminal, it's going to create this text file right in the
same directory here and you will see that this text file gets updated.
So if I continue refreshing.
Or maybe close it and open it again.
This will get updated over and over again because the terminal you see now it gets updated because as
the build progresses, the output stream of this application from native image is redirected from the
terminal to this output text file.
So we are seeing the output instead of terminal.
We are seeing it kind of live in this text file.
Right.
And this is good if you want to as scripted and kind of do the compilation automatic or you are running
this kind of compilation and builds on a server and you don't want the terminal to be busy with your
compilation, you just want to redirect and then save the output.
So if something goes wrong in one of the bills, you can also look at the outputs, right?
So we saw that it it redirects the output to a text file and and then our build is successful and we
can actually run my app, my underscore app.
Obviously, it works fine.
But then the other thing that we notice is that when you redirect the application like this, the terminal
is still busy.
So, so let me just delete this build again.
If I look at the terminal, when I ran this previously, the terminal was busy, right?
So it doesn't release the shell, it redirects the output to the text file.
But the process is still makes it keeps the shell busy.
So.
Basically if we pass a ampersand, you see now it immediately releases the terminal so I can go ahead
and do other commands.
It's fine, but that process is still running.
You see this build output is still running and we are building, but the terminal is not busy and this
is good.
If you're trying to run multiple bills simultaneously in the terminal, obviously your processor, you
should have enough processing power to handle that.
But then the terminal is free.
You can go ahead and do other stuff and then your process is running in background.
So basically this ampersand whenever you tell.
Now it's also fish is informing that there was one job running in the background.
This has ended and everything is done right.
So if you want to run a command in terminal and you know that it's going to take a long time and you
don't want the terminal to be busy, you want to also run other commands, you can run the commands
in background.
So in order to run a terminal command in background, you ended with ampersand.
Ampersand means, hey, run this command, but run it in background and release the terminal.
Don't make the terminal busy.
I want to enter other commands.
Right.
And that also includes, for example, this my app, I can run it and the terminal has to wait for the
app.
Right.
But then I can tell it.
Run my app, but release the terminal.
So run this in the background.
As you can see, it immediately returns but then it is still prints the output to the console because
my application also it releases the terminal but it it is still generates some output to the terminal.
So the terminal has to go back and print it.
Right.
And then the fish is intelligent in the sense that it tells me, hey, there was one job running in
the background and it was this command and now it's ended, it's finished, right?
So again, I recommend that on macOS or Linux you run fish on top of your current terminal because it
adds more features, right?
So the build output, again, we redirected the native image output to a text file and then we can also
use the ampersand command so that we run it, we run the build in the background.
Usually when you have a build server, a server that you use, let's say a server has 64 CPU cores,
so you can run multiple bells simultaneously because your server has enough compute power or CPU power
to handle.
And then a.
Basically you can when you run one build in the terminal, you want to run it with the ampersand so
that the build is run in the background.
And then you also want to redirect the output of the native image to a text file so that if something
goes wrong, you go back and look at what went wrong, right?
If Native Image encounter an error, the output is still going to be in the text file.
Right?
So that's the thing.
Later I will show you that in macOS and Linux we can run, we can write Shell commands that automates
this kind of build processes.
And then in the Shell command, obviously we redirect the output to a text file so that we log the build
process.
So that's one of the things, right?
But the point here was to show you that there are two types of flag for the native image.
One of them is hyphen edge colon.
The other one is hyphen are colon.
Right.
So there are two types of commands.
And most of these are booleans so you can enable them with plus sign disabled them with minus sign.
So hyphen edge colon plus or minus build output breakdowns build output colourful build output GC warnings
build output links show links in build output.
Again, default all of these build output options.
The default is plus except for this one build output prefix prefix build output with the PDP ID is the
process ID and then the image name.
The default is negative.
So if you again run multiple bills simultaneously on a computer, each run each build is a separate
process.
Right.
And then you can if you want to distinguish which builds have finished, you can also pass the PID and
in.
If you enable this, the native image is going to add the process ID that was used to launch the native
image so we can go ahead and actually test this again.
So let's delete this.
And let's go back to our terminal.
All right.
So I'm not going to redirect to output.
Let's just keep to the terminal, but let's keep the bell.
The colorful.
So we plus and again you can always add the multiple flags hyphen edge plus and what flag do we want?
We want to build output prefix with a plus sign so that we enable it.
All right.
And in hyphen classpass here and this.
So let's run these.
So now it's obviously it's a colorful and now it's actually giving the process information.
And the reason is that sometimes something goes wrong in the process, CPU or operating system decides
to terminate the process unexpectedly.
But all operating systems keep a background log of all the processes that are running, how long it
took and other stuff.
Right?
So, so if you know the process ID, you can later go back and check on the OS level the logs that the
operating system does of what was wrong in the process or if something happens right now, everything
worked fine.
This process terminated, my application was generated, right?
But then in the terminal, in the output of the native image, it also logs the which application,
which native executable was generated and what was the process like for launching this native image
application?
Right.
So when you run a native image, you're running an application which is native image, you feed it your
class file and it generates something.
So it's a process that is running.
And again, right now it's running in the foreground of my terminal because I didn't use ampersand.
Ampersand means run it in the background, don't print anything to the console.
Actually, it prints to the console as it is still allowed to print to the console, but it kind of
relinquishes the control of the console.
The shell, right.
The shell is not busy.
All right.
And let's go back to our PowerPoint and finish up on this.
So belt output progress report progress in belt output enabled plus by default and then build output
use new style use new build output style default is plus.
Right.
So again.
If I think that there was some old style of the output that the native image prints to the console and
now they switch to the new style and it's a basically by default enabled, we can actually go back and
test this.
So let's copy this, build output, new style and then go back to our terminal to the next one here
and then we are going to run our application.
Let's remove the previous two flags that we passed to a native image and then we're going to say hyphen
edge, minus, build output, new style.
Again, a belt flag.
It starts with hyphen colon and then minus means this is a Boolean flag, we're going to turn it off
or set it to false.
So which means don't use new style output and then we run it.
Oh, actually, we made a mistake.
So I'm going to terminate this process.
So let's delete this output again and then go back to our terminal.
So yeah.
So hyphen edge colon hyphen build output, new style.
And now here.
So warning option build output.
New style is deprecated and might be removed from future versions.
So this is the old style.
It shows the likes, the name of the app, the process ID class list caps set up.
So for example, in the native VM version, JDK 11, this was the style that it used to print to the
console, right?
And now they in the 17 they switched to the new style, which is colourful, nice.
It gives you more information.
It walks you through all the steps and also tells you that okay, I also print build artifact to here.
So it just tells you that I created an executable file called to my app.
All right.
So this is the concept of build flags in the future lectures.
If there are some important flags, I will definitely walk you through them.
Most of these, again, are Boolean flags.
You turn them on and off with plus minus.
And there are two categories of the flags either hyphen, edge or hyphen.
Ah, I hope you enjoyed this one.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.