Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on how to set up the Native Image tool as an external tool in
Eclipse.
And so far we've seen how to do it for Eclipse projects, right?
The projects, the Java projects that you create inside the Eclipse ID and we said that the way Eclipse
manages its projects is that it compiles the Java source files and put them in the Bing directory so
you can set the being the being directory of your current project to the basically as the workspace
working directory when you run the native image.
And we said that a better approach is actually to set the working directory to the project location
and explicitly provide the hyphen f argument for the native image, the class path.
And then we said that you have to use the project class path environment variable, which is very important
and the eclipse already is aware of all the dependencies on your for your Java project, every directory
that is inside the class path.
All right.
Now with Maven, similar thing.
You go you open an external tool configuration, you click on this new button, you give it a name,
let's say native image maven and you point it to again contents home lieb svn substrate vm being directory
and in native image remember native image doesn't come by default with the crawl VM, you have to install
it separately and then the working directory.
So Maven compiles and then puts the stuff all the classes into the target classes.
So instead of the being directory you can point it to the classes directory, target classes inside
the project.
So what I'm doing here, there are different ways obviously to set this up.
Let's go back here.
Let's zoom in.
One is to use the workspace, location, environment variable, internal variable and give it an argument,
a relative path, which is project name.
And then for a slash target for slash classes.
And we know that if you use call in and some argument, it's actually the argument for this internal
variables and workspace location can accept arguments.
And what it does is you provide a relative path to the workspace and this whole string will be substituted.
So we saw it here, workspace, location, this internal variable can accept an argument, right?
And this argument is the relative path to your directory from the workspace, the root of your workspace,
right from the worker.
So you can just look at the tree view in the eclipse ID and then figure out quickly what this relative
passes.
And then the workspace location eclipse already knows that, right?
And so you can put the work in directly to the class's target classes.
And then the same thing Java type name.
This returns the fully qualified name of the class file and then the output, the name of the binary.
And then you can it can only be a name or a path to a file, right?
Previously we said the dot, dot forward slash and 84 slash project name, which means after you compile
it, go one level up from the working directory.
Basically it goes in the project location and then goes into the native directory.
This directory called Native, which is in the project location and then creates a executable file called
Project Name, whatever the name of the project is or the name of the class Java type name, etc..
So the same story here.
So again with Maven, it compiles it and it puts the classes, all the packages and all the classifiers
inside a directory called target classes.
It clips, it puts them in the Bing directory.
And then basically when you specify an output file name or an output path to a file, it puts the binary
into working direct.
So if you don't specify this output, it just puts the working directory, basically the executable
file after compiler and puts it inside the working directory.
You can specify absolute path through here to some file and then after the compilation, that file is
generated inside whatever path that you give it.
So let's head to a list and try to create a Maven project.
So this is our previous Java project.
This is an Eclipse project, this is not a Maven project, which means the build system is the internal
build system of eclipse.
Right.
And we know that what it means is that eclipse creates a bean directory inside your the root of your
Java project and then mirrors whatever you have in the Z in the being directory.
Right, all the packages etc. and we select any directory that is not marked as a package is not recognized
by eclipse IDE as a package.
It's not going to be inside the being directory.
Now what we want to do, we want to create a maven directory.
So we're going to go to order.
And then inside the maven we're going to say a MAVEN project.
And we're going to tell it, create a simple project and put it in there.
Whatever the workspace location is, let's add it to the working set, our working sets.
I believe it's called Native Image Advanced Resolved Workspace Projects.
For now, we're going to ignore it.
Group ID, Java Dot Native dot image and in artifact ID Native Image Demo Versioning.
Let's start with 1.0 as snapshot packaging.
We're going to add jar the name description.
Let's leave this open.
We don't want and resolve resolved workspace projects.
We don't need to worry about that now and finish.
So this is going to create a maven and you see the difference between obviously there are some differences
between a Java project, a project that is managed by Eclipse, right?
The build system is Eclipse and whatever is managed by Maven, obviously the directory hierarchy is
different.
Here we have a CRC and your packages, here we have CRC, main Java and then you add your packages here.
So it's the main resources CRC test, Java Z test resources.
And then it also shows you the obviously the Z directory here and this is target and target for now
it's empty.
And in the route of your Maven project, you have this pom pom file which basically tells the maven
what to do.
So if you're not familiar with Maven, I recommend just try to maybe Google it and understand what Maven
is.
And basically Maven is a build system and it doesn't have a Java compiler or anything, right?
It relies on whatever Java or Java C you have on your path.
So which Java C basically it relies on the JDK that comes with your that is installed and recognized
by your operating system.
MAVEN is just a tool that uses the JDK to build your application, and the beauty of Maven is that it's
independent of which IDE you use.
Now the problem with the internal build system of the is like Eclipse or other IDs is that each IDE
has its own build system like the directory hierarchy, the class path entries and how they manage.
We know that for example, Eclipse creates a dot project dot setting.
So if I open up a directory here, you see we have this dot setting.
These are the settings that are related to the eclipse dot class path.
This is only something that Eclipse IDE understands.
If you try to open this Eclipse project in another IDE, they probably won't understand it.
Same with the DOT project.
This is something that only Eclipse IDE understands.
So transforming.
Or if you create a java project with one IDE and give the source code to another one, if they try to
import it in another IDE, they most likely are not going to be successful in the first try.
But that's not true with Maven because MAVEN is an external build system.
Now IDs have support for it, which means IDs can figure out which MAVEN is installed on your computer,
and then they just can use that maven to build your application, write your Java project and the beauty
said Maven is independent of IDs.
Maven is something that you separately install on your computer and IDs can use that, right?
So if you have a Maven project, you can always import it in any ID and your ID.
Obviously, most of the IDs these days, they have support with MAVEN.
They have built in support so they can use Maven to build your project and therefore you don't get any
headache of the fact that one project from one IDE is not compatible with another.
Now Maven has obviously one more advantage, which is the main advantage, and that's dependency management.
MAVEN has online repositories.
You can specify a dependency on a JAR file, and Maven can go and search into online repositories.
And if it finds it, then it can download the jar file and add it to your class path fully, automatically.
And usually IDs like Eclipse have a nice graphical view of what's going on, what Maven is doing.
So I have installed Maven on my computer, Apache Maven 385.
Let's quickly open up a browser and see what is the latest version of Maven.
So let's say download Maven download Apache Maven.
Maven is a project organized by maintained by Apache organization and the latest version is 385, which
I have it here.
And as you can see, my maven home is user local maven 3856 because I'm using the home brew to manage
my maven.
Whenever there is an update, I use Brute.
To update my maven and just and then the JDK, you see Maven doesn't come with the JDK, but when you
look at the hyphen hyphen version, it also picks up on whatever JDK that is on your path environment
variable.
So and it also recognizes Java home environment variable, which I have already set up Java home.
So basically it also searches and you can also define another variable called Maven home.
So Maven underscore home.
You can also define that, basically pass it to this address.
All right.
And yeah, so again, Maven is a Bell tool.
Maven understands how to build your system.
You put your source files in the directory that Maven understands or expects, and then Maven calls
the cause the.
Basically Java C, the java compiler manages your dependencies, make sure everything is on the class
path.
All the dependencies are available.
So let's create a new package.
It's called Java.
Underscore.
Native, underscore.
Image.
And I'm just going to copy and paste that test class that we had.
All right.
So we're getting an error because we don't have that dependency on the other projects.
So for now, I'm going to leave it.
I will show you how to add dependencies, internal dependencies, but for now we're just printing something
to the console.
Hello from Java and external tool in a MAVEN project.
Right.
All right.
So everything is said.
So we develop our Java code, we put our packages and all the Java classes, source files inside the
SRC, main Java, if we have any resources, extra files, something like a text file or anything CSV
file that our Java project requires, we put them in the Z main resources.
And then what we want to do right now, the target directory is empty, right?
So if I open it up because actually what happens this integration or actually it's not empty.
So the reason is that the way that Eclipse ID supports MAVEN projects is that it uses Eclipse compiler
to compile the Java files, but it recognizes that Maven in MAVEN, all the class files has to be in
the target.
So right now this let me hide up the hidden files.
We have this target eclipse compiled this class file using its internal compiler and then it creates
the package hierarchy inside the classes.
Right.
That's how this ID eclipse supports MAVEN projects.
It recognizes where to put the packages and then the the class files.
Right.
But in general, you don't need to do that.
Some IDs don't use their internal compiler to compile the MAVEN project.
So what you can do when you have a MAVEN project, if you right click go to the run as not only we have
Java application, but we have Maven build, right?
So and then now you can execute MAVEN commands and those commands are passed to the MAVEN tool that
is installed on your computer right now.
It says embedded 3.8.1.
I don't want to use the embedded that comes with eclipse.
I want to use my external.
And the external is let's edit is 385 is the latest version.
All right, finish, apply.
And now it works fine.
So we want to by default, we want to use the external maven tool that I have separately installed my
on my computer because that's the latest version.
And let's hit apply.
Let's say we want to clean it.
When you execute Maven Clean Command, it's going to clean delete all everything that is inside the
target directory.
So let's run this and.
And what you see here is that it's running the native image demo maven clean plugin, deleting everything
inside the target.
So if I open up the target again.
Now these classes is empty.
We deleted the automatic compilation that Eclipse had done.
Right.
So if I run this.
It's not going to.
There is no class in here.
So therefore there is no eclipse.
Cannot execute it.
If I make some changes and save it, Eclipse is most likely is going to recompile.
So classes now eclipse it quickly recompiled.
And then the test class is available.
And now if I right click and run it, it works, right?
So basically eclipse every idea has its own internal compiler.
I mean some ideas might not but most modern ideas like Eclipse or intelligent, they have their own
internal compiler, at least Eclipse does.
And when they support a Maven project, basically Eclipse by default uses its own internal build but
puts it in where it's compatible with the maven.
Right.
It understands that this project has a maven nature.
And one thing here is that if you see it right now, the compatibility it sets up, it's using JDK 17,
but the competitive compatibility is sets up to JDK five, which means I cannot say war as is Hello.
Now Eclipse says that remember the JDK is JDK 17, but the compatibility is by default with MAVEN projects
inside Eclipse is set to JDK five.
That's why Eclipse is giving giving us a warning, right?
So it says change project compliance, compliance and go to ten so we can do that.
And now the compliance is set to JDK ten, but I want to set it to JDK 17.
So how do we do that?
So we just go here and select JDK 17, and now this works.
She sold eggs.
And let's run this.
It works fine, right?
And if we do a six out run time dot version, remember, Virgin is a static method.
It tells me which JVM it's running on.
It's running on 17.
All right.
But now let's say instead of using Eclipse, I want to use Maven to build my project.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to right click on my project, run as Maven Build, and I'm going
to tell you to clean and then compile supply run.
So it failed.
So I cleaned up, empty this directory and it failed.
So why did it fail?
Because.
So it cleaned.
It used a clean plugin, and then it used the compiler plugin and then compiling this one source file.
And then source option five is no longer supported.
Use seven or later build failed failed to execute the compiler on project is it says use seven or later.
So why is it that we already set the compliance to 17?
That's because MAVEN doesn't care, doesn't understand Eclipse projects.
Maven only understands pom or pom file, so you have to give it properties a
compiler,
I guess it's maven dot compiler, dot source, let's say 17.
And in May when the compiler target 17.
If we save these and then try to rerun that command again.
Maven build, clean, compile.
Let's see if this works.
Now build successful.
So basically again, Maven, when you run the build your Maven projects inside Eclipse with the external
maven build, it doesn't understand the Eclipse project or anything.
It just looks at the point file, looks at the configurations and then executes those.
There are some dependencies here.
We will talk about them later and then you can also look at the file.
Right?
So these properties.
Maven compiler.
Source.
Target.
Again.
These are a quick tutorial about Maven and how it works.
And inside the Eclipse idea.
Again, Eclipse uses its own internal compiler but puts the classifiers at the correct location.
Now let's say we want to build an external tool for Maven, and I've already set something up here.
Let's go back and use the most recent version of the LLVM 22.1 contents home.
Uh lib.
SVM and then being directory native image.
This is the most latest version 20 2.1.0 and I'm setting this to project location target classes.
All right.
Working directory and I want to select a Java file in my.
In my tree view inside eclipse.
And then I want the native image to basically or the eclipse to pass the classified fully qualified
name of the class file to that.
And then I'm telling you to remember we are inside the working classes, so I want to go back up to
the project location.
So to level up dot, dot, dot, dot and I want to go inside a native directory and then create the
executable file there.
So let's apply and let's close.
So we want to create a directory which is not part of the MAVEN project, let's call it native, and
then we're going to select our source file.
And we're going to select our native MH 17 maven and running.
Let's see if this works.
Fine.
So right now, a native image tells us, hey, I'm a, I'm building this, uh, java native image test
class.
So initializing.
Building universe parsing methods in lining methods.
Compiling methods.
And success, right?
So it puts it in the native image demo, native Java and Native Image.
And if you look at our native, we do have a.
We do have a target.
So.
So if you open up a terminal here in this native and if we say Java native test class, it's going to
work.
Hello world from Java.
A Hello World from Java an external tool in Maven project.
Hello.
Is this a string.
And then 11 three JVM psi.
So this is running on top of the compact JVM that has been compiled to native binaries.
Right.
So right now our external tool is successful for running basically maven compiling and MAVEN prices.
You have to point it to the classes.
Now, alternatively, as we mentioned, we can duplicate these and set it to project location and then
manually provide the hyphen P and then a project class path.
Because even though this is a Maven, Project Eclipse is aware this is inside Eclipse.
So Eclipse is aware of the project class path.
All right, so let's rename this or maybe let's copy and paste this to another name.
Um.
Uh, demo class.
All right.
So and then we're going to select this.
We're going to run our external tool, which we just duplicated.
Now the class path is explicitly set, so let's run these, see if this is successful or not.
Google VM.
Native Image generating java.
Native Image.
Demo class.
Initializing.
So let's wait a little bit.
Let's see if everything goes fine.
Performance analysis done.
Building universes.
In lining methods.
Compiling methods.
And it failed.
So there was an arrow linking the native image.
So it says.
There was some error going on.
Oh, that's okay.
That's because.
So we made a mistake.
The mistake we made was we actually changed the working directory.
And the problem is that when it was in the linking phase is when after compilation it tries to build
the final binary.
But this path was not correct so it couldn't find this native.
So in the project location we just have to tell it dot from the current working directory which is project
location and go inside the native and create a binary.
You know, that was a mistake.
So let's run this one more time.
So this directory exists because the Native Image Command is running from the root directory of the
Java of this Maven project native image demo.
So the native directory is directly there.
So when the linker creates the executable, it's able to find this native directory and puts the executable
file there.
All right in lining methods, it's almost done compiling.
And after that, the linker creates the executable file and everything went well.
So we have this.
We already had a terminal open here.
So let's see Java, native image and then demo class and it works fine.
All right.
So we were able to successfully create an external tool for MAVEN project.
Just note that the the most important thing about MAVEN is dependency management.
And Maven provides a very nice and easy way to manage all your dependencies.
And then and then the eclipse ID when you have this maven project inside the eclipse ID, it already
is aware of all the dependencies.
Therefore, it's very easy to set up this shell command so that all the dependencies are there, right?
So in the in the next lecture, I will actually use Maven to add dependencies to this project and then
we will see what happens.
And the nice thing about this configuration of the external tool.
Which we manually ask the eclipse ID to provide, basically substitute this variable project class but
with all actual class path entries.
And therefore we don't really need to change anything even if we add lots of dependencies to this project.
So please stay tuned and I'll see in the next one.