Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
I'm going to continue our discussion on the native image build output options and we saw that there
are two types of options and you can look at the very comprehensive list with the hyphen, hyphen,
expert options all.
And one of the categories is the build output options.
And again, the two types of options are either hyphen edge Colin or hyphen or Colin.
As I mentioned in the future lectures, I will go into more details of these if any of the options are
very important.
For example, we saw that the build output options, they are hyphen edge and it and all of them are
boolean and you enable or disable them with plus or minus plus means enable them and then minus means
disable them or set them to false.
And then we also look at the default values like pretty much everything by default is enabled except
for this one build output prefix this we saw that it prefixes the output name of the native binary and
also the PID or the process ID that was run PID image name and it's disabled because we don't care that
much about it.
And I mentioned also about this pipeline thing and the bash terminal and we saw that there are two types
of pipelines.
One is this operator, which is called Pipeline.
The other one is the like the greater than symbol or the arrow operator, which redirects the output
of the application to basically a file.
Right?
This pipeline operator redirects the output of the application to another application.
That's how you can change it.
Right.
And if you just want to look at all the expert options all and then filter only the ones that have this
build output stringing them, you can pipeline the output of this command, right?
Native image, hyphen, hyphen, expert options all and then pipeline the output and use the grep a
binary like it's an application that its job is to filter out all the lines of a text or whatever is
the output of another application is using the string that you provide.
So we only filters out and the fish terminal is very intelligent.
It shows you this string in a red, which is very easy to see what's going on.
So if I execute this command and say pipeline great build output, it only filters out and shows me
the outputs that the options that have this built output is stringing them breakdowns, colorful GC
warnings, links, prefix progress using USD.
All right.
And now I want to basically show you the same pipeline with a application.
We write a Java application and then we compile it to native executable binary.
And then you can, for example, feed to inputs if your application needs some input using this pipeline
a basically operator in terminal.
So let's head to our eclipse.
Now previously I had this test test two and test three directories and I actually added them to my class
path.
So let me open up a terminal at the root of my Java project.
If you look at my class path environment variable, which my terminal understands that because I define
this in my bash.
RC So that every terminal session that I open, they are available for this class path and test three
test and test two.
Right?
So any Java class, the Java source file that I put on any of these and I just run Java on it, I don't
need to specify the class path because if you don't explicitly, explicitly provide the hyphen CPP or
hyphen hyphen class path, then the Java Sea and also the JVM, they just search for the class path
environment variable.
So what I'm going to do, let's delete these previous artifacts that we created.
I'm going to create a new or maybe let's just copy and paste this Java file.
Spades pasties.
Let's call this a command line or terminal pipeline.
Terminal pipeline.
So obviously the name of the class should be the same as the source file.
If it's a public class terminal pipeline.
All right.
What we are going to do, we are going to ask the user to let me also clean up everything here.
Now, we saw that the command line arguments actually get passed as this a string array, but we don't
need to really do that.
Right.
The other way of getting information.
So so one way is to use the string arcs, right?
And these are past when you launch your application.
But besides that, you can use you can also use the standard input.
So the way we do it, we use the scanner class.
A scanner is new scanner.
And then here you want to specify an input, a stream, and for that you provide a standard input to
your KVM.
So system.
Remember when we in the Java source file when we want to talk about JVM, it's the system class dot
in it is a input stream which is an abstract class, right?
A static final, an input abstract class and a standard input stream which means input to your JVM.
And now you can see what's going to happen, right?
I can I can have some other application that outputs some text and then when I pipeline it to the input
to my JVM.
So system dot in means something that feeds information or a byte array, right.
Or array to my JVM.
And the JVM can read them one byte by byte.
Right.
Obviously, that's an inefficient way.
That's why we have a scanner that provides buffering.
So the standard input is stream.
This stream is already open.
We know that as long as soon as you run your job application, there is a dedicated stream to it.
And then while for example, we know that a scanner follows the basically a iterator pattern.
So it has has has next, next and has next line, etc..
I want to has next goes through the output or basically whatever is fed to the scanner word by word,
right?
Returns to if this scan has another token.
Token is just a word means that some non whitespace characters, it reads them until it hits the first
whitespace character.
Right.
So when has next we're going to do a cis out or system out?
Now we're using the standard output of our JVM, which is by default is hooked to the terminal.
Whatever shell or command, prompt or terminal, you're running your Java application in it, right?
So we're using the terminal, the input stream, a standard input to our JVM and we're using the standard
output of our JVM to print line and scanner next.
Right, scanner dot next.
I think this is going to work.
I believe a scanner has a next method.
Let's just check on that.
Yes.
So it returns a string.
So it reads next token token means a non as basically it starts from some point in your byte stream
or carriage character.
A stream starts from a character that is not a whitespace and reads until it hits the first basically
a first whitespace.
Right.
So next reads word by word.
And obviously a scanner is it or in general it's rebels something like this.
These are one time use so once you because these are kind of like the iterator pattern, right?
So once you consume the iterator, you cannot reuse it again.
So once you hit the next, you kind of need to create a new scanner, right?
So so what we do, obviously, we first need to scan, compile this and note that I'm not even in this
test directory in my terminal.
I'm inside the Java native image, which is the project but doesn't matter.
I have my class path ready.
Right?
It's set up.
It's already inside.
So the Java Sea already is aware of this basically test directory.
So I just tell you the terminal pipeline dot Java.
Now it's not going to obviously find it because when you use Java C, you kind of need to give it the
full path to to the file test terminal pipeline.
All right.
And this class note that I did not basically import the so basically we already had imported the scanner.
Right.
So if we didn't import the scanner because a scanner is in the Java util java duty and we know that
Java util by default is not imported.
Right.
So once you run this without importing that, it tells you a error saying that I don't know this type,
this scanner.
So that's why you kind of need to say that import java dot you tilde scanner now import remember import
is just a basically another way alternative way of just using the fully qualified name.
I could just use the fully qualified name and I don't need any import statement, but usually fully
qualified name makes your code a little bit ugly.
So we prefer to do the import, the type or the class itself.
And then interesting thing, if you look at the byte code, there is no import a statement.
Import statement has absolutely no effect on your byte code on your class file because the compiler
actually replaces this scanner, this line with the fully qualified name and I will show you.
So import statements have no effect.
Now this is different from C++ application.
Whenever you include another header file in your C++ source file, the the preprocessor actually copies
the entire content of that header file into your CP and the compiler goes through them.
So if you include iOS stream in many different CP files, the compiler has to go through them and compile
them again and that could be time consuming.
That's why there are other things like compiled headers, so the headers that are already compiled to
binaries and so the compiler doesn't have to do that usually.
I mean the compilers are pretty fast these days and the computers are fast.
So people don't really notice the fact that if you include iOS Stream, which is a pretty very huge
header file, right?
If you include, for example, I assume in many different CP files, then the compiler has to compile
it over and over again in Java.
It's not like that in Java.
The import statement doesn't do anything.
It really doesn't change the class file at all.
It has zero effect because at the compile time the compiler removes this line.
It's like this line doesn't exist and it rewrites the type with the fully qualified name.
And at runtime the JVM looks at the type which is the fully qualified name, and it starts from all
and searches in all the directories that are on the class path and sees if it can find a type with that
fully qualified name.
And as I mentioned in my my past lectures, fully qualified name means JVM expects a directory hierarchy.
So from the class path when Jvc's Java utility scanner searches in all the directories that are on the
class path to see if there is a directory called Java and then if there is a directory, it searches
inside that to see if there is a directory called util.
If there is a directory called util, then it searches inside that to see if there is a class file called
a scanner class.
If it cannot find it, it says a class not found error or class def error or something like that.
Again, I repeat these concepts because these are very important and these happen behind the scenes
and something that most Java developers, people who don't have much experience with what happens behind
the scene, they might not notice that these are very important concepts again.
So to summarize in Java, import statements have absolutely no effect on your class file.
So let's rewrite these and then let's open this class file with a class file viewer.
I don't want to decompile it.
And as you can see, there is absolutely no mention of.
Report.
The statement write The class has a fully qualified name right now.
I didn't put it in a basically, I didn't put it in the package.
So it's just the name of the class.
And then the compiler provided a default, no argument constructor, which is public, which just calls
the constructor the superclass.
And then we have a main method.
And as you can see, we are creating a scanner and the scanner in the source code was replaced with
the fully qualified name.
So this is the effect of the import statement.
So you can either directly in your source file type java util scanner or you can just type a just the
input, type the import the statement wants and then use a scanner.
This word is kind of multiple times and then the compiler replaces all those words with the Java utils
scanner.
So that's that's just the meaning of the import statement.
All right.
So we compile this and obviously we can also run this again.
I'm not going to explicitly specify the class path here because this directory test where my class file
is is already on my environment variable class path.
So I'm just going to say that terminal pipeline.
OC class not found exception.
So let's see.
Okay.
So the reason is that now by default.
So I think what we should do.
Hyphen C p let's try to give the class path.
So, so java, hyphen c p from wherever we are going to test and then terminal pipeline.
Oh, okay.
So I was typing the name wrong.
So Java terminal, let's make sure we do in line ning.
All right.
Now it works fine.
We don't specify the class path, but.
But then a GM search is also in the directory.
If the class path environment variable is defined now, it's waiting for us to type something to the
console.
So hello.
How are you doing?
Doing.
And then we hit enter, right?
So the scanner system in a scanner waits until you hit the enter.
Whenever you hit enter, it means that you finished up.
And then now it prints them to the console.
It is still waiting for us.
So more text hit, enter more text.
Right.
So basically when you hook this up to the standard input of your console, now you can add text here,
right?
And then if we print enter now it's waiting indefinitely.
Right?
So this application doesn't terminate because it's hooked directly to the standard input.
So I'm going to hit the control key to give the terminal or the operating system a signal that, hey,
I want to terminate this application.
So Control C is a signal to your operating system that to kill this process, right.
So so that's it has next what we're going to do in order to not go into an indefinite loop we're going
to say has next line so line then is kind of searches for backslash.
N Right.
And then we're going to print a line by line and next line.
So this way we are, we should be fine.
So let's compile and then let's run.
Now it's waiting for us.
Hello, how are you?
And then as soon as we hit enter, it's still the same thing.
Now it's print the entire line instead of printing word by word.
Right?
So again, command C, we terminate this.
So what we're going to do first, we're going to put something to the console.
So we're going to say that see out.
Enter, for example, enter your name or your.
Enter your first name and then.
Let's see.
And let's use print.
So we don't want to go to the next line.
And then after that, we create an scanner and then we're going to say that a string name is a scanner
next.
So this scanner is hooked up to the system in so we can call it any time we want and try to read something.
So right now we're saying next next means next a string, right.
Which comes from the terminal itself.
And then we're going to see out.
Your name is percent is dot formatted and in name.
All right.
So let's go ahead.
We're going to compile and then run and enter your first name, let's say Sam, and then your name is
Sam.
Right?
So it's it's working properly and then the application terminates.
All right.
Now, the thing here is that the.
What if I don't want to?
What if I want to automate this process?
Let's say I want to have some sort of I have a job application, I want to test it on terminal, but
I don't each time I don't want to basically type the inputs manually.
Let's say my application experts expects lots of inputs.
Right, so we can use this pipeline.
So.
Let's say if I echo use echo.
Sam it's just we know that the output of this command, remember, echo is also an application, and
you feed it some something.
It just prints it to the terminal.
Right now, I can say echo Sam and then pipe it to something.
And that's something is just my Java application terminal pipeline and it says enter your first name,
but it doesn't wait for you because when you pipeline the output of this application goes to your goes
is redirected to the input of your second application and it so it inputs it to the redirects it to
the input of the JVM and the input of our JVM is hooked up to our scanner, which is expecting to read
a string and then print it to the console.
Right.
So this way.
It actually didn't wait for us to print something because the system in is now has some character at
that is being fed to it using this pipeline operator right.
So it just says that your name is Sam and then it didn't wait for us to hit enter for example, here.
Now we could basically say backslash n here.
So if we go ahead and compile again and then run and now it doesn't wait for us to type anything, it
just immediately reads whatever a stream that comes from the pipeline operator from the previous application.
And obviously because we are just reading from a scanner, we are reading next word or next token.
If I have a two words here, it only reads the first word.
So what we can do, we can read it.
And then so let's also say enter your last name.
So this name becomes first name.
And then we're going to say that
last name again.
We use the scanner and then your name is percent as percent as first name and then last name.
And then what we're going to do, we're going to compile and then run.
And now you see it doesn't wait for you to enter anything because it has already an character, a stream
in the pipeline.
So the input of the JVM already has is being fed some characters and then it says, your name is Samba,
right?
First name, last name.
So it reads the output of these and then basically works fine.
Now this is now we're running on Java to test our application, but now I can also basically compile
it, write native image and then say Hyphen c.P.
I'm going to feed it just the class path, right?
Or maybe let's go inside the.
The test, by the way, in the fish terminal, if you just say to execute a directory, it is.
Remember in the past when I reviewed the concept of terminal, I said that directories have executable
permissions.
So if I just try to execute a directory, the fish terminal is very intelligent to realize that, okay,
this is a directory, so it just goes into it.
Now if I exit the fish terminal, the terminal that by default comes with the Mac OS is not that intelligent.
If I say test, it says that test is it's not executable.
But the fish terminal is very intelligent.
It knows that when you are executing a directory, it means you want to jump into it.
So actually.
Okay.
So where are we?
So this test doesn't exist.
So let's go to this directory so I can use CD.
I can just type the name and the terminal.
The fish shell is very intelligent to know that you want to see the OR change directory into it.
So that's the shortcut in Fish Shell is, instead of using the CD command, just type to just try to
execute that directory, dot forward, slash the name of the directory and it's going to work fine.
So test note that this doesn't work.
You have to in the Mac OS or Linux, you have to use DOT and the name of the application.
In this case it's a directory, right?
And now I jump into test and now I call my native image and then hyphen CP.
Let's just use here, we don't need to use the class path and then the terminal
pipe lining and then terminal underscore pipeline.
So we are compiling this class file the output of the executable file, the name is Terminal Pipeline.
It's going to quickly compile.
It's going to be pretty fast.
Probably takes one minute or less than one minute.
All of my CPU cores are fully maxed out because by default the native image uses all the threads available
on your CPU so that it reduces the compilation time.
So what I want to show you is that not only we can pipeline to the JV team, which runs our classifier
application, we can also pipeline to the native executable binary that comes from compiling our job
application.
So if I say terminal pipeline, this is my Java application.
Enter your first name, Sam.
Enter your last name Bob Samba.
Right now we can say Echo Sam Bob but instead of running the Java, which is our JVM, we're just going
to just run our Java application which was compiled to native executable binary.
And you see that first the output streams are printed and then it reads the input to our to input the
input stream that comes to the application and then it prints the correct output.
So pipeline is okay if you want to, for example, basically automate automatically provide inputs to
some application.
It could be a job application running on top of JVM.
It could be a Java application that has been executed to native executable binary.
So what I'm saying is that pipeline is not a feature of the Java, right?
It's a feature of the operating system and the terminal, the shell.
Now another feature right now we're using the command line or terminal pipeline.
But what I can do, I can create a text file, let's call this input the text, and then I am going
to put Sam and Bob here, for example.
All right.
Now let's see what happens here.
I'm if I if I want to print the context, the content of a text file to the terminal, I can use the
cat command, cat input the text.
And now you see that what, where I'm going with is instead of using the echo.
So remember if you say Echo, the name of the file, echo assumes that everything is a string and you
just want to print it to the terminal, which is not correct.
Right.
What I want is to basically read the input of this text file and cat reads the input of a text file
and then also prints it to the console.
So what I can do, I can say cat input the text, but instead of printing to the console pipeline it
or feed it to another application, which is my terminal pipeline.
So it reads the input and the input is fed to my application.
So it says Your name is samba, right?
So that's another way.
So we've also seen that.
We've also seen that we can redirect the output of an application to a file.
Right?
So I can say execute this, but then redirect the output to terminal text.
Right.
So.
Uh, so let's see, Sam, Bob.
And then it finishes.
So it waits for your input in the terminal.
But then the output of this application, whatever you use to, let's say, whatever you feed to the
system, dot out it's not going.
So if you look at the terminal that it says, enter your first name, enter your last name, and then
we provide this input in terminal and then the output of the application again was redirected to the
standard to the file instead of the terminal, which is the standard output.
So I hope you enjoyed this lecture and now I have a very solid understanding of this redirection and
pipeline thing.
Sometimes, especially when you're running an application in the background, what you want to do,
you want to redirect the output to a text file or something to a log file so that you can track those
applications in the background to see what's going on with them.
Right.
So please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.