Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on external tools for running the native image with a MAVEN project
inside Eclipse IDE.
And we saw how to set up a MAVEN project in Eclipse ID, how to set the run configuration, how to set
the compiler version properties for source and target to, let's say, JDK 17.
And then we saw how to run Maven build.
We set that by default.
Eclipse uses its internal compiler to compile these, and it knows that it has to put the classifiers
inside its target directory.
That's how MAVEN applications work.
Right.
And but then let's do a thing here is that we said that the reason people use MAVEN is twofold.
One is if I share this project, the source file, this whole project with some other person, maybe
they use different IDs.
Right?
And we said that if the project build of that project is managed by the ID, then importing this Eclipse
project into another ID like a IntelliJ is probably not that easy, but with Maven people don't care,
right?
So first of all, most of the IDs have support for Maven.
And the other thing is that you don't really need to rely on ID to build this MAVEN project and create
the artifact.
Let's say eventually this project will be a jar file, will be compiled and packaged as a jar file and
other people can use it as a dependency.
Right?
So Maven only understands poem.
So I can actually let's I can actually open the root here actually in a terminal.
Let's open it in a terminal.
As I mentioned, after I installed Maven, it's added to the path environment variable.
So mv vn which is the MAVEN command is available and I have this poem directory maven tool only understands
poem.
Right?
So if I say ambient clean, it looks at the poem, understands that this directory has a poem.
So it's a maven project and it tells me that I'm cleaning everything and it was successful.
If now we look at this target directory, it's fully empty, right?
The classes is fully empty, right?
So the maven clean actually doesn't clean up the target.
It cleans up the classes because this classes is where all the class files are.
This is the root of our class path for the Java project.
Now obviously now if I try to run this in, Eclipse is going to give us an error because I removed all
the class files.
So the main class, this demo class is no longer available, the compiled version of it.
But then I can go ahead and if somebody gives me this Maven project, I can go inside this root directory
that has the file and I tell my machine to just compile this application.
And again, Maven looks at the poem, understands all the configurations.
Remember, all the configurations are in the poem, for example, the compiler target, etc. And it
tells me that I'm compiling two source files and putting them in the target classes.
So if we say LS Target and in classes, now we have this job on native image and inside that it's going
to be our
inside, that it's going to be our two classes that are on the class path, demo class, test class,
right?
And now if I go back to Eclipse and try to run it, it's going to work because I use Maven Build Tool
to compile with JDK 17.
And then Eclipse knows that in order to run a Java application, which is part of the MAVEN, it has
to search inside the target class's right target directory and inside that there is a classes set.
So Eclipse Eclipse is very well aware and that's the beauty of having a Maven project inside Eclipse.
Now if you are more familiar with Maven, you know that you can't.
You don't even need to create a Maven project inside an ID.
You can just create a directory, use maven, basically use the MAVEN machine and then archetype, for
example, and then give it and it creates a directory, creates this hierarchy, assuming Java is our
main resources, etc..
So the beauty of MAVEN projects is that the build system is independent really of the IDE and almost
all ides have support for MAVEN projects.
You can't just import them into the ID and IDs, recognize what's going on.
Now.
Another important benefit which is the most important benefit or the strength of using MAVEN in an ID
basically, or instead of using a built in Project Eclipse build, we use MAVEN build is dependency
management, dependency management.
What does it mean now?
Obviously when you're developing a code, you don't want to write everything from scratch, right?
So let's say I want I have two integers, 250 and 75.
I want to find to find the greatest.
Common divisor.
What is the maximum?
What is the greatest integer?
The largest integer that these two numbers can be divided by?
And there are algorithms for finding these.
And you probably can.
This is a very simple case.
So you can probably get a guess that the answer GCD the greatest common divide is going to be 25 because
25 times three is 75, 25 times ten is 250.
Right.
And so here I guess that but I want to have a I want to use I want to have a code or a library to write
it.
So obviously, I don't want to spend my time to write a code from scratch to implement algorithm because
this obviously is a very fundamental concept.
And somebody has to have somebody has already written a function for this.
There is it's definite, right?
So I just want to find a library to find a library to do this.
And I happen to know that Google Guava has a int math class that has a function GCD.
So this kind of comes down to you can either Google it to find a function in Java that calculates this
or implements this algorithm.
I happen to know that Google Guava already has a class that do this.
So what I want to do, I want to add this Google duo Guava as a dependency to my MAVEN project.
So let's open up a internet browser and search for Google Guava.
Or maybe we can go just to Maven Central, which is the main online repository that Maven uses for searching
for dependencies.
Right.
So it's a very huge dependency and let's say search for Google Guava.
And so Google Guava is the Google core libraries for Java.
Every basically every Java developer has already heard about Google Go.
It's a very important library and we want to use the latest version.
And another benefit of MAVEN is versioning.
So sometimes an upgrade when a library goes from one version to another, some backwards compatibility
is broken.
So you can actually tell Maven which version of this library to use.
I want to use the latest version and I want to use Maven.
Right.
So you you can if your build system is great IV and other things that you can select, I wanna build
with Maven, so I want to choose this Maven.
So how do we add dependencies?
You open up the file.
Remember Maven only understands poem and eclipse.
IDE happens to also interpret the poem.
Eclipse provides this nice graphical view.
You can go to the purely text version of the poem, which is an XML file and what the way this works
is you create a dependency tag.
So I'm going to hit autocomplete, control a space and create a dependencies tag, right?
And then I'm going to copy and paste this dependency code that we just basically copied from the MAVEN
Center and let's say command F to do auto format.
All right, so now our application has one dependency as.
As soon as I hit save you see Maven goes and searches in your local maven repository dot MB to inside
your home directory.
If the jar file is guava 31.1 was not available.
Maven goes to Maven Central and downloads this jar file.
And after that eclipse, Eclipse understands that and then it adds it to your basically class path.
Now what's interesting is that not only this grow was added, a lot of other jars were also added,
these three and these three.
That's because this guava also has dependencies.
So this is the main strength of Maven or MAVEN projects is that if the dependency also has dependencies
of its own, Maven understands that it's able to handle everything right.
And again, this project in Eclipse.
Eclipse understands that this project has a maven nature.
So it understands that not only it has to create, it shows this nice maven dependencies view and it
shows you Google go on is now on the class path but also all the dependencies of this are also on the
class path because I mean, you cannot have this dependency and not have its own dependencies on the
class path, right?
Everything has to be on the class path.
So now that this is inside the Google guava.
Com Google comment and then there is a mass package and inside that there is this int math.
And inside this inch math, there is a GCD, greater common divisor.
So basically it says returns the greatest common divisor of A and B, so that's exactly the functionality
that we want and it's a static method, so it's very easy to use.
So all I have to say, I have to say var, let's say y equals int math.
It's the name of the class from google comma common math, int math and it keeps automatically as the
import.
And then GCD 250 and 75 and six out
GCD of 2250 and 70 is plus y.
Let's make sure that this works.
Let's run it as soon as I save this eclipse, compiles this and puts it in the target classes so I don't
need to really run Maven build when this MAVEN project is inside eclipse id.
So if I run this it tells me that the GCD of 250 and 70 is 25 as I expected.
Now what I want to do.
I want to what I want to do.
I want to actually ask the user to input two numbers so I can either do this or use a scanner.
So instead of doing this, I'm going to say that six out enter two integer numbers with a space and
I'm going, I'm not going to add a print and then I'm going to create a scanner, a scanner, a new
scanner, and I'm going to hook it up to the, the to the system dot in right.
The input stream is system in.
And then I'm going to say that a a is a or int a or number one is a scanner.
That's next int and then int number two is as candidate next int.
And then what we want to do, we want to say int y is int mass dot gcd of non one and number two.
And then if we're going to print so percent d percent D percent dx.
So I usually prefer instead of just breaking this string and using the plus operator, I'm going to
use the formatted string.
So now I'm one num two and why it's much easier.
So let's test this in java.
Enter to integers to 5075 and then the GCD of 250 and 75 is 25.
172 and then the GCD of 172 is four.
All right, so everything looks fine and we have to it says that this scanner is a resource.
There is a resource leak, so we kind of need to close it.
Usually, this is this doesn't is not required if you don't.
So if the scanner is hooked up to the system in because the system in is never closed as long as your
Java application is running, right.
So if your scanner is hooked up to the system in the input, a standard input is stream to JVM.
You don't really need to close it because this is going to be open unless there is a particular reason
that you need to close the scanner.
All right.
The reason that eclipse marks as auto a resource leak is because the scanner implements the general
interface of clothes.
And that's why the clothes bill extends out clothes over.
So any article possible is basically eclipse can flag it as resource leak.
That's the only reason.
Right?
So right now, there is nothing especial about this.
But now when it comes to actually compile this application, this job application to native executable
binary, right, that's the power of Java and the VM.
You can quickly develop an application which has huge amount of dependencies.
We just added Google Guava.
It also has huge number of other dependencies and MAVEN has no problem.
And now I want to compile this class, which is a demo class.
This is my job application.
It has a main method.
It's the entry point to my job application.
I want to compile it to native executable binary.
Right now this native directory is empty and we already set up an external tool.
What I want you to appreciate right now with this last setup that we did is that we are asking Eclipse
to provide the project class path for the native image.
We're not explicitly adding it, providing the class path eclipse, we're just providing this placeholder
which if which is an internal environment file for eclipse.
Now note what happens when I look at the command.
Wow.
Hyphen friend.
All the way to here.
These are all the dependencies that now we have on our class path in order for us to successfully run
our job application.
And again, Eclipse is replacing that environment variable project class path with automatically with
all these.
So native image hyphen cpp eclipse provides world class.
Now there is really no way for us to manually figure out what directories to add to the class path to
run this native image.
That's almost impossible.
There's so many.
If you add a jar from your from Maven and that jar already has lots of other dependencies, it's it's
almost impossible.
Right.
But that's the beauty of this external tool in the Eclipse IDE because eclipse always tracks down what's
going on.
Eclipse is aware of the class path.
That's why you can run this job application, which is a MAVEN application in your in your in your eclipse
ID.
Right?
Eclipse understands what's going on, on the class path, etc..
So all we have to do, we don't really need to change anything, even if we have a huge number of dependencies,
doesn't matter as long as you provide this hyphen.
CP as as, as long as you ask Eclipse to provide the class path for the native image, we are going
to be golden.
Right.
So I want to really understand the power of this.
So here we created a quickly use an external library, Google Hour, and then if we're using that external
library and then we're calculating this GCD and now we're compiling this entire application to a native
executable binary.
So a native image is running eclipse provides all the dependencies, all the class path stuff.
Right now, so far there is no problem in aligning methods and hopefully after after this the compilation
finishes and we get a native executable binary.
Done.
Everything was successful.
There was no error.
So in the native image we have this.
So let's open up a terminal here so we can use the internal terminal of eclipse.
So the Java native image demo class enter two numbers two 5075 GCD of 250 and 75 is 25.
Again, we use an external library and we use Maven because MAVEN is amazing for dependency management
and then Eclipse ID is amazing for keeping or basically tracking the project class path because with
Maven, if you add a jar for suddenly there might be lots of other jars that added to the class path
because of the dependencies that this jar file this discoverer has.
And it's really impossible for us to manually track those dependencies.
But then once the Eclipse ID tracks those, it enables us to write a job application very quickly.
Like in 2 minutes I wrote this and then now a native image compiler to the native executable binary.
So I can quickly say demo class, run it, enter two integer numbers 100 101.
Obviously the GCD is one.
We can rerun it again.
Enter two integer numbers 21 and 63.
Obviously it's 21, etc. So I hope you really understand this that Java and Maven has this huge library
maven central and then you can use Maven inside Eclipse ID to manage your dependencies.
Eclipse ID always tracks your class path and once you set the external tool to to use the class path
from eclipse ID, you are golden.
You you can quickly write a very complicated application, java application with lots of dependencies
and then you compile it to a native executable binary.
I hope you really enjoyed this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.