Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on the tracing agent that comes with the VMD CVM.
And we said that by default the agent will write the configuration files after the JVM process terminates.
But sometimes even during the sometimes you want to make sure that everything gets regularly saved and
dumped to the configuration file.
So in addition, the agent provides the following flags to write configuration files on a periodic basis.
Right?
Sometimes, maybe.
I don't know.
If JVM somehow crashes, then nothing is written as the configuration file.
So you want to make sure that you practically write the configuration files, all the calls that have
been intercepted by the native, by the agent, you want to make sure that it periodically dumps the
intercept, all those interceptions to two files.
So config write period period seconds right executes a periodic write every number of seconds as is
specified in this configuration supports only integer values greater than zero config write initial
delay seconds.
So this is the initial delay from the.
So how long will it take from the time you run the JVM run application until the first time that the
GVM, the agent dumps all the configurations, all the calls that have been intercepted to a configuration
files the number of seconds before the first write is scheduled for execution supports only integer
values greater than or equal to zero.
Obviously the delay can be zero, which means as soon as.
As soon as we we run eight schedules a dump of the interceptions enabled only if config right period
seconds is greater than zero.
Right?
So if config right period period seconds is not zero.
Or basically if it's zero, which is a default value, which means we don't want to write periodically.
So and then there is no point in having a delay because the only way that if we're not writing periodically,
so the only option is to dump everything after JVM 10 minutes.
So the example, the way you do it, we saw that we run the JVM from the VM and then we tell it that
we want to activate an agent that's the dash or hyphen agent lib and then call in which type of agent
it is.
It's the native image agent and which property of this native image we're going to set.
We're going to say that config output directory and we saw that there is also an option for config message
directory.
So but that config managed for mostly for use cases when you want to run application multiple times
with different inputs right here, we tell it, we periodically run this and then maybe during the execution
we give it multiple, um, basically inputs.
So config output directory.
And we said that it's best to put it in the meta inf and then native image inside the meta.
That's the default.
And then now if I want to add additional parameters or properties to this native image agent, we separate
them with comma.
So comma config right period seconds is 300.
So every 300 seconds, every 5 minutes.
Config, right.
Initial delay, seconds, five.
Right.
So wait until 5 seconds to schedule the net.
Which means 5 minutes and 5 seconds after the in the JVM runs, the first dump of the configuration
happens.
It is advisable to manually review the generated configuration files.
I mean, usually they are the most the most the two mostly important configuration files are the reflection
and agenda.
I mean, resources are also sometimes also, I would say reflect and generally are the most important
ones.
But resource config is also in the second most important files, right?
Uh, because the agent observes only code that was executed, the resulting configurations can be missing
elements that are used in other code paths.
Right.
That's why we also have that config merge directory.
It could also make sense to simplify the generated configurations to make any future manual maintenance
easier.
And as I mentioned, the generated configuration files can be supplied to the Native Image Compiler
tool by placing them in a meta inf slash native image.
So this is a directory native image inside another directly called meta inf.
And all the configuration files are inside this native image directory on the class path.
So you want to make sure that when you run the native image, you obviously have to specify the class
path for the native image tool.
And also you want to make sure that this method in native image directories are on the class path.
And then when you do that, you don't need to explicitly tell the native image that, hey, I have some
configuration files, native image by default searches.
The class path for this naming matter.
If Native Image, if it finds this directory hierarchy, it automatically realizes that hey, you are
feeding it some configuration files, for example, in a jar file using the image.
And we already know that inside any jar file there is a meta inf.
So you can configure your build tool to make sure that there is a directory inside of it called Native
Image and then basically all the configuration files are there.
This directory or any of its subdirectories is searched for files with the names JNI config, the JSON
reflect config json proxy config that JSON and resource config dot JSON which are then automatically
included in the build.
Not all of those files must be present, so you don't need to have four of them.
Any of them that is present.
Native image by default picks them up from this default naming convention method slash native image.
When multiple files with the same name are found, all of them are included.
Now what does it mean?
Obviously you cannot have files with the same name in the same directory, but you can instruct the
native image that hey, I have configuration for us in multiple directories, you see.
And then obviously configuration files should always have the same name, but we can have multiple files,
multiple configuration files with the same name in different directory directories, and we can include
all of those directories as directories that native image can search.
In order to do that, obviously you have to enable a explicit flag for the native image.
Important cases where we need to use VMM tracing agent.
If you have JNI calls, I will show you an example.
Reflection we've already seen this reflection is important because sometimes loading a class dynamic,
loading a class is deferred completely to runtime.
No, nothing is hardcoded in the source code, so there is no way for the native image to understand
it.
And resources.
Our application requires some external resources such as images, data, files, and whenever you build
your application you want to and let's say you package them as a jar, right?
You want to make sure that you use some sort of.
Class loaded because the job of class loader to load classes on a class path at runtime and load them.
They can also search for resources that are on a class path.
We can take advantage of the external tool in eclipse ID to set up cores to grow VM tracing again for
different scenarios and.
And we've already seen this in the previous lecture.
So let's head to Eclipse.
And try to, first of all, look at these two ideas that we want to not only save the configuration
for us, we want to actually periodically update them if there is any particular change.
Because remember, the most successful thing, the ultimate goal is to be able to predict all the configurations
that are associated with all the paths that the code can take.
Right.
Our Java application can take.
So let's head to Eclipse.
So we had this, uh, basically, uh, file, uh, reflection demo and what I'm going to do actually.
Let's copy these.
I'm going to say that we're creating a reflection version for and instead of basically supplying this
zero.
The name of the class as a command line arguments, I'm going to ask you there to provide a, uh, um,
an input.
Right.
Instead of command line arguments at the time that we launched JVM, I want to ask, use it.
And the way we read the input from the standard user is using the standard input.
So scanner scanner, new scanner, and then we hook it up to the input stream, which is the system
that in.
And this is always open until you explicitly close it, which really there is no need.
The only reason that Eclipse, uh, complains about this resource not being closed is that a scanner
implements the general interface of order closure.
So next a string.
So we're going to say that code and enter the name of the class and then we're going to do a print,
for example, here and then and then we're going to say that
out class loaded or backslash?
Double code backslash.
Double code percent is was successfully loaded.
Successfully loaded and then a dot formatted.
And then we're going to say class.
Dot.
Get name, for example, get canonical name.
We can say good name.
Right.
And then you see eclipse complaints about the scanner saying that there is a resource leak.
But in reality, when you hook the scanner up to the system input because the system is always open,
it's not supposed to be closed until the JV ten terminates.
But we're going to be a more precise here and saying that, okay, we're closing this so eclipse compiler
doesn't complain, so let's delete this.
Let's select our reflection demo.
And if I go back to the last run configuration that we had, we.
We were supplying these arguments to the program, but then now we don't need it.
So it says, Enter the name of the class.
Let's say you tell forge a complex, complex and say class successfully load it, right.
Um, so basically actually what we want to do is class not found exception.
I'm going to remove these and then we want to handle.
So first of all, what happens when we can either put this in private resources or through the declaration
out class not found exception?
And then let's see what happens when we don't put a um, basically and let's say we want to ask these
three times so four int equals zero less than a three plus plus.
We're going to say that we want to ask user to load some classes.
Again, this is something that there is no way for the static analyzer to understand it because we are
the name of the class.
The name of the class that that has to be loaded is deferred completely to runtime right in the source
code.
There is no way, there is no hardcoded string, there is no information about which class is going
to be.
So let's run this again.
So we're going to say that util for j dot complex, dot complex class and class successfully loaded.
Okay, so maybe let's terminate this and also put this print out here.
All right?
So let's run this one more time.
So you tell for dot complex, dot complex, successfully loaded, let's say some something and then
we get a class not found exception.
Right?
So this throws an exception and our program terminated.
So I guess the best practice here is going to be to remove this, not throw this out of the main and
then try to handle it again.
So
we're going to say that try we're going to make sure that this handles this.
All right.
And then we're going to do a catch here catch.
And then we're going to say that class not found exception.
And then we're going to say that.
Or basically
was not found.
Was not.
Found so.
And then obviously what we need to do, we're going to say that a string class a name is let's get the
name as the string.
From the input and then pass it to here.
And then we're going to basically.
Pass these to this formatting.
Yeah.
So let's add a semicolon here.
And actually we should put this outside the try.
And, um.
Yeah.
Let's use the class name here, the actual name.
And then if it's not found, we just tell it, hey, whatever string that you put it, it didn't, we
couldn't find it.
So let's run this again.
Util forge dot complex, dot complex class successfully loaded, blah blah blah.
It was not found and in java dot lang dot a string and loaded and then the JVM terminates.
Right.
And we can go this indefinitely.
Let's say we want to try ten times.
All right.
So the point here is that now let's also delete our previous compilation.
What we want to do.
We want to go here and then run our tracing agent.
So.
And then we want basically to tell it to.
So Java Trace, let's duplicate it.
Java Trace underscore let's say periodic periodic.
And then what we're going to do here, we're telling that agent this is our directory and then config.
Let's zoom out.
Let's go back to PowerPoint.
So config right period seconds.
So let's go back to Eclipse.
And let's say we want to save every 2 seconds, right?
Apply and then run our Java application.
Enter name of class.
So native image agent warning file or directory has been modified by another process.
All output files remain in the temporary directory.
Okay.
It's interesting that it's giving us this warning.
So.
Let's see.
Um.
Can you tell for Jada to complex that complex and then enter another class, blah, blah, blah.
So it's says saving a lot of temporary things and then enter the name of the class java lang string
and then enter the name of a class.
Some other stuff.
And let's say we want to terminate.
And let's look at what we're getting.
So reflect config.
We're not getting anything.
Uh, reflect config.
So basically I believe each one of these have a timestamp of what time it was.
So we were trying every basically 5 seconds or every one second.
Right.
So towards the end.
So at the end we had these to a string and complex.
So basically it creates a temporary directories and every second it saves them.
So you get lots of configuration files and the native image again includes all these in the configuration.
At the end, all these directories will be added, right?
So in the upper level, which was exactly at the run, it didn't save anything, right?
So again, this might not be that much of a useful feature, but it's good to have again, again, this
is one of the cases that you really need the configuration files because there is no way for the static
analyzer of native image to understand which class we are dynamically loading.
Right, because this is a string that is completely its value is completely deferred to runtime of the
job application.
So I hope you enjoy this lecture.
Please stay tuned and I'll see you the next one.