Hello and welcome to another tutorial.
We're going to continue our discussion on Native Image and compiling the Java applications to Native
Executable Files.
And I'm going to discuss a very important and also very interesting topic of how to handle Java resources
when we are compiling a Java application to native executable binary.
Now sometimes at compile time, we need to our source file, it needs to have a load some resources
and then when we run our job applications, obviously JVM handles those kind of resources, but then
how does it work when we actually want to statically compile the application to executable file?
How do we ensure that those resources are correctly taken care of?
So a resource is data, images, audio, text and so on.
And this in this particular lecture, I'm going to focus on the text resources, basically text files
that a Java program needs to access.
Resources can be included in Java Archives Jar as well.
Basically, when you package your application, if there is, let's say a text file or some sort of
CSV file that has some data and your application really requires those to be available.
Right?
When you launch your application, it has to read some stuff from a text file or a CSV file.
You can always also include them in the Java archives or jar because when you write, when you work
on your Java project, eventually the goal is to package it in some format like Java and then distributed
as the binaries like Jar.
So JAR has all the binaries of your job application, which are all the class files, but then you want
to also bundle all the resources, all the files that your application also needs into that Jar Archive.
And obviously, in order for the packaging to successfully bundle them, these resources should be on
the class path at compile time.
Right?
And maybe not.
It's obvious it's not the Java job of the compiler to handle resources.
There is a tool called the jar that comes with the JDK.
It's a command line tool and that can handle packaging your Java, right?
And again, you have to specify the class path for that.
And on the class path those resources should be available.
So if I open up a new terminal here, I have JDK 17 from Oracle on my path.
So Java, hyphen, hyphen, Virgin, we have the JDK 17, and one of the tools is Jar Hyphen, hyphen
version.
It's Java 17 for JDK 17.
And if we just look at the help menu, hyphen, hyphen help, and then as you can see, it has.
So the job of the jar is you give it your application to class path and then it bundles them into a
Java archive.
So Jar hyphen hyphen create is for creating a archive and then you can specify the name of the jar and
then all the classes that you want to bundle and then you want to also specify a manifest.
Again, if you're not familiar, manifest usually has extra information for runtime.
For example, what is the class path when the JVM tries to load the jar?
How the class path should look like for the all the files and packages that are inside the jar jar hyphen
hyphen.
Create a hafen for a file, a food judge.
So this is the US.
Specify the name of the output hyphen, hyphen, main class if you are creating a executable jar and
then if you want to also add module information, you can do that.
And then you see after the classes you can also specify the resources that can be bundled into the jar
file.
And so if you already have created a jar and then you just want to update it with more classes, you
can use the hyphen, hyphen, update.
So you are if you're working on a very large project and you don't want to run the jar on all the classes
all the time, some classes might not change.
Maybe later on you just want to add basically one more class.
Then you can just update the currently available jar and then you see there are some also options hyphen
C or hyphen hyphen create creates the jar a hyphen I or generate index creates index about which classes
packages are there.
Hyphen Lee's List Table of Contents.
Hyphen Update If you want to an archive a jar file, you can use hyphen hyphen extract and it just extracts
the I believe it.
There's only like a class files binary files this exact that hyphen hyphen describe module hyphen hyphen
validate.
And so as you can see in basically not only you can package classes, you can also add manifest and
then you can also add resources so resources can be bundled with your application if you your application.
Really requires some resources to be available.
So about the text file, we cannot directly access resources in a jar file using the file class.
Now, obviously when we say resource and accessing a file, your first thought should go to the file
class that comes with the Java IO package.
Right.
And file is an abstraction of the operating system.
Remember operating system terminals, they understand files, write file paths, file permissions.
We discussed all of these concepts before, but then Java is all about abstraction.
Java wants to everybody to on any possible platform like Windows, Mac OS, Intel, CPU, AMD, CPU,
arm, CPU, Java wants everybody to use the same API for handling this kind of stuff.
That's why file is more like an abstraction of the underlying operating system file system.
Different operating systems have managed the files differently.
Remember a file or data on a permanent storage device like a hard disk.
It's just to a computer, to a machine.
It's just zeros and ones, right?
The way that the operating system interprets them, gives them actual meaning that the humans understand.
Right?
But under the hood it's just zeros and ones, a sequence of bytes.
And you might be already familiar that Java provides byte streams, write a stream's input stream and
output string.
Same with even C++ APIs.
Right.
They all handle files in a stream of bytes.
More like sequential access.
I believe you.
You can't really access a file in a parallel way because it's just the limitations that the operating
system have on how to access the files.
So a file class that the Java provides in the Java IO package, so I'm going to write it a Java IO package
file class is an abstraction of the underlying operating system OS file system you don't care about.
If you're using Linux, it uses its own file system.
Mac OS uses its own file system, Windows and TFS right.
It uses its own file system, different operating system used their own file system.
Let's focus on a file that has textual context or content or characters.
Again, characters don't have any meaning to a machine, to the hardware, right?
Characters are just a sequences of zeros and ones like any other data.
What gives them meaning?
The way the applications that we write interpret those sequences of bytes.
That's why we have encoding like UTF eight, UTF 16, etc..
What this means again, if you're not familiar, I'm going to give you a quick explanation.
Encoding means you look at the context content of a text file, right?
Or any file doesn't matter.
It doesn't have to end with a text file or any kind of file.
Right.
And then what happens is that you start reading all the contents in the sequence of bytes, and then
if this the contents represent text, then based on the encoding you choose, let's say you choose UTF
eight, which means every eight beats or every one byte translates or maps to a character.
And then the applications, the softwares that we use, read those bytes and on the display they show
those characters, right?
Really literally the concept of fonts.
Every operating system has a font library and then based on the characters, it can display like every
pixel and pixel on their screen so that that character is shown right.
So eventually the job of the applications and the operating system together is read those bytes, translate
them or map them to characters and lighter pixels on the screen based on the font library that you choose,
that the application chooses, so that you see the correct actors.
And Java, I believe, uses UTF 16 internally for managing for translating
basically characters or streams of bytes into characters.
All right, so we can use the scanner class to read the text file.
Again, if you're not familiar with the scanner, I highly recommend that you get to know it.
It's a very, very versatile class, which, especially in the most recent versions of the JDK, it's
very handy, very useful.
Whenever basically whenever you want to read some text, not just from the file, you will see that
I will show you examples from anywhere, even from the terminal, right?
If your application wants to get some inputs from the user in the format of text I mentioned before,
that terminal is just a textual application.
It's a great graphical interface that only works as a text.
Write everything that the user inputs to a terminal.
It's just a string, right?
So a scanner is a very versatile class.
Let's say we have a text file and we want to read its contents and then bring those content into our
application.
Then we use a scanner class and it's in the Java Util, right.
It's from Java util package.
And then it's a very powerful class for dealing with reading and tokenizing text.
So a scanner reads the text, which means it reads a file, you give it a file and then it reads it
byte by byte or based on the default character encoding of the platform.
Right.
So when you install Java, JVM knows the default encoding platform and then it reads and tokenize is
tokenizing means if you have like a stream of characters, there's always a whitespace that it's delimiting,
it's a delimiter or indicator of where a word is stars and where a word ends.
Right.
Obviously, if we have a word that has multiple parts, we usually use hyphens.
So we don't have a space to say that it's a two it's a one word.
Whenever you have white space, it means you definitely have two words.
So the scanner organizes them based on the white spaces.
And then and then you can ask a scanner to print them to the console, etc..
So the path relative or absolute should be passed to a scanner class as a file.
So if you look at the constructor of the scanner, it has a huge number of constructors.
You can give it a file so that tell it, hey, it's going to go access the contents of this file, read
them and then encode them as characters.
Right?
Remember, a scanner is all about text or you can tell it input a stream instead of telling the scanner,
hey, go.
Instead of giving it a file, give it an input.
A stream again, a stream means it's a sequence of bytes, and then a scanner again reads those bytes.
And based on the encoding, the character encoding, it translates them into characters.
Path pass.
I believe it's a more, more recent concept than the file, but it's more or less the same story.
Path means, hey, there is a text there, text file and in this path and then go access it readable.
Anything that readable in anything that can be read, you can also do that readable by channel.
Again, we're a scanner, we feed a scanner bytes or a string.
And in the old versions of the JDK, if this string was actually a path to a file, then a scanner could
access it.
But they actually remove that functionality.
So when you give a scanner, the constructor of the scanner, a string, it actually tokenize that exactly
that a string.
So it's not accessing the file based on this string as a file path.
So if you want to a scanner to access a file, you have to use a file object and the other parts are
the same, the other construct the same.
But then you can also provide a character set, how a scanner translates those bytes that it reads to
characters so you can provide, I believe by default.
Obviously the constructors that don't have this character said they use the default platform character
encoding, which most likely is going to be UTF eight, or you can provide the name of the character
set or character encoding as a string, cursed, cursed and all the ones, right?
So the construct is that don't take a cast and the construct is that also take a character set or the
encoding.
All right, so let's head to Eclipse and try to, first of all, access a text file and read the contacts
using a scanner.
And then and then we come back, look at the next slide to see how we're going to handle Java resources
like a text file, how to embed it actually in the native image that we compile and built.
So inside this eclipse, I created this class resource demo.
I have this very simple run me that is edge again.
Extensions don't have that much meaning.
It's just because any file, regardless of its extension, is a binary file.
The contents on the hard disk are saved as zeros and ones.
So when I double click on this, the this tab pops up.
This is a plugin, right?
That eclipse has that reads the context and then if it tries to display them as text file, right.
Tries to use the UTF eight encoding or whatever default encoding that eclipse uses to.
Convert those binaries into text file.
So let's say I want to read the contents of this file.
So again, it's something that I want to read.
So I immediately go and create a scanner, a scanner, a scanner, a new scanner, and then I want to
read from a file.
So if I use the A string and tell it the path to this file relative fast.
So when I want when I run my job application using Eclipse, it sets the working directory to the project
route and my file run me that is in the project route.
So I can say from wherever you run your application, run me that search.
All right.
And then as kind of follows the iterator iterator pattern so we can say while a scanner has next, we're
going to print out a scanner dot next, which whenever a scanner reads, obviously it's kind of also
provide some buffering, which is good because buffering helps speeding up the process because usually
accessing the file, accessing a data on a hard disk is the bottleneck, right?
If the data is already in the RAM random access memory, the access is going to be fast.
The fastest access is obviously when the data is actually in the cache of the CPU.
It's very close, right?
So from the cache to the ram to the hard disk, these are where the bottlenecks start to show up.
But here we are when a scanner reads the this text is going to tokenize it.
So if we run this, you might be surprised that you were hoping to access the contents of this file,
but it's not the case anymore.
So when you pass a string, it's can actually tokenize the string itself.
That string becomes the source of the textual content.
For example, if I say Hello, how are you doing?
Right.
And if I run it, you actually see that a scanner tokenize this string itself, right?
So you cannot pass a string.
That content contains a path to a file and a scanner won't work.
So you have to pacify a new file and then a string path to the file class, which is an abstraction
of the underlying file system of the operating system.
Now you can tell it run me that asset.
Obviously, when you're accessing the file, the file might not exist, the name might be wrong.
So you have to enter handle that file not found exception.
All right, so let's run this.
Now we are accessing the contents of this file word by word, because this next method goes more by
word.
We can also read line by line.
So has next line.
Again, a scanner is a very powerful iterator.
So next line you can also directly read numbers integers that will float.
So if I run this is just reads the first line and then terminates, right?
So that's how we are accessing textual contents.
And so if we use another constructor that is scanner that asks us for the character encoding, so we
have file and then we can say a car set which comes from Java now dot.
Default for name, class available car sets, it creates a map.
So let's look at the first look at the available car sets.
Right.
Or character encoding.
Lets available, can search and then it's a sorted map so we can say available car sets for each and
then for key and value pairs we're going to do a see out.
Basically he goes to value and then dart formatted K and V.
Let's see what we get here.
So you see there are lots of lots of different character in Coatings.
One of them should be UTF eight.
Obviously, one of them is going to be UTF 16, UTF 16, basically B and L, a little Indian, something
like that, I believe.
Or these are something.
So these are extensions of UTF 16, UTF 32 and Windows encoding and then other encoding.
So Java supports lots of lots of different encoding.
So let's see what happens if we run out a scanner.
But then we're going to use the available car sets and then get it's a map.
And then we're going to say UTF eight, which I believe it's going to be.
So it has the IO exceptions.
Let's see what exception we're going to handle.
It's just IO exception.
So when you pass the file, it uses file not for an exception, but this constructor throws IO exception,
so it's not justified.
So let's run this.
Cannot enjoy Cassatt nude because Cassatt is null.
That's interesting.
So let's see.
UTF eight.
Do we have a dash here?
UTF?
Yeah.
Yeah, we have to use a dash.
So, UTF dash eight.
So let's also come in this print.
Yeah.
We are still doing.
What if we changed the character encoding to UTF 16?
Now we're kind of not seeing anything.
What if UTF eight UTF 32?
Still nothing so UTF eight works because that takes while was created with UTF X encoding right.
Which is, I believe, the default encoding of the MAC OS operating system.
But if we print this more.
Let's see.
Let's try another thing.
ISO 8859 something like this.
Let's see what we get now we this is still works fine interestingly.
Yeah java hyphen version.
So I mean if you know that your particular text file has a very specific encoding, you can directly
use it in the scanner class.
Right.
And then you can also access as I mentioned before, you can also access, for example, in scanner
is very versatile in the sense that it's you can hook it up not only to files or feed it directly a
string.
You can also hook it up to a streams for example system that in and we've used this before.
Oh by the way, eclipse compiler complains that a scanner is consuming a resource so it has to be closed.
And I've mentioned this before that whenever you hook up the scanner to the system input, you don't
really need to close it because system as soon as you run your job application, the system is always
open.
That's the input system that is always open and it doesn't close up until you terminate your job application.
So basically we can read something and then so let's run this.
So we feed some information.
Hello, how are you doing?
And then it prints it to the console and then we can say something else.
So the system is always open and it's always listening.
New input.
And then a scanner is also always reasoning.
It's kind of listens to this input stream.
Whenever there are some bytes available, it reads them and then translate them into character.
All right.
So this was the introduction to this string.
Now what I would like to.
This was inside.
This was the introduction to the scanner.
What I would like to quickly show before ending this lecture is that we're going to give the new file.
And it was run me.
That s h.
Let's also remove the unnecessary imports.
If you run this, this is going to work.
Fine.
And then if I select my this class and try to compile it to the native executable, what you will see
that obviously the compiler succeeds because the static compiler of the native image doesn't care what
this is.
Right?
This is string, it doesn't care.
It just cares that you're accessing a file.
So that's fine.
It says, okay, that voice should be available at runtime after the compilation succeeds.
So you will see that the compilation succeeds.
But obviously when we run the file, things are not going to work that well because first of all, in
our source code we're using a relative path and this relative path will cause some problem.
The other thing is that even if we use an absolute path to this file run media search, if when I compile
that absolute path is hardcoded in the source file, if I give it to some other person on some other
computer, if they run it, they will not.
The application will crash because that hardcoded file is specific to my directories.
Right.
So we have this compiled file if I run this.
I say resource demo, it's going to fail because find not found exception, right?
Because I said you're running your job application and in the binary of this application there is this
dot run dot asset.
What this means is that we're using a relative path.
So if I try to go one level up, I'm in the route of my project and try to say Native Job, and if I
run this, this works fine.
Why?
Because now in this binary, it tries to search from the current working directory, which is now here
because we use dot in this string and tries to find a file that called the run me search.
And that void now exists in this working directory.
It is run me dataset.
Right?
So now the application six is and you see the problem here we we use Java to be platform independent
but now that when we compile to the native executable file that that hardcoded name of file is is problematic
because first of all, it depends where we run it from, right?
If we use a relative path in our source file, then you have to run your job application really from
a from a specific working directory to make it work.
If I go anywhere else, let's say go into a this app directory and then try to say that, okay, go
one level up, go into the native directory and run this.
This is going to fail because again, this dot is like astronomy dot search means from wherever you
run this binary executable binary, there should be a file in the same working directory called Run
Me Dataset.
And obviously in this app directory there is no such file.
Right?
So we want to write a Java code that is platform independent, which means we don't want to tie ourself
to a particular hardcoded file name.
Instead, we want the JV team to somehow locate that resource when we run our Java application, because
once that happens, the native image has a compact version of the JVM inside.
So once our Java code is independent of how to, it's not directly tied to the file system of the platform
and it somehow can dynamically locate the resources.
Then when we compile to the native executable file, then there shouldn't be any problem.
All right.
So this is a topic of the next lecture.
I hope you enjoyed this one.
Please stay tuned and I'll see the next one.