(upbeat music)
Well, this is gonna be a short video
because the Vector class
is essentially a thread safe ArrayList,
but Vector actually came first and we're gonna take a
look at the Vector Javadoc and we'll see,
if we scroll down a bit
that Vector has been there since the beginning.
It has been in the JDK since JDK 1.0.
If we come up to the top here,
now, if I go back to ArrayList,
so this is the ArrayList class,
we'll see that that's, there was only added into
the JDK in JDK version 1.2.
Now, if you've been using Java as long as I have,
you might remember when ArrayList was introduced.
Before that, the list go-to class was Vector,
and so the question is if Vector was in JDK version 1.0
and it has pretty much the same methods
as the ArrayList class,
why was ArrayList added to the JDK?
Well, the answer lies in the documentation.
If we scroll back up, we'll see right here
in big bold letters for ArrayList,
this implementation is not synchronised,
and if we go back to the Vector class,
it says unlike the new collection implementations,
Vector is synchronised.
So Vector is thread safe meaning it's okay
to use it from different threads without you having
to synchronise the code.
But ArrayList is not.
So if you only read an ArrayList,
then it's safe to use it from multiple threads,
no data will be clobbered,
but if you use ArrayList with multiple threads
and one or more of those threads is writing
to the ArrayList by adding,
deleting, setting or changing objects in the list,
then you could run into a conflict.
You could have threading conflicts,
and so in that case, you'd
want to use Vector rather than ArrayList.
So if you need thread safety, use Vector.
If you don't, use ArrayList.
Now, the reason that ArrayList came along
is that synchronisation has an overhead involved.
So it slows things down,
and so when only the Vector class was available
and Vector is synchronised,
if you wanted to use a list backed by an array
and you wanted to use the class in the JDK,
you were pretty much forced
to use a synchronised class even
if you didn't need synchronisation,
and so because of that,
ArrayList was eventually added to the JDK,
so that if you don't need synchronisation,
you would have a class backed by an array
that you could use that doesn't
have the overhead involved with synchronisation,
and so that's why ArrayList came along.
It was because developers were saying,
hey, we like Vector, but what do we do
if we don't need synchronisation?
We don't want the overhead associated with it,
and so a couple of versions later, ArrayList came along.
And so here you'll see that the documentation
for ArrayList itself says
if a thread safe implementation is not needed,
it is recommended to use ArrayList.
So you only want to use the Vector class
if you need synchronisation.
If you don't need it and you use the Vector class,
you're going to be using a slower implementation
for no reason, and that's why you
want to use ArrayList unless you need
a thread safe implementation.
So if you need thread safety,
use Vector, if you don't, use ArrayList.
Okay, so let's say we do want to use Vector.
Well, Vector is backed by an array just
like ArrayList is and so let's go back to the IDE now.
And I've created a project
and I've added the same Employee class we had
in the ArrayList video,
same fields, same everything,
I basically just copied
and pasted it from that project.
And right now I have this using an ArrayList.
Now, if you want to use Vector,
because we are assigning
this into a list Employee instance rather
than ArrayList Employee,
all we have to do is change this to Vector,
because Vector also implements list
and so that's why rather than using
a specific implementation in the declaration,
it's always better to use the interface
that the implementation is using
because then you can switch out to another class
that implements the same interface
without having to change any code.
So let's take a look at the Vector constructor.
Let's go to the declaration, and let's go to this.
We'll have to follow this down until we finally get
to the actual code where it's doing the work.
We'll keep going.
And here we are and we'll see that an array is created.
So it's using backing array just like ArrayList is.
If we go back to Main now and we take a
look at the implementation of add,
and this time I want it for Vector, there you go.
It's synchronised, and so
that's the difference between the add method for ArrayList
and the add method for Vector.
Let's have a look at the ArrayList add method.
I'll go to the other project,
the other IntelliJ project for ArrayList.
So here we are back in the project we worked with
in the last video and if I go to this add method,
I want the ArrayList add,
we'll see that there is no synchronised keyword here,
and so I want to reiterate
that if you don't need thread safety, then don't use Vector.
You don't want the overhead that comes with synchronisation,
and if you do need thread safety,
then you want to use Vector rather than using ArrayList
because if you use ArrayList,
then you're going to be responsible for synchronising
all the calls to ArrayList methods,
and so why do the work when the Vector class
has already done all of that for you?
And that's it.
That's all I'm gonna say about Vector
because it's pretty much the same
as an ArrayList except that it's synchronised.
The last two videos about ArrayList and Vector though,
they're probably been review for some of you.
I just want to make sure
that we covered the two most popular classes
in the JDK when it comes
to just having a simple sequential list,
so in the next video, we're going to move on to another type
of list called a LinkedList.
I'll see you there.