(lively music)
(logo whooshing)
(keyboard clicking)
All right, so in the last video we wrote a method
for adding values to the tree.
Now let's write a get method
so that we can get values from the tree.
This won't be very complicated.
It'll be similar to what we did for insert.
We're gonna start in the TreeNode class.
I noticed that in the last video,
I actually put the insert method and the traverse method
above the constructor.
Nothing wrong with that,
but I like to have the constructor at the top,
so I've moved the constructor up above the methods.
I'm gonna insert he get method right here.
We're gonna say public TreeNode
will return the TreeNode for the value get,
and of course we need the value we're searching for.
We're gonna do something very similar
to what we did in insert.
We're gonna check the value against the value of the node,
and if they're equal,
then we found the node that we're looking for.
If they're not equal,
we're going to search the left subtree or the right subtree,
depending on whether the value we're looking for
is less than or greater than the value of this tree node.
I'm gonna say if value equals data, we're done,
so we're gonna return this.
We're gonna return this tree node.
If that's not the case,
we're gonna say if
value is less than data,
then we wanna search the left subtree,
as long as the node has a left subtree,
and so we're gonna do the similar checks that we did here.
We're gonna say if leftChild
is not equal to null,
then we're gonna say return leftChild.get value,
and so we're gonna down the rabbit hole.
We're going to call this method recursively,
and we're going to look for the value
in the left subtree.
If the value isn't equal to the data,
and it's not less than the data,
then it has to be greater than the data, so we'll say else,
and we could go else if rightChild,
but to keep it kind of symmetrical I'll put the if in here.
If rightChild
is not equal to null,
then we wanna return rightChild.get value,
and so in this case we're gonna go down the rabbit hole
and look at the right subtree.
If the value is not equal to the data,
it never equals any of the data,
we'll actually come down to this line of code,
and we're gonna return null.
If we make it down here,
it means we couldn't find the value we were looking for
in the tree,
and so we're gonna return a null TreeNode.
Now that we have a get method in the TreeNode class,
let's add one to the Tree class.
We'll say public TreeNode get,
and we need the value.
We'll say if root is not equal to null,
then we'll just call the get method on root.
We'll say return root.get value.
Now, if the root is null, we'll return null,
because that obviously means that the tree is empty,
and so the value that the caller is looking for
is not in the tree.
Okay, so let's go back to our main method,
and let's look for a couple of nodes here,
so we'll say intTree.get,
and let's look for 27.
Actually, I'll print these out
so we know that we actually found something,
so System.out.println, intTree.get 27,
and System.out.println, intTree.get,
let's get 17,
and let's get a value that doesn't exist in the tree.
Let's get 8888.
Okay, so let's run.
This is the result of our traversal.
I'm gonna put a System.out.println right after here.
In our traversal, if you remember, we're just using print,
and so it's not starting a new line,
so let's run this again just to clean up the output a bit.
Okay, so when we look for 27,
we're getting a node with the value being 27,
when we look for 17, we're finding 17,
and of course when we look for 8888, we get null.
That's the get method.
Most of the work is done
in the TreeNode version of the method,
and as usual we call it on the root from the Tree class.
Once again, if we make it down here
it means the value isn't in the tree.
We're gonna make it down here when we hit a leaf node
and the value is not equal to the data,
because in that case, if the value is less than the data,
well, the left child's gonna be null, so we just drop out,
or if it's greater than the data,
then the right child will be null,
'cause we're dealing with a leaf and we'll drop out,
or it's possible we're not dealing with a leaf,
and the value is less than the node,
but there's no left child, there's only a right child,
or vice versa,
when the value is greater than the value in the node,
there could be a left child but no right child.
Basically, once we hit a node
and the direction we wanna go in
doesn't have a child in that position,
we don't do anything in here, we just return null,
and that basically says that the value isn't in the tree.
Okay, so we talked about the fact that's it's really easy
to get the minimum and maximum values
from a binary search tree.
Let's code min and max methods to do this.
We'll start in the TreeNode class,
and I'll put them under the get method.
Let's code the min method first,
and then the max method
will basically be a mirror image of that.
We'll say public int min.
Now, I could return a TreeNode here,
but when we implement delete, we're actually gonna call the,
I can't remember if it's the min or max method.
I think it might be this min method,
and we're gonna want an Integer returned, not a TreeNode.
We could return the TreeNode,
but then we have to call getData on it,
and to avoid that I'm just gonna return an int.
Okay, so to get the min, once again we start at the root
and we travel all the way down the left edges.
If this node doesn't have a left child,
then we have found the minimum value,
because that means we've been travelling down left edges,
and we've hit a node that doesn't have a left child.
That means this node is the minimum value.
We're gonna say if leftChild equals null,
then we're gonna return data.
Remember, we're just returning the int, not the TreeNode,
and so if the left child is null,
this is the node that contains the minimum value.
Otherwise, we wanna continue travelling down the left edges,
so we're gonna return leftChild.min.
That's pretty straightforward.
We travel down the left edges
until we hit a node that doesn't have a leftChild,
and once we hit that node, that's the minimum,
and so if this guy here doesn't have a leftChild,
that's the minimum value.
If it does have a leftChild,
we need to keep travelling down the left edges.
Now we're gonna add the max,
and I'm sure you could probably write this one yourself now.
With the max we start at the root
and travel down the right edges, so I'll say public int max,
and we're gonna say if rightChild equals null,
then we have found the maximum value.
Otherwise, we wanna just go down to the right,
except we wanna call max, not min.
If you copy and paste,
make sure you change this one here as well.
That's it for TreeNode.
Let's go to our Tree class and add the min and max methods
that are gonna call this,
and of course by now you've probably caught on
that we'll just be calling min or max
on the root if the root isn't null.
We'll say public int min.
If the root equals null, what do we wanna return here?
I'm gonna return Integer.MIN_VALUE.
That's the smallest value you can put into an Integer.
Now, of course, this makes the assumption
that the tree doesn't contain, or can't contain that value,
but this is just an implementation
to show you how trees are implemented under the covers,
or to give you a taste of that.
So, for this we'll just return Integer.MIN_VALUE.
If this is an empty tree,
we're gonna signal that to the caller
by returning the absolute smallest value
you can store in an Integer.
Otherwise, we're gonna return root.min.
The same thing, of course, for max,
except the only thing we'll change is
we'll return Integer.MAX_VALUE,
the largest integer you can store in an Integer
if the tree is empty.
Otherwise, we'll return root.max.
Public int max,
if the root equals null,
then we're gonna return Integer.MAX_VALUE.
Otherwise, we'll return root.max.
That's it.
That's it for finding the minimum and maximum values.
Nothing complicated here.
Let's go to our main method,
and let's print out our minimum and maximum values.
I'll say
System.out.println intTree.min,
and System.out.println intTree.max.
I'll comment out all these guys
so we're just seeing the mins and the maxes.
For the max value, I believe that's 32,
and the minimum value is 15.
So, we're expecting 15 for min and 32 for max,
so let's give it a whirl.
There you go: we got 15 for our minimum value
and 32 for our maximum value.
That's all there is to finding nodes
and finding the minimum and maximum value
in a binary search tree.
We need a way to delete nodes now,
and delete can be a little more complicated
because we have children to worry about.
We'll start looking at delete in the next video.
I'll see you there.