(techno music)
All right, so in the last video,
we learned the insertion sort algorithm
and you saw the implementation
or at least one implementation,
and I said that insertion sort is a quadratic algorithm
and it is, but if the sequence of values
that we're sorting is nearly sorted,
then insertion sort runs in almost linear time
and it does that because it doesn't have to do
as much shifting.
Think about it.
If the most of the values are already sorted,
then only a few values will actually have to be inserted
into the sorted partition
and the amount of shifting will be reduced.
Now a computer scientist named Donald Shell
realised that if we could cut down
on the amount of shifting
that insertion sort would run a lot faster
and so he came up with something
that's known as the Shell sort algorithm
and that's what we're going to look at in this video.
So how does Shell sort work?
Well, it's a variation of insertion sort
and what it does is insertion sort chooses
which element to insert using a gap value of one.
So every time insertion sort runs,
it picks off the first unsorted value
and then it compares that value to its neighbour
and it keeps shifting the neighbours to the right
until it finds the correct insertion point
for the element that it's inserting.
Shell sort starts out using a larger gap value,
so instead of comparing elements to their neighbours,
it compares elements that are farther apart
from each other in the array.
And then as the algorithm runs,
it reduces the gap that it's using.
And the goal is to reduce
the amount of shifting that's required.
So as I said, as the algorithm progresses,
the gap value is reduced.
So Shell sort traverses the array with a certain gap value
and after it's done its first traversal
with the initial gap value,
it decreases the gap and it does it again
and it does this and this is very important,
it keeps reducing the gap value until the gap value is one.
Now when the gap value is one,
we're essentially doing an insertion sort.
So the last iteration of the gap value
will actually perform an insertion sort.
But at that point,
the array will be more sorted than it was at the beginning.
And so essentially what Shell sort does
is it does some preliminary work
using gap values that are greater than one
and that preliminary work puts the elements in the array
and perhaps closer to their sorted positions
and then at the very last iteration
when the gap value becomes one,
it does an insertion sort.
But that final insertion sort will be working with values
that have had some preliminary sorting done on them.
And because of that,
there will be a lot less shifting required.
So one question is well, what do we use for the gap value?
How do we figure out what to start with
and how to reduce it?
And you're going to see
that there is a tonne of theories about this.
We're going to go out now to the Wikipedia article
about Shell sort.
So here we are at the Wikipedia article
that I've linked to in the resources
and here's a table with different initial gap values
and how to reduce the gap,
what sequence of gap values to use.
And as you can see, there's quite a number of them.
The important thing to note
is that the way that you calculate the gap
can influence the time complexity.
And so here we have a time complexity column
and depending on what gap we're using,
the time complexity is different.
We have a logarithmic time complexity here.
Here's a quadratic time complexity.
And so the gap value you choose can influence
how many steps the algorithm requires so keep that in mind.
Let's go back to the slides.
Okay, so there are a number of ways
we can calculate the gap value.
One really common sequence that's used for the gap value
and the gap is also called the interval
is the Knuth sequence.
I think that's how it's pronounced.
I've never pronounced it before or said it out loud
so I don't know if the K is silent or not,
but it's the Knuth sequence.
And this says that we calculate the gap
using three k minus one over two.
And the initial value that we want to use
is based on the length of the array.
What we want is we want to use the value of k
that's going to calculate to a value
that's as close as possible to the length of the array
without going over.
And so if we had an array of let's say 20 elements,
we would wanna start with k equal to three.
If we were to start with k equals four,
the gap would be 40
and that's greater than the length of the array
so that won't work.
And so when you want to use this sequence,
you want to start with the value of k
that's going to result in a gap value
that is as close to the array's length as possible
without going over.
Now in the implementation I'm going to show you,
we're not going to use this sequence,
but it's a common way of calculating the interval or the gap
so I thought I'd show it to you.
We're going to do something simpler than that.
So what we're going to do is we're going to base our gap
on the array's length and we're going to initialise the gap
to array.length over two.
And then on each iteration,
we're going to divide the gap value by two until we hit one.
Now our array only has seven elements in it
and so the first gap value is going to be seven over two
which is three and then the second gap value
will be three over two which is one
so we're actually only gonna have two iterations
for this array.
So on the first iteration, we'll use a gap value of three.
And then on the final iteration,
and this is always true for Shell sort,
the gap value will be one.
And at that point, we'll be doing an insertion sort.
But because we've done a previous iteration
and we've moved some of the elements around,
some of the elements will be closer
to their sorted positions.
So let's go through this.
So we're gonna start with a gap value of three
because we're gonna use array.length over two.
We're gonna initialise i to the gap and j to i.
And as we did before with insertion sort,
we're gonna save the value
that we want to work with into newElement.
And then what we do is we compare the element
at index j minus gap
so that will be three minus three is zero with newElement.
So our gap is three and we're starting with element three
so we basically wanna compare it.
Because the gap is three,
we wanna compare it to the element
that's three positions away
and so we compare seven with 20.
Seven is less than 20
and so what we're going to do
is we're going to assign 20 to where seven was.
So instead of doing what we were doing with insertion sort,
which is we're comparing to the neighbours
and shifting up one,
we're comparing using a gap of three and we shift by three
and so 20 has been shifted up three places.
And then we're going to set j to j minus gap which is zero
and we've hit the front of the array at this point
and so what we're going to do is assign newElement
to position zero.
So what we've basically done
is we're kind of doing an insertion sort
but we're using a gap of three.
So what we're gonna want to do next now is move i to four
and j becomes i which is four,
the newElement is 55 and we're gonna compare 55 to 35
because that's three elements away.
55 is greater than 35 so we don't do anything.
Everything remains as it is.
And now i will be five, j will be five,
we're going to compare one to minus 15
'cause minus 15 is three elements away.
Okay, so there's nothing to do
because one is greater than minus 15.
And so now we're gonna move to minus 22
and we're going to assign that to newElement
and we're gonna compare it to the element
that's three positions away from it
and minus 22 is less than 20
so we're going to assign 20 to position six.
Now at this point, we're gonna subtract the gap from j
and then we're going to compare minus 22
against what's at position zero
because we wanna go three elements away again.
Minus 22 is less than seven
so we're going to shift seven into position three.
And at this point, we've hit the front of the array.
There are no more elements to compare minus 22 against
and so we assign minus 22 to position zero.
And at that this point, we've hit the end of the array
and so we have finished our first iteration
with gap equal to three.
Now notice that the array is more sorted now
than it was before
and we've moved minus 22
all the way to the front of the array
and we did that with one assignment.
And so in insertion sort, pure insertion sort,
at some point we would have had to have shifted
minus 22 down or rather in the implementation I showed you
every single element would have to have been shifted up
to make room for minus 22.
But in this sort of pre-sorting phase,
when we're using a gap of three,
minus 22 is moved very quickly down
to the front of the array.
We've also moved 20 closer to its sorted position.
20 started at the front of the array
and now it's only two positions away
from where it usually ends up in the sorted array.
So you can see how doing this preliminary work
before we get to insertion sort
will cut down on how much shifting we have to do.
So at this point, we're gonna update the gap.
We're gonna divide three by two and we'll get one
and so at this point,
we will actually do an insertion sort
because the gap is going to be one
so we're gonna be comparing everything to its neighbours
and when we shift we're gonna be shifting up by one.
And so at this point, we'll do an insertion sort,
but we're doing an insertion sort on an array
that has had some preliminary work done on it
and so there's gonna be a lot less shifting
and that's what Shell sort is all about.
So Shell sort is an in-place algorithm
just like insertion sort.
We're working within the original array.
Now as you saw,
it's really difficult to nail down the time complexity
because it's going to depend on the gap.
It's gonna depend on the method that you're using
to choose the gap.
In the worse case, it can be quadratic.
We saw that when we went out to the table in Wikipedia,
but it can also perform much better than that.
It doesn't require as much shifting as insertion sort.
So as I said, it usually performs better
than insertion sort.
However, it's an unstable algorithm.
Insertion sort is stable,
but Shell sort is unstable and you can see why.
It's because in the pre-insertion sort phase
when we're comparing elements
that are far away from each other,
it's very possible that if we have a duplicate element,
the rightmost element will be shifted
in front of the leftmost element.
So the fact that we're examining elements
that are further away from each other
can lead to the relative positions of duplicate items
not being preserved.
Now one last note before we go to the implementation.
You can also improve bubble sort using Shell sort
and it would be the same type of idea.
You would use a gap interval.
Remember in bubble sort,
we're always comparing elements to their neighbours
and then we're swapping and bubbling elements up.
Well, it's the same sort of idea.
So in bubble sort, if we use a gap of one,
that means we compare it to the neighbours
and everything gets swapped up one position.
Things get bubbled up.
If we do some preliminary work
and in this case rather than just shifting elements,
we'd actually swap them, we can improve bubble sort.
So you can apply Shell sort to insertion sort
and bubble sort and improve both algorithms that way.
With insertion sort,
you're cutting down on the number of shifting.
And with bubble sort,
you'd be cutting down on the number of swaps
that you have to do.
Okay, so that's it for taking a look at
how the algorithm works.
Let's implement it.
I'll see you in the next video.