Hello and welcome to the level 3 of our self-driving car A-game.
So now the challenge is going to be to still do the round trips between the airport and the downtown.
But this time by avoiding obstacles and we will do all the obstacles ourselves you can draw any difficulty
of obstacles.
I'll try not to be too tough with the car because I want to make it to level 4 but let's keep this challenging.
All right.
So as usual we're going to select all these codes and execute and then we go with level 3.
So let's load our brain.
Here we go brain is loaded the car isn't around trips properly.
And so now let's throw some obstacles.
All right.
So what can we do now.
First let's roll something like this.
OK.
And then what we can do is draw another obstacles like this and then maybe something like this.
Something like this.
And something like this.
Let's see what it does.
All right.
So now what it's going to do.
OK.
Avoiding this obstacle now avoiding this one no mistake again.
So still it has to learn it's still exploring avoiding this obstacle.
Perfect.
Very good.
Is it going to avoid this one.
Great.
It did.
And going to the downtown and now going back to the airport avoidance obstacle.
Great.
Now is it going to avoid this one this time.
And no we're still on the stage.
It's OK.
I'll get this sticker.
Maybe something like this will be better.
The car will understand more because right now it is being quite stubborn.
All right.
Still avoiding this obstacle it seems not to have any problem with this one.
What kind of problem with that one.
Better now.
You see I got thicker which means that the punishment was harder with a worse word.
And now it managed to avoid.
And this one avoided as well.
Perfect.
Now we have a functional self-driving car as it seems.
So we're watching this one again.
Great.
And now avoiding this one great still going on some sun but it's ok.
It's it will be punished for that anyway.
Avoiding this one.
So sorry this this one was totally unuseful But you know we can do something like this if you want.
You know to get this even more challenging for the car.
All right.
And OK we can add a big tip here so that it doesn't cheat because it's still crossing the tip of the
obstacle and we can do the same for the other tips of the other obstacles that we go there we go there
we go.
Now
let's see what it does now.
OK.
There we go again trying to reach the airport now.
Perfect.
So it's going around the obstacle is not trying to find the best path.
But anyway the goal is to reach the two goals the downtown and the airports.
Then we can add some code to you know try to find the best path.
But we definitely already have a soul train car.
All right.
Great.
Great job.
And there we go again.
I still get you on the Simpsons so it's still in Panish we can actually look at this core function which
is here as you can see it gets the punishment and this corporation is actually decreasing with time.
So that's because I got the obstacles figure and
right now as you can see it's trying to avoid the tips of the obstacles more and more.
It's doing them better and better job as you can see you know it's going around faster now.
Except for this one.
But if we save again and look at this core function as you can see we see some kind of improvement here.
But anyway the car is going to get better with time.
But I think that right now we can say that level 3 is past because any way it manages to do the round
trips between the airports and downtown by going around obstacles.
And that's what we wanted.
So yes maybe.
Let's move on to level 4.
Level 4 is going to be very challenging.
I don't think we'll be able to pass level four but that will be the challenge of this model.
You will have to change something in the code to pass level 4.
It will either be something that it has to do with the word or something that has to do with you know
the strategy of the game or even something with the neural network or something with the D2 an algorithm.
Well you will look for it you will do some research and you will try to get an even better card than
this one that avoids any kind of obstacle that will never go into some sense or that will try to find
the best way.
The best path the shortest path.
So good luck with that.
It's going to be excellent practice for you.
And I can't wait to see you solutions.
So now let's move on to level four.
And this time it's going to be very very challenging.
So I'll see you in the next tutorial and until then enjoy.
I.