Hello and welcome to the final level of the self-driving car challenge.
So this time my goal will be to beat the self-driving car not the level four because I want to challenge
you into improving the curves improving the AI or maybe improving the strategy so that you can beat
this challenge yourself.
So I'm going to make a highly complex road that will still go from the airport to the downtown but maybe
too complicated for the car to find its way.
So that will be my challenge so that I hope we can have fun with the challenging homework.
So let's do this let's approach this level.
So let's select everything then let's load the brain and there we go.
Now with the round trips between the airport and the downtown.
So it's going to take some time so I'm just going to put on some music and here we go with the road.
And there we go.
Here is the road.
And as you can see the car seems to have a lot of trouble.
So that's exactly what I wanted.
It's you know doing these little round trips in the same part of the road.
That's a problem.
It doesn't find its way right now to the downtown.
So how can we fix this.
Can we do need to change the strategy or do we need to change the parameters of the neural networks
that has changed the synopsis in the brain of the car.
Do we need to do something with the words you know maybe get a worse word when it's not finding the
goal as it is the case right now.
So so I don't know that for you to find out as you can see the rewards is not very severe when it's
not finding the goal.
You know it's not getting closer to the goal.
The reward is just minus 0.2.
That's not a severe bad reward.
You could try to decrease the reward even more like setting a reward equal to minus 0.5.
Maybe that will work.
And just throwing some suggestions to help you.
So that's a change you can make with the word strategy.
And then of course can make some other changes with your new network.
So you know in this section we create the architecture of the new network we choose to have 30 hidden
neurons in one hidden layer.
Maybe you can try to change the architecture by trying some more layers or some more hidden neurons
I don't know.
That's another suggestion for improvement.
And then you can also try to change something in a deep learning algorithm or something you can move
onto the course and find out about the other algorithms.
Maybe there is another one that will manage to handle this situation.
So good luck.
I look forward to seeing your solutions try to draw that same road that's perfect.
That's really pretty exciting enigma.
And if you want me to give you a hint or if you want me to explain quickly what the problem is.
Well you can see that right here.
When it reaches that point it's going back and that's because when it's reaching that point it's getting
too far away from the goal which right now is downtown.
You know when it's reaching that point if it goes further Well it will go further away from the goal.
So that's why it's going back here.
And so you have to change something in the code something in the strategy to maybe punish it less when
it's getting further away from the goal.
Maybe that's the solution.
I'm just throwing some suggestions.
I don't want to give you solution too fast but that would be a really good exercise.
And that's typically a problem that can be countered by engineers when they're making a self-driving
car.
But anyway I think that's a pretty cool enigma.
So I hope you will have fun and before solving this homework maybe you can do another very efficient
homework which would be simply to try to implement all this again.
You know just implement the exact same one that will be excellent practice because so far you've just
listened to my explanations but there is a huge difference between listening to something and try to
do the thing yourself.
Oh oh did you see what happened.
It just found its way.
That's amazing.
It's funny how it got out of it.
But I'm sure there is a better strategy to get out of it more efficiently.
And now it seems to be pretty good.
Maybe I'm speaking too fast maybe it's going to solve this.
No.
Here we go.
It's getting stuck here again.
That's pretty challenging for the car right.
But I'm sure this can be solved.
That's your go.
So good luck and please let me know about your solutions.
And then I.