Hello and welcome back to the course on artificial intelligence.
Today we're talking about the first part of A-3 see the actor critic part.
So here we got a synchronous advantage.
Actor critic algorithm.
And we're going to be talking about that underlined Akrotiri.
That's where we're going to start.
You could technically start anywhere but it just makes a lot more sense to start from a critic because
that way we'll have like a very consecutive explanation of intuitive understanding of what's going on
is going to facilitate us.
But if we start surprising yet at the end of this aberration.
All right so so far in this course we've come up with a deep conditional Kule learning which is illustrator
here so we've got the computer seeing the pixels so the actual image and pixels not just a vector.
So it's not cheating it's actually seeing exactly what a human sees it sees the monsters it sees the
health it sees the parameters at the bottom it sees the card or it sees the gun it is exactly the same
thing as a human would see when playing this game.
Then that image is passed through a convolutional lair and then it's passed through a pulling lariats
flattens and goes into a neural network and then at the output we've got actions as remember we've got
those cube values then we apply a action selection policy to them.
So for instance we apply a soft Max and we find out which action we want to take.
And so there is some exploration plus exploitation going on.
There are a combination of the two.
So that is how deep convolutional cool learning works.
But now let's see what we're going to do with it.
So for simplicity's sake just so that it's easier for us to operate with is because we're going to adjusting
this image and moving it around.
We're going to replace circles with squares with these or these rectangular boxes.
And we also are going to get rid of those lines and between just change them to arrows so this doesn't
change the essence.
This is just the representation on this chart.
This is still even this representation is still deep convolutional Kule learning is just going to be
easier for us to modify it and show exactly what it is.
So that's just how we are going to represent things from here.
And what does or this specific part so is starting.
Remember we're starting like step by step we're starting with the active critic part.
So we're going to see how we go from deep crucial Kule learning to A-3 see step by step and first step
we're going to introduce this this actor critic PARTOVI here so we're going to talk about that.
So the first thing that happens is this last bit.
The output is actually we're just going to redraw it like this so it's exactly the same output exactly
the same q values are exactly the same action.
So if he if you had eight possible actions you still have eight possible actions which is going to put
them at the top so they take up less space so nothing so far nothing has changed so so far.
This and this are exactly the same.
But now this is where the active critic part comes in.
We're going to have a second output.
We're going to have the first one as a set of outputs and here we're going to have a separate individual
output so technically we are going to be using our neural network.
So once an hour.
Or the image and everything like the values go through the network from left to right over here.
They don't just spit out one set of values they spit up actually two sets.
And so the top said we really know what it is it's it's possible actions but here we're actually going
to have another extra value so let's have a look at that.
What is that value.
So here we go that's the top.
So we just kind of like reduce the size of this illustration.
The top output is are the cube values as we discussed previously for the actions.
So they're the same thing.
Everything is same.
But then now this bottom part and the top part is actually called the X or we're going to give it a
name that's the actor because that's the part where the agent chooses what it wants to do so that it's
like it's acting it's as if it's performing on stage and it'll make more sense once we have the second
name up on the screen as well.
And then the second output is just like one value and that is V of S so that is the value of the state.
So if q of S is the Q of A is the q value of a certain action and as you can see that's why there's
action one action two action three are up to action six or higher meaning actions there possibly are
in that state.
So in a given state s What is the q value of taking action a action to action one action to and so on.
Then here we're also predicting we are also using neural network to predict what is the value of the
stage we're actually in and this part is called the critic.
And so that's the intuitive for the kind of not even full intuitive that's just like the start of the
intuition behind actor predict that there's two outputs now from the neural network not just one.
P before we just had that one at outbred which we now call the action.
But now we have two outputs Akshara and critic.
And there's going to dynamic between them which we'll explore further.
But for now it's important to understand that we're predicting not just the values of the actions that
the agent can take from the current state but are also predicting the value of being in this kind of
state using that same year old network.
So that's the core of the first step into the active critic.
And now we're going to need to talk about a synchronous which we'll do next tutorial in order to understand
exactly what's going on between duty and the final thing for today is that all of these key values as
we know that's also called Pulse.
So in some literature in some blogs and some discussions you might find in the active critic you might
find the author talking about Cue values on the side of the actor in some in other literature and blog
posts and discussions you'll find the agrah the author talking about the policy so and usually is use
the user like a Greek letter P for representing the policy or just say policy of state.
So altogether these are the policy of state of is because as we remember the policy is that if you put
all the actions together the possible actions and then it's deciding which action to take.
So these are going to be like the probabilities of taking each action so that's the policy.
So don't be thrown off if you see one or the other.
They basically mean the same thing.
So on one hand here you've got the policy or the q values on the other hand you've got the actual value
of the state and they're being predicted from that year on that.
So that's the start of the active critic will continue of this in the next tutorial when we're talking
about a synchronous and look for see there.
Until then enjoy the.