Hello and welcome back to the course on artificial intelligence.
In today's story we're talking about the final a in a 3C.
We're talking about advantage.
So there it is.
We've already spoken about actor critic and a synchronous previously.
And so he built a way to what we're going to be looking at today and with advantage we're going to put
everything together.
So this is what we have so far we've got a neural network which is shared between the agents the asynchronous
agents and then we've got the critic which is also shared between age and so.
How does this all play out and why is this critic shared between the agents.
Let's have a look at that.
Well understands better we're going to look at an example we're going to look at this agent for instance
and see what happens when he's in a certain state and he needs to make a decision what action to play.
So this agent is in a state he sees this image and then what happens is this information goes into the
neural network it goes to the convolutional lair then goes into the pooling lair then it goes into the
flattening lair and then from there it goes into the hidden layers of the neural network and then as
an output he gets all of these policy values that you values are the policy.
And also he gets the value the critic.
And so as we know neural networks in order to operate they need to propagate certain errors or losses
back through the network.
So this way in order to update the weights so what waits or so what losses are we going to be dealing
with here.
Well we're two losses.
We've got the value loss and the postals.
So the value loss is linked to the value partial loss is linked to pools and so valuable.
We've already dealt with it before.
We know that we have rewards and we know that we have a discount factor so basically this is very similar
to what we were talking about in the conversion in deep learning tutorials.
Basically the network predicts a certain value V and at the same time we can estimate what should be
based on what we know about the environment so far we can estimate what should the value be in the state
and by comparing the two we can calculate the value loss and then back propagator network update the
weights.
So that's that's bracing for the new thing here is the policy loss.
And so what is this policy loss and how does it work.
Well this is the part where this whole situation where the critic is shared between the actors or between
the agents is going to finally emerge.
So to understand palsu loss we need to introduce a value called Advantage hence the name of this part
of the story on this whole part of the Salyut the advantage and the advantage is calculated as Q of
as an A minus V of s.
So basically the Q value or that you chose to play all of the action that you chose to play in the state
that you are in state S minus the value of that state.
So this is the difference between the two and that is called that one.
And the advantage is used in the calculation of the pulseless.
Now we won't go into the formula of the pulseless calculation because it's quite complex it uses entropy
or you can use entropy doesn't have to.
We're not going to dissect that formula but we're going to understand this on an intuitive level.
Why are we doing this why are we calculating this advantage and how is it going to help us.
Well let's look at this premise for a second.
The Q value here comes from what the neural network predicted for this agent and so predictive of in
this specific action in this specific state for the action that it can play so it's got these actions
and it can slide one of them and it can play it well whereas the Wii value is the value that is dictated
by the critic.
It is the value that we have here in this shared part and that's the key here that this part is shared
so the critic break because this is how the credit comes into play.
Because we've got a value that we choose or the action that we choose to play for this agent in that
state.
But then the critic can tell us what is the known value of that state what is overall the known value
for this whole group of of agents that are performing together because their sharing doesn't answer
because the initial B because they're sharing the critic they're all contributing to this to these v
values that are being calculated for a different set so the whole a.z algorithm says OK.
So the critic knows a v value how much better is your q value that you're selecting compared to the
known v value.
That's what it's saying.
So that's basically it.
So that I'm going to select a q value here based on my my policy based on whether whatever we use like
a soft max function or on or a Epsilon Grealy policy or something like that.
And of course we'll be out exploration plus exploitation combined in there but we selected Q value and
now the question is what is the extra.
What does that scolded ones what is the advantage that your selected action brings compared to the known
value of that state and that is the essence of the advantage and basically then that is used to calculate
the policy loss and then the policy loss is then back propagated through back to the network.
So they're both back propagate through a network and the weights are adjusted in order for the network
to better represent the value of the critic and also so that's the top part.
But then this also part of the key here is that the value the weights are bakra.
When is this post-offices back forget that rates are adjusted in such a way so that this advantage is
maximized so like that's that's intuitive side of the intuitive understanding of it that we are back
again this policy last through the network in order to help maximize this advantage.
And what that means is basically that when an agent comes across bad actions like actions where the
q values less than the known value for the state.
So basically the whole ATC algorithm knows that the value for the state is something X and then all
of a sudden you came across a very bad action and the and you did it you chose about action.
And what that means for the enthusiasm is that well why would we do something like that when its worse
than we already what we already know about this whole environment and what could could have done.
So we shouldn't do more of that.
And therefore the weights are just in a way so that happens is rarer.
So that happens less rare.
So thats a less frequent occurrence that we choose that bad action.
On the other hand if you choose a very good action where q value is greater than V or much greater then
where during this backwardation of the Polish loss through the network the weights are going to be update
and in such a way to really reinforce that to encourage reassure that to happen again so that the weights
will be adjusted in such a way that so the atresia algorithm will think oh well that does really cool
that Wantage was very high there.
I should do more of that and therefore you will update the weights in such a way that will be more likely
to occur in the future that action.
So and therefore that is you know thats how the network is slowly slowly going to adapt and slowly going
to construct itself into something that on one hand calculates the value correctly and then on the other
hand or as correct as possible.
And on the other hand it encourages or it has actions which have a high advantage.
So there we go that's that's this part.
And now let's have a look at another one just to reinforce what we just discussed at the top 1.
So same thing here.
The top agencies a situation a state is in a state and then needs to decide what to do so since this
information to the networks of this image use internet regrows to convolutional they're pulling their
flattening Lehre goes into the hidden layers and then from here we get an output we get the acute values
of the policy we get the V values again the same thing we've got two losses.
We've got the value loss which is here Polish loss which is here value loss.
We already know how is calculated.
When we discussed this in the deep Q learning and just discussing just now as well.
So that's how the value was calculated and then the policy loss again in order to calculate that which
we're not going to go into for him.
But on an intuitive level we're calculating that advantage which is okay so we took a certain action
we chose a certain action based on our selection policy whether it's soft Max or upselling greedy or
whatever other social policy that we're using.
And then what's the action we took Now let's compare it to the known and value of the state which comes
from the shared critics so this critic is kind of like if you think about it's kind of observing all
of these agents at the same time is looking at this one look at this one this one they're all contributing
towards a critic to get the critic more up to speed with the environment to make sure that the critic
is representative of what's going on in the actual environment so that the weights.
This is that's where the value loss comes in so that the weights of the actual neural network that they
reflect very well the actual situation of things in the environment so that they can then rely on this
value and then use it here.
And so basically.
So all of these agents all of these agents are contributing to this critic.
But then at the same time through through this valueless but at same time the critic is observing the
decisions or the policies of these agencies.
It's like it's like going looking back at the like I'm trying to draw like an arrow to the poles an
arrow an arrow.
So looking back at them at the decision that they're making is criticizing these decisions through that
vantage and saying OK you made a decision you chose this you chose this action.
That's great.
Now let's calculate the advantage or disadvantage ranch's is a equals you know the Q value of might
have made the decision I made or the choice I made to the I made chose to take minus the known value
to the critic.
Not about the critic.
So Kalika the difference if it's a low difference you're Polish then when you polish your losses back
propagated through the network the way it's going to be adjusted is going to encourage the weights to
be adjusted in such a way that that doesn't happen again that that Q value or that Q value is going
to be lower so that because our policy selects the actions based on the q values the higher the Q value
the more likely it's going to be selected.
So if we were using like an arc Max policy then we just always select the one of the highest as you
remember we discussed this then we'd always select the one with the highest value.
But we actually were using a probabilistic approach where I was using like soft Max or upselling greedy
policy.
And then we were basically selecting where we can select any one of them but the higher the cube the
better.
So if we selected something and then the advantage was very low then bomb the network is going to be
added in such a way that next time the value of that certain action is going to be less and maybe something
else will be more.
So that's how that is split out and on the other hand if we select something where that advantage is
going to be high then this is going to go into the policy laws and then the networks and we update it
so that is more commonly observed event like scenario.
And so basically this whole Polish loss helps the network adapt or morph in such a way that we do.
Moral of the good stuff good good actions and good things and do less of the bad things.
And that's how these two losses come into play and that's how they're back appropriate.
So hopefully that clears up in a very intuitive way of course we didn't go into the formulas into into
the complex mathematics behind all of this and like into the very intricate details.
But at the same time hopefully on the intuitive way in an intuitive way.
All of this clears up why we have the actor and the critic and how they interact together that you know
you have these agents asynchronous or synchronous side of things.
Then this is this is your actor and critic and this is the advantage and how that all comes into play.
So these are synchronous agents.
They're going.
They're playing this or exploring the environment and working through environment and they're all altogether
contributing to a critic which is then observing their policies observing the actors which is what this
is called.
And through the through that vantage and therefore coming up this poses a loss and then policy and value
loss or back propagate to just the network in order to.
On one hand represent the true way of things in the environment.
Another hand to improve the actors performances.
So there we go.
That's that's a quick recap of the intuition we discussed.
Once again hopefully this is all coming together on an intuitive level and of course in the practical
tutorials We'll talk more about how all of this works in Atlanta we'll walk you through this process
of building owners.
But having this this image in your mind and this like kind of like a roadmap of everything how it comes
together will be well should be I hope will be very helpful for you to better navigate the practical
side of things.
And in terms of additional reading for today we've got two elements so first one is on the advantage.
So here we've got high demential continuous controlling using generalized advantage estimation by John
Shulman and this is an image of a stick figure getting up like standing up.
And here you can find even more about advantaged and advantage and you'll find all the different types
of advantages.
You've got the general advantage in estimation and you've got advantages that you use actually in the
in the forms in the calculations so if you want to find out more about advantage and exactly how it
works the formulas behind it and some of the the top top elements or formulas and no holes in the space
of this advantage.
We discussed them.
This is the article to go to.
And one more one other element that or piece of work that we wanted to remind you about is the blog
a series of blog post by Arthur Giuliani which we've mentioned a couple times already.
This is part eight which is specifically about A-3 sea.
So here you can get a nother explanation.
So with a bit more mathematics about what is going on and you maybe you can pick up some additional
things from here.
Just two things to keep in mind first of all as always this blog is intenser followers we're using pi
torch.
So keep that in mind.
And the second thing is that the way we structured our approach is we talked about active critic first
then we talked about a synchronous.
And then we talked about advantage whereas in log Arthur's first talks about a Synchronoss an actor
critic an advantage so keep that in mind so hopefully that doesn't throw you off.
But other than that of course is a great piece of content.
And we do highly recommend checking it out for some additional information.
So there we go hopefully enjoy today's tutorial.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then enjoy.
I.