Would you like to save yourself a huge amount of time money and frustration and guarantee the success
of your marketing efforts.
Wolins training I'm going to show you exactly how to do that.
You're going to learn a simple process to gather a list of products and services people desperately
need and will pay money for.
Same process will able to collect powerful sales copy to use on your sales pages Facebook Ads emails
and other marketing materials on the same simple process will help you to build an email list of people
to sell to even before you have a product or have ever written a blog post.
Sounds pretty good doesn't it.
Well what I'm going to be doing is showing you how to set up a market research survey for free with
Google Forms.
I'm going to show you the three questions that are pretty magic questions that are going to getting
some incredible responses.
I'm going to show you how to distribute the survey to get their responses on how to analyze the survey.
So there is nothing more powerful in marketing than intimately understanding a customers pain points
and desires.
And this is what this process is going to enable you to do.
It is going to save you huge amount of time because you wouldn't believe the amount of people who say
to me you know I'm disappointed in my Facebook ads didn't work and I say Well did you address any pain
points.
Did you address any of their desires.
I take a look.
None of that's there.
And so you got to understand that is step one even before you write a blog post even before you do a
Facebook ad etc..
So I've used this market research process to develop my own products and services and you can too.
I use it for companies I've worked for and for clients.
And at the end of this training you will have this process as part of your toolkit to really find all
the valuable information to them.
So let us get started and create that market research survey.