Welcome to Facebook marketing in this training you are going to learn how to use Facebook as a powerful
marketing tool to grow any business.
And I'm going to walk you through the steps to set up a Facebook page step by step to create content
and build an audience of tens of thousands of potential customers.
But before we get into that I do want to take a minute to talk about why you should be using Facebook
as a marketing channel and how it's really different to other social networks and marketing channels
out there.
So we're going to get through five reasons.
First reason is simply that there's 2 billion active monthly users on Facebook.
And if we look at a chart of all the social network sites here you can see that Facebook is way out
in front with really over 2 billion users.
So why is this important to say a marketer or business owner.
Well Facebook is so big that really no matter what country you're in no matter what age group you're
targeting your potential customers and audience are going to be on Facebook.
It's just a fact with an audience that that big two billion people.
So if you're not sure which marketing channel you should be focusing on you can focus on facebook because
your audience are there without a doubt.
It's just that big.
And you couldn't really say the same about Instagram or something like that.
It's got more of a narrower age range although that is expanding at things like Twitter again is more
specific type of user not everybody has Twitter.
Not everybody has snapchat.
Not everybody has Pinterest but everybody or almost everybody has a Facebook profile so you can really
target them there.
So that's the first reason.
Second reason is that the average Facebook user has two hundred friends.
Now why is this important.
It's important because that allows Facebook to have a very viral effect because if two friends like
a Facebook page a Facebook post then if they have a third friend that's interested in similar content
Facebook is going to show that to them and that's what really creates this viral effect.
Very very quickly is that Facebook is able to really show content to your friends group and it just
expands so quickly.
Now that is not the same for something like say YouTube like I use YouTube personally all the time but
I have no idea what my Khant what my friends look at on YouTube.
I never see a video that they like.
And so it doesn't create that same viral effect between friends.
Now the third reason that you should be using Facebook is that it has real profiles and this may seem
obvious but this is actually the reason that Facebook was able to dominate social media.
They weren't the first social media site but they were their first social media site that got people
to create real profiles and it was because they really want to connect with their friends so they obviously
put in their real name.
So why is it important for business.
Well let's say if we look down at it at a post here.
If I click in and I can see the people who are really engaging with my content and then I can click
through to their profile.
I can get a sense of who they are what they're interested in where they are what other content that
they like and that allows me to build up a very clear buyer persona for my business.
You couldn't say the same for YouTube or reddish or even Twitter.
People tend to create these pseudo profiles and not their real names because there wasn't that incentive
to really connect with your friends.
So that is something extremely unique to Facebook.
And not only does it make it good for you know seeing who your competitors audience are get a real clear
picture of them.
You can do for your own but also it's very powerful in terms of if you're looking at your analytics
and you want to see you know some analytics on your audience.
He can be very clear you can be very certain that you know their age gender their location is extremely
accurate because people have put that in themselves and also then for Facebook ads you can much better
target people based on who they are and that is an extremely powerful reason to market your business
on Facebook and because they have real profiles.
So number four and in case you weren't aware Facebook owns Facebook Messenger WhatsApp and Instagram.
And if we go back to the most famous social networks worldwide of the states you can see that one two
three four five six seven a 10 even one two three four five six in the top six Facebook owns three of
them.
So Facebook you know setting up their first.
It makes it much easier for you to say connect with people on Facebook Messenger.
That's all integrated.
Also it's much easier if you have people on Instagram or you're setting up an account there to invite
people from Facebook across Facebook ads is also integrated so you can you can even target Facebook
users on Instagram in ads.
And what's up.
You can be sure that there's more integrations and opportunities opening up there.
So again if you're not really sure to get where to get started Facebook really can just leverage and
be used to grow audiences on all these other platforms as well.
Now the final reason that you really want to market your business on Facebook is because Facebook has
a powerful platform and even if you don't have the budget or not considering advertising on Facebook
right now you need to have this in the back of your mind as a reason to really just grow a business
on Facebook.
And this is because you actually it's no longer possible to even create ads on Facebook without a published
Facebook page.
So that's why you'll need to set up a page if you want advertise.
But also if you have an audience built up well then I can say to Facebook Ads Hey I've got an audience
built up.
This is what they're like and go out and find more people like that.
And so with a bit of a sample you can give that to Facebook and they can really find more people like
that.
Otherwise it's going to be much harder for Facebook to really understand who are the type of people
engage or content.
You know what are their profiles like where they based.
So by building up a Facebook page and building up an audience then that would really improve your marketing
efforts on Facebook probably by 10 times.
So those are the five reasons why you should use Facebook as a marketing channel and how it's different
to other marketing channels out there.