Welcome to or marketing by the end of this training you'll be confidently using curagh as a powerful
marketing tool to drive website traffic and generate sales for your business.
Curagh is one of the largest question and answer websites in the world and it's a lot less competitive
than other marketing channels like Facebook Instagram or YouTube.
It's also growing extremely fast.
So now is really the time to get in in this training.
You'll learn how to answer questions that attract a huge audience that you can then funnel back to your
Web site.
I'll show you how to identify questions that you can really answer and I'll show you how to structure
me your answers so you can really grab people's attention and move them back to your Web site.
I'll even show you how to use Cure's dots so you can identify what you're doing well in order to grow.
And I'll even show you how to track in Google Analytics the traffic from individual questions and also
how that contributes to the goals of your web site.
We'll be covering all of this as well as plenty of other tips and tricks so that you can get the most
at a keyword.
Let's get started.