Welcome to YouTube marketing.
By the end of this training you will be confidently using YouTube as a powerful marketing tool to drive
Web site traffic and generate sales for your business.
In this training you're going to learn how to produce valuable content to build an audience and to attract
subscribers.
I'll show you how to enhance the design of your YouTube channel and make it look as professional as
possible.
You'll also learn how to optimize your videos for the search engines so that you can rank number one
and you learn how to use YouTube analytics to grow your channel.
I'll even walk you through how to create your first few too bad.
We'll be covering all of this as well as plenty of other tips and tricks so that you can get the most
viewed you.
Let's get started.