In this video you're going to learn how to use live video on Facebook to grow your business.
So first we walk you through the practical steps to go live on Facebook and then I'll give you a couple
of ideas about how you can use it to grow your business.
So the practical steps to going live is very simple.
At the top of your news feed here you're going to see the option to create a live video.
You might just have to prove access to your camera.
Now right now I've just covered my camera with a sheet of paper.
But you can read it in here select the page that you want to share it on.
So I could change that here if I wanted to.
And then you just want to say something by the video that you're putting in.
Then you can select your camera on the microphone that you're using so you can change those Iran if
you want to you can plug in their camera so you can do that and you can even share your screen as well.
I'm using the Chrome browser and you can toss it in this Chrome extension to enable screen share which
you can use for presentations or you could use even for game play as well.
So I can just put in a test title and then you cannot in tags if you want if you're doing game play.
You can see that you can tag a video game so that will show up.
So in terms of the setup it's very quick and then to go live itself you just click go live you can see
you get it can't end like this and you can see that my comment came at the top and then you're going
to see you're able to you can write comments in here.
And also if anybody is commenting on your video you're going to see this pop up in the sidebar here
in the right as you're talking and as you're appearing on camera so you can read the comments as you're
going live.
Now once you've finished your live video then you can just click Finish.
And then what is going to happen after that.
Is that a replay of your video will be available on your timeline.
You can just click on if I refresh the page.
This should COBE come up almost immediately.
And you can see there it is there.
If any anybody commented on this while I was doing it that would have been shown up here.
And you know people could read back and watch this later as well.
So how do you actually use this.
Well what are some use cases of it.
Well on your home page you can just use this for something like an Ask Me Anything.
This is an example that I did just ask me anything about Facebook live.
Are Facebook ads you can promote that in advance.
You can send them an e-mail notification saying I'll be doing a live.
Ask me anything on Facebook at this time.
Join in and then they can just click through at the appropriate time and log in or you can do it or
not as I've done it here just a short one minute to minute video.
And then I said you know ask me anything I'll answer questions even afterwards.
And I got quite a lot of use for this one video quite a lot of comments and then I ultimately went ahead
and just answer those Collins and then promoted Darkhorse course that I was kind of about Facebook and
said I created at a later stage.
So I put an update in afterwards.
How else can you use this.
Well you can use this not only on your own Facebook page but you can do this in Facebook groups.
So here's an example of this was it not for you to me in structure if you click into this you can see
that he said I'm live in the instructor club for the next hour I'll be answering many of the questions
so and a little bit of a build up before this.
He was commenting in this group saying I'll be live on X days if you have any questions just let me
know below.
And then he just went live under his personal profile and started to answer some questions and you can
see quite a lot of comments in here which he went ahead and answered.
So you could do this under your own name in a Facebook group and then start to talk a little bit about
your business and how people can learn more.
Or you can also go live directly on your own Facebook page.
There's a couple of use cases for them.
I particularly like that example of someone leveraging this to get in front of a Facebook group and
to really help that group but also talk more about his own business as well.
So now that you know how to go live on Facebook create a live video for yourself or put this strategy
in your back pocket for later.