It's now time to refine your creative on what people really see when they see you are out in this lecture
you're going to learn how you can pull images from your web site to use as part of your ad hiking free
stock images from Facebook to Zura and hey you can even use existing posts as part of your ad and there's
a key and Vantage in doing that.
Now as a reminder we are still working here inside the ads create tool working at the final stage of
the creation process which is the third level and the first thing that you'll see here is the option
at the top of the page to create a brand new ad.
We're using existing posts now.
As I said I'll walk you through both of those scenarios.
But the key thing regardless of which option you choose he has to choose an ad format that is appropriate
for your objective.
So you can see here that I have a number of different options to choose from and my example campaign
here.
My objective is to get clicks to a Web site.
And so I want to choose an on format that is really appropriate for that.
The best option for clicks to Web site is probably a carousel where a single image not probably a single
image and just be as simple as people will see the image they click on the image and they'll go outside.
I wouldn't want to choose a single video for this type of campaign because if I choose a single video
people will just watch the video and not necessarily click through.
So be sure that you select the format that is appropriate for the objective that you have set up here
in the campaign level.
Once you've chosen your odd format the next step is to start building at UROD and create something that
looks good.
You can see here now for the odd preview.
Nothing is showing up.
I really want to select the media for sure and that's the next step.
Probably the easiest thing to do if you have a Clix to Web site campaign like I'm setting up is simply
just plain your web site you are all on Facebook can really pull the image from that page and show it
up here as part of your ad.
They also pull some of the text from that page and you can see already I'm starting to get something
that looks pretty good.
So that's how you just simply pull the images from the landing page that you were sending people to.
And that was one of the fastest was just create very very simply.
Now if you do not have a good image on your landing page we do have the option to add images from your
own computer here and upload them.
If you don't have those you can add in free stock images.
And this is a great resource that's built into the tool and really can save a lot of time digging around
trying to find something good.
So how this works is you just simply type in a keyword like business success as I've chosen here and
I can try and find an image that looks appropriate So this one looks pretty good here.
I'm going to and just click Done.
Now one cool thing at this point is you can add in up to six different images at no extra cost.
What Facebook will do is then test those six different images and see one which really performs best.
So this is something to do a quick split test that you can do even at this stage very very easily.
And I wouldn't worry about this too much but if you're one or two images that you want access to this
can be good to do at this point.
So that's really how you add in images from your own computer.
We're using those free stock images.
Now the final option you have is to use an existing posts and there is a key advantage in doing this.
The advantage is really that all of the reactions and comments that you've got on your original post
will be shown in the.
And so for example you can see a preview of it here.
This was a live video on Facebook that I did it in show biz live now it's being sponsored by.
You can see all of the cards that I got there that gives huge social proof.
If people see that in their Facebook news feed they go hazed a lot of people are interested in this.
You know maybe I'm going to be interested in it as well.
Now a key thing to do is if you are choosing an existing post remember once again to use an ad format
that is appropriate for your objective.
So in this particular case here this is a video and this wouldn't be appropriate for my ad as I want
to get people to click through to my Web site.
But how you can really choose posts and find one that are good is once you've added in your face Facebook
page here you're going to see a list of page posts below that you can choose from.
Click on the dropdown and you can see in terms of the most recent all of the different posts that you
have put out and this doesn't give you a lot of information about which one you should choose.
And so what I recommend is maybe coming into your Facebook page insights coming down to posts sorting
all those posts by reach just by clicking on this here.
It's going to show from the lowest to highest.
Click it again shows it from the top to the bottom and I can pick out an appropriate existing post with
the odd format that I want.
That's really going to work in my case here.
Now I'm going to set one up from scratch because none these posts are really I think appropriate for
the ad but that is a great option to do if you have existing post or even to think about going forward.
Can I put out some posts prior to a campaign test them out then use them as part of the campaign.
So in this lecture you've learned how to really select the media for your release.
Uploading an image or video from your landing page or website from your own PC using the stock images
or using an existing.
Go ahead and take a few minutes to dig through your own archives or add them in from your web site or
use those free stock images.
And go ahead and try and find images that are bright higher resolution and that really look attractive
and will make people want to click on them.