The number one thing that you can do to have success on Instagram is to follow some top accounts in
your news so you can really understand how they've laid out their profile what information they're putting
their most importantly what content are they putting at it that is getting a huge amount of engagements.
So to find those topics and sort you want to do is come to the discovery tab in Instagram and you can
see that by default Instagram is going to be suggesting some icons and even highlighting some content
here.
And what do you really want to do to find a consignor needs either to type the current names right in
the top here or start to look for some key words in your business.
So let's just imagine that I was a personal finance planner.
I could just type in something like personal finance
Now what I want to make sure that I'm selecting here is not just the top posts or hashtags but in particular
I want to look at individual people here.
And then you really want to scroll down and start to really have a look into some of these accounts
here see how many followers they have.
See the way that they laid out their profile.
They're using some the most use here they've got a link to their Web site they've got their email there.
And importantly is then the type of content that they're putting as.
And this is probably the best way for you to understand.
Is Instagram for you.
If there are people here getting engaged in on their content and you can be guaranteed that you could
do the same thing as well.
And let's click in to some of their content to see which engagement they're getting.
So 87 likes so I will look at this 170 likes and we can get a sense as a couple of quotes here.
There's pictures here but what we might want to do if we don't think that this is the greatest match
and it can for us to model is right beside there it can't beside the Follow button.
There's a little drop down blue arrow and then we can see some other suggestions even if we click see
all we can get a full list of these similar accounts on a similar topic.
And here we go Dave Ramsey.
He's got a blue tick beside his name.
So that's a verified account.
And he's also said he's popular there so this could be a good occasion for us to model if we were in
this age.
We can see a lot more followers this time Ryan 586 K and he's got a link there.
Call email directions and let's have a look at some of the contents.
5400 likes.
Congratulations.
It's a repost.
Excited to announce I became debt free.
OK.
So here is some interesting type content if I was in this nation really showing people who have achieved
a goal that maybe I'm a consultant to help them to achieve.
And essentially this is a repost again so this is somebody else's content that this guy Dave Ramsey
has just reposted and tanked and the Instagram account of the actual people in the picture.
So already I'm building up a very clear idea of how to do well on the type of content that I can put
out.
There's some kind of people here becoming debt free.
There's some quotes here that's kind of related to this Naish.
And you can see that even for this type of business there isn't a requirement for you to appear hugely
on camera all the time and be like an Instagram celebrity is beautiful and doing their nails.
There are other possibilities for using Instagram to market a business and that's why I wanted to start
with something a little bit more that you wouldn't think would fit perfectly with Instagram but you
can see here he is America's trusted voice of money huge following getting a huge amount of engagements
on his posts.
So if I wanted to get into this niche then I go ahead and follow him on even from here.
I can go ahead and do the dropdown arrow again and start to find similar accounts there and even it's
going to show me some popular people.
So it's going to take a while for me to go ahead and click through and find those top can that you can
follow.
It'll take you maybe 10 minutes to find five the cance but this short exercise is really going to accelerate
your success on Instagram because you're going to be modeling people who are already successful on the
platform.
And as you can probably guess or know that is just the fastest straight line to success.
So what I would recommend you do is come into this Gurpreet tab of Instagram typing in your keyword
or any top profile on Instagram that you may be already aware of and go in there.
And from that one account you can find for other kinds to follow and then not information and their
their information is start to appear in your news feed.
And so you're going to be constantly updated with whatever posts they pop.
That's going to be in your news.
That's a great way to track those top accounts just by coming into the home section.
So go ahead now and follow five cance on Instagram.
This is the quickest way that you're going to accelerate your success because it'll tell you ahead of
Letcher can't the exact type of content that you should be posting to get engagements as well.