To actually build our Web site we are going to be using a web site builder called WordPress.
And in this video I want to explain briefly why we're going to be using WordPress.
Before we jump in to the actual steps and I also want to explain why we're going to be using WordPress
over other options out there like weeks we believe Squarespace et cetera you might have seen some of
these other Web site builders ad there.
Well I think the most important reason to use Wordpress is because it is the most popular Web site builder
or content management system as it's also known.
So 29 percent of the Web uses WordPress like this is insane from Hobby blogs to biggest sites to the
biggest news sites online.
So you can see some of them here.
Vogue magazine Bloomberg ad Beyonce Jay-Z like a lot of people use Wordpress So it is by far and away
the most popular option.
Now weeks weebly Squarespace even combined all of them are less than 1 percent of the Web sites out
there.
So if you're picking a platform to learn and to understand I think it's much more valuable to learn
WordPress because there is much more demand in terms of businesses and clients for people with wordpress
skills.
And personally I think that's a great reason to learn how to use Wordpress now.
Another great thing about Wordpress is that it's open source software so nobody actually owns WordPress.
It's actually free software and now in order to get our site up with what our own domain we do have
to pay for hosting.
So it's not like it's free to have a branded WordPress site.
But what is interesting and what I like about this open source software aspect is that you can never
just be they can never just raise the prices on you on weeks for example.
You're kind of bought into their whole platform.
If they raise the prices well then you can't really just easily move your site somewhere else on WordPress
if you're hosting company which is who you pay to keep the site up.
If they actually increase the prices well then you can just move to another hosting company.
So I really liked that aspect that it's open source and it gives me a sense of security investing time
building a site that I know that for the long term it's always going to be there on them and they're
never going to increase the prices without me having an option to switch.
So I really like that about WordPress as well.
Now the final thing about Wordpress which I think is a great reason to use it is that they have a massive
team and plug in ecosystem so teams are essentially skins that you put on top of Wordpress and it can
completely change the look and feel of your site.
And there are roughly 10000 WordPress themes out there and that means that you've tenderize in options
to change your site.
For some companies like Wake's they maybe have a couple of hundred.
So there's just much more options for word press.
Similarly they have what's called a plug in ecosystem and this allows you to add additional functionality
to your site.
There's over 50 ties and plugins and these are just little pieces of functionality that you can add
to your site very very easily.
You just install them and essentially you can automatically that function of the inn.
And so it's great to have so many options to this whole in which you wouldn't have would.
Another Web site builder like weeks are we accept etc. they just don't they're just not capable of creating
all of this extra software because all of this extra software is created by independent companies and
that's the beauty of really that open source aspect of wordpress.
So to sum up then why use Wordpress over some other Web site builders.
Well number one twenty nine percent of the Internet use it so your Create your building skills that
are much more valuable in the marketplace to its open source which means you're always protected in
terms of a company shutting down or price changes.
And number three then there is a huge theme and plug in ecosystem which really allows you to change
the look and functionality of your site very very easily.