In this video you're going to learn how to set up event tracking in Google Analytics and the reasons
why you would want to use it.
So event tracking reports appear here underneath the behavior section and the events section here in
google analytics.
And really the benefit of using event tracking is that it allows you to capture user interactions on
your site which Google Analytics does not automatically capture.
So some examples of this to make it really clear are tracking how many people click on a click to call
phone number on your Web site.
So imagine you're a local business you have a phone number at the top.
You really want to track how many people click on that because that is the main purpose of your Web
site to click to get users to click on the Web site so they can make an order from you.
And normally with Google Analytics we cannot track this because when they click on that phone number
it will just open up their phone and they'll die dial straight away.
Now obviously we don't have our Google Analytics installed on their phone so there's no way that we
can really track you know that they went there.
And also at it's not like when they click on that link they go to a thankyou page that we could track
at like we normally do with goals in google analytics.
So that's a very clear example for event tracking and probably the most common use case.
But there probably.
There are plenty of other ones as well such as clicking on an external link to a third party a live
chat application.
Again we can't track this because it's not like they're going to another page on our Web site and obviously
we don't have our Google Analytics installed on this third party tool.
So it's another example clicks on email addresses similarly it's just going to open up in your at you
know e-mail clients video plays.
Again it's not like they're leaving the page.
So we can't really track that interaction.
So that happens on the page same as podcast plays at same for say if they select a color or size we
can't track that normally abandonment of a form fields they don't complete anything.
Movements have even a nice scrolling then the page or clicks to social profiles.
Again these are all examples of things you can't normally track with Google Analytics and that is the
big advantage of event tracking.
So now that you understand the benefits of event tracking and use cases Heidi set it up.
Well the first step is really to copy the tracking code template so to tracking events a snippet of
code is added to the link on the site that you want to track or when the link is clicked.
This interaction is tracked and displayed as events in Google Analytics like we have seen here.
So what we need to do is really give a way for Google Analytics to receive the category of that event.
What type of action it was on maybe a even give a label to it so that when we look at a reports here
we can really understand what type of category event is what type of action it was.
And also the event label like what particular product was a clicked on.
So that is what we want to do.
But the first step is really just copy the link and then this code is really added to the normal length
that we would have on our Web site.
So this is a full example of it all put together here.
So this is an example of a link that you would have on the back of your on the back end of your Web
site.
So this is what it would look in its coded form so we have a link to download a PD.
Now you might be thinking Can't we track downloads of PBS by going to.
Thank you Paige.
Yes we can normally but in this example we're saying that they just click on a link and they download
the PDA straight to their computer.
We don't send them to a tiny CU page where they can download us.
So in this scenario and that's why we would be using event tracking.
So what we have here is the normal length that we'd have for them to download the PDA.
And then we also have this extra information that we're sending an event to Google on and it's saying
they downloaded a PDA F and it was this particular PDA.
And this is the text here that would appear on the Web site as a user reach reads it they just see download
PDA.
They wouldn't see any of this extra information.
So that's the first step.
Copy the tracking code template.
Next step is to replace the template fields.
So we want to replace the category action label and potentially the value fields to describe the user's
interaction with our Web site so that we can really see that once we open up our Google Analytics reports
like this category action and label.
So the category this is required.
This typically is the object or group of objects that was interacted with could be like the video or
the PDA f then the action is the type of interaction could be like play or download or in this example
here could be things like product clicks onto cars removed from cars etc. then then you have label.
So this is useful for summarizing what the event is about.
For example the name of the video or the name of the PDA f or in these examples here it's the name of
the particular product and you have the option to add a numeric value as well associated with the event
that could be a dollar figure if you wanted to track that.
So that step to replace those template fields so you can really send information about the interaction
to Google Analytics as a step number three is to implement the tracking code.
So you need to manually add this link plus all this extra event tracking code to your Web site.
So you'll need to log in to the back end of your Web site and add this code in.
And this is really the full example once again that's what it's going to look like when you code it
in or just copy and paste that.
But this is all that the user will see when they click on your Web site.
So to summarize in this video we've looked at the three steps to setup event tracking the use cases
for us and how to find the reports in google analytics.
So what I'll do is I'll put the template for event tracking in the description is video along with the
example so you can really take that and use it for yourself and track those user interactions in Google
Analytics.