In this video you're going to learn how to read an email sign up form to the sidebar of your web site
and also how to add a pop up form or show you how to do this for free.
And this will really help you in your goal to build up an email list and create a list of potential
people that you can sell your products or services to.
So the first step is to log into your MailChimp Keynes and then click into the list that you want to
create the son of forms for once inside then you want to click on sign up forms and it's in here that
you're going to see a couple of different types of sign of forms to create.
Now for a sign form in the sidebar of your website you can click on in bed of all forms and in sitting
here then that you can change the look and feel of your sign up form.
So for example you can change the title that appears here.
You can also show only the required fields just the e-mail where you can show all the fields you give
them the option to put in the first and last name.
And you can make some other adjustments there if you want.
And then once you're ready you just need to copy and paste this code onto your Web site.
So what we need to do is paste this code onto our Web site so that when somebody signs up on our Web
site the information in their email address will be sent back to MailChimp here and they will be added
to our list.
So can just control a Control-C copy all of that.
Now what I'm going to show you Heidi to do is how to add this to a WordPress Web site.
But essentially the process is going to be quite similar.
And if you need to step by step guide for your type of website builder just look at the support guides
for your web site builder.
So what you need to do is come in to log into the back end of your Wordpress Web site.
So I'll just do this now and then for a WordPress website you come down to appearance and widgets.
Now the layout might be slightly different depending on the team that you have for your Wordpress Web
site but all just walk through the steps here.
They're essentially going to be the same and you want to really add a widget to your side bar.
So a widget is essentially just a little feature and you can do that by adding a custom hate mail.
Then we want to copy that code paste that into the custom paged him mail widget there and click save
and then we can go ahead and do is just go open up our Web site because we want to see if this is actually
working.
And there we go there is our e-mail sign up form in the sidebar of our Web site now.
Now I will say sometimes it can take a couple of minutes for this to show up on your site and sometimes
what you may need to do is actually go ahead and delete your search history.
So tear your cash so that then these changes will be reflected.
So now that we have got the e-mails on a form in the sidebar of our Web site let us go back and look
at another type of e-mail sign up form you can include.
So we're going to come back to our list to start the process again and then we're going to come to sign
up forms and then in here we want to do subscriber pop up.
So we want our pop up you've probably seen them everywhere.
And so we want to put something like this on our site.
We can do that and actually can change the image here and upload that I've actually uploaded this previously
so you can upload an image or something similar to that.
You can again change where this appears on the Web site and it can give you a preview of that.
They'll also give you preview on mobile.
Actually if I was doing this properly I'd adjust that image.
So there's a couple of good things to check before you go ahead and you can adjust the settings.
Like when does this pop up show up.
For the purposes of this demonstration I'm just going to say immediately so that I can show you working
but you can time this after five seconds after 20 seconds.
They scroll to the middle of the page when they leave the page etc..
So you can just all of those things yourself.
And there's a lot of cool things that you can change there the font color spectra.
So now I want to view the code because again we want to put this on our Web site so that any e-mails
collected will be added to our list in Milchan.
So we need to copy this code.
And again we need to put this on our Web site and this will be different depending on the type of web
site you have maybe even the word Berstein you have.
But I'll show you how it's done with my one here.
So what we want to do is come to theme options.
And then I want to click after I come into perience team options come to general settings and it's in
here now that I can actually place in head or code.
This theme is great because it gives me a specific section to do just so I can just paste that in and
then I want to go and click save changes.
Now again we want to come back to our Web site to make sure that it's working.
You might need to make it wait a couple of minutes.
Go ahead and click refresh the page.
Sometimes your blog page or your home page can take quite a long time to reload.
So sometimes easier to come into a some page and you may need to click around a bit and act on that.
Now I've come into a page or blog posts and I can see this popping up immediately so I know that is
working and I can maybe go ahead and just test that I put in my email and what I'm already subscribed
to this list.
But you can see that it will.
You can go ahead and then what you can do is that you can go ahead sign up and what a good thing to
do is come back into your list on MailChimp to make sure that HUD has been signed up.
If you have any problems with any of the code or anything.
Go ahead and check out the support guides on MailChimp.
They are excellent and they have a lot of really walk True's that it will help you.
It's best if you have any problems to really check out the support guides there and they will slow to
support guides for different types of sites etc..
So to recap in this lecture you've learned how to build your email list faster by adding a email sign
a form to the sidebar of your web site and also a pop up form.
So come in to MailChimp get the code and put it on to your Web site.
Following the steps that you've learned in this video.