To start advertising on Facebook the first step to take is to set up your Facebook Advertising can't.
And in this video I'm going to walk you through that step by step and also answer some very common questions
that come up.
So the first thing to do is to log into Facebook Tulkarm on your normal Facebook profile.
So the Facebook profile that you use on a daily basis to connect with your friends and read your news
feed.
Now if you don't have a Facebook profile just go to Facebook dot com.
Follow the prompts and set one up.
It will only take you two minutes once you're inside your Facebook personal profile come across here
to the right hand side and click on the dropdown and then come then click on create ads by clicking
on this button.
You then create your Facebook advertising account and once it loads up watch you will see on screen.
Here is what's known as the ads create tool and the ads create tool is a tool with in your Facebook
advertising account that guides you through the process of creating an ad for now watch you can do is
come down to the bottom left and just click close.
So already you have created your Facebook advertising.
I can't.
But in order for your odds to go live you do need to add some billing information.
So let's set that up now.
Come up to Odd's manager here.
Come on down to all tools and you can come across here to billing and payment methods.
Now at this point I do want to say that Facebook often changes its interface.
So if the buttons aren't in the exact same positions don't worry the steps are going to be the same.
So once you find billing and payment methods you can just click on this I once that loads up is very
simple for you to add in your payment method you just click on the big green button here and you can
out of debit or credit card Paypal online banking Facebook and coupon etc..
Now to reiterate you don't need to set this up right now.
If you want to play around with the advertising and can't even go through the process of creating an
ad but you will need to set this up if you want those ads to go live.
Now before we leave this billing information there is one other thing that's a good idea to do and that
is to set up an account spending limit.
So if you want to control how much you spend and really put a limit on the maximum that you can spend
on Facebook ads you can set up an account spending limit.
This is probably a good idea to do if you're a beginner advertiser and we want that safety net in place.
All I have to do is click on set.
Can't spending limit.
Type in the amount that you want to set the limit as for example 250 and then just simply click to set
that limits.
Now with your advertising can set up your payment details on.
And your current spending limit in place you really everything you need in order to start advertising
on Facebook.
However before we move on I do want to answer a very common question which is can you advertise on Facebook
with a Facebook page.
And the answer is yes.
If you don't have a Facebook page you can still create or not.
However you can only show that out in the right call him or Facebook uses single image as your format
and you use the traffic advertising objective which sends people to your Web site.
So to give you an example of what that looks like you can create an ad on Facebook like this one here
on the right hand column and just an image and it can only bring people to your Web site.
So watch you're missing out on if you don't have a Facebook page that you can put ads in the news feed
here you can to use things like video or lead ads where you can put your ads on Instagram on other platforms.
So even if you are a solo printer and you're trading off of your normal Facebook profile it still is
a great idea to set up a Facebook page so you can use all of these advertising features.
And just to quickly show you how to do it come down to the dropdown here click on create a page and
you can follow the prompts to really set up a page for yourself.
Not only does that give you access to all of those extra advertising features but a Facebook page in
general gives you great access to information about the demographics people interacting with your page.
What are the posts that are really getting a lot of engagement and this information you cannot get on
our personal Facebook profile page or even within a Facebook group setting up a page is really a must.
If you're serious about Facebook Marketing now there is one other scenario where you can advertise on
Facebook without having a Facebook page.
And that is where you are advertising on behalf of an employer or on behalf of a client.
Now in order for them to argue as an augmented their page what they need to do is log into this to call
a business manager.
It's with in the ads manager tool and here they can come down to page roles and really assign you as
a new page to one under advertiser and in this way you can access all of those advertising features.
I really do the advertising on behalf of them.
To recap the steps to setting up your advertising count are very simple.
Just log in to Facebook dot com and come down and click on create ads with your advertising account
to set up what you will need to on some payment information before those ads can go live.
And setting up an account spending limit is a good idea.
If you don't have a Facebook page I would recommend you go and set that up not only to tap into all
those advertising features but also to access all these great analytics that only come with Facebook
pages in the other scenario.
Ask your employer or inclined to argue in the business manager too.
You can really get set up to start advertising on behalf of them.
So we'll finish up there and I'll see you in the next video.