In this video you're going to learn about camera science a new format that is very flexible and customizable.
We'll start by understanding what a homicide is and the benefits of it.
Then you will learn for which are the objectives.
This format is available once again.
It's not really suitable or available for every type of Facebook campaign.
We will then look at a case study so you can understand how this new ad format fits in to a wider Facebook
ad campaign.
We will then look at how you can create these campuses and because it's a little bit different than
just uploading a video or an image.
And then finally we'll finish up once again in the hands create tools we know how to set up a campaign
using this format.
So let's start really by understanding what these canvas ads are as the name suggests.
It just gives you a blank canvas in order to create your ad.
And let's scroll down and straight away to really have a look at an example 10 years of we come there
a little bit further we can start to get an idea of it here and I'll just play this video.
So what you can see here is that this company that company has started to build the collection.
It looks a little bit like snapchat if you're familiar with how Snapchat works.
You can scroll down and you can scroll across there's videos involved.
It's quite an immersive type of advertisement very flexible.
And the idea is that you can completely customize this for yourself.
You can see now it's coming down into products.
There's a binary button you can customize all of that stuff yourself.
So it's just a very flexible format.
Which can ultimately end up on the e-commerce site like we see here but Stefani's is looking a little
bit like snapchat.
So I think anybody who's very familiar with slop snapshot creating content there to create a commerce
side is going to be very simple for you for people like me a little bit older who aren't as good on
snapchat or don't even use it.
This is going to be a bit of a more a bit of more of a learning curve to get this right but that's essentially
what it looks like.
It's a very flexible format.
Now coming up to the Facebook Ads guide let's understand what objectives you can use this format for
because once again it's not available for everyone.
It's not suitable for everything right now.
Right now in the Facebook gods guide where we can see it is available is for brand awareness so you
can see here that the ecommerce site is available for app installs.
It's not.
But this might change over time.
So the best place to keep Come and see this is in the ads guide it surveiled for brand awareness.
It's available for clicks through web site.
You can see it here not available for any of these here store visits.
Let's see if it's available here.
Yes.
And we can see for video views.
I think it is available yet and also web site conversions.
So if you are thinking of using this odd format.
Be sure to come into the ads guide first.
Just type in Facebook Ads guide into Google and really check if it is a vailable.
Now let's have a look at a case study to see how companies are actually using this form and how it fits
in to a bigger campaign.
So what we have here is Dykeman Poland what they do is they run a family run footwear business and they
use this new ad format to create a highly successful brand awareness campaign.
So that was the objective for the campaign.
So here is some some of the metrics and that you would associate with a brand awareness campaign.
Twenty five point increase in AD recall.
So there are some metrics and tests that they do around for brand awareness seven point increase in
favor ability and three point increase in attribute rate things overall metrics really for brand awareness.
And you may not be totally familiar with them but the bottom line is it was a big success.
So I think let's look down at some of the details to really see how they used this.
So what they did was they featured this girl here who's a famous singer and fashion blogger in Poland
and she picked different shoes from a new range.
That would be suitable to show in this canvas.
Now here's the interesting part that they use the camera side really as a part of the bigger campaign.
They still use photo photo carousel video ads along with this new canvas format which really allowed
people to explore engage engage with the full range.
So again it's a little bit like the collection ads that we've seen previously.
It's a bit more about storytelling and engagement and definitely drifting towards the new way that people
are interacting with social media like Snapchat et cetera.
So the key takeaway here is that it was part of a bigger campaign.
And but it does involve all of these other elements as well and it's a little bit similar to the election
campaign.
Now where can you get started with this.
Well the first thing that you can do is come into your Facebook page you're going to see here and the
final town here publishing tools any admin to Facebook page will be able to see this and you can see
down here that there is canvas here and you can click on Create.
So instead of diving into the ads created it's probably best to start here to create your canvas.
And then in your ads pray tool just select this so you can see that you can take it toward to understand
this better.
You can just open a blank canvas.
There is only two examples but there's not many there yet.
Let's have an explore of some of the layouts here.
So single street screen put together a camera that complements the message and storytelling and full
screen media.
So let's have a look at this one here.
This they'll start to load up hopefully and you can use it to really use the guide.
Maybe let's just start with an open come see you can see you can put in a button carousel photo products
that once your product catalog is uploaded and video.
So let's just put in a video and see you can continue to add components as people scroll then scroll
left scroll right etc..
So I won't go through all the details of setting it up but once you have got a canvas created all you
need to do in your and create two is select the appropriate objective.
So for example it's just like a traffic campaign objective.
Once again the ads said is Ozzie learned how to set up already the audience Plaisance budget and schedule.
We've covered that before where there is a difference.
Now as Dan at the ad level and you can see the commerce ad format showing up what you can do then is
select the canvas so that's why I was recommending you build on first hand side of the ads too.
And then you can combine unselected here it brings you up to the same screen but it's maybe just easier
to keep focused on one thing build the creative first and then he can just simply and in from there.
So now that you understand what homicides are the marketing objectives that you can use them for and
understand how they're so flexible and customizable come into the publishing tools.
Your Facebook page and mess around with creating one for yourself to get more familiar with this new
format.