In this video you're going learn about business manager what it is why you would need to use it and
how to get set up.
So what is business manager.
Well it's a free tool from Facebook that really allows you to stay organized and have good business
hygiene.
It allows you to manage Arcanes pages and people who work in them all in one place and it's completely
free as well.
So who would need to use business manager.
Well let's start by defining who wouldn't need to use business manager.
So if you are a Facebook page owner you're the only person working on that page and you're also the
only person running ads in the attic and attached to that page.
You're probably not going to need to use business manager.
All you need to really do is understand what it is.
Now if you want to become a freelancer or you want to hire freelancers to work on your Facebook ads
or you have employees working on various Facebook pages in a case where you're going to be working in
an agency with their business manager is going to be a tool that you will use on a daily basis.
So it's important you're really familiar with this.
So why would you need a business manager.
Let's look at some of the more detailed scenarios here.
So you need more than one account.
If you want to create separate accounts for every client or business that you serve it allows you in
business manager to do that and you can pay for ads with different payment methods and organized by
objective for reporting.
You also need business manager if you want to request access to pages or accounts and you want to do
that if you've clients.
So you can get access to their pages and that accounts and run ads on behalf of them by becoming an
analyst or advertiser.
You'll also need a business manager to assign permissions to a lot of people working together so you
can assign specific role based permissions to otic hands pages and other assets that your business manager.
So you might have people working on your team.
You want them only to be an analyst and analyst analyze reports it could be another person on your team
who is an actual advertiser and sets up campaigns and run them and has some control over the ad spend.
So Inside Business Manager you can really assign all of those rules and permissions.
And finally a business manager will give you a business novel insights and reporting he can get a full
view over 200 different pages and that accounts out one.
Now if we come down here we can see a couple of images giving us an overview of a business manager a
kind and this one is good to look at because it's full.
Right now you can see there's a ton of applicants down here at the bottom.
So a little bit blurry.
I know but this is just to give you an idea.
You can see all of the pages added into this business plunger kind of the top ones some alerts and things
to look for.
You can see the rows and permissions being organized here are going to show you had to do that ton of
employees all different responsibilities.
And finally here we can see some of the audiences created in those can be managed there as well.
So how do you get started.
How do you create your business manager.
I can't.
Well the first thing that you want to do is make sure that you're logged into your Facebook page.
Once you've done that this is your personal profile.
Then you just need to click on Create it can't.
And this is where you give your business name.
So if you are say a freelancer just working for yourself and you want to take on clients you can just
put it in your own name here or your personal name if you've come up with a name for that digital agency
you can pop in the name there or if you were a business like a normal business cycle like dot.com you
would just put in like there and click continue and really follow the steps.
Now once inside what you're going to see is something similar to this.
It might be empty if there's no pages or otic hence added in yet.
And that's the next step that you want to take.
Once you've created your business mind your account you want to start to add in any of those pages that
you're going to be working on any of those out I can say you'll be working on and any of the apps that
you might want to be working on as well as show you how to do that.
Now what you want to do is come up to the right hand side here and click on business settings now this
is where we can add rules and permissions and all that stuff.
I'll show you how to do that.
But for now you just want to start by adding in any Facebook pages that you have.
So once in here you can see I've just got one business page in this business find your account right
now.
I can come up to the right hand side here and add anymore.
So there's really two main options here.
One is clean the page so if your business already owns a page you can just claim this or if you need
to own it.
For example if another company created it for you you can claim the page and it moves into your business
manager can't as well as this.
You can also request access to a page.
So if you wanted to work on behalf of somebody whose Facebook page run ads for them you would request
access to it so you could really run ads on behalf of the client.
The page will still belong to them.
You just get access to it.
So these are the two different scenarios you can see people who own a business use business manager
people who want to work for the business and do freelancing and agency work for them.
Also used business manager it's the midpoint between those two and really allies and people get access
without handing over full permission.
So that's the first thing that you would want to do inside business manager claim the page or request
access to a page.
You can also create a brand new page in here as well now as well as adding a page in what you also may
want to do is add any apps into business managers so similar to the other options.
If you own up and want to start advertising it you can add it in here if you want to start advertising
on behalf of other apps.
You would add them in here.
It's the same process again really add new OPS Clayman up.
Your business will control the source that it moves it into a business manager or request access to
an app and that really allows you to use this asset on behalf of another business.
Now one thing is if you want to use the apps on moving into biz Niger you need to really have the app
I.D. and you get that by the by really registering and configuring an app on Facebook for developers.
So that's a first thing that you need to do if you haven't done that already and then you can move it
into business manager.
The key thing about a business manager is even if you have created a Facebook page through your own
personal profile when you move it to business manager it's almost like creating a business entity like
a company.
It's not directly connected to you.
Like as if you were a sole trader it's putting it up into a separate entity and that allows people to
access it like employees or external people.
So that's the key benefit of it.
Now the great thing is is that you can always come back to your business manager any time is well inside
of your odds manager.
You can just click on the dropdown and you can also come up here and click on business manager here
and you'll be brought to the screen.
I remember that all of the activity is here under business settings and you might even want to bookmark
that page so you can access that easily in the future.
Now you understand what business manager is why you would need to use it.
Go ahead and create an account for yourself if you need to use it.
Following the steps that you've learned in this lecture.