In the last lecture we got your YouTube account set up.
And in this lecture no you are going to find the keywords the really topics that you're going to create
your YouTube video around.
We're going to achieve that by doing YouTube keyword research and I can show you three different tools
to really find that out.
So firstly to explain a little bit more what really keywords are it's what really people type into the
search bar here to find solutions to the problems that they have.
So remember that our strategy here ready for YouTube is to focus on search ability and discover ability
on the first part of that is doing our keyword research.
So we really want to create content around what people are already searching for not as a way for us
to be able to get found to increase our viewers watch time build up our audience and then get those
people back to our Web site.
So people come into YouTube they use it like a search engine just like they use Google.
So coming back down to our keyword research the first tool that we can use is Google's autocomplete
feature.
Now we can use this in private browsing mode and I'll show you that.
Let's just start within YouTube as well.
And as I said we want to focus on simple how to videos so you can just to get started something like
how to.
And you can see here some of the suggestions that YouTube comes up with.
So how to write a blog post hundreds keyword research.
Now I've already search for these.
That's why they're coming up.
You can go how to increase how to increase speed.
Each views.
You can see some of the things that people are typing into YouTube here.
How to stop biting your nails procrastinating.
You can see these is some of the things people searching for had to grow.
You can see that there's some of the suggestions there as well.
So that is one way that you can really come in to find things that people are searching for.
You can also as well you don't have to start with how to.
You could start with something like as CEO the topic.
So as CEO tutorial as CEO for beginners you can type in standing like Google Analytics tutorial certification.
Now you can see that these ones coming up the top are suggested because I've already searched for them
and that's why I'd maybe recommend you open up an incognito tab in come back into YouTube and this won't
take into account your historical searches into what it really suggests.
So if we look at Google Analytics I can see Google on its tutorial 2016 reports exam WordPress I can
search for something like WordPress tutorial Web site from scratch etc. So these are the things that
you can really do to get a lot of ideas very very quickly.
Google or YouTube is suggesting here what other people are searching for.
So you can really do the same thing and as well as looking for words that come after you can actually
put a space the frontier.
Sometimes it shows you where some people would put beforehand.
Let me see if this comes up.
Not in this case but sometimes that does work as well.
So when I say that our strategy is really to make how to videos.
It's not just for the word how to I mean it's more training education videos and so could be something
like a c c or tutorial which is the one that I have done before.
And you can see here that SVOD tutorial for beginners step by step.
I didn't come up with that side of myself.
If I go as CEO for beginners and then as CEO for beginners I can see step by step guide here.
So this is what people are really searching for I came up with that title simply by using Google Audio
suggests and you can see that thought it has led to huge amounts of views for me.
And I just added in the 2016 then because I saw that people were searching for 2016 as well.
So including all of these things that people are really searching for was how I really came up with
that idea.
Now returning to are returning to our keyword research process there see YouTube autocomplete is the
first thing that I recommend you do using the browsing mode it's gonna give you a more accurate view
because your search history one skew the suggestions.
Now what you can do after that is once you find something interesting like I have here what you can
use is the keyword everywhere chrome extension.
Now this is within Google and I've set this up earlier in the horse as well.
But you just type in say your keyword as CEO tutorial.
And now because the Google keyword everywhere chrome extension is installed I can see these search volume
and the cost per click for this keyword.
So firstly you just need to get this set up it's very easy to install.
You can still add on Chrome or Firefox on really the main benefit of it then is it shows you these search
volume here right underneath the search bar the search box which is really really handy.
So not only do I know that a keyword like SEO tutorial is something interesting I also see that it's
called great search volume on Google.
Now these are the figures for Google.
But if people searching for it on Google then there's a very good chance that they're searching for
it within YouTube as well.
And even if I take that auto suggestion and look for a title that's a little bit longer I can add that
in and test as well.
So so SEO tutorial for beginners.
Now I can see that that still gets for one hundred and eighty searches per month.
So not only would I be in a position to maybe rank for as tutorial I'd also pick up searches for people
to type in SCA tutorial for beginners and even if we extend out to 2016
but it doesn't get any specific searches.
But I bet as it's thought it was except 2016 probably will doesn't show up here.
But a lot of people do search for those to get up up to date views.
So that is the step once you find maybe some suggestions in YouTube using the autocomplete feature.
What you want to do is actually come in here and check these search volume for those keywords.
Is that actually a popular keyword.
And you can really test all of the variations on the length of those keyword phrases using the keyword
everywhere tool.
Now just to explain cost per click before if you've never heard of this before it's really this is how
much advertisers within Google are paying to advertise for this particular term.
So if advertiser sizes are playing two dollars and seven cents per click for this term well then you
know it's quite a valuable term and that somebody who maybe is searching for us editorial might be inclined
to maybe buy my course on SEO which is essentially what I want them to do.
OK.
Now as well as using the autocomplete using keyword everywhere you can use the google keyword planner
tool.
This is once again a free tool that you can use.
You can just type in the google keyword honor.
It's very easy to set up an account.
It's actually the google keyword planner is a tool within Google AdWords so you just need to sign into
AdWords.
They might try and get you to create ad campaign.
You might hit that as soon as you open up this you can actually skip that process there's like a button
down the bottom here saying skip that campaign what you want to do is really come into tools and keyword
planner here.
And it's similar to the order suggest in youtube and in google it just kind of give you a lot more information
so you can come in to search for new keywords you can put in something like a topic like this and you
can click on get ideas then you will see these search volume here some of the keywords that people are
searching for.
And again this is just more ideas that you can really have to create videos topics you can see the popularity
of the mall going back a step actually you can see that I've got this targeted to the US much you're
going to remove that.
I want to see the search volume for these particular terms globally because the product or service that
I'm offering is can really be used by any media globally.
But if you've a local business or you're only serving a particular country you might want to change
those targeting options.
So this is really giving me more ideas more keyword ideas and you can see that there's a huge list here.
There's probably over eight hundreds here.
And it's not just related to the term you can see that there's other terms there they're closely related.
So that is how you can do keyword research.
Probably the simplest method is the order complete and you can just keep using the title as it gets
longer and longer just like I've done here to pick up those additional searches not just for the very
short first keyword like ICAO or even as historical.
I'll be picking up searches for all of these terms.
So go ahead and do that.
Use these three tools and then we'll see you in the next lecture once you've picked that topic to really
get started on your video structure.
I what I would recommend is don't agonize over this decision.
Just pick something.
And by going through the process you're going to really learn a lot more.
You probably won't have big success on your first video but all you want to do is find something go
through the process you're going to learn so much more if you do.
So I really encourage you to do that.
And then in the next lecture will really get to how to structure your video so you can really increase
that watch shine.
I'll see there.