A key part of setting up your Pinterest profile is to claim your Web site.
And by doing this you're going to get a back link to your Web site.
You're also going to appear higher in the Pinterest search results and you also get access to these
handy features and you're also going to see your Web site on your Pinterest account.
So what you want to do is come into your settings come down to claim Web sites and they now you just
want to type in your domain name here.
And then you can click on the submit button.
Once you do that you're going to see two options here in order to verify or claim your Web site.
And essentially what is happening here is you want to put a small piece of code on your Web site that
sends a signal back to Pinterest and then Pinterest knows.
OK well if they have access to the back end of the site and they've added this code well then they must
have ownership over the size and then they can verify that.
So there are two options here.
And if you're not at all technical what I would suggest you do is you can come to help Pinterest dot
com type bin and search for confirm your site and then you're going to see a little bit of a better
explanation of these two options here.
And also you can get instructions for a popular hosts so that could be for blue host Go Daddy.
It could be for web site builders like Shopify weebly Wake's etc. and even WordPress.
So what I'm going to show you had to do is how I verify this for my size.
I pick the ad hatred the mail time option.
And so what I need to do is copy this then come into the back end of my site.
I have a WordPress site.
And so I'm coming then to theme options.
And then to appearance theme options general settings and in my team here I have an option to put in
Hetter code and I just add that in there and paste that in.
I just did that again paste that in quick save changes.
Now as I said even if you have a WordPress site the layout might be slightly different depending on
the theme that you have.
So it's best to really look at the support guides either on Pinterest or for your web site builder so
you can get the exact step by step.
Now once you've got that done you just want to click next.
And then what Pinterest are going to do is they're going to really check that you on that site and they'll
let you know by email in the next 24 hours.
Now if we come to our profile page we can also see that our Web site has been added to the top of our
bio.
So this is really great because it'll help people to click through them and we can get more Web site
traffic.
So that is how you claim and verify ownership of your site.
Not only does it help you rank higher in the Pinterest search engine it also gives you access to a bunch
of additional tools and of course you get the link to your Web site at the top of your profile.