In this video you're going to learn how to select your campaign type.
And this is the first step to set up a campaign outwards.
So what you want to do is go ahead and log into your outwards accounts come command to the campaigns
tab quickly.
Plus button and click new campaign.
Now as I said this is the first decision I'll make.
And you can see that there are five different campaign types.
So I just want to run quickly through each of these at a high level so you have an understanding of
them and then we'll select the ones who we can really go through our example campaign.
So firstly we've got our search network and this really allows you to reach customers interested in
your products or services with text as you're probably already very familiar with seeing this.
These are the ads that appear at the top of the search results.
They're just text ads and pretty simple.
Now next up you've got the display network and this allows you to run different kinds of ads across
the web.
So this is really a key part of Google's advertising platform that not only can you appear underneath
to search results but they've also partnered up with a ton of sites so that you can advertise on those
sites as well.
So here's an example of one of those partners sites that is allowing Google to put ads on their Web
site.
It's called W3 schools and you can see here is an ad from Google on their Web site.
Now today they put this.
They allow Google to put this side here because they get a cut of the ad revenue.
And you can see that this format of this ad is a banner ad which is obviously different than to the
text that's just here.
Now if we click this open you can see that you can advertise your business all over the web but add
words an earn revenue from your web site with ads sense.
So you may have heard of ads sense before and this site would have got set up with ads and so that they
can earn revenue from Google advertising platform in terms of for you.
What is the benefit of this.
Well you can really put different types of ad and not only put them on the search results but also in
sites that maybe your customers spend a lot of time on.
Now coming back to our campaign types we've also got shopping ads promote your products with shopping
ads.
So if we look at this you can see the format of these ads are quite different to just plain text.
You have got the pictures here.
And this really goes right down into the private pages.
We've also got video ads.
And primarily this will be ads that you can put on YouTube.
It's all done within the same words platform and campaign set up process.
So for example here's an example of one of those ads on YouTube that just is on top of the video before
it starts.
So you T-bonds can be set up in here as well.
And then we've also got up and saw.
So these are these ads will for the most part appear in other people's apps which is they've got a similar
process where they have a partner apps where they advertise in kind of similarly to how they do it with
their web sites and the display network.
Now for this example we're just going to pick the search network it's probably the simplest one to get
started on.
And you can see that there's options to drive sales leads and Web site traffic.
And we're just going to click web site traffic that we want to put in our business web site so I just
put it on the Web sites and click continue.
Now the cool thing is is that you can go through this process with them just to experiment yourself.
You can go right to the end of the process and you won't need to put your credit card on until you actually
want the ad to go live.
So even if you're not sure if you want to advertise just yet or exactly how it would work I would just
encourage you to come in and set this campaign up so you can really give it a go.
Now we can just put this as test campaign what we can do is we can just select it so appears only on
the search network and not also on the display network.
So we want to really keep this as a search only campaign.
And for now we'll just leave it at that.
But that is the first step to really set up your outwards campaign to select your campaign type.