In this video you're going to learn how to use Twitter and in particular I'll show you the five different
types of ways you can communicate on Twitter.
General treats mentions replies read tweets and DMD's I show you an example of each of those and explain
the difference of where those different types of ways to communicate on Twitter appear.
So one thing that can be very helpful to understand these differences and especially if you're new to
Twitter for any question is to click on your profile here and you'll see the option to open up the Twitter
help center.
So if you open this up in a new link you there's really a ton of information here.
If you ever get stuck or of questions I'd recommend you come in and check the size.
And for this video there is a great article about different types of tweets
which really is very helpful to understand these different types of tweets so let's read through this
and then I'll give you an example of each.
So the general tweets a message posted to Twitter containing text photos or video.
Where does it appear.
It appears on the sender's profile page on Home Time Line and who sees it.
It appears in the home timeline of anybody who's following the sender.
So let us come into the profile give you an example of this.
You should see the option here to write your own tweet or at the top right hand corner.
So I'm just going to say hello world.
Now Twitter.
There used to be a limit of 140 characters.
Now that's been increased to 280.
So just be aware for these general tweets that is the limit.
And if you want to send that then you just click tweet.
So this will appear on my profile page.
And it's also going to appear in the home timeline of anybody who's following me.
Right now.
No followers.
But if we look at the timeline it essentially would be it would appear here for anybody who's following
me in their time line so they could see that.
So that is the first type of tweet on the first of the five things that we're going to look at.
And second we have mentions so a tweet containing another Twitter account preceded by the symbol is
a mention.
So for example if we take this we can go back to our account we can click tweet here at the top.
We can click Healthwatch supports we are mentioning an account and we're using their to their Twitter
profile or handle names so we can click a tweet and then we can refresh the page and we can see this
mentioned here.
So where does it appear it appears on our profile page.
Like we can see here.
And then also for the recipient it appears in their notifications Taieb which is accessible by them.
So if I was Twitter support come into my notifications tab and under mentions I could see anybody who's
mentioned me right now nobody's mentioned me on this account so nothing is showing up.
So who else might see this.
Well anybody on Twitter who's following the sender of the mentioned that's me will see it as a tweet
in their home timeline and places that will never appear on anybody's profile page unless they wrote
the message.
So simply it's going to appear on my profile page.
And also it's going to appear in the timeline of anybody who's following me and the recipient is going
to get that notification as well.
This is a great way to get the attention of different Twitter accounts and start to connect with them.
We'll be talking more about mansions but it is a fantastic future replies.
It's the third of the five types of communication we're going to look at.
So we're apply is when we respond to another person's tweets where it appears for the sender it appears
on our profile page where does it appear for the recipient.
It's in their notifications tab as well like mentions replies will also appear in the recipient's home
time line if they are following the sender.
So if they're following us they're going to see it in their home timeline and also in their notifications.
So let's have a look at this.
If I come in to my timeline we can see a tweet from somebody that we are following.
We can at really reply.
So we can say
Great article and hit reply.
So once again this is going to appear in our tweets and replies here on our profile page so you can
see there.
And it's also going to appear in the timeline of anybody who's following us.
So let's move on now.
We've also got tweets and what we could do is we can see a tweet from somebody that we think is great.
If we read tweet this
where does this appear while it appears on our profile page and it's going to appear in the timeline
of anybody who follows us.
So there's actually a separate article on this.
Read tweets and a retweet is really a reposting of a tweet.
And the use cases is that it helps you and others quickly share treat with all of your followers.
So that's essentially what it is.
Where do they appear.
You can see tweets by people who follow in your timeline.
And you also see it in your notifications.
So Charlie here will see in the notification that not only if I commented but also that I've retweeted
his article.
Find a way to communicate on Twitter is with direct messages.
And once again you could just type this in the Twitter help center to find out a little bit more about
this or get a refresher on us.
Go might have to twice like that.
So really direct messages are the private side of Twitter.
That's a great explanation for it.
And you can use direct messages to private conversations with people about tweets or other content.
So direct messages are the most private way to communicate on Twitter.
They won't be seen by either your followers or their followers.
So let's have a look at sending one of these.
We'll have a look in here and charities that can't.
Usually you'll see the option to direct message somebody right underneath their bio here and it seems
like Charlie has disable this.
So let's just have an look for another example here.
You can see that underneath their bio that they have that option to message.
And then you can send somebody a direct message here and it's only going to be at the recipient who's
really going to see that.
And that the private conversation between the two of you and this can be great if you want to reach
out to people and discuss something more private.
Or you can move on to an e-mail or something like that.
So it is another way to communicate on Twitter.
Some people will have enabled some people not.
Sometimes you need to follow the person before you can have a DMM or direct message them.
So recapping in this video what you learn to do is to send General tweets mentions replies read tweets
and direct messages.
Those are the five different ways that you can communicate with influencers potential customers or existing
customers on Twitter.
And remember if you do need refresher on any of those you can come into the tour help center and really
have a look at the guides there just to refresh your knowledge.