In this video you are going to learn how to answer a question on curagh seeking at maximum Chicks back
to your Web site and also answer it so you can stand out from competing answers and be the top answer
for the question so that you can really get a hold of views for the question.
OK.
So I'm going to walk you through just how to answer a question the process that I use and the first
thing to do is really to edit your credential.
So as you can see right now says Zama certified Google marketer etc. but this doesn't really relate
specifically to the question that I'm answering.
And so what gives me the opportunity to do is just edit my credential and make it more relevant to the
question that I Mansouri than the reason that I would want to do this is because if we scanned and here
at some of the other competing answers I can see digital marketing experience marketing content copywriter.
So nobody here is really saying that they're like Facebook card's expiration and an easy way that I
can stand and then is just to change my credential I can get a credential for this topic Facebook ads.
So mean this in
and every time that I answer a question about Facebook gods it'll show against plants or that I'm a
the cots expert.
So I can say that now that I can see that's come up and just click out of this and you can see it's
changed to Facebook Ads X..
So if somebody is scanning that and through the answers here they see right next to my name I'm an expert.
Well then automatically I have an advantage over the other writers here because I seem like I'm more
of an authority on the topics.
That's a simple trick just to get ahead of the competition without even answering your question.
Now in terms of how do you stand that once you write your answer will I think you really need to essentially
write a headline that's going to grab people's attention.
So the question is how effective is the new Facebook the ads.
And so I really wanted to write something that's going to grab the attention of somebody who has that
same question in their mind.
So what I'd like to do is write a headline something like lead outs are a huge deal.
So that is going to pull them into start reading my question.
Now the next thing that I like to do for all of my questions is to after my headline in a relevant image
so I'm going to upload an image from my desktop here that relates to the question.
So this is a visual of what the leader on Facebook looks like.
So you can see there's three basic steps to it.
So already I've got a headline that stands out then an image that relates to the question and if I scanned
and three other answers here none of these people have images where they don't have any headline that's
grabbing my attention so I think already after changing my credential headline or an image I'm ahead
of everybody here.
And that's really what you want to be thinking about not just answering questions but answering questions
better than anybody else.
Now after that you want to maybe give a quick summary so that you know you're a huge deal and give a
little bit of an explanation of why they're a big deal.
So I got in an Art Shell and I want to leave that unbolted lead on to reduce the sign a process to just
two clicks without ever leaving Facebook's.
That's a little bit of an explanation of the image here.
And then you can go on to give a little bit more detail so obviously I've got this prepared before this
can take you a little bit of time and just on both this thankfully they give you a little spell checker
there.
So I'm saying this is a huge deal for mobile users that no longer have to wait for a new page to load
and Trojan through external web sites.
I'm saying what are the advantages of these ads are backing up really the headline here that I've said
the ads are a huge deal why are they a huge deal.
And I go on to explain it that it really makes it easy for people to sign up and submit their information
to your business.
And also the Facebook pre-populated sign up form and there's no pain for people to fill that at.
Maybe give some information to back up or statistics to back up the answer that you're giving.
So here we go.
I'm backing it up now I'm saying this development has led to amazing results for businesses.
I've seen businesses generate 60 percent more leads then they expect to go at 37 percent lower cost
per lead.
So I've not only said how it's different from one of the benefits of it but also some of the results
that are being driven the business and it's always good to include a link to a resource in your answers.
I've said here that the best part is that the leads gathered from the Dadds always good to check the
spelling coming directly out of here database VSC or am sinking.
So this is just some information linking off to Facebook about how to actually integrate delete ads
with your CRM system.
So again essentially just a backing up why am I saying they're so good.
And once I've given the answer this is the key part.
So by being helpful in my answer and now I want to really get them back to my Web site.
So what I've said here is you know if you want to learn more about it it's how to set up lead in other
types of face the kinds of documented everything here.
And then I think back to my product where I have a full explanation on how to do Facebook cards etc.
so we can see that I've just included a link there to my site and you can do that easily.
You can hide in the link like that and then you just want to click submit and maybe have a quick read
through it.
Maybe we could see a bit of a block of text here.
Maybe we could
help some things stand there.
Pre-populated to sign up for and maybe it is just two clicks.
So it's good to
unbolt this part.
To both some of the text in there to really help people look at the key points in there and that will
help you start a note from the competitors who just have a block of text.
So now I'm going to submit my answer.
I now have the option to share this on Facebook or Twitter which can be great too if you are following
there.
For now I'll just skip it and then we can come back and look at the question here.
And right now I'm just already automatically in the in the first second third fourth position.
But as more people begin to see this question and even if I go ahead and share that out on social networks
then I'm going to start to get views on this.
When people are going to start to opt for this question so I can move towards the top.
But as you can see I think it definitely does stand out a lot better than the other questions there
that you know how to answer questions on your own and structure them to get the most visibility and
click through.
Go ahead and answer a question for yourself.