In this video you're going to learn how to add a channel icon and also how to add a description to your
YouTube channel and add links to your other social media profiles.
So to get started you want to just click on customized channel after you've created your channel and
then you have the option here to add your channel icon so add on can just click on the Edit button and
click on edits and then you really want to upload your channel icon.
Now for this example all this upload a picture of myself here.
But really you want this picture to be something that is either a closeup of your face if it's a personal
channel or the logo for your company and you want to keep this as simple as possible because this will
be shrunk down and appear underneath your videos.
So you really want to keep it simple and use the same logo that you might be using on other social media
platforms as well.
So once you have created your icon and I did that in and you want to come back and start to add a channel
description now it may take five or 10 minutes to actually get that icon to show up.
So don't worry if it doesn't show up straightaway.
It just takes a little bit of time to come through.
And then let us have a look at the really about page.
This is where we really want to add in some information about the company or your own channel so you
can see the first option here is challenge description sort of click this open you really want to write
a little bit about your business here on what you're all about.
Now I know this can be hard to do especially if you're just starting out.
So one of the best things that you can do is just come in to YouTube and have a look at the description
of similar businesses to you.
So let's have a look at this.
Look see here compering.
And if we come across to their bite page we can see their description here.
So obviously they mentioned what they're about we love hair and so they create tutorials kind of describing
what their channel is about and at kind of describe what all the videos are better.
It's not just the company but also water the videos really abide and make it clear in the first couple
of words they've done here.
What is the key word that could be Instagram if you're teaching Instagram could be digital marketing
could be law Cobi whatever real estate.
So really get get make it clear what you're all about.
Right from the start and then like they done here this is a good idea if you want to promote some of
their social channels you can do that.
So the best thing to do is really have a look at a couple of similar similar channels.
And if you don't know who those channels are just start to type in some of your key words into YouTube
and you're going to find their videos pretty quickly.
And then you can click through to the About section.
So after you've heard your description you have some other details to fill here.
You cannot in an e-mail so people can contact you directly through YouTube for business inquiries.
You can go ahead and select your country there so just change this to Ireland.
And then here you can also add in links to your different social media profiles or web sites or if you
click and you can really just paste the URL if you want.
So for example
and if I click add here I actually do need to specify a name.
You can just say Web site and you can see this shows of his web site and actually underneath here the
channel arch it shows up as well.
So if we look at our example we can see they get luxury hair extensions that's actually a smart thing
to do to show people exactly what to do and what they can get by clicking here.
And then you can also see that they have links to their other social media profiles as well which they've
put in here.
So now that you know Heidi you are a channel icon and a description email and links to social media
profiles.
Go ahead and do that for yourself and use existing channels as inspiration and to help you speed up
this process.