In this video I'm going to give you a quick tips so you can easily pin content from around the Internet
in just one click.
So before I show you how to do this I just want to remind you what the normal process is.
So you can pin content to your voice from.
From Pinterest itself and the search engine here or you can also go and pin stuff from around the web.
And if you want to do that you click this option from around the web.
You have to say get the your L of the article you want a pin or image you want to pin paste that in
and then you select the image here that you want to pin and appears and then you add it to the board
so you can see the lobe bit of a manual process.
You have to copy and paste that you were all in in the first place.
So to speed up the process a great tool to use that's absolutely free.
Is this Pinterest browser button from Chrome.
Now this does only work on the Google Chrome browser.
So if you don't have Google Chrome you can just download that for free.
Just type in download Google Chrome to any browser and then use one click get browser button and you
can just type this interview goes well I will put this link in the description in the video so you can
click right through.
Then you just want to click add extension and now I'll show you really how this speeds up the process.
So say you're browsing online you're catching up with some news from your industry and now you can really
have this browser extension button here.
And so if you're reading an article like this just as you do for your own personal you know keep yourself
updated and you might think on that would be great if I just added that into my Pinterest to can't.
And so my followers can benefit from it as well.
So what you do is then click the icon that might need to reload the page here.
And then we can select the image so we don't need to type in your l manually.
And then we can just select the board that we want to add it to and then we can go ahead and see it
now.
So you can see it's a lot less friction to add stuff to your Pinterest account.
And I think the key thing is while the key benefit is that just as you're reading articles or news and
you want to add them to a board it's very easier to do rather than remembering to go into your Pinterest
account open it up picked up or not pin paste you are Ellen.
So it just makes it a lot easier to add content quickly to your Pinterest account.
Now here's another tip that really takes this tool to the next level and that is to get your team mates
or even freelancers to install this tool as well for you.
And what you can do then is when you've created a board you can add them as a collaborator.
Just type in their email there send them the invite tell them to download this extension as well and
then they can just start pinning content as well automatically to there to that account.
So not only does it make it easier for you to add content but if you just tell your teammates or even
instruct a freelancer to do this for you they can very quickly add a lot of content to your Pinterest
account and that will help you really grow your falling much much faster.
So that is how you pin content to Pinterest in just one click.
You can go ahead and get the browser extension and chrome.
I'll also put the link in the description.