Hey welcome back.
So I've covered a lot in this section.
It's time to put it to use so we have an exercise here that's a bit larger than what we've done so far.
It asks you to define two separate classes card and deck these two classes can form the backbone of
any card race game you want or to code up poker blackjack or any of the other card games you would need
a card and deck class or it would at least help.
So the specifications are laid out here.
I want to go over some of them.
So if you just want to dive into this you can read this lecture.
I think by the time I publish these numbers will be different.
But if you just look after this video there should there's an exercise you can read the instructions
there.
Keep that open.
Try it on your own.
I recommend doing it on your computer in a sublime file or text editor file and then using the tests
that I've written to check your work rather than writing everything in you to me browser tools because
it actually won't show you results it only shows you the test results.
So I recommend doing it on your own on your computer until you feel like you've got it and it's working
and you've tested everything.
Copy and paste it into the browser then check if you got it right.
OK.
Also I'm going to have a complete walkthrough after this.
So if you do just want to build it with me that's another option.
So the rules are the specifications.
There was a card class and each card only has two attributes.
A suit which is only going to be hearts diamonds clubs or spades and then a value ace two three and
they're all single string characters.
So Ace isn't a king is a K and so on.
And then all the numbers are numbers but strings.
And then the repr method should just return a of clubs or J of diamonds or seven of hearts.
So just the value of suits.
OK.
And that's it for card.
So there's really no functionality on it.
Just hold some data and has a nice representation.
And of course you need to define it.
And that sort of thing.
Deck is where most of the work comes in.
So a deck class.
Each instance of the deck class will have a Cards attribute that automatically is set to all 52 possible
instances of card so cards is going to be a list that contains 52 cards each an actual card instance.
So when a new deck is initialized in that init you should automatically set the cards attribute to be
a list containing all of these all instances all possible combinations.
I wouldn't manually code it just take these values in the list take these values in a list using nested
loop or a nested list comprehension to create a bunch of cards and save each instance to the card list
attribute.
There should be an instance method called Account which just returns a count of how many cards are left
in the deck.
The repr method the representation should just return a string like this deck of 52 cards or 12 cards.
The number of remaining cards in a sentence.
And if you want to pass the tests that I've written just make sure it matches this format.
So don't do something like there are five cards left say deck of five cards and that's just to get the
test to work if you care about that.
OK.
Then there should be a method called deal with an underscore deal.
Again that's to signify that a user or no external code shouldn't be calling deal directly.
It's for internal use.
It's just a convention and it should accept a number like two and it should remove that many cards from
the deck from the end or remove two decks or two cards from the end.
It may need to remove fewer though because you only have one card left in the deck.
You don't want to try and remove too.
You want to remove one and if there are no cards left.
Just return a value error that says all cards have been dealt deck should have another instance method
called shuffle and shuffle can actually just call.
You could either try and write your own shuffle that can be a pain or use a random import random and
use the built in shuffle.
But the idea is that there's going to be an instance method on deck called shuffle.
So it's fine if all that it does is use random shuffle but you should actually make an instance method
called shuffle in an important note.
You said if there are cards missing from the deck it's not a full deck then you should return a value
error that says only full decks can be shuffled.
So there have to be 52 cards in the cards list.
Then there are two methods deal card Cingular which uses the builtin underscore deal method to deal
a single card from the deck.
So just call deal 1 and then deal hand which accepts a number like five or 10.
I don't know any games where you get 10 cards but five.
This is an example and it should call underscore a deal and that should return a list of cards.
So this should return a single card from the deck when it's called.
And this should return a list of cards from the deck.
Here's a quick example of how it should work.
So I could create a new deck doesn't need any information when I make a new deck.
It's always 52 cards I call it my deck and if I print it and just look at what is printed out we get
a deck of 52 cards.
Then I called shuffle on it and then I use the deal card an instance method saved the result a single
card to a variable called card and I print that single card and you can see a of hearts.
So it is a card object an instance of the card class but because the representation has been set all
I see is this nice little string.
Then I called Deal hand which returns a list of cards.
In this case five as you can see here I have five cards in a list that I'm printing.
And then finally I tried to print or I didn't try.
I printed my deck at the end and now it tells me it's a deck of 46 cards because I've dealt six total
cards five here and one here.
We started to 52.
Now we're down to 46.
OK.
So if you're interested in doing this on your own.
Give it a shot.
I recommend doing it locally on your computer running it in your terminal making sure things work.
So you can debug then copy and paste it once you feel ready and see if the tests work with your version.
Otherwise stick around and I'll build this from scratch in the next video or two.
See you then.