Hey welcome back.
Brand new section here all about something called decorator's and you may recall I mentioned decorator's
once or twice in the O P section when we saw how to create a class method.
You write at a class method in front of it.
That's an example of a decorator but that's all I'll say about it for now because first we actually
need to review some really important concepts about functions and more importantly higher order functions
to review a higher order function is just a function that either returns another function from inside
or accepts a function as an argument one or more functions.
I should say as an example of passing functions as arguments to other functions we could do something
like define a function called some and some excepts another function.
And what is going to do.
So we pass a number and like 10 and then passing a function like Square.
So it looks something like this some 10 square squares not defined what it should return to me is the
sum of the first ten squares.
So then we need another function called Square.
So if we defined that def Square just takes X and returns X times x.
That's simple enough.
And then I call some with 10 with square what we're going to do is in here we'll make a variable called
Total and then we'll do a loop.
We can start simple.
For I in range let's go with Nahm instead in range in total plus equals.
And then we call Phunk with no.
OK.
So the result when I call this here some ten Comus Square.
It's going to pass and 10 here and the function square here set totals would be zero for number and
range.
Technically this starts with 0 which doesn't really.
Kind of a waste because in our example we're summing 0 0 0 0 we're adding that to zero.
That doesn't matter.
The next time through however Nahm is 1.
So we're adding phunk of numb.
So square of 1 which is 1 we add that to total next time through number two.
So we phunk know which passes to enter here and returns 4 and we add four and we keep going.
So this works or it should work.
And at the end we define need to return total and then to see something that's out of print here.
OK.
So 3 the way that our loop is set up we might need to adjust it.
But if we print this right we get five.
So what it did or what it did is it summed the square of zero square one in the square too which gives
us 0 plus 1 plus 4.
So that gives us 5 if we don't want to start at zero.
We could shift things up one could do one comma and plus one like that.
And if we run this now we get 14 which is squaring 1 2 and 3 and adding them together nine plus four
plus one.
OK.
So the other thing I'll show you know of course we can find another function called cube.
We don't know if you can hear that siren outside
sounds like I'm in a war zone.
Ok I'm back.
That's just the weekly Tuesday at noon.
Syren just a test.
They always do in San Francisco.
Reminds me every time I hear it.
Another week of my life gone by.
So where was a defining cube function.
You can also just return x times x times x.
And now I could pass Kuban instead and that should give us a larger number.
Yes 36.
So it's cubing 3 cubing 2 and cubing 1 and adding them together.
So this is just to show that we can pass functions in to other functions as arguments we have to we've
defined.
And I guess I'll just put both of them down here so we can see and there we go passing them in.
They're being called from inside the function.
So that's one type of a higher order function which is passing functions as arguments.
And now here's an example of nesting a function inside of another function.
So there is a function called greed and all that greed does is it calls another function called mood
that's defined inside so get mood just returned randomly either Hello their go away or I love you and
there's a space at the end and then it's called user's choice from random.
We've seen that before.
It's called right here.
And then we just concatenate the person like Toby that's being passed in as an argument and then return
that result.
So when I call greet Toby It actually ends up calling Get mood inside of grete get mood returns.
Hello there.
Go away.
We concatenate that with person save that to result and we return.
Toby or I love you Toby and we can run it.
There we go.
Go away.
Toby I totally agree.
He needs to leave.
Change your mind.
Hello there Toby.
Anyway so that's an example of just running a function inside of another function that they're nested
inside of one another.
But we're not actually returning a function we're just returning the result or part of the result from
a function combined or something else.
So what we can do also.
I don't know where this piece showed up.
Come on what we can do also is actually return to function.
So here's an example of that.
So very similar all that we have.
I'm using choice again.
Let's look at the inner function first.
It's called Get laugh and it just picks a laugh.
Ha ha ha ha.
Ello well or maybe we can stop one of those chosen randomly and we returned that from get a laugh that's
all that it does.
Then we have this outer function called Make laugh funk and it doesn't return the choice.
It doesn't return the result of running this.
It returns the entire function so it's not returning hahaha.
LR Well it's returning this.
OK.
So this is a trivial example but we're creating a function that creates another function that returns
function to us.
So we have laugh which is just a variable name call it whatever we want.
Equal is the result of running make laugh phunk the result of this is returning get left so it's just
this make life funk.
So then when we execute laugh we're executing this and it returns one of these choices and are printing
it out.
So let's see what happens.
We execute it.
We get oh well see.
Well give me a ha ha ha ha.
There we go.
OK.
That didn't just blow out your ears.
So we've got a function returning a function here.
That's another way of writing a higher order function.
The last thing I'll show you is basically the same thing except working with an argument.
So now we have a function called Make laugh at phunk.
So the difference is that we're going to pass in someone like Linda.
I'm sorry Linda and we're going to use that person's name and return it from the inner function.
So we have the same pattern.
It's called Make laugh at funk.
And it just returned get laugh but get.
Now not only picks a choice like haha ello ello or t.
But also it returns the choice with the space and then the person's name so person.
And this is important person is not defined instead of get a laugh it's not passed in.
To get life.
It was passed into make laugh at funky it's a parameter to the outer function but we have access to
it in the inner function.
Ok so this is actually what's known as closure.
But I don't want to complicate things with with jargon.
Let's just focus on what happens.
So we return get left from this outer function get laugh is this and that just returns a randomly chosen
life.
It's a string with a laugh and then person's name.
When we then call make laugh at func and they pass in Lunda.
It's returning get laugh and get laugh.
Has access to person so that every time I call laugh at it knows that person is Linda because when I
construct urbanize I set up everything and I called Make laugh at phunk we return get laugh.
Person was Linda.
So every time Micallef we get Hollander or elsewhere Linda.
Linda.
So let's prove it.
Execute it.
There we go.
I'm running four times.
And so we get.
Hahaha Linda Helliwell under here Linda.
OK so none of these are particularly useful things.
Maybe doing something like this you know passing and functioning at something.
I mean we saw it with generators and recreated the for loop.
Forgot about that example when we rewrote a for loop we passed in a function to enter the function and
called it.
So it is something that you will see.
I'm not trying to say this is this is super weird or out there just more that these examples are silly.
No greeting or saying hello well or something like that.
Probably not what you'll spend your time on writing code but it's important because next in the next
video we're talking about decorators and decorators basically are just functions inside of other functions
functions that wrap around other functions.
So you just need to be comfortable with the idea of higher order functions of functions accepting other
functions as arguments and functions returning other functions.
OK next up decorator's.
If you.