We did it.
We made it to the function section or at least part one of functions.
This is really the last of the great topics that we have left to cover with Python.
There's a lot of material left to cover but it's a lot more kind of nuanced pieces or more advanced
things to talk about but functions are pretty much the last important essential building block to Python
that we have yet to discuss.
We have we've kind of seen them in the periphery.
We talked a little bit about them.
We've been using tons of built in functions things like print and Lenn and counted all those things
but now we're going to see how we define our own.
And I'm personally really excited for this section in the next couple because we have a bunch of pre-written
tests interactive code exercises in the browser that have you write functions so you'll be writing almost
3000 functions if you do all of the exercises.
You'll almost write 30 functions in a matter of one or two sections so you'll get tons of practice.
Spend a lot of time on those tests because functions are so important.
It's worth it.
So let's get started.
And the first thing we talked about are the key objectives for the section.
So first we want to describe what the function is and how they're useful be able to talk about the utility
they provide.
Then we want to discuss what the return key does be able to write a function using it and also talk
about how side effects relate to the return keyword.
Then we'll learn to add parameters to functions so we can accept input and then spit out output different
output depending on the input.
After that I want to talk about how to define and diagram scope what is scope and then how does it work
and how does it relate to functions.
Lastly we'll learn to add keyword arguments to functions.
But before we get there we need to answer the simplest most important question.
What is a function.
Well we've been working with functions a whole bunch.
Like I already mentioned things like print or land for the length but also all the built in list methods
or dictionary methods.
Technically they are called methods but if you didn't watch a video where we talked about the distinction
methods are a special type of functions.
So there are all functions that are all built in functions.
So what do they have in common.
Well officially a function is a process for executing a task which I kind of think that's a bit stuffy.
I just like to think of them as a bunch of lines of code wrapped up into a nice little package that
we can recall at any point.
It's like shrinking down a bunch of lines of code and making it reusable.
But what's important is that we don't always get the exact same result every time we call a function.
It depends on the input we provide which can alter the output we get back.
So it's like a little box and not every function accepts an input.
But some of them do.
And when we provide an input we get something out.
Something happens.
So another way of thinking about them is they're just a useful way for executing similar procedures
over and over.
So it's not always identical.
You can write functions that do the exact same thing every time no matter what.
But most of them that we'll be writing will do similar things like add two numbers together.
But the result depends on the numbers that we provide.
So here I have a simple list called colors and you know we've seen so many different built in functions
something like print that's a built in function.
I pass in colors and it prints out colors or I pass in a string and it prints something.
But this time we get a different result.
Likewise we could do color dot append which is another function and I pass in Violet.
It takes that input and add it to the end of colors.
So it does a process and it's repeatable.
But there's also functions like clear that we've seen which don't require any input.
They do the exact same thing every time.
And if we look at colors it's totally empty so clear will always do that.
It doesn't matter if we provide an input or not.
And this section will see how to write both types of function ones that accept input and ones that don't.
So why do we care about function.
Why use them.
The first reason is that it helps our code stay dry which is an acronym that a lot of teachers like
myself rely a bit too heavily on when teaching functions.
But it's easy to remember dry stands for don't repeat yourself.
So it's a way of keeping our code clean and not repeating ourselves.
The opposite is wet write everything twice WTT.
So we want to keep our code dry and functions help us do that cause let's say we had a task that took
10 lines of code to do if we wanted to accomplish that three times we would have to write 30 lines of
code just repeat each ten lines three times.
But if we had a function to do it then each time we want to repeat the task it's only a single line.
So it helps clean up our code and prevent code duplication.
And it also is useful for abstracting away code and what that really means is a lot of times there's
things that we don't want to do.
We don't care about other members don't want to have to worry about.
And it's better if they're pre-defined or someone else you know abstracts the code away.
So for example something like print if you had to write the print function every single time you wanted
to and every program that would be a lot of work you would have to figure out how to connect Python
to the standard output how to actually print something to that to the terminal.
It's not that hard but it's not something that you usually need to worry about.
It's been abstract away.
Similarly things like generating a random number while we could write our own code to do that.
It just makes sense for that to have been done by someone else.
It's kind of abstracted away we don't have to worry about it and we could do the same thing if we were
building our own tools or own framework for other Python developers to use.
There might be a function or two that we give other developers for free that they are able to use and
that we've abstracted away.
And lastly another reason I think that's worth discussing is that functions can help you not only reduce
duplications in your code but organize it logically make it clear what is happening where.
So here is the rock paper scissors game that every factory using a couple of functions.
If you didn't see the rock paper scissors sections don't worry about it and it shouldn't make that much
of a difference.
But before it was just a jumble of code what people would call spaghetti code all over the place.
But with functions now things are separated into discrete tasks.
So we have some code that displays a header.
We have some other code that picks a computer move.
We have code that calculates winner.
We have code that starts a game that displays the winner and it's clear you know what each bit of code
does rather than just having it be all willy nilly all over the place.
Functions allow us to organize things.