Hey welcome back.
So this next section is all about another data structure.
This time it's the dictionary.
So let's first just to find some basic objectives what we want to do in this section.
We want to be able to create an Access dictionary data structures as well as just explain what they
are.
Describe how they work.
We'll use a couple of built in methods to modify and copy dictionaries.
So fortunately there's not as many We need to talk about compared to lists.
Well learn to loop over dictionaries iterate over them using loops and dictionary comprehensions we
saw list comprehensions we'll also see dictionary comprehensions and then one of the things we also
do is compare and contrast dictionaries and lists to data structures.
How are they similar and how they're different.
When would you use one versus the other and then it's actually a good place for us to begin.
So lists are great.
We use them a lot but there are some severe limitations.
They really work to store a particular type of data or a particular set of data where things make sense
in the list.
Lists of I don't know users lists of names lists of items but then things get a bit more complicated
if we're working with data like we're trying to model individual instructor or an individual item in
a shopping cart.
There's more information that we'd want to store.
So for example what is this information here in a list.
What does it represent.
It's unclear what this is.
We have a collection of values a string of boolean a number a string and a boolean.
But I don't know what it's referring to.
It's just we don't have enough information to make sense of it.
So wouldn't it be nice if there was a way to describe this data with more detail.
So here's another example.
This is not a data structure in Python This is just me kind of outlining some things you might want
to store.
Let's say we had a shopping cart which would be a list so that easy we could do something like you know
cart equals an empty list.
But then each item in the cart with what we know right now you know an item might have a name like cat
litter a quantity would have three of them in my cart and a price.
Nineteen ninety nine.
How can I store that all in this cart.
I could do it as a list and start off with cat litter and then the next element in the list would be
the quantity of three.
And then the price which was nineteen point ninety nine.
This theoretically could work but it's really unclear.
We have to know going into this that the item at index 0 is the name of the item and the item at index
1 is the quantity.
It just doesn't make sense.
So what we want instead is a way of describing that data and encoding more information rather than just
an order which is what a list encodes we can use a dictionary and a dictionary consists at its core
of key value pairs.
You'll hear me say that a lot key value it's basically pairs of information pairs of data like a label.
And we use keys to describe our data.
And then the values are the actual data they represent the data.
So if we think of a list we can think of key value pairs in the list.
The keys are all indexes indices 0 is a key and the data might be the string blue in a dictionary.
We actually control the keys on our own and we can decide how we want to store data and under what key
makes a lot more sense if we just look at a dictionary.
So here's an example.
This contains all the bullion information from this last list back here that we couldn't decode their
string and boolean and numbers.
We didn't know what these meant but in a dictionary you can actually see oh names are supposed to be
called OWN DOG.
Supposed to.
Well this is said My dog has since moved on.
I should update this slide.
Well I own a cat still so owns cats.
That's true.
Number of courses for favorite language is Python is hilarious.
False.
Very funny.
Forty four is my favorite number 73 is actually taking its place recently.
As you can see though this encodes a lot more information rather than just the zero with item is called.
And the first item is true.
And so on.
This actually explains what each thing is.
It's on the left we have keys and on the right are the corresponding values.
And also notice the curly braces.
So this is just one way to make a dictionary but they are always key value pairs.
And the keys and values are separated by colons.
And then just like with lists we denote the next item with a comma.
So our kids are almost always numbers and strings as you can see over here.
Forty four is number but everything else is a string.
But the values can be anything they can be another string a boolean a number they could be another dictionary
or a list and a lot of the time what we'll be working with is more complex structures or we have nested
lists and dictionaries together.
So going back to this example here of a shopping cart rather than each item being its own list it would
make a lot more sense to have each item be a dictionary where we could have you know name would be equal
to and it's to be a string name could be cat litter comma and quantity quantity could be three and so
on.
And what we end up with is a list of dictionaries for each item in the list has multiple pieces of information.
So we'll get to that.
But let's start by just defining our own little baby list in Python so I'm going to make a variable
and we can just call this one cat and work with my cat and we need a name.
We don't have to have a name but I'll give her a name which is blue and age and I don't know I think
she's three somewhere between three and four.
Let's do three point five.
And separated by commas again.
Let's go with is cute.
And she's not as cute as you used to be.
To be honest I mean she's not a kitten.
She's aging.
To be expected.
But she's still pretty cute.
So I'll give that to her.
And hit enter.
If I look back at cat.
There we go.
Our data is in there.
We have strings for the kids and for the values we have a number another string and a boolean.
So another way to create a dictionary is to use the dict to make sure I pronounce that t very clearly
could get in trouble here.
The dict function which is just like the list function or the string function which is used to either
create or cast convert a data type.
In this case the most common use of dict is to pass in keys and values separated by an equal sign.
So it looks like this dict parentheses and then whatever key equal to whatever value.
OK so let's try that out.
Let's make another cat called Cat 2 and we'll use the dict function and then in parentheses we just
pass in key value with the equal sign separating it.
So let's do name equals.
I actually don't I don't have a name for my new cat yet.
I'm calling her Kitty.
And if you look at Cat 2 it puts name in quotes as Kitty as a corresponding value.
And if you wanted to add in another piece of information like age just use the equal sign again separate
them by commas.
And she's about half a year.
And if you look at Cat 2 now we have name as a string and age is a string Kitty.
The value is a string.
And the age value is 0.5.
All right.
So that's two ways of making a dictionary totally up to you what you prefer.
I typically use the first method because to be honest it's more similar to how pretty much every programming
language does it.
Well that's not quite true.
There's a couple that do something more like this but it's really up to you.
I'll use both throughout the course.
It's nice not having to type quotes here.
So there is one advantage to that.
OK.
So now we have data in there.
How do we get it back out.