A welcome back to a brand new section we're still talking about object oriented programming but we're
moving on from the basics.
So this section covers a couple of things.
I'll just lay out the objectives first.
We're going to talk about inheritance.
What that means why you'd use it and then we'll learn how to define or to add inheritance to our classes
including something called multiple inheritance.
Then we'll learn what method resolution order is and understand how it works and why you need to care
about it MRO.
That's coming up.
Then we'll talk about a fun word called polymorphism which sounds a lot more intense than it actually
is.
And then finally we'll learn how to add special methods to classes.
I know it doesn't sound very specific but we'll just wait until we get there to talk about what that
means.
Now let's just dive right in and start talking about inheritance.
OK.
So here's a side that says inheritance.
Imagine that we have a user class from the last section making a web site like Reddit.
I don't know if everybody uses Reddit but unread it.
If you sign up for an account you're just a base regular old user but on each sub Reddit there are moderators
who are just regular users who have been promoted or selected as moderators to help moderate the content
remove things that are either against the rules or inappropriate you know help handle trolls and spam
and all this other stuff.
And then further above that there's another level called admin or administrator and think admins based.
I don't know exactly how it works but let's just say in our example admins can remove any comment by
anyone regardless of the subject or wherever it is on the site.
They can delete anything.
Change things in the database do whatever they want.
So there's different levels but we want three classes and let's say we're trying to represent all three
of those with our code.
What we could do is make three different classes.
User moderator admin but there's a lot of content that's shared between them.
Each one has a user name and an email address and a password and each one has a method called comment
and log in and log out and all of that functionality is exactly the same to all of them.
What we could do instead of redefining that everywhere is use inheritance to actually only write at
one time in a base class.
So that's what inheritance allows us to do.
It allows us to define a class which inherits functionality from another class which we usually call
a base or parent class.
So in the example that I just gave we could have a user base class that had all of the things like user
name email log in log out comment and then administrator could inherit from user.
Likewise moderator could inherit from user but we're going to start off with something a bit simpler
and first we have to actually answer how we create this relationship how do we tell Python that one
thing is inheriting from another.
And it looks like this.
We pass the parent class as an argument to the definition.
If the child class so we haven't seen this.
Here I have two classes one called Animal.
This is the base class and then I'm defining a class.
Cat doesn't do anything at all.
But notice that there is an argument being passed in the name of the Animal class.
So usually we just write it.
Classes like this up until now.
But if we actually pass in an argument like this it tells Python this cat class inherits from the Animal
class.
So here's the same code just in a single file so we can run it.
All that is going on.
I have Animal class and there's a class attribute called Cool.
I set it equal to be true and then there's an instance method called make sound which takes a sound
like meow or growl or worth or whatever and it prints.
This animal says and then the sound.
So we could make a new animal you know a equals animal and then do a dot make sound and let's go with
chirp like that you execute the code says this animal says chirp.
That makes sense.
This should not be new.
We're making a new instance of animal and therefore we can run animal instance methods on an instance.
But now if I create a cat let's go with blue equals a cat.
And notice there's nothing instead of cat.
You do have to add this pass otherwise Python will give you an error saying expected an indented block.
If you don't have that there but there's no init or anything else right now.
But there's no data we're passing in either no instance attributes or instance methods in cat but it
didn't Herridge from animal.
And so if I run this now and then I just do that's two blue dot make sound.
And then passengers sound like meow lose the cat.
And if I run it we get this animal says meow.
Even though make sound is defined as an animal instance method.
I could also do something like print blue dot.
Cool and cool is a class attribute added on animal but Blue has access to it and they could do the same
thing with cat dark cool and animal cool because the cat class inherits from the Animal class the class
attribute cool is available.
So I should see three trues printed out.
Cool.
One thing we can use a built in function called Is instance to actually verify for us that blue is a
cat but blue is also an animal.
So let me just show you if we just pass in blue and then a name of a class like animal.
Let's start with cat and let's just do a print instance when common to everything else out.
So is instances a boolean method should return true or false.
If Blue is a cat and we get true and if we change it to it's blue an animal we also get true.
And technically we could change it to it's blue object.
So all of these classes every everything in Python inherits from the base object class.
So by running this we also get true.
And we could use it instance we could test if a list is a list.
So you may not use instance that often but here it illustrates to us that blue is an instance of cat
but at the same time it's also an instance of animal.
And of course this is a really silly example with no methods no instance attributes really nothing going
on but I'll show you in the next video may have something more complex how it really can help save a
lot of space in your code.
A lot of time and just reduce duplication.
So that's coming up next.
But for now this is a quick intro to the idea of inheritance.
Next I'll show you how to actually use it in practice.