Hey welcome back.
Time for a brand new section here all on file IO.
So file input and output.
So we've been working with python files obviously at this point including multiple files that are all
python files and that's great but this section is all about working with files that aren't python files
that don't necessarily contain code.
And this is a really well everything's important in this course in my opinion.
But let's be honest some things definitely are more important than others and file IO is crucial if
you're interested in things like data science or web development for example in data science.
A lot of the stuff that people work on it depends on the project and the company or what they're doing.
But a lot of the time you're working with data sets.
And for example it might be a publicly available data set from the New York City crime statistics whatever
whoever puts those out there might be a big data set of thousands and thousands of lines in a CSP file
for example that has all the you know crime data from the last 10 years in New York and you could analyze
it with Python and spit something out or in web development.
A lot of the time you know you're working with H.T. mail and Javascript and CSSA files.
You'll need to read those files in from CSSA file into your Python code and then send the contents somewhere
else.
That's just one example.
Or you know there are people who actually write entire books using Python and Python will generate PTF
files for example and it needs to be able to make those files and save those files.
Ok so all that stuff are not going to get into making books and data science just yet.
But let me talk about what we will get into in this section.
So we're going to talk about things like reading basic files in writing basic files so adding content
in and saving it.
We'll talk about an alternate syntax using the with blocks to read and write to and from files will
describe different ways of opening a file and some of the nuances around all of this.
And then we'll focus on two data formats.
The first one is C S V.
So comma separated values very common data format.
We'll talk about how to read C S V and right to see Esrey files.
And I didn't add this in here but we'll also talk about Jaison javascript object notation.
A really common data format as well.
And we'll talk about how Jason interfaces with meshes with Python and how to read and write.
All right.
So in the next video we'll dive right in to reading basic files.