A he made it to the next section.
This one is on iterators and generators to kind of scary sounding words.
We've talked about where we've used the word iterator before.
When you're talking about loops.
But now we're actually going to dive into some of the nitty gritty and trying to understand things like
the difference between an iterator and iterable or how we define our own iterators how we make a custom
class iterable then we're going to talk about generators and how it fits in with this whole picture.
So it should be fun.
We're going to dive into the details of how Python works or at least how loops work.
So first objectives we going start off by comparing that word iterator and iterable.
They are not the same thing.
Then we want to understand these two important functions.
One is called it her and the other is called next.
Then we're going to learn to build our own simple for loop.
So we'll be using what we learn will recreate the for loop on our own.
We'll define it and then we're going to move to generators.
We're going to talk about what generators are how they can be used we'll compare generator functions
and generator expressions and then we'll use generators to pause execution of expensive functions.
Basically two parts to this entire section.
First we talk about iterators and iterable.
Next we talk about generators but they all kind of have to do with one another.
All right then in the next video we'll start by talking about iterators and iterable.