All right.
Welcome back.
So this entire section is all about the command line also known as the terminal.
It's not the most glamorous thing ever but it's really really important for the rest of this course
and I'll be really upfront.
We're not covering any Python in this section which I know might be a little bit of a bummer but it's
for really good reason.
We have to have a solid understanding of mastery of the basics of using the command line in order to
move forward with Python.
In fact we'll be using the command line and pretty much every single video from here on out.
So we got to start here but we'll keep it quick.
Keep it to the basics just the minimum you need to know in order to work with python.
Oh I should mention I did add a couple of videos and photos of my two adorable cats.
Somewhere in this section.
So I don't know maybe that will help you get excited about it.
If you're not excited OK so let's start by talking about our objectives in this section.
There's a couple key things that we want to take away to prepare us for working with Python And The
first is we got to define what the command line is.
Pretty straightforward.
What is it and why should you care.
Then we're going to learn the basics of command line navigation and file structure along with that.
We'll learn how to manipulate files and folders using the command line.
So we'll be able to look at folders and files create new ones to the existing ones.
Move them around that sort of thing.
So those are the three key points we want to take away from the section.
Like I said I'm going to keep it brief.
If you already feel comfortable doing these three tasks relate to the latter two if you're good navigating
your file structure creating deleting moving files and folders around then you might be able to just
skip this section entirely and move on to Python.
But if you're not confident in your ability to do that.
Hang in there.
This will be quick and like I said keep photos of my cats so let's get started.
So what is the command line.
What's it do to put it shortly.
Or not so surely in this case the command line is a faster and more powerful way to maneuver your operating
system.
So if you're on a Mac you might be familiar with the Mac Finder or on Windows the Windows Explorer.
These are graphical user interfaces so if you've never used a command line this is how you interact
with your computer.
Use your mouse.
We can open up files.
You know you can click on things you can delete by dragging to the trash or right clicking depending
on the system that you're on.
This is how the majority of people interact with their computer and it works great but the command line
works better.
It's a little uglier.
That's probably the hardest roadblock to get past.
It's just text but it's faster and far more powerful.
Once you kind of get up and running with it.
So rather than using our mouse to click on things and double click and drag items we use special keywords
just text so these special keywords that we're going to learn.
But you do everything you can do with a graphical user interface plus a lot more.
So here's a quick example.
Here's a command and it's pretty trivial silly example but what it will do is search in a file called
report that TXI.
So an existing file.
And let's say this file is filled with out and ten thousand lines of text.
This SCD command said is going to then search this file for all instances of the word dude and it's
going to replace it with my name.
But it's going to take the result of that with all the replaced dudes into a new file.
It's going to make call report new dirty XTi.
So again we're going through file reports that replacing all instances of the word dude with cold and
storing that all in a new file called Report new data 60 in a single line.
And most of this is something you probably don't need to do often.
If you had to do this with the UI or gooey it takes a lot of work.
At best you would need to open up the report file.
Maybe your text editor has a way to find and replace.
So even if you find and replace using your editor rather than doing it manually you then still have
to save the result.
Copy it.
Make a new file open.
Not in a new application.
Paste the new code in their saved report.
New data 60 and it takes a lot of time.
And that's just one silly example but pretty much everything that we do is going to be faster.
Using the command line.
So that brings us to the next thing which is how are we going to use it in this course.
And really why why do we need to even talk about how to relate to Python.
Well first off we're going to use a terminal to just navigate around our files so we'll have around
a hundred or more files maybe 20 different directories for this course and will use the command line
the terminal to navigate through them to create and remove new folders and files to move.
Copy and paste those files and most importantly as far as how it relates to Python.
We need to use the command line to actually run code as Python.
So we're going to write code and files of say a file called my code.
Python IPY just putting code in a file doesn't really do anything have to execute it using Python.
So we need to be able to navigate through our folders find the correct file and then execute Python
with that file.