All right welcome back.
So in this video I want to talk about sequel injection.
I want to show you an example or two of things that you definitely want to avoid and how they could
potentially be exploited.
So typically we'd be talking about web apps or some form of an application where you know it's out to
the general public and people are logging in or are searching or doing something where they're interacting
with your database.
They're searching for something that search term then goes and you find all things that match in the
database or they log in with their username and password.
And this is actually kind of a bad example because if you knew what you were doing you would never store
a password as text you would never do what I'm about to show you.
But with the example I'm going to show you this is a terrible exploit.
So the first example you'll notice I'm using a different database.
It's not the friends database anymore or my friends.
It's called users.
And I already inserted I already created a single table called users where we're just storing a username
and password.
And basically what I want to do is to simulate.
We can imagine it's a web app but it's going to just be a Terminal app or a command line based app where
it asks for a username in and ask for a password.
And if those match the given username and password or the password stored for a username in the database
then we'll say you know successfully logged in or something.
So if we look at the database and I just do select star from users you'll see I have three users in
there.
So colt is a user name and that's the password was the username password and then blue.
She's a cat she doesn't really have you know highly evolved ideas about passwords and security so her
password is meow.
So I need to log in with a username and the corresponding password and the query we're going to do basically
looks like this select star from users where username equals and let's say I enter.
That's going to be an annoying one.
Let's do blue.
And password has to match.
So password would need to be meow in order to select who.
So password was something else.
We don't get anything back.
So it's simulating.
Remember these are going to be variables.
These aren't going to be hard coded in.
So we're going to ask a user to provide those.
And if the user gets the right combination we'll say welcome back and if they don't we'll say failed
log in or something like that.
And remember it's not a good idea to store your passwords directly like this ever.
I'm not trying to say that this is how you should do it.
I'm doing this all to show you what could happen if you're not sanitizing your inputs if you're allowing
users to just write pure sequel basically and you're injecting it into another query.
So it's exit out of this no just type fancy character.
There we go and let's come back here.
We're going to have a query that looks like select star from users where username equals and we'll come
back to that and password equals and we'll fill that in in a moment too.
But let's start by asking a user name for or asking a user for their user name so it's a user name equals
action is going to do you to make it shorter.
Input Please enter your username and then we'll do password equals input please enter your password.
OK.
So we have those two bits of data.
Then we're going to make a query.
So I'll just call it query and make it an F string.
And remember this is not what you want to do.
I had a video on this already.
We don't want it directly at our data in like this but I would put you right there inside the quotes
and then he goes right here.
So if all things worked whatever our username is whatever the password is our query is just going to
have those stuck in there if we are non-malicious if we're a nice user who is not trying to exploit
the fact that we're just interpolating variables this should work.
And let's take a look.
I'll do a c and do it after I create see.
Execute query and then let's do that fetch one and just print that.
Those make it a variable result and then will do if results.
Print.
Welcome back.
Otherwise we'll print failed loggin.
OK so now we have the set up here.
And if a user enters a matching username and password we should see welcome back.
So let's begin by testing out the happy scenario.
Please enter my username so blue and then meow and we get we'll come back if I try tried again with
blue and a wrong password.
We get failed log in.
OK.
So that all is how we would want it to work.
But the thing is because we're not sanitizing or not parameterize parameter rising are our inputs.
We're just sticking them directly into the sequel query a user could actually write sequel in as part
of their password.
So let me show you an example instead of this let's say I don't know Culp's password it's a really long
password anyway but I'm going to do is type a single quote and then that essentially ends the password
and then I'm going to say or one equals one and I'll come back to why I'm doing that and then I'm going
to add this comment and then I'm going to hit enter.
And it says Welcome back.
What is that about.
Well let's step through what I just did over here.
So if this is the query that we're trying to complete and I came in and said user name was called.
So that's all good.
And password is.
I came right in here and I typed a single quote which sublimest is annoying.
It just deleted that single quote.
But I typed this single quote right here and that ended the password and then I said and I said or one
equals one and if we ignore so ignore this at the end what I'm basically saying is select star from
users where username is called and password is empty string or one equals one which is always true.
That's basically me saying Do all of that stuff or just true.
And remember the way that works if if one side is true the whole thing is true.
So this actually selects all users select start from users where one is one select all from users where
always true that's just going to give us everything.
Now we're only fetching the first one.
But the point is that it's letting us in and I'm getting.
Welcome back.
Now why did I have to add in this dash dash.
Well that's how we do comments and sequel.
If I put two dashes in front of something or hyphens or whatever they are it commented out and we have
this problem of the extra quote at the end.
So if we put two dashes there it eliminates that says that's just a quote.
Don't worry about that.
So this is a super simple example of something that you could do and it all hinges from the fact that
we're adding some data or some it's supposed to be text into this query inside of these quotes and I'm
basically taking it over.
I'm commenting out that second quotation mark there.
It's not going to show up here as is color coded because it's instead of an F string.
But you can see there what I did I closed off that first password and just said password is empty or
I could put anything in there.
It's not mattering it doesn't matter anymore.
Because of this part or one equals one.
So that's that's not good that we can do that.
So the the other way of doing it remember is this where I leave this one as a bad idea come down here
and say like start from users where username equals and this is where we do question mark and password
equals question mark.
And then when we execute the query we pass them both in a reorder this just group them together like
this and then we're going to pass in a tuple that contains username and password.
And those should both be added in inside of our query.
Where are those question marks are they will be subbed in.
But we can't it won't allow us to add other sequel code.
So let's verify that it works.
So Blue says make sure it works read do it correctly.
OK.
Welcome back.
Now I'm trying to be malicious again and I do close a string and then or one equals one common to everything
else out failed it doesn't work anymore and that's because we're doing it the right way now where we're
not trying to interpret it on our own.
We're letting the library the sequel light library take care of it for us and prevent any sort of malicious
injections.