All right we're back.
So for the next couple of videos we're talking about strengths.
One of the data types remember we are going to revisit booleans and lists and dictionaries.
They get their own sections strings.
There's not quite enough to make it its own standalone section but there is enough that we need to do
a couple of videos.
So here we go in this first one we're just going to talk about the different ways of declaring strings.
So we saw how to declare strings with double quotes but we can actually use single quotes or double
quotes and it doesn't really matter at the end of the day.
But you need to be consistent.
So here's an example.
My other string equals a hat with single quotes.
And then my string equals a cat with double quotes.
So whichever one you use the beginning you have to use the end.
You couldn't use a single and then a double.
So either one is fine.
It really is up to you and what you prefer.
But it's important that you stick to the same convention in your own file.
And when I say it's important it's really just a stylistic thing.
It won't make a difference.
You can have a string in double quotes and then another one in single quotes.
It's not going to break your code.
They'll be equivalent to one another if you try and compare them as well.
So it doesn't really matter.
But you should be consistent.
But along with that when I hop over to my terminal I have Python 3 open.
Now as you can see we can do things like name equals coat or name to equals cult and we like that name.
They look at name too and notice that when they returned back to us they actually don't look any different.
So the quotes it's sort of just like a way of getting it into Python.
But then once we actually print them back or just return them as we did earlier.
Print name they look exactly the same.
So next I want to show that you can actually use quotes inside of other quotes.
So let's say I had something like this.
Message equals.
And then I'll do double quotes he said and then I want to have a quotation inside of this if I tried
to do this he said hello there.
What do you think will happen if I hit Enter right now.
Well we have a problem.
So what I'm trying to do is have a quote inside of a quote you know I'm like I'm quoting he whoever
that is but when Python reads this it just goes from left to right.
And it says OK there's a string called he said and there's a space and then it stops because it finds
the matching double quote.
So it ends.
And then it just finds Hello there which is not inside of quote and it throws an error because it doesn't
know what this is referring to.
So another option would be to use single quotes inside or vice versa.
You single quotes on the outside but we can use single quotes instead of double quotes or double quotes
instead of single quotes.
And now if I look at message you can see it says He said hello there and just really quickly I could
also do the same thing.
Message do message two equals you single quotes.
I am funny.
Inside of quotes mean that's what my friends told me they always do those air quotes and they tell me
I'm funny.
And if we look at message two you can see perfectly valid it's using double quotes instead of single
quotes.
OK.
That's all I wanted to mention.
You can use them together.
There's no problem in that.
But you just need to make sure that whatever you open your string with you close with.
Next we're going to talk about something that sounds a lot more fun than it is called escape sequences.