All right.
So now we're moving on to the second type of loop in this section which is the while loop.
So both while and for loops can be used to iterate over a collection or to repeat something ten times.
Anything you can do with the for loop.
We could do with a WHILE loop.
That's what I'm trying to say but there's also a lot of things you can do with a WHILE loop that you
can't do with a for loop.
So I think of while loops as a distant cousin and some sort of far off relative to a conditional statement
an if statement.
So here's the syntax.
So we have a while and then we provide a boolean expression.
So this is a single variable.
I'm tired which is a boolean variable set to True or false but it could be something like while x is
greater than 20 or while number is less than 100.
Basically any boolean expression goes in this while loop.
So we fill in the blank here and whatever code we have inside the loop indented will run.
While this is true.
So while loops continue to execute while a condition is truthy.
So just like a conditional statement will execute once if a condition is truthy.
A while loop will continue to execute while it is true.
But then at some point it should become falsie and that will stop the loop.
So is another example.
We said user response a variable to be empty.
We set it to none.
We could also do an empty string and then we write.
While user response is not equal to please notice the colon.
Just like all the other loops and conditional statements.
So while the user does not type the word please ask the user for a different input and say I didn't
say the magic word.
So the effect of this is the first time through user responses none.
So this right here is true.
User response is not equal to please.
So then we ask again an update user response.
And let's say this time I type an hello.
Well that's also not equal to please.
So it repeats and it asks again and then this time I say please.
And then the loop halts and that makes his condition false.
So everything finishes.
So I did mention you could do everything you can do with a for loop using a while loop but they do require
more setup because you need to have usually an existing variable that you're using.
So you declare a separate variable unlike in a for loop where we can create a temporary variable that
only exists in that loop and we don't have to actually initialize it on Earth.
And one last warning before we dive into writing some while loops.
You need to be careful because the way that while loop works as it continues running while something
is true and if you never flip it over if you never take that condition and make it false the loop will
continue forever.
And that's called an infinite loop and it won't like ruin your machine or anything.
You'll need to halt it but it will ruin your program.
Nothing else will be able to happen it will keep going forever until you intervene.
So that's not good.
We don't want that so I'll show you an example of what would cause that.
But let's start by typing some simple while loops so I'll make a file I'll call it while P Why I must
start by doing a simple loop that asks for user input.
So let's say that message equals input.
What's the secret password.
And then we'll have a while.
So while a message is not equal to what should our password be.
Let's have our password be bananas Colin.
We're going to first print wrong and then let's also just re update message and ask for what's the secret
password and then afterwards we'll say.
Correct.
OK.
So we're going to ask for input and if the user enters anything other than bananas this is going to
be true messages not equal to bananas.
So we're going to print wrong and we're going to ask for message again and then this should eventually
hopefully our user types in bananas.
It's going to be me and I'm going to type bananas which will make this false message will be equal to
bananas which then helps the execution of that loop and we move on to print.
Correct.
So this whatever comes afterwards only runs when this finishes.
OK.
Let's try it Python 3.
Wild up p y o Python 2 What am I doing.
There we go.
What's the secret password.
Blue purple orange or Touraine pie.
And let's go with bananas now by Nanna's.
Correct.
And it stops.
So that's our first example of a while loop.
OK.
So I'm going to comment that out and leave it here and now I'm going to show you how you could convert
a for loop to a wild how you can use them interchangeably.
So let's say we're going to put the numbers from 1 to 10.
I know very boring with a for loop.
We could just do for Nahm in range 1 and we need to go to 11 because it's exclusive.
And then we'll just print no.
Right.
So we've seen this before.
We get 1 through 10 with a while loop.
We can do the same thing but we need to first declare a variable.
So I could call this one numb or let's go with yeah is fine equals and we'll started at our first number
which is 1 then what we need to do have our while loop while numb is less than 11 or we could do less
than or equal to 10.
Either one will do less than 11.
We're going to print.
No but if we leave it at this.
Can you tell what's going to happen.
We'll get an infinite loop because nothing is set to 1 and it never changes.
So one is always less than 11.
So this just goes forever and ever and ever and ever until we force quit it.
Let's see what happens.
Generally don't want to try and get these Yeah there we go.
OK I'm going to hold that command C or control C and you can see we got oh man I'm scrolling as fast
as I can at a couple of thousand maybe ten thousand or more.
Is printed out.
So we don't want to do that now.
Never change from one.
So what we need to do is update number.
So I'm going to do none.
Plus he calls 1 to same as numb equals number plus 1.
So we're adding 1 to it each time just like this works where there there's a range which starts at 1.
It prints and then is an increment to two and a prince name is incremented to three.
And once it gets to ten it stops.
Same idea except in a while loop.
We have to declare the variable first and we have to update it manually on our own.
OK let's try it now Arrigo 9:59.
OK.
So that shows how we can take a for loop and converted to a while loop or that we could use a while
loop and in place of a for loop.
But if you're just trying to do things like print numbers well that's not a good example but if you're
trying to do something that you could do with a for loop I generally use a for loop because it's shorter
and quicker.
So a last change we could make if I wanted to only print odd numbers for example what I could do is
just change what I'm incrementing by.
Let me clear my counsel on that again.
We get 1 3 5 7 9 and you know we could also add a conditional statement in here whatever code we want
just like we can with a for loop.
So really the way a while loop works.
It's just like in a single if statement.
Except it continues to run until that condition is false and you just have to be conscientious about
infinite loops that will get you into some trouble.
So that's it for loops or for while loops at this point.
We're going to get some practice with exercises but really just to sum it all up.
Both loops.
You can print numbers out or you can loop a specific number of times but the difference with a while
loop is it's more flexible where you might have something that might run once it might run 50 times
and you don't know because it's built upon a boolean expression.
So it might be.
Using user input it might be getting data from a database and looping through that versus a for loop
like we have right here is always this loophole always run 10 times this one this while loop could run
10000 times or it could run once.
So while it's more flexible.
But if you do need something to happen a set number of times a for loop is much shorter and more pretty
smart you know sync it anyway so that's enough of talking at you.
Let's do some exercises.
Let's try building a couple of things with while loops.