Hey welcome back.
So this video will be another kind of fun one.
I'm just going to show how to use special methods along with inheritance.
So what we're going to do is create something I'm calling a grumpy dict with a T or B dict where we're
inheriting from the Dictionary class or type technically.
And what we're going to do is basically keep the same functionality but then add in some grumpiness.
So for example I make a new grumpy dict and if I just print D which is the dictionary tells me none
of your business and then it gives me the data.
Nothing crazy.
And then let's say that I want to change something or add something or in this case I'm changing city
to be Assef and if I just do that it's just a normal dictionary nothing should happen.
But I may print the after.
So you can see what happens.
When I run it says it why do you always have to change things.
Fine setting city TSF.
And then we can see it actually did set city to SFO so we're not just printing things out we're printing
things out and being kind of jokey but then continuing on with the regular behavior because afterwards
when I run print once again it tells me none of your business.
But then we see city has been changed to S.F. Or here's another bit of functionality called D which
is the name of the grumpy dictionary and I try and look for something that's not in there.
Instead of getting an error I wrote something that says the thing you want isn't in here.
So sort of grumpy dictionary but see how we actually implement it.
So I'm going to make a file called grumped beat up.
And we're going to define our class.
I'll just call it Grumpy dict and then inherits from DECT.
And the simplest place to start would just be by setting up our representation method.
Our E.P. our self we've already seen this but there's going to be a bit of a twist here.
If I just try and do you know printed Grumpy's string like none of your business like this we can just
leave it at that.
And actually we do want to return to print because we're going to then print down here print.
Let's make a new grumpy dict.
So let's just call it data equals Grampy dict pass in a dictionary.
Notice we didn't have to define in a nit.
And why is that.
Well we inherit from dictionary.
We're not doing anything else special or fancy with the data not no instance properties or attributes.
We're only concerned with adding some methods.
So the init in dict will run instead because of that MRO thing we saw a couple of videos ago.
So I said some data in here.
Let's just go first is Tom and animal is cat.
It doesn't matter.
OK.
And if I print data right now all that we'll see is none of your business.
And that's where we get none of your business.
That's it.
So what if I want to actually then call the dictionary representation.
It's really easy.
So instead of returning none of your business what we can do is print your business first and then return
super.
Which is dict dot double underscore our EPR which is going to call the dictionary's version which is
the one that we print out.
You know the format that looks like this.
Now if I do it we get in your business followed by first time animal cat.
OK.
So another one that we can set up is called Missing double underscore missing and this is what will
be called if the key is not in a dictionary.
So it's already implemented on DECT but we can override it self.
And then the key that it's looking for that the user is looking for.
And then we can just return.
Let's just do a print and even return.
And let's just do the thing you want actually instead of the thing you want and then put in key.
Well it ain't here when you didn't have string.
So this will run whenever we look for something in data so if I just tried to do data of I don't know
city there is no city key instead of grumpy Dichter Instead of data.
And so missing will automatically be called in usually on a dictionary that throws an error.
It now we get you on City.
Well it ain't here.
So grumpy.
All right.
So that's missing.
Now let's add in our final little thing which is when we actually update the data so what if I said
data city equals S.F. or Tokyo.
If you want to find all of this out you can look in the documentation.
It's the same page I was on in the previous video where we saw things like Lenn special magic methods
here here's missing.
Here we go set item.
So this will be called to implement assignment to self bracket key.
So basically whenever something is being added in or set so it's not only added but updated as well
in a dictionary or in a list.
But in our case we're working with a dictionary.
This will be called so we can override it.
But notice key and value are parameters.
So let's do that now.
Def set item self key and value just like this.
And then what do you want to print.
Let's say you want to change the dictionary and then let's do another print.
OK fine.
And then lastly what we need to do is call super dot set item because if we didn't do this you need
to pass in key and value as well.
If we didn't do that and I just left it like this if I said data city Tokyo and then I printed data
again it wouldn't ever update because said item stop right here.
This is all it does.
And you can see that here we only have first an animal.
But if I call super said item it will print my grumpiness first and then still go ahead and call that
item in the dictionary.
So now we get city Tokyo.
So now we have a very grumpy dictionary.
Anytime time we make changes any time I print it out tells me you know your business but it still printed
out if something's missing.
Nothing happens.
You just get a little message and if we said something we get a grumpy message and then it actually
is set in the dictionary.
So the whole point of showing this to you was to show you two things.
One get more practice with these Dunder magic special whatever methods that Python uses behind the scenes.
And two I wanted to show you that if you do inherit from any class especially in a preexisting type
like dictionary we can still call the parent class methods even if they are these Dunder methods like
we have here and we can extend them even if all we're doing here is grumpiness.
It's just a silly example but replace this code with any other add on that you want any additional functionality
and you can still rely on the base functionality so you can extend upon a list or a dictionary or some
other class that someone else wrote.
Kind of fun stuff and I won't keep going.
But we could alter how the entire method works which is how to basically how it should iterate over
a dictionary in our case or a grumpy dictionary and how things should work how the reversed version
should work how it works to delete an item how contains work.
So this is to check if something is in a dictionary so we could really quickly add that one in which
is just def contained self item.
I know I said we're done but I could just have it return.
No it ain't in here.
Supposed to return true or false.
So maybe I'll just have a print.
No it ain't in here and then have it return false no matter what.
Even if it's in there.
So now if I tried to do city in data I get.
No it ain't in here and it returns false even though it is just grumpy.
We don't want to deal with it.
Ok now I'm actually done.
But it's fun you keep adding these in but I'll stop I promise.
OK.