A welcome back.
So this video is an exercise.
It's also a code along.
It's one of those where you can pick if you want to build it with me or if you want to try it on your
own.
But the idea is to kind of force you to use a package that you've never used before.
So we're going to make a really simple ASCII art printer.
You run it.
Here's a screenshot.
It asks you what message do you want to print and what color.
And in this case I said print hello world in magenta and we get hello world printed out in magenta.
So the first thing I should mention that you do not need to do this part manually.
You could but it would be a huge pain to try and put this all together.
Instead what you need to do is use a package called pi figure.
So if you want to do this on your own research the package go just google it and read the documentation.
Install it with Pip and then try running help and just looking at how it works or look at an example.
All we need is a single line to print this or a single line from this package at least a single function
as well as the import.
So two lines technically and then to get the colors can use the same package we used in the last video
term color.
Let me do a quick demonstration this time I'll say I hearts Kitty and I'll print it in.
Let's go with Suyin.
There we go.
The heart looks kind of messed up but let's do one more and this time I'll just print Python with three
exclamation points and I'll do it in blue or green.
And that's what we get.
The last thing I'll show is that I have a default color.
So if the user enters let's say just print jibberish that's fine.
But if I try to enter orange or a bunch of characters My default is magenta.
You can pick your own.
So I'm just checking is the value not one of the permitted values which if you need to remember what
those are.
You can look in help but it's pretty much blue green magenta red.
Oh I already forgot cyan and yellow I think.
But you can just pull up help with term colors and you can see that.
So give it a shot if you want to or follow along.
As I build it but the idea is that you're not supposed to know how to use this right out of the box.
You need to go through the process of you know any developer who finds his package for the first time
you go and read and you look and explore the documentation to give it a shot.
Or let's build it now to get it.
So the first thing we should do is install the package and I've already given you the name.
So we just need Python three Dasch am Pipp install.
They get.
I already have it installed so it will tell me that.
But if you don't then it should take a moment and install and we can start off.
Let's just open up Python 3 and import PI piglet and then run help.
But rather than rather than running help on the entire thing.
If I do that you'll see we get so much stuff what we want instead is to look for this Figler that format.
I'm going to quit out of fear and instead we can do help.
PY fuckwit dot piglet former figure that sounds so ridiculous saying that multiple times and we can
see there's this function figure format just takes in text and then a font which defaults to standard
so the text is what we want to be formatted and what that will actually do if you try running this make
a variable just called results equals and then we'll do PI.
They do not fit good format and then pass in high and we look at results.
This actually is the ASCII art text in a string and just has all these new line characters.
So when it's actually printed out would you print results.
We get high so this is a magical line and all we'll need to do is ask the user for input and then pass
that input into here and that will give us the ASCII art.
And then when we print it all colorize it.
Using the term color package so lets quit and make a new file and all call this file.
ASCII art.
P Why.
OK so let's begin by importing pi.
Figure.
And then let's just ask a user very at the very beginning.
Let's ask for a message.
There will just be input.
What would you like to print.
And we can also ask them for the color but we won't do anything with it yet and it will just be another
input what color.
OK then we'll just take that in the message very well and we have this pie Figler dot piglet formats
which we just saw and we'll pass in message and I'll save that to a variable and we'll just call this
ascii art or ascii message.
And then at the end we'll just print ASCII art.
So this is the magical line we're just asking for input.
Let's just see what happens.
So that's Python 3 ASCII art.
What would you like to print.
Let's just do.
Hi there.
What color.
It doesn't matter.
We're not using it.
And we get high there.
So now all we have to do is get the colors working.
So that's just going to be important.
And then it was called term color and rather than importing term color like this I'm going to do from
term color import colored which is what we saw in the last video and then I'll make another variable
called colored ASCII equals.
And it's going to be colored and then we pass in ASCII art.
That's what we want to be colored.
And then a color.
And let's just default right now to have colored be green.
And then we'll just print colored ASCII.
OK.
So we were getting the ASCII art over asking for input and we're taking it and formatting it using fake
PI fake it then that comes back and then we're passing it into colored which we've imported from term
color and then that returns a colored version but it doesn't print itself.
We then have to pass it into print.
And let's try running it let's print glob law that's red and we get blah blah as green.
Perfect.
So now we just need to connect the color portion.
So a user can enter a color and then we'll just pass a color right there.
So whatever the user types we passed in under the in the keyword argument color.
And now let's test it.
What I want to print.
Ello ello ello.
And we'll print it as blue and that works I'll do the same thing and I'll print it as yellow.
But then the problem is what if I just try and print orange.
It breaks everything.
So let's write some code to defend against that.
And the first thing we could do is just look at the permitted colors.
Open a Python 3 import term color and then we'll do help turn color and you can see available text colors
right here.
So I'm just going to copy that and then go back and I'll just printed or cut and paste it here.
And the first thing that will do.
We're just going to test if the user provided color is in and we could make this whole list if we wanted
to we're going to need to put quotes around everything is kind of annoying but we make it a list and
then just check is color in that list.
And if it's not then we'll set color to be whatever default we want white or magenta or blue and actually
rather than a list.
This would be a good use case for a tuple because we're never going to change this inside of our application.
We're not going to have code that is adding a color or removing a color.
This is just sort of a constant list so I'm going to make it a tuple because it will just it's lighter
weight and I'll add in my quotes.
There we go.
Save that and I'll just call it Vout.
Valid colors equals that tuple.
Put that up top.
Cool.
And then after we get a user color we'll just write an IF statement if color not in valid colors then
we'll change color to be whatever default we want.
I'll go with magenta.
The closest thing to purple of course and that should be that.
So we have our valued colors list.
If whatever the user enters is not in this tuple tuple nimblest.
And if that's the case I'll give it a default value of magenta and then use that color variable down
here.
Otherwise if it is in this list then we'll just print that color.
Let's test
so I want to print I'll just do haha.
And this time I want green that works.
That's the same thing.
But I type orange I get magenta because orange isn't an option sadly.
And if I type blue that works OK so I'll stop there.
We built a very simple application but it's combining two different modules.
The one refactor we could make is do the same thing up here all that we're using from PI forgood PI
figure it is figured format.
So I'm going to instead do from PI figure that import format.
Those are the only things you need.
And so then I can remove this pi Figler it and our code is a little bit cleaner and you know we could
wrap this up in a function we could call it def print art and it could take in message and to color
and then we'll just move this code inside of there.
All of this and then these two things we ask for user input.
We'll just pass them in to print art message color.
Totally unnecessary but it's just I just want to show you because we haven't been using that many functions
yet still pretty fresh in our course memory.
So this is something we could do.
Valid colors is only used inside of this.
There's no reason to make it global.
We can just define it in there and that should be that.
That's just I check.
See if it still works.
What do we want to print those print red in red and it still works.
So now we've just created a function called Print art and it takes two arguments and that's pretty much
it.
OK.
So we combined two different modules to make something pretty simple.
But still bigger and better than what we could do on our own.