OK so that's one use case for a class attribute.
Keeping track of things sort of like analytics if you will about the individual instances of the classes.
How many have been made.
The average of something across all of them.
Now another common use case would be to actually create validations.
So let me show you what I mean.
OK.
So I made a new file called Pet.
Why.
And the idea here going to make a pick class that each pet has a name and a species instance attribute
so name could be fluffy.
Species could be dog but we're not going to stop there.
We're actually going to create a list of permitted species for pets.
So we're not going to allow someone to have you know a three headed dog as a pet or a crocodile or a
lion or something.
So we're just going to create a class attribute that's going to store the list of permitted species.
So let's start by just doing class pet.
Well define our simple knit self first then let's go with name and species just like this.
And let's just do self-taught name equals name self-taught species equal species kind of boilerplate
ish in our initialize method and we can just begin by doing.
I don't know cat equals pet and name will be blue.
Species will be cat and then we'll do one more and it will be a dog.
Dog will be called Why it and species is dog.
All right.
So this is all review.
Now the thing is I don't want to allow someone to do pet.
Fluffy is a tiger for example.
And to prevent that I'll create a class attribute called Let's go with a loud and in here we'll just
put in things like cat dog fish and let's do that as well.
I apologize if your favorite pet is not here just for the sake of keeping this brief.
I'm not going to add in every possible pet.
OK.
So these are the allowed pets and this could be a class attribute.
Well it will be in our example but it actually doesn't have to be all I'll talk about when you would
make something a class attribute versus when you would just move it into a net.
But for now let's just keep it as a class attribute called allowed.
And all we're doing here is add a little check if species not in a.
And it can't just reference allowed and need to reference pet dot allowed or alternatively This is something
we haven't seen.
I can actually use self allowed which is the syntax we use for an instance attribute.
I will come back to that but let's leave it at pet allowed.
So if species is not in pet allowed Let's raise a value error and just have an F string in there that
says something like You can't have a and then to add the species in pet.
All right you can have a crocodile pet.
You can't have a grizzly bear pet.
OK.
Otherwise we'll just add name and species as instance attributes.
So at this point I'll copy this over.
Move toward terminal open a Python 3 and it make a new pet.
Let's go with Tony and Tony is a tiger that's not in a loud.
So I get value error.
You can't have a tiger pet.
But if I just do pet let's do a variable C equals PED's and it will be blue again which is a cat C works
just fine.
OK.
So we have a class attribute allowed.
Now the question you might have is a perfectly valid question is why does that need to be a class attribute.
We're only using it inside of this init method.
We could just move it in here into the method and just change this to be in a cloud.
This is not a class attribute.
This is not an instance attribute either.
This is just part of the init method.
It exists in that scope.
If I just copy it over and paste everything I look at cat or let's try doing pet allowed.
It's no longer defined because we don't it's not a class attribute but I also can't do cat not allowed
either or dog got allowed.
It only exists in this method and if possible you want that to happen if you don't need access to this
in any other method you're only using it in a net.
Put it here.
However let's say that I wanted to also prevent a user from changing dog species manually because right
now there's nothing stopping someone from doing dog that species equals Tiger and just overwriting the
species property after we initialize.
As you can see here I have dog.
I could do d'Agde out species equals whatever I want Tiger.
No problem.
And technically we don't really have a way to officially prevent that but what we could do is create
a method and that method could be def change or the standard would be to call it set species and then
it should take in species.
And also we need self.
And then all that we would do here is set self species equal species but we want to do the exact same
thing where we check if it's allowed.
So rather than copying a loud over here again where now we're defining allowed twice.
Not to mention the fact that what if we change allowed we we add a species in there or we remove a species
we don't want to have two copies so we can make a single copy the class attribute go back to that and
then changes to be pet that allowed.
And then here we don't need to redefine it and we just do our if and I'll just copy this exact same
thing.
I missed the beginning but now we have our same check if species not in pet allowed raise the same error
and then otherwise set species to be the new species Paiste everything.
Now if I look at cat that species cat that I could change it using cat set species and the new species
I try and set it to Tiger I get an error but if I try and change it to a rodent or would we have rat
that works.
And now if I look at cat species it's rat.
And so then we have pet allowed is still cat dog fish and RAT.
Now here's the cool thing.
I mean Cool's an overstatement.
But here's the thing that I can do if I add something to a loud pet dog allowed.
And I do not append what would be a new species said it's allowed.
How about hamster.
OK pig pig.
There we go.
So now if I look at pet dog allowed it contains pig and I don't have to update anything in order for
my cat.
That said species to work I can now set it to pig because we said aloud as a class attribute when I
updated it.
All of our pet instances the individual objects know that pet dog allowed is now one thing longer it
contains pig.
So now I can set cat species to be pig which makes absolutely no sense but cat is now a pig.
So here's a little diagram I threw together.
It's kind of messy but it shows what's happening.
So we have the pet class with a single class attribute called aloud.
In this case just to make it fit in this block I only added dog and cat.
Then we have each pet instance.
This first one has a name an instance attribute called name set to Fluffy instance that should be called
Species said to dog and then it has this thing called allowed but it's actually pointing to the pet
class attribute allowed the same thing over here.
So when I say that it has an attribute called allowed on the instance that's technically true but it's
only referring to the same pet class attribute.
It's very kind difficult thing to talk about.
But let me show you with concrete memory address proof that they are pointing to the same pet class
allowed.
OK.
So we have two pets we have cat and cat has a name which is blue and then we have dog.
Another instance of pet and dog has a name which is why it so they have your own individual copies of
name they are instance attributes and then we saw pet dot aloud which is a class attribute.
But the thing is that cat actually has its own attribute called aloud and dog has an attribute called
aloud as well.
And they are not unique individual copies and to prove to you and I'm talking about there's this function
called ID.
We haven't really seen before but if I run cat that allowed this is going to give me the unique ID that
Python assigns things.
So look at this number here.
Don't memorize it or anything but I'm going to do the same thing with dog allowed.
OK.
And they are identical.
And one more thing for a change to pet that allowed.
They are all the same.
So what this shows this is that cat that allowed dog that allowed pet dog allowed all point they all
refer to the exact same pet class attribute.
There's only one allowed attribute even though it's kind of weird.
And this is something that's somewhat unique to Python at least compared to some of the other languages
I've worked with personally where the actual instances still can access allowed.
You don't have to go through Kapilow pet.
You can go through the instance but this is just a reference to pet dog allowed hence the little arrow
here and that does mean that inside of our class I could create the class attribute allowed and refer
to it using self that allowed like this instead of pet that allowed.
I prefer to do that allowed.
It makes it very clear that this is a class attribute.
But self would work here as long as we're not updating or assigning value to self-taught allowed.
We're just accessing it.
It's going to access pet allowed.
But the moment I do something like this so we have pet that allowed already this list and we have cat
that allowed if I change to cat allowed to now be a list that just contains Tiger and bear like this.
And I look at Cat aloud it's now Tiger Mbare.
And if I look at pet that allowed there they're not the same thing anymore.
So what I've done is actually made an instance attribute called aloud and set it to this only on cat.
So dog allowed is still referring to the class attribute.
Oh I am worried about this explanation it's kind of a lot I'm saying aloud a lot.
It really doesn't seem like a real word to me anymore.
Repeated it too much but hopefully this right here helps illustrate my point that the individual instances
are referring to the pet attribute on the pet class and that when we set cat up allowed to Tiger and
bear we overrode this arrow we kind of severed this connection and we gave cat its own version of allowed
but dog is still pointing to the pet class.
To summarize everything we've seen in this video has and a lot of class attributes exist on the class
you can use them for things like keeping track of analytics or you know a count of how many instances
have been created.
You can use them for things like validations as we've seen here.
However if we were only using this once when you know a new pet was initialized it would be better to
not make it a class attribute just put it in this method and it goes away after the method is done just
like any other method or function we've defined.
But because we wanted to use it more than once we use it down here as well.
And on top of that we don't need a unique version of this and every single instance of pet We made it
a class variable that exists once.
OK.
This is kind of long.
I apologize for that.
There's a lot to talk about here.
Next up if you get more practice to finding your own another class and another class with a class attribute.