Welcome back.
In this video we're going to do a slightly more complex example.
And I'm also going to show you how groups work in Python when we're working with rejects.
So the rejects we're going to use I've already written it out.
It's based off of some things that I found on mine.
It has to do with you or else so let me zoom in a bit.
OK.
What it states is that every you know needs to start with HTP and then an optional s because some will
be HTP as others won't they'll just be HGP.
Then we have colon slash slash BW And then the dot which we have to escape.
So it's the backslash dot.
Then there I found this out between 2 and 256 characters for the D.
What would you call it the domain name Google Gmail whatever the domain name is you to me.
And it's upper case lower case letters and dashes to to 256 followed by another dot.
So this is going to be you know HTP colon slash slash WW.
Google dot and then for the com for the top level domain it's two to six letters that are lowercase.
And then afterwards.
So let me just type something that matches that should be a match.
But then this entire large chunk at the end notice there's a star at the end which means zero or more
optional.
And these are any additional characters that could come afterwards like Slash search slash.
I don't know.
Q Do you have a question mark for the query string question mark Q equals taco's or something.
This all matches this is after the column.
So these are the allowed characters there we can have ampersands have question marks.
Yeah I didn't write this all from scratch.
I found somebody who knew more about it than I do about what characters are allowed.
So this is our rejects and it will match things ranging from that to simpler.
Yes you know cat.
I know that is also a match.
OK so I'm going to copy it over here to Python.
Me wrap the whole thing in quotes make it our raw string.
Notice how it changed.
There were some problems here and that are oh I just broke it.
There you go.
And yeah it looks good.
OK.
What we're going to do is to compile
that string a giant regular expression save that let's just call this you Arel rejects equals.
OK.
So now what I want to focus on is that there's a lot of components to this you know.
And we can start by just you know doing what we've already seen matching a string which is just your
average x dot search and then let's just see if we do HTP colon slash slash BW dot.
Oh was that YouTube dot com slash videos or something like that but save that variable.
And then let's print match dot group and just make sure that it works and when I run my file I call
that you are elde up Hawai and it works fine to the match.
OK.
What I really want to focus on however is if I was just showing you you know how to do a slightly more
advanced regular expression this is kind of just review of what we've seen so far.
But I want to show you what happens when we add parentheses in here to add groups.
Imagine that we have a bunch of you are Elves but say we're building some sort of application where
users submit you URLs.
And I wanted to take some sort of I want to do some analytics on I want to keep track of how many links
are coming from YouTube.
How many sites are HTP versus HEG.
Yes.
I want to just break things up.
So I want to know that this is a valid you Arel which right now it is matching the entire thing.
But what if I also wanted to know in particular what was the base domain.
So ignoring everything after this dot com ignoring whatever random stuff comes afterwards I just want
to know what the base domain was.
I think it's called based on me and I'm going to call it that.
And I want to keep track of that for the district's purposes or because I want to go you know go get
an icon for YouTube to match this you are well let's just let's just go with it and say that's what
I want to do.
Well it's not too difficult.
All we do is put parentheses around anything that we want to group and you little piece of data that
we want to extract separately.
And we saw that if we go back all the way back here if I put parens around a start after the dot to
do including the w w w w w and then after the dot com or dot org or whatever the top level domain is.
And now I add in you are el HTP colon to slash slash.
Google dot com slash blaw takes a moment it matches the whole thing.
But then also I'm getting this google.com as it separate.
Match capture.
So I could add another one in.
Let's say I want to know if it's HTP or HTP S P S.
There we go.
Now it's telling me all right the first thing that you put Prendes around it matched HGP.
And the second one you put Prince around matched GWW Google dot com.
OK.
Let's go back to Python now and do the same thing.
So we'll have our first group just to know you know the protocol if it's HTP or age.
Let's say we're just trying to keep track of that for some reason just just go with me with this example.
And then here we'll wrap it around WMW all the way to here which is the top level domain dot com dot
net dot us and let's do one at the end as well just so you can see this movie anything after the dot
com or whatever the top level domain is the query string an additional path other information in the
URL.
And now if I still if I print matched out group nothing should change.
It still gives me the entire match.
So I'm not saying you know I'm not altering the behavior of that but if I instead do matched up groups
with an s.
So actually let me do both I'll do group first and then groups first.
It gives me the whole match.
But now it's giving me this tuple that has my first group which was the protocol.
The second one which was you know the whatever we're calling this the base you r l b w w d u tube Delcam
and the third one was the additional information.
So I've extracted those separately now you can imagine you could do the same thing with the phone number
if you want to grab the area code separate so that you could try and figure out you know most your users
where are they coming from what area codes.
And you know assemble them or do some sort of analysis on that or email addresses you want to extract
you know what provider people are using the most is that Gmail is at Yahoo.
I assume it's Gmail but you could still find that out.
Also I'm going to comment this one out.
If we pass in a number to match that group like one and I refresh or redo my code you'll see that it's
giving me the first group.
The behavior is slightly weird here.
I'm going to just copy this a couple times in a Doomadgee group at 0 1 2 and 3 to lead you to print
here.
So a matched group of 0 is going to give me the entire match.
It's the same as just doing Match.com group like this.
But if I pass in a one that's going to give me the first item I kind of don't like that it's set up
like this personally because everything else in Python starts counting at zero.
But this is how it is.
Let's look at it.
OK.
So zero gave us the entire string that matched.
Then we had the first item which was the protocol then the domain and then everything else.
So if we wanted to we could do something I'll just fast forward through this just a sec.
Ok I'm back.
I mean delete this one.
All that I did was just add some strings just to print out nicely the protocol and then the domain and
then everything else separated.
And if I run it there we go.
It's pulling those pieces separately.
Let's just test it with a different string Now now let's do HGP s GWW dot.
I don't know.
I keep doing Google.
How about my web site.
Com that's put a dash in there because that's allowed.
And let's add a query string and so slash by no question mark data equals law.
And I don't know.
Equals.
Yes but stewed dog been doing too much cat stuff recently.
OK let's test it out.
There we go.
Protocols HTP s.
Here's the domain.
And then here's everything else.
OK.
So that all has to do with adding parentheses around.
Pieces of our rejects pattern so that we can access them later individually.
Now remember this gives us everything just some that up.
It gives us oh well actually that's groups.
Sorry about that if I do group.
This gives us everything in a tuple using groups.
But if I do group or group 0 it gives us the entire match and that's pretty much it.