Get this video has no new information in it.
So skip it if you don't care.
But I do feel like there's so much coverage in this section.
It would be nice to have a little recap video.
Or you could just check out the recap slide so we covered all the ground.
We started by talking about the basics of lists.
We saw how to make a simple list.
They are a fundamental data structure for any ordered information.
So there's a key thing.
The order remember all lists are indexed starting at zero.
Lists can be any type even other lists which we just saw nested lists so we can have strings in there
we can have numbers we can booleans other lists.
Want to talk about dictionaries.
Anything and they don't all have to be homogenous we can have a string and then a number and then a
nested list we can modify this with a ton of list methods that we saw we can add to them with things
like impend we can remove from them with things like pop we can sort them reverse them.
There's a whole bunch of things we saw slices are their own sort of beast which are ways of dividing
up while their way of taking and copying sections of lists.
You could copy the entire list.
You could go from the middle to the end go from the beginning to the middle but then only do every other
index slices or their whole thing miscomprehension it was another big topic and it's used everywhere
in Python when it Szeryng iterating over lists strings and ranges and even more data types like dictionaries
so we haven't discussed yet.
And we can use them to create duplicate lists we can use the list comprehension to create a duplicate
that modifies a list by multiplying every number or adding conditional logic.
There's a lot of things we can do and then we talked about ness of this.
They are essential for building more complex data structures things like gameboard modeling real world
data chart data tabular data matrices.
And then finally we talked about swapping and swapping is just a nice useful trick that you can use
to just swap elements in a list.
Use the comma to separate them and then equals to assign new values.
And it's something we use when when you shuffle lists or sort them and write our own algorithms.
OK that's a lot lot.
In this section.
So I recommend that you practice if if you're feeling weak on list comprehension with nested lists and
conditionals.
That's OK.
If the syntax isn't quite sitting right with you yet don't panic but make sure you're good with the
basics of lists using list methods.
Slices the basics of list comprehension accessing nested loops and the basics of swapping and then move
on and celebrate that we're done with lists but also we're not because we're going to use them in everything
from here on out.
Anyway I'll stop talking.
Congratulations.
Hopefully you survived.