Hey welcome back.
So we've seen how to define a class with instance attributes and instance methods.
Then we saw how to use class attributes.
So the next logical step is to see class methods and I'll start off by saying that these are actually
pretty rare in the wild.
They're not all that commonly used instance methods are used by far more often like 50 maybe 100 times
as often.
In my experience at least most of this stuff will be writing or instance methods.
But with that said it's good that you know how to write a class method and you'll know how to recognize
one if you see it on something else that you didn't write.
So let's just dive into it.
Class methods are methods that are not concerned with specific instances but with the class itself.
So just like a class attribute is not concerned with individual you know specifics of a given instance
of that class it's concerned with the class itself.
Same thing with class methods.
And because of this there are a lot less commonly used and frankly less useful but sometimes there's
some functionality that doesn't care about the instances it doesn't matter about the specifics of a
given user or a given pet or ored card deck or poker hand and it's concerned with the whole concept
of a poker hand or a user.
And so that could go on the class.
So I'll show you an example.
Before we go any further you might have noticed I skipped this little parent that ocal here when I was
reading it out loud.
So class methods or methods with the at class method decorator.
So we haven't talked about decorator's yet.
Basically all say about it for now.
It's a little bit of Python magic.
Syntactic sugar.
So what people would call it that goes in front of a class method.
So this here's a class method.
Don't worry about what it does.
But notice that this at class method is on the line in front of it and or before it and that signifies
that the next method is actually a class method not an instance method.
So by default to make something in an instance method we don't do anything special because are just
so much more commonly used.
It made sense to make that the default.
And when you do need a class method you preface it with at class method just like this in a bit we'll
actually learn how to define our own decorator's.
This is a decorator here and you'll come to understand how this works and what it's doing behind the
scenes.
For now though let's just consider it Python magic that makes this a class method.
OK.
So let's actually define our own.
Here I have that same user class we've been working with.
I just made a new file called class methods.
Why copy this in.
So I'm going to show you two examples of class methods.
The first is going to be a simpler example.
That's not all that realistic.
And the second is going to be a more commonly use or more common use case for class methods.
But it's a little harder to grasp.
So I'm going to start with a basic one.
We have this class attribute active users we could define a method that would just return of 0 statement
that says how many active users there are at any given time.
So first up let's talk about where to define class methods.
There's not actually a standard like for many other things.
You know these magic methods that Dunner methods should go up top.
They don't have to but they should.
And that's kind of accepted as common and convention with class methods.
There isn't an equivalent style.
So it's up to you but you should just be consistent for now.
Just because these files are educational I'm going to put the new stuff up top so you don't have to
scroll to the bottom to see any of the new class methods.
But that's not me saying that every class method should go at the top of every class.
OK.
So we could define a class method.
We start with this class method at class method decorator and then we define the name of the function
and the method must just call this one display.
Active Users or something.
And the thing about class methods automatically the class is going to be passed in this method whenever
we call it.
So rather than self just like down here Python automatically passes in the instance of the user and
calls itself as a parameter.
Here we could name this self.
Remember the name doesn't actually matter.
But the standard is to go with CLX for class.
So this signifies to us that what we'll be working with inside of this method is not an instance it's
the actual class.
So if I just did a print CLX here you'll actually see that Skelos is the class user not an instance
of user.
So let me just show you that.
Now to call class methods.
Let's go down.
I have two users I can call user one dot what we call that display active users.
But I also can do user display capital you user and that's what I prefer because it makes it clear that
we're calling a class method has nothing to do with this instance.
So we can technically do this and I'll show you both.
Let's start with this one.
Just print user display active for users and need purines of course to execute it.
And there you go.
You can see that CLX the parameter what was passed in was the actual class user.
It's not an instant.
You don't see that whole object id thing with all those numbers afterwards like we would if we printed
self-oust.
And just to show you we can do the exact same thing.
I actually don't need to print this because I'm calling print in there execute it now we get the same
thing.
So either syntax to call it we can call the instance dot class method or the class named class method
either way because we defined it as a class method the class will be the first argument that's passed
in.
In this case user.
So as far as some functionality here we could just do a return to an F string and we'll just return
how many users there are.
So we'll say something like.
There are ups I don't want that inside those braces.
There are currently and then in the Brace's reference CLX active users just like that.
And after that what we want let's say active users.
There are currently three active users something like that.
So now to print that comment that out or delete that will make two users.
And now we can use to use or not display active users we need to print the whole thing and then let's
do it twice and make two more users afterwards.
And before I forget we need print to execute that.
And if we call it now we get there are currently two active users.
Then we created two more users than there are currently four active users.
So that is a very simple class method.
It could be a class method in this case because it doesn't rely on any information that is particular
to an instance.