All right.
So in this video we'll build a potential solution to the guessing game mini project.
If you were able to get that without too much difficulty you may not want to watch the entire video.
You could skip to the end and I do have some some notes on potential ways of structuring this that are
better than others.
It's it's opinion but you may want to take a look or you can just look at my solution code.
And if you struggled with it you may want to watch most of this video if not the whole thing.
I'll walk through it step by step.
Let's head over to the starter code and the first thing we have here the random number that the code
to generate the random numbers from 1 to 10.
I won't go into much detail at all but basically it gives us a number from 1 to 10.
So let's just make sure of that.
Let's try running this I get 7 10 and you can trust.
Oh there we go included one in 10 as well.
So it is inclusive.
Drives me insane ranges.
Our exclusive rant is inclusive.
I don't know why.
So now that we have a number picked.
Really our logic that we need to happen is we need to check is that guess what we need to get a user
guess first.
So that's going to be the easiest part will do.
Guess equals input and then to say pick a number from 1 to 10 out of space.
So it's a little easier for the user to tell.
And after that our logic is really to check if they guessed correct.
So if a random number and guess are the same or is guess less than random number we tell them to low.
If gas is greater we'll tell them too high.
So just a simple conditional statement that we can add in.
So let's just do let's not even worry about the loop and getting things to repeat.
Let's just start off with if guess equals equals the random number.
Exactly.
We'll print you've got it
elif.
If gas is less than random number will print too low.
And finally we can just do an else because there's no other option.
We'll print too high.
So this should work one time through.
But there is a problem which you hopefully are getting more accustomed to this.
We have a type issue.
So if I run this he asked me to pick a number or type 3 and it says less then the operator is not supported
between strings and ints.
So this is still a string.
So I need to convert gas to an end so I'll just do it.
Guess And now let's actually at the end let's print what guess or excuse me random number is so we can
tell if our logic is correct.
So I'm going to pick five and it tells me to high and the number was supposed to be 4.
Let's do a pick one tells me to low.
It is supposed to be three and who knows.
Let's see if I can actually get one right.
Probably not but we'll trust that our logic works if I do guess correctly OK.
I won't waste time with that.
So we're getting too low correct and too high.
When are supposed to.
So now what we need to happen is we want to repeat this process.
And when do we want to repeat it how long are we gonna repeat it.
We want to keep going Intel guess is equal to a random number.
So that's kind of itself to a wild whoop.
We could I guess you could use a for loop although it wouldn't really work because while technically
we could assume that a user only needs a maximum of 10 guesses so we could loop through with a for loop
10 times and then break out when they get it right.
But that that I don't know a user could forget something or be distracted and guess the same number
multiple times in which case they would potentially make more than 10 guesses.
So a for loop is not the best option.
Also with a for loop if we wanted to suddenly expand our game to go from 1 to 100 We would also have
to not only change the random number but change the for loop itself.
So a while loop is much better when we don't know how many times something will run.
While loop is always better.
So what we'll do is we'll run this while guess is not equal to random number.
We'll keep going and we can get rid of this.
And the first thing we'll do is while the guess is not equal to the random number we're going to ask
them for a new guess.
And we'll check if guess I mean and everything.
If guess is less than the random number or print to well you and Aliff guess is greater than random
number some switching things up just a little bit.
Well print too high and then we'll do an else and we'll print you one.
There is a problem here which maybe you have spotted which is the very first time we run this guess
is undefined.
So we move the code into the loop because we want to continually ask every time inside the loop for
a new guess but that leaves I copied it.
Eric cut it out from up top.
So the first time guess doesn't exist.
It's going to try and compare something that doesn't exist to a random number.
So that's going to be a problem.
I'll show you the error we get we go invalid.
No no that's not the same error.
That's because I forgot my lovely Colon's Rico.
Now we should get the error I'm expecting.
Here we go.
Guess it's not defined.
So what we could do is just start by setting guess you go to an empty string or something or two none.
And if I do it now.
Pick a number from 1 to 10.
Let's go with five to high.
OK.
1.
Oh I guessed it and you could see afterwards.
It tells us the the number was 1.
We still have this print at the bottom.
Let's do one more.
Let's pick five again.
Got it right off the bat.
Five two high.
Let's go with one two low three.
I won.
Cool.
So that's the basics of the guessing game actually.
This is the simplest possible solution we could do where we repeating things and the game runs one time.
So as soon as we win it's over.
So the last thing I'll show is a version where the game keeps going.
It asks the user you want to keep playing.
And they type Y or and or yes or no or something like that.
So what I'll do is actually make a new file.
I'll just call it guessing V-2 and I'll duplicate my code over there.
But there's a couple of changes I'm going to make and the first thing I'm going to do is change is actually
quite a bit.
I mean do a while true so this will loop forever.
But then what we'll do is in this else here where the user won or where they win the game it won't break
out of the loop dead.
But I'm going to ask the user.
So let's call it a variable called Play again.
Equals input.
And what am I doing as a string input.
Do you want to play again.
And then we'll do.
This is kind of standard to see in terminal y slash n and they just type Y or and hit enter and then
we'll just add a conditional if.
Play it again.
Don't need those parentheses although they won't hurt if it equals Y.
If that's the case what are we going to do.
We're going to generate a new number.
So this line right here OK.
And we'll set user I guess or in our case guess to be numb again.
Otherwise that means eight types and or anything else.
Technically what will we do.
We're going to quit so we can print.
Thank you for playing
and then break and that's it.
So let's see if it works.
Q They included all the cones would be needed this time for if and or else.
OK let's see what happens.
Python 3 guessing V-2 Oh I thought I'd check for those Colon's this is.
That's pretty bad.
I apologize.
OK let's try that again.
OK.
So pick the number let's go five again.
It says I won right away.
I want to play again.
Yes.
Picks another number list five again this time on to low.
About nine to high.
Eight to seven.
So it must be 6.
And I won.
Do I want to play again one more time.
Pick number from 1 to 10.
One two three four five six seven and I won.
This time I'm done playing.
And I'm out.
Cool.
So one small change we could make.
We no longer have to initialize guests appear because our while loop is not depending on guests anymore
like it was over here because this is just a while true it keeps going forever until it hits this break.
So the difference is that this is going to play as many games as the user wants.
This one plays one game so it loops through until they get it right.
This one loops forever until we quit and that's it for our guessing game.
So next up we're going to take our rock paper scissors game and make it I think a lot better.
Similar idea.
We're going to make the game repeat and we'll actually have a winner and a loser.
We'll keep score.
You'll be able to play against the computer rather than just playing one time and having it end.
He'll be able to know who gets two out of three or who wins the first five or whatever it is.
So it's a lot better in my opinion.
So that's coming up next.