Hey welcome back.
So pushing on with tuples we're going to talk about iterating over tuples and then also the two built
in methods they come with.
So first up we've already seen how to iterate with tuples.
You may not have thought about it at the time but when we use items and we did a for loop with you know
dictionary items we are actually using tuples already but technically that items returns a list where
each value pair key value pair is its own tuple instead of a list.
But we can just iterate directly over a tuple using the exact same syntax as a list.
Nothing changes just looks like this.
So if we could have a tuple of names for name and names.
Print the name and that's it.
Very straightforward.
We could do for month and months print a month just like that and that's it.
I think I already have months loaded up here.
So if I just hit enter.
There we go.
We get every month printed out and that's all there is to using a for loop.
We can also use a while loop.
So also how to print them out backwards.
So we would start with a variable and we'll just call it.
I started at the last index so that's going to be the length of months but we need to do minus one because
the length is going to be 12.
The highest index is 11.
And then we'll just do well high is greater than or equal to zero.
And we don't have to have those parentheses.
While that's the case we're just going to print months of I and then most importantly we need to decrement
in this case because we're going backwards.
So let's see what happens.
Make sure don't have any syntax errors.
And there we go.
We get December down to January.
So that's that for iterating Now as far as methods we get for free with tuples.
There's actually just two.
So it's pretty quick.
The first is count which we've already seen as well.
It just returns a number of times that value is in a tuple.
So here's an example.
Three is in here three times.
We have one and two if I tried to extort count one tells me it's in there one time for track that count
three tells me it's in there three times.
And that's that's it.
It's nice and straightforward.
I could demonstrate it but I think it would be a waste your time.
And then index which you've also seen so index will just tell us the index that a given value is found
inside of a tuple.
So if we have the same table and I want to know k where is the the index of 1 inside of this tuple.
It gives me 0 because I said this year with index if I try and ask for the index here's something that's
not in the list.
It will give me a value error.
So it doesn't return false or something it gives you an error.
And if I try next to something that's in there or I want to know the first index of something that's
in there multiple times like three it will only give me the first matching index and that's that for
the method.
Just a couple quick things to cover.
You can have nested tuples so I could do something like this is not going to be a very good example
but I had a list and I could do one two three and then have four comma five and there come a six.
If I wanted to and if I hit enter here you'll see that everything looks fine.
We have a tuple instead of a tuple.
If I wanted to do something like Nom's zero I get one.
But if I do.
Number three it gives me four or five.
So if I wanted to get 5 out of there I would need to do 0 1 just like this.
So just like nested this same thing is totally fine.
Also I should mention we we also can use slices.
So if I do.
Zero colon number that goes in the beginning to the end.
If I did something like 0 2 4 it goes from 0 up to the fourth index next year 1 two three four non-inclusive
and we could also you know use a step like this and that gives us every other value added for tuple.
So slices also work.
So that's pretty much it to tuples.
It really comes down to the fact that there like a list except the lighter weight.
They take up less space but they are much less flexible because they're immutable.
You cannot change them.
So it's really just best for data that you know is not going to change that order does matter.
And you want it stored in some sort of list like object but you don't want to go for a full blown most
then use a tuple call.
Next up will see sets.