Hey welcome back.
So as I mentioned in the last video we're going to start by focusing on projects regular expressions
in isolation outside of Python outside of any programming language.
Just practice them mean to show you a tool in the browser that's really useful.
It allows you to live and test things out and on and test strings and see how your regex works.
If it works the way you want it to.
OK.
But to start just a warning or a disclaimer there are a ton of reject symbols characters special little
bits of logic and information that you could know about and that you could use.
I'm just going to cover some important ones.
I could go on for like five six seven hours probably at least make a separate course on projects.
I'm just going to cover some of the basics and the most useful things.
And also you know I'm no rejects expert what I do most of the time if I need a regular expression I
start building it on my own but then if there's something that I feel like I don't know what the heck
I'm doing I go and Stack Overflow I see what other people have done.
You don't want to you know try validating a credit card on your own.
If someone else has done it and they know a lot more about how credit card numbers should be formatted
what they should look like.
So I'm not trying to you know come off as some guru of regular expressions.
Honestly I usually will use something else I found online or somebody else's regular expression unless
I'm doing something very unique that other people haven't done.
In which case I just pull up the docs or I look at this page the rejects cheat sheet there's a bunch
of these online.
But if I scroll down you can see these are all special characters and symbols and things that we can
do in regular expressions.
Put them all together.
I mean there's there's a lot here.
So we're not going to go over all of them but I am going to point out some important ones and to start.
I'm on a web page called Pipex.
If you just Google regular expression editor right rejects a browser there's tons of these out there.
But I like this one it just has simple pretty interface and it is tailored for Python regular expressions
as I've said a couple of times are separate entities away from any programming language but they have
kind of slight flavors in different languages so a python regex there might be some small distinctions
from a javascript regular expression.
So it's better to use something that is python specific even though we're not writing any Python yet.
OK.
So the way this this works by the way we have test strings down here are a giant test string.
I'm going to fast forward and put a bunch of text in here.
OK.
So I have some sample text so we're going to work with.
Now up here is where we define our patterns our regular expressions that will be tested against this.
So it's just a live editor a life way of seeing things and matches will be displayed down here.
So before we learn any of the complex symbols or the special syntax if we just put a single letter in
here you would never you probably wouldn't do this with the.
But if we just wanted to find all matches for the letter D for example I can just type the letter D
and you can see down here it's highlighting for me the first match the second the third the fourth match
and the fifth match.
And all on the screen.
Hopefully this is big enough for you to see that they've all been highlighted so I could also just tack
on another D.
Now it's only going to find matches where there are two D's in a row which is right here.
Same thing with three Ds for example or what else can we do.
I only want to find D's that are preceded by a C C D.
That's what I get here.
So the point is you can just type regular characters in here if I wanted to find matches for cats it's
nice and simple.
I want to find a smiley face.
It's not as simple.
And that's because I'm using a parentheses which has a special use.
So the first little magic symbol I'll show you this is just like in Python if you want to escape the
meaning the special meaning of a character.
Like if you want to add a new line in Python use backslash and same thing here we use backslash Pirenne
or what we'll see later backslash dot.
If I just do dot on its own it has its own special meaning that matches everything.
Which is what it means.
Just match anything.
But if we add backslash dot it only matches an actual period as you can see there.
OK so getting ahead of myself.
I just wanted to show you that you type letter in here or a word I capital I with a space I added a
space after I get this.
Notice that it doesn't highlight when I do I doesn't I like this because it is case sensitive.
There's an option here we can tell it to ignore case.
That's something you can do in Python as well.
But for now just be aware of it.
OK.
So let's talk about our first batch of rechecks syntax.
So there are special characters they all or most of them that we're going to see.
Start with the backslash here.
So if you wanted to match a number any number containing 0 9 that's all of them so far as I know we
can use backslash lowercase D.
So if I wanted to do that now I can do a single one like backslash D that will match 40 or 4 and 9.
It's hard to tell that they are separate matches.
What's the best way of doing this.
Let me do a couple more.
She is 49 years old.
I am six seventy five years old.
He is three OK.
So all of these there's five matches here.
But if I only want to match people who are double digits people who are you know teenagers or above
I could do two backslash D's in a row and now I have to find a pattern any digit from 0 to 9 followed
by another digit zero tonight.
And they have to be touching one another.
So if I had you know three space three for some reason it doesn't count and thus I had a space in here
it's literal.
So that's backslash.
D stands for digit.
We also have things like backslash W. which is a letter digit or underscore I think it stands for word
character.
So if I just do a single one of those backslash back slash double you can see it matches almost everything
that doesn't match the dots the for the sign or the smiley face because those aren't considered words
character so was any letter uppercase or lowercase any number and underscore.
Next we have backslash s.
Well that stands for whitespace character.
So you saw me doing things with a space where I did you know one word.
Let's do one word character followed by another word character with a space in between.
And that works.
But you can also use backslash S which matches things like tabs.
And I think new lines as well.
If you ever have questions find any cheat sheet like this one as mentioned.
Scroll down find a backslash and it tells us any whitespace character and gives you an example.
And it's just generally useful.
So if I change this to be a word character followed by backslash s and then another word character can
see you know it's highlighting things correctly or getting a space in between but it also matches things
where there's a character and then a new line and then another character.
So that backslash as is matching that new line.
And if I had a tab in here it would also match that.
But I don't have tabs.
OK.
So that's the first three.
They also have reverse analogues inverses I don't know what the correct terminology is.
Use a capital letter and they are the negated version so not in the capital D.
Backslash capital-T is anything that's not a digit.
Same thing with W..
Capitalize it means not a word character s not a whitespace character.
So back here let's go with backslash.
Capital W..
And that gives us anything that is not a word character remember a word character was any number any
letter capital or lower case.
And what is an underscore.
So here we're getting all the spaces we're getting.
The smiley face the at symbol the periods.
Those are not word characters or if I do backslash capital D It gives me anything that is not a digit
number from 0 to 9.
So that gives us everything else.
Same thing backslash as capital.
Everything that is not is space.
So let's say I want it to match all five letter words five five letters only.
So I could use or numbers I could do backslash W for the first character and then and the second one
and the third one and the fourth one then the fifth one.
But I want them to be five letter words not you know these are being matched because those five word
characters in a row.
But it's part of a giant string.
So instead we could bookend it on either side.
We could do a space like that.
But the problem there let's see if I add a space here this is five letters but it's not being highlighted
because there is not a space afterwards.
So instead of using spaces get rid of that I'm going to use whitespace characters.
Now you can see we're successfully getting the words that are five letters long not substrings of bigger
words and includes things that end on a line that are the end of the line.
Notice it does you know we're selecting the spaces.
And if we were trying to just extract the words we'd have to do some some extra logic and we'll learn
how to do that later in this section.
But for now we are matching that pattern.
Then finally the dot I told you it has a special meaning.
It means any character except a line break.
We saw that earlier in the video.
So it's sort of like a wild card anything except a new line.
OK.
So that's the first batch of regular expression characters are going to look at.
We have a couple more in the next video and one more video after that then we're going to move to Python
and.