OK so the last thing to discuss are on parameters and arguments are what's called keyword arguments.
So let me just show an example here we have a function called full name.
It has two parameters.
First and last whatever usually is passed in first is going to be assigned to first and the second argument
would be assigned to last.
However using keyword arguments we can actually specify directly inside of the function call.
So let's take a look at this example right here.
I'm specifying let's call full name and I want last to be steal the parameter last should have the value
still.
Never mind the fact that first is listed first in the function declaration.
I want last to be steel and first to be caught and we get the exact same result as if we had just pass
code then you don't know why use my name again.
Gets kind of dull.
So both of these examples return the exact same thing.
And also this first example if we just left off first equals and last equals and just add cold to combis
deal would also print the same thing.
So keyword arguments just allow us to specify if we know the name of the parameters.
So it only works if we know the name of the parameters.
But we can specify which argument corresponds to which particular parameter.
So the order doesn't matter anymore.
So back in this xponent example where we have no in power power has a default value.
If I wanted I could do print xponent and let's say I wanted to do three and set that to be power and
then numb is four.
So in this example even though I'm passing three in first it's going to be assigned to power and then
four will be assigned to No.
And so then the result of this should be four cubed which is what four times four times for 64.
Let's double check here.
So that's just called exponent and there we go.
We get 64 so we could also do the exact same thing but switch the order and get the exact same result.
So all this is just to show you that using keyword arguments by specifying the exact names of the parameters
we can alter the order that things are passed in.
Also it just makes things if we look at you know the function call here is very clear what's happening
where it's maybe people would argue even though it's more syntax it's more legible as far as how this
works than just for number three because here you it's not clear you know what's the number what's the
power.
Here it's very explicit.
So let's just double check.
We get 64 twice.
It works exactly the same way.
So why would you use keyword arguments.
Well aside from what we've already talked about which is it adds some flexibility.
You know we can change the order we pass things in in.
It also will become a lot more valuable later on when we talked about passing a dictionary to a function
and unpacking the values from a dictionary.
That's all I'll say about it for now when we get to functions Part 2 which is coming up after we do
a bunch of exercises after this section we'll learn more about passing a dictionary to a function and
unpacking it.
The last point I want to hit home is that even though it does use an equal sign it is very different
from default perhaps.
So when you define a function and you put an equal sign in the function definition you are setting a
default parameter when you invoke a function and you use an equal sign.
You are making a keyword argument.
So here's an example again the same full name function.
But this time we've given a default parameter first defaults to cold last defaults to steal.
So this is what we've already seen a couple of videos ago.
The default value.
COLD STEEL.
So if we just call full name on it's own and don't pass any arguments and we get your name as cold steel
because these default in this case we are using keyword arguments what we're what we learned in this
video where I can explicitly say last is supposed to be enthusiast first is supposed to be Python.
So that allows us to switch the order up.
Not that you know there's a real compelling reason to do that here but just to show you this is different
than this.
These are two completely different features of Python functions even though they both use an equal sign
depending on the context and makes a big difference.
Default values default parameters appear in the function declaration down here keyword arguments when
we actually execute it.
All right.
Hopefully that makes sense.