Oh right we've made it through some of the tougher stuff in this section I'm looking at you.
Class methods.
That was a toughie.
And this quick video should be a nice breath of fresh air.
So it's all about a little magical method a Dunner method just like Annette called repr I think it stands
for either.
Why no sense for either represent or representation or potentially representative.
But I think it's representation what it does is it allows us to define a representation of an instance.
So in this case in this case human that when we print or turn a human into a string we can control what
it looks like.
So currently in our User class I'm working in a new file called repr.
Why if I just print Tom which is a user you've already seen this before we get this hideous looking
thing.
So with repr we can control.
We can return a string.
And that is what will actually be printed out so we can define it up top with all the other donder methods
I can get double underscore heart EPR.
It's an instance method so well yourself.
And for a user we could just return something simple like first name so self-taught first when you add
those brackets and then maybe an age just to do self that age just like that doesn't really matter.
But now this is important.
When I print a user we get Tom is 89 which maybe is not the best representation but hopefully you can
see how this can be useful but doesn't really unlock anything new but it just makes development easier
because we can come up with custom representations that when we print something that it also when we
turn the thing to a string which print is doing behind the scenes.
Let's say I make a new user called J.
ECOs user.
And let's not use from String class method.
Let's do user names.
JUDY STEEL is my mom and I don't want to say our age who get upset let's say she's 18.
Now if I print J will get the same thing but if I did J equals the string version of J.
And now I print J.
We'll also get the same thing.
And this just shows that when you print something Reppert is called and then return to me into a string
repr is called Behind the scenes as well.
So this repr method is not only something we define on our own.
For example take a list or a dictionary.
Those things when we get them printed out we get this little representation of them.
But remember there are actually instances of a class of the last class or the dictionary class and by
default they would look something like this.
But because of this a little bit of magic Python calls it's going to look for a way of turning it into
a readable format first and then printing that up.
OK.
So just so you know this is something you can do double underscore R E P R R.