Hello welcome back.
So this video is on a topic that I think is a little bit dreadfuls probably too strong of a word but
let's just say not exciting.
It's an important topic though and it's one that's going to come up a lot more when we talk about object
oriented programming and defining our own classes.
But it's a topic called scope and it basically refers to the fact that variables and properties in Python
are not always available in every single part of an application or an every single part of our code.
There are rules governing where our variables can be accessed and so far we haven't encountered any
problems because we haven't been working with multiple functions or nested functions or basically anything
that would cause scope issues.
So what I want to do in this video is just introduce the idea of scope.
Show you a couple of problems that arise with functions and solutions to get around them.
So the first thing to know is that in any function whenever we define a variable inside that function
it is scoped to that function meaning it's only available inside that function.
So here's an example.
In this case where this variable instructor is not defined inside of the function it's defined up top
outside.
And that's called in the global scope to come back to and inside of say hello.
I am just returning that value which should be called.
And then we run to say hello we get hello cold.
So this is should not be new but this example we have say hello where we're defining instructor inside
of say hello.
So it is scoped right here.
An instructor is only available inside the bounds of this function.
So up to here and afterwards so we can run say hello and it works.
It's going to print erve return.
Hello instructor.
But if I try and then print instructor directly I can't access the variable instructor.
Outside of this function.
So let me show you proof of that.
I have the same code here.
I have instructor defined inside of say hello and if I try and run this I get name.
Instructor is not defined as he can see here and let me actually change this of the instructor to an
instructor one and I'll have this equal to how about Mary and instructor to his colt so I can print
instructor one.
But if I try printing instructor too and I change this to be instructor too I should be able to print
instructor one afterwards but not instructor too.
And you can see I get Mary but then Python freaks out with instructor too because it only exists inside
of this function.
So this is a really important concept when you define a function and you have variables in there.
Whether it's instructor or a list or 20 other variables they are scoped to that function.
They're not available outside of it.
There are ways of having access to them outside of that exact function.
For example you can return them.
So here we're returning.
Well it's a string.
Hello instructor but we could also just return instructor and we would have access to it any time we
called to say hello we could save it to a variable.
But as far as talking about the strategies and structuring our programs I'm going to wait to handle
scope in that context until we talk about object oriented programming and classes.
So for now just know functions have their own scope and we can access variables outside of those functions
that are defined inside of a function.
Now next up is this thing called Global.
I talked about how there is a global scope.
So for example this variable right here is called Total.
It's not defined inside of a function.
This is every variable we've defined well pretty much every variable so far.
That's not in a function it is considered a global variable.
And there's a problem if I try and actually manipulate the global variable inside of a function like
I tried right here where I have a function increment and it just says OK take this variable total and
add 1 to it and then return total seems like that should work.
But it actually doesn't.
Here's proof for you.
It's the exact same code but try running it.
I get this error local variable total referenced before assignment and this actually tells us a lot.
It not only says that it can't find the variable total but it says that it's looking for a local variable.
So because we're inside of a function when we referenced total It assumes that there is a local variable
scoped to this function called total.
And the reason for this is that it's actually not really a good idea to use global variables.
Sometimes you need to but you want to minimize the number of them.
But that is for another conversation.
When we talk about object oriented programming.
So for now we do have global variables and if we need to have one if we needed something this is a silly
example because we don't have to have a global total we could move this inside.
But for now just to explain how all this works there is a way to tell Python don't look for a local
variable inside this function called Total look for a global variable called total and that looks like
this.
The global keyword.
So what this line says right here instead of the increment function it's basically saying whenever I
use the total variable name I'm actually referring to the global variable total.
So this one up here and we have to do this first before we can actually manipulate total.
So if we go back to our first little bit of code over here and I just add in global floatable global
total I'm saying hey guys inside this function total refers to this total the global one.
Now if I try executing it well we don't get an error.
Let's actually print out the results.
So print.
There we go.
And we now get the correct total which is 1.
And every time I run this in a stupid little function.
But I should increment total by 1 and then if we printed out we should see two and three and so on next
time.
So the key thing to takeaway here if I want to manipulate a variable that is not defined inside of this
function it's in the global scope.
I need to first tell Python what I'm referring to when I say total because by default it's looking inside
of this function exclusively to find something called Total.
The other thing I should mention if we're only doing this be common to all this out if I'm only trying
to access a value I'm not trying to change it.
So for example I have name set to Rusty and if I have a function that just says def greet and all that
it does is print name.
Very silly but if I called greeds just like this it's going to work just fine.
We're able to access the value.
I can say what is the value of the name variable.
And that works you can see we get rusty but as soon as I try and do something like name plus equals
steal I want to add my last name to Rusty and it run it.
Now we get the same problem name is not defined in the local scope.
Now if I did name equals rest steel if we take a look.
Now that should work just fine because I am defining a name variable in the local scope.
So if I don't care what was it what was in name before I could just overwrite it.
But if I'm trying to manipulate the existing value I need to first say global name like we did up here.
OK.
So that's that for global.
I know it's kind of weird heady stuff it's maybe not the most intuitive thing ever.
One last thing.
Talk about the scope.
And then we can take a breather.
There's another keyword called non local non-local.
Let us modify a parent's variables in a nested function.
So for example here I have a function called Outer with a variable set to count and then enter.
I'm able to access this count variable manipulate it because I've declared it as non local.
So it's very similar to global except count right here is not a global variable.
It's not defined in a global scope it's defined in the outer function's own scope.
So this keyword non-local basically says this variable count that I'm referring to from here on out
is not defined in inner and it's not defined in the global scope but it's find in a parent or some other
function that I'm nested inside of.
So we can take a deep breath because as this note indicates you'll know you will not find yourself using
global or non-local all that often but it may help illustrate how scope works.
And it's really important to understand the just the concept of scope that not every bit of data is
available everywhere in a Python application or program.
It really depends on how it's broken up into functions and then really into classes and objects which
will spend a lot of time talking about scope then.
So my advice to you is to not get too hung up on any of the stuff in this video.
I just wanted to kind of put it out there laid on the table say hey there's this thing called scope.
Don't freak out though because we all spend a lot of time with it.
What's most important at this point is getting comfortable with functions writing functions with parameters
and default parameters and return values and all of that.
OK.