Welcome back.
So the next big question is why aren't you programming and along with.
This video shows some of the first code that has to do with O.P. and also introduced two topics.
Two big ideas.
Encapsulation and abstraction.
But let's start by talking about why object oriented programming.
It's important to mention that O.P. doesn't allow us to do anything we couldn't do without opii it doesn't
unlike any doors or functionality that we didn't have before.
Remember plenty of programming languages out there don't even support O.P. period so they're capable
of doing the same thing at the end of the day can make a poker game and each language or each type o
p is just about how we structure things and organize things and it's really a human way of thinking
of creating these specifications and classifying things.
For example you know we have animals in this world right.
However many I don't know hundreds or thousands or millions probably millions of species but I don't
actually know.
We have all these species and they're all animals but we classify them into smaller groups.
We organize them.
That's a very human thing to do.
Well with O.P. we can do the exact same thing.
And this analogy isn't just limited to the idea of classifying things.
Actually if we take an example like this Redfox species is Vulpes VOLP as well.
Not only does it belong to species but it also at the same time is part of the full PPIs genus and the
mammalia class which in itself it's called the classicists same idea classifying things and it's in
the domain you Kerria.
So what this shows us is a topic we'll learn later on called inheritance where we can actually have
classes that are related to other classes.
So this one fox at the same time is a species it's also a mammal and you carry out an anyways or leave
it off there.
But I just wanted to show this analogy doesn't just end the idea of organizing things.
When we talk about inheritance this will actually show up again.
So O.P. is really just a nice thing we can do in our code.
That's what it comes down to.
So why is that it's easier for humans.
It's how we think it's easy to organize things.
It's nice and pretty and we put bows on things but it is not a fundamental thing you have to do to make
things work.
It's just to prevent yourself from going crazy and getting headaches and creating really long files.
It's just a way of breaking things up and or breaking them down and classifying them.
Earlier I mentioned the term encapsulation.
Here's for the first time it's going to show up.
The goal with O.P. is to encapsulate our code into a logical hierarchical groupings using classes.
So once we learn to define our own classes we'll be able to take giant application of that program whatever
it is and break it down and encapsulated into these individual classes.
Suppose we're making a poker game.
So we want to model Poker using Python.
We don't have to make any classes we don't have to do anything.
We don't even have to make functions if we wanted to you could do everything.
One line after another.
It would be very repetitious.
A lot of people would call it spaghetti code because the logic for poker is actually quite long to do
some of the comparisons to figure out what hand beats what.
But let's just not even get into that detail for now let's just say we are going the object oriented
route and we want to organize things into classes.
Here are some of the distinct entities we might come up with.
Oh that's a picture so he can have a game class.
So every time a new game started all the functionality and data superseded with a game is in a game
class then a game can have multiple players.
So each player has information like you know their name and their bank balance or their chips balance
and then we have things like a deck and a deck would have you know information about the cards.
So there would be a class for each card potentially a card would have a class.
I mean it suits a color red or maybe just suit.
And then a value is it a king or seven or an ace and then a deck would consist of or at one point would
have 52 cards in it.
Or more depending on how many decks were playing with.
And then you know a poker hand would consist of multiple cards and chips potentially bets.
There's so many things we could do.
Maybe we're playing on teams so we could create a team class.
It's really totally up to us.
And that's where the bulk of the challenge with O.P. comes in is that it's about figuring out what needs
to be its own class.
So it's not always about making every single possible thing in class because if there's going to be
just one property in there one attribute and no functions then maybe it doesn't need to be a class.
So it's really that's kind of the skill of it and we'll talk a lot more about that.
But I don't want to just show you a slide here.
I want to actually show you a quick example.
So here in this file called Poker duppy why I have a half baked representation not using O.P. just using
functions and that's it to model decks of cards so we have cards and a deck of cards.
So the first thing I'll show you there's a function called Reset deck and all it does is it returns
a big list of cards.
And I didn't even go with 52 I just did 24 cards.
You can see each card has a value like Ace in a suit hearts.
And then the ace of diamonds three of hearts.
And so on.
And then we're just putting them all together into a giant list and returning that at the end.
So then to start a new game or to make a deck I would call poker deck equals reset deck.
And that gives me this right here.
OK then let's say I want to shuffle the deck.
Well we have a shuffle method from random.
So then I can just call random dot shuffle and I pass in the deck.
So we're passing deck in poker deck itself is simply a list its class is a list.
So no O.P. yet then I have a function called Deal hand and it's up here and what it does is it takes
in a list of cards and then a number of cards to deal.
And so it will take let's say I pass in my poker deck and then I tell it to five cards are playing to
I don't know five card draws.
It is called.
I don't play that much poker anymore.
So we want to deal five cards off the deck and it returns two things.
The deck which has been altered it has five fewer cards.
And then the hand the five cards that came off and we could return those as a tuple and then down here
when I call deal hand I can assign poker deck to be the the actual deck that comes back and then hand
one to me the hand that we get back.
So this is kind of a lot of work.
If we look at what's happening here we're basically passing poker deck into everything.
Anytime we want to use the deck the associated functionality with the deck shuffling a deck creating
a new deck dealing hands from a deck we pass a list all over the place and contrast that with the OTOP
approach.
OK.
So here's an example using AOP.
Now this is not all the code in this file.
I've actually defined all the classes and this this one does more than the previous example but what
I just want to show you is how your code is organized and what it looks like now.
So I have a deck class.
So to make a new deck I just call deck and we'll talk a lot more about I would create classes in the
next video.
But notice the functionality deck shuffle.
So I don't pass in a list anywhere that represents the deck.
All of the associated code is inside of this deck.
It goes along with the deck.
Same thing with doing a hand.
All I have to tell.
Deal hand is how many cards to deal.
And then you know it automatically knows which deck we're talking about what the information is.
It's all encapsulated inside of this deck.
So if I actually really quickly showed you here here's a definition for the deck class and you can see
there's methods like count or deal shuffle deal a single card deal an entire hand.
All of this functionality is inside of deck so that the whole point of that was just to show two ways
of accomplishing the same thing one the O P version actually involves more code at the end of the day.
But it also results in it easier to understand and to think about organization for our program.
All right.
Next I want to talk about encapsulation.
So when we talked about modeling a deck of cards let's just focus on deck leave all those other entities
alone.
What are the possible things a deck would need to have pieces of information.
And what are the things that should be able to do the methods.
Here are some examples or some ideas.
We have a deck class and it would have a cards list.
We'll talk about private in public in just a moment.
A card list that would store you know the actual cards in that deck.
Then we could have a max card's attribute potentially.
So when you're playing with a single deck or if you go to a casino in Las Vegas a lot of times they
play with two or four.
I don't know if that's actually right but I know it's more than one deck.
A lot of the times in a shoe of cards.
So we can store that information.
There might be a shuffle method to mix the cards up a deal card method that will just take one card
off the top and then a deal and method that might call a deal card and deal hand will take two or three
or five cards and return them and then count how many cards are left in that deck.
So these are this is just some examples of the functionality and the attributes for one deck.
But now I want to talk about this idea of private and public what these underscores mean.
We'll talk a lot more about it as we progress.
But the idea is that some things don't actually need to be exposed to the outside world or to the programming
outside world where it can just stay inside of an individual deck.
For example the list of cards the list of cards is not something that we need access to directly.
We can access them through deal card or deal hand.
Same thing with Max card that can stay inside the deck versus something like shuffle or count deal cards
deal hand those need to be exposed.
And before we go any further I should just be clear Python does not actually support true private or
public variables or attributes or methods.
There is no distinction.
So the way that we make something private and I'm doing air quotes right now even though you can't see
me putting an underscore in front of it then that's just a way of giving it a name that makes it clear
to other developers.
This is only to be used inside of a given class not outside.
It's not supposed to be public even though there's nothing stopping from someone accessing it.
It's just a convention and that's all that Python supports.
So there's no way of actually preventing a piece of data or a method from only being available inside
a class like you could in something like Java.
So the entire point of this slide is to show you you can take an entity like a deck and break it down
into the pieces of information attributes needs and methods and not all of them need to be available
outside of that individual class.
And this leads us to the term encapsulation.
So encapsulation is really referring to the grouping of public and private attributes and methods into
a class making abstraction possible.
OK.
So we haven't talked about abstraction yet.
That's next slide.
It really comes down to kind of what we already talked about when we make a class.
We only want to expose the bare minimum the things that we might need to use from another class or outside
of the class and everything else.
We just keep it inside encapsulated.
I like to think of it as a little bubble.
We want the fewest entries and exits in and out of that bubble.
So for example we we decided that the cards list instead of a deck is private.
We're never going to direct the access cards.
Instead we'll deal a hand or shuffle the deck which will in turn each of those methods internally will
work with cards but we might want something like the length of the cards how many cards are left in
the deck to be accessible.
But if we're going to make cards private then instead we could make our own public method called Count
or remaining cards and inside are for mating cards or count.
It could run at length or line of cards and return that.
So we'll spend a lot of time talking about you know how you decide what to expose to the outside world.
And again there is no real distinction in Python.
Everything is public.
But if we are a good developer we follow conventions and we leave things alone that are designated private
even if they're not officially private.
So this leads us to abstraction.
Abstraction is just the idea of exposing only the relevant data or the bare minimum of things.
To create an interface to something more complex so we hide the inner workings away we abstract that
away and we provide an face into that.
So if the deck example we hide the cards all of the cards and we just create these interfaces in to
shuffle them or to deal a hand or deal a card I think of a more real world example like if you're driving
a school bus or any car would work.
We have a steering wheel.
We don't have to know about all the inner workings of you know how the steering wheel works and power
steering and everything that's happening behind the scenes.
We just turn the wheel.
That's our interface.
And it does everything else behind the dashboard or behind the scenes and underneath the car.
It's kind of a dumb analogy but same idea here.
We hide the inner workings and we just expose what's needed.