Already.
So at this point you should have a command line or terminal installed or up and running on whatever
platform you're using.
So whether you're on a Mac PC or you decided to go with Cloud 9 it doesn't matter.
But you just need to make sure you have it installed.
Because from here on out we're going to start typing some commands.
So if you skip to this video go back a couple of videos before this and install a command line.
So before we can actually learn new commands Let's talk about the file structure of our computers.
So all computers are organized with directories or folders and then files.
Basically your machine is just a bunch of folders instead of other folders instead of other folders
in hierarchy so there's an order there.
And what's most important to us right now is that there's a top level directory which is known as the
root directory.
It's also represented by a slash.
So here it is a visual representation of the root directory which again is just slash.
So all the files in My Computer are somewhere inside of the root.
My desktop is in there my photos.
It might not be directly instead of fruit it might be 20 or 100 folders down the line but eventually
everything is inside of it.
So computers are organized in a tree like structure where we have folders inside of other folders sort
of like the branches of a tree.
And I just have two represented here.
TNP temp and users but in the real world there's probably a dozen or more folders inside of my root
directory and then inside of the user's directory for example you might have another directory.
In this case colt you will probably have one depending on your user name for your computer that matches
that username.
But that's not really the key thing here.
What's more important is just the basic structure.
It's a tree like structure where we have a bunch of branches instead of other branches.
And there's a top level thing called the root.
Now why does this route matter.
Well every single file and folder on your computer has what's known as an absolute path.
So an absolute path is just a way of referring to a file or folder based off of its position relative
to the root.
So for example this colt directory is located instead of users which is located inside of root.
So from anywhere on my computer or whatever folder I'm in I could refer to the absolute path of this
colt file or directory by saying slash for the root users for the users directory and then I add another
slash in between any other level any layer.
So it's slash users slash code.
And if I had another file or folder after this I would need another slash for every layer afterwards.
So again absolute paths always start with Slash and then it's just the full path to get to whatever
file or folder.
So next we have a very big broad question Where am I not.
What's your place in the universe but where are we in your terminal.
So when I open up a new terminal window will actually do right now just command and on a Mac I make
this bigger What directory do I started.
And you might think that I'm in the root directory but I'm actually not by default all terminals will
open up in what's known as the home directory.
So the home directory is represented by the till the little key usually above your tab.
You need to hit shift and then whatever this key is above the tab in order to get that till the.
But that's the default directory on almost every computer when you open up a terminal.
So it's usually the user name of your account on the computer.
So in this case in my slide it's cold on my actual computer I believe it's called steal but that's inside
of a user's directory inside of root the slash.
So these are the only two symbols you need to know for directories.
Root is slash.
And then the home directory which is where pretty much everything that you do in your life is represented
by a Tildy.
So the rest of this on a typical computer is sort of default operating system stuff that we don't have
to mess with ourselves.
And we can actually see when you open up that new window I have a little till the here and that tells
me that I'm in the home directory.
But what if I actually wanted to know the exact absolute path of where I am.
Fortunately there was a command for that.
So this is our first command.
PWT stands for print working directory and it tells you the full absolute path of wherever you are in
the command line and we haven't learned how to change directories how to move around.
So right now it's always going to tell you the exact same thing.
So if I was inside the stuff directory which we don't know how to do that just yet.
But if there wasn't another directory instead of my home called Stuff and I wanted to use PWT I would
get SAS users slash cold slash stuff I remember that first flash very important signifying the route.
So if I hop over here to my terminal and I just type PWT I get slash users slash cold steel because
I'm not inside of a stuffed directory yet.
I'm just in the home directory by default.
So that's all there is to PWT print working directory gives you the full absolute path of wherever you
are.
So in the next video we're going to learn how to change where you are but as a quick example I have
another terminal window open and I'm not in the home directory.
So I did some witchcraft.
You'll learn how to do in the next video to change directories.
And if I type PWT this time I get slash users slash cold steel slash desktop slash top secret.
So I'm actually inside of this folder right here has nothing in it called top secret on my desktop.
And the for absolute path looks like this.
OK.
So the next video we're going to learn how to change directories how to move around using the command
line.