Okay in the last video are decorated functions meeting greets or rage not the decorator but the decorated
function didn't accept any arguments.
We just always had Greek and that's fine.
But most of the time our decorated functions will accept arguments.
So let's talk about how to make that work.
Here's an example where I have a function called shout and it just returns a wrapper function.
And inside the wrapper all that we're doing is calling upper on the result of whatever function was
passed in.
So we should be able to do something like Hi I'm I don't know Todd.
And it should return Hi I'm taught in all caps.
When we add the decorator What do you know.
I have it in a file.
All ready to go.
We have the shower decorator we have greet and order are both being decorated by shout.
So if I call greet I don't know when it's printed.
By the way print greet sure.
Todd all lower case Picture I'm not messing up my indentation let's execute this.
We execute it.
We get Hi I'm Todd yelling or shouted.
All right so that works fine because inside the wrapper function and shout all that we have is recalling
the function of passing in a single name.
But then if we have something like order down here we run into a problem because Order has two arguments
main and side.
So the idea is that we could do something like print order.
I don't know.
Burger and fries.
And it should shout Hi.
I'd like the burger with a side of fries please.
But shouting It's a very polite shout.
And we want that to work.
But right now it's not going to because wrapper takes one position of argument but two are given.
So these functions have different signatures.
This one on an argument.
This one wants to say how do we handle that.
Well it's not too bad.
We've already seen the solution.
We just use args and quarks cards.
KW args whatever you want to call it.
Next slide please.
Dumped it.
There we go.
This is the standard decorator pattern.
Most frequently the wrapper functions that are decorator returned will accept an unlimited number of
arguments and keyword arguments so we can just use args and quires to take care of that gives our wrapper
functions the most flexibility so to update our previous example.
I'll just comment that went out so I can leave the broken version and then down here.
All we wanna do is update this to be start args comma quarks as two stars.
And then we just pass both of those in.
OK now if we run this no problems there we go.
Yo it's working just great or shouting she is me and we can easily define function now like well that
only returns.
I don't know Helliwell and we can make that shout.
There's no argument.
It just returns ellabella every time.
And if I call print well what do we get elsewhere in all caps.
So we have flexibility now with our decorator that we set up and the wrapper can pass in any number
of arguments or keyword args and it should work just fine.
So just about verify that we could do make equal surprise side equals burger and switch it all up and
it still works.
Hi I'd like the fries with a side of burger please.
Story Of My Life.
Fries are always better than the burger.
All my friends make fun of me for eating the fries first.
Anyway that's pretty much it for this video.
Just wanted to show the more standard pattern.
By the way this does not have to be called wrapper.
We're just returning it.
It can be called anything but the standard is wrapper because that's what it's doing.
It's wrapping around a function manipulating altering enhancing the behavior in some way.
If you're still wondering why should I care about this.
Hang in there.
I usually try and explain why something matters upfront but in this case I wanted to wait until we get
the syntax out of the way.
So I will show you some useful real world examples in a little bit.
OK so that's decorator's with multiple arguments or different signatures for the decorated functions.