Before we practice with miscomprehension Let's see one more thing that I can do which is quite powerful.
You can actually add conditional logic to our list comprehension using keywords that we've seen before.
Like if and else in our first example here we have a list of numbers from 1 to 6.
It's called numbers and we have two new lists of Odd and Even numbers based on the conditional logic
at the end of the list comprehension.
So that's right here and right here.
So we're just saying take every now add it to a new list for each name in numbers.
If that name divisible is divisible by 2 meaning it's even numbered 2 is equal to zero.
Or in this example no mad 2 is not equal to zero.
So important to know the if keyword needs to come at the end after the name of the list or whatever
we are iterating through string or a range.
If you're using an ELSE key word things look a little bit different.
This might look confusing.
It kind of is.
And it just takes a bit of practice to get used to.
So you might be wondering how exactly do you possibly remember all of this.
Well I kind of forget the syntax a lot especially when we add the else in.
And I just look it up when I need to you know to build the slide or if I'm using it in code to measure
it's not too bad to just go find it online.
There are so many posts on stack overflow or tutorials about it.
So I would just recommend that you use.
Be willing to look things up and don't feel like you have to just commit everything to memory immediately
because engineers get too hung up on the syntax and not the conceptual stuff behind it.
OK.
With that little diatribe over let's look at this example and try and walk through it.
So there's a start of a list comprehension here but then we have an F and then an else.
And then for I'm in numbers.
So the syntax is definitely different.
But what this will happen or what this will do is it will take even numbers and multiply them by two
if they're even.
And otherwise the only other situation is that they're odd.
It will divide them by two.
So for every name and numbers from 1 to 6 if it's even if not made to zero.
Multiply it by two.
So that's how we get 4 and 8 and 12.
Otherwise divide it by 2 and that's how you get Point 5 1.5 and 2.5 and we can also combine this with
the in keyword to check for certain conditions.
So here we're taking a string and turning it into a list with no vowels and joining it back into a string.
If the character is not in the list of vowels.
So here we have this is so much fun.
Exclamation point with vowels that's a name of the variable and then we're using join which we saw earlier
we're doing char for char so for each character in with vowels if the character is not in H E I O or
you then we will join together into the string.
So it will take each item in this list.
This is going to generate a list and then joins them together.
So it might help to walk through this example and make some space here.
So remember how just joined works on its own.
You do something like this that join and then in parentheses passing a list like one that's two words.
And next year period they're OK.
And it joins every item in that list with an empty string.
But if we added a space or dot dot dot it joins them with that whatever we call it on it's a string
method.
So that should be review.
But then when we pass this in this list comprehension The result is this list right here.
Basically we're removing all vowels from this is so much fun.
So for each character in that's why this is so much fun string.
If a character is not in a IOU then we'll add it to the list.
So we end up with this list.
There's no vowels.
And then we join that together using an empty string.
And that's how we get this.
It's something like that.
All right.
There's a lot to list comprehension.
I know it might be overwhelming.
So we have some practice after this video get some practice get some experience with them.
If you have questions lingering on any of the examples I recommend you try running them yourself and
tweaking them and see what happens.
It's easier to walk through and try and piece together how things work.
So as I mentioned not to freak you out too much but try to get comfortable the syntax.
You don't have to memorize everything.
You know you don't have to be able to do a list comprehension with a if and an else condition right
away.
But when we do push on we get to things like dictionaries will be using their own kind of comprehension.
Same thing with set.
And so it's good to get the fundamentals down now.
OK.
So good practice post questions if you have them and don't panic.
This is this is really cool part of Python in my opinion.
So don't let the newness of it depress you discourage you.
How about that.
All right.
I'm going to be quiet.
Goodbye.