Pay.
Welcome back.
In this video we're going to focus on Ellis and another command called PWT and I'm also going to talk
about path's absolute versus relative paths.
But before we get there I want to run through the exact specifics of what we'll be using the power show
for.
It is a very powerful shell as the name implies there's a lot to it.
We're just going to hone in on a couple of things.
Navigating around creating and removing folders or directories and files and then executing Python scripts
for that last one we will have to install Python first.
So that will happen in the next section and then we'll be using the command line the Power Shell alongside
Python.
But to start let's just talk about the operating system file structure.
So for some of you who are devout Windows users this might be review but we're going to go through it
very quickly.
So operating systems whether it's a Mac PC or something else.
Organize the content on the data on the drives in a hierarchy a tree like structure with parents and
children.
Think of a family tree.
We're probably all comfortable with this idea at this point.
Just having worked with computers you opened up folders you put files on them you can put other folders
and it's this branching like structure where you have nested folders inside of other directories.
But at some point there is the top level root directory and on a PC that is the backslash it's the root
directory.
And so we could describe every other folder or file on our machine relative to that backslash to the
root directory.
For example if I had two directories inside one called Program Files another called users.
And then instead of users I had another thing called called another directory I would access Colts the
directory first by referencing the backslash.
And then the next layer down users and then the next layer down cold.
But it's separated always with these backslashes.
So each layer through I need to add a backslash and you've probably seen this before.
So to access this the absolute path based off of my root directory is C..
Slash users slash cost.
Next there's another special name for a folder.
So we saw the root directory the top most level directory.
There's also one called the home directory which has a special symbol used to reference the Tildy which
is usually above the tab key at least on Mac keyboards.
It's that little squiggly line and that's a symbol that's used to reference the home directory and on
PCs the home directory is your user directory.
So not the users but your specific your particular user account directory.
And actually it's the default directory that opens up when you open a new terminal.
So in the last video we saw that briefly opened power show and I was already in this directory.
The name of my account.
So that will be different for you.
Whatever your username is but that is your home directory so any time you open up power show you'll
be in there.
And if at any point you're in the power show and you're not sure where you are.
You can type this other command.
So we've seen ls.
There's also PWT print working directory and that tells you the full absolute path of where you currently
are.
So if I was in the stuff directory and I typed PWT I would get C backslash users Colt stuff.
That's the full path that's printed out to me.
So if you ever are lost and you need to know where you are you can use PWT.
OK so back in my power shop you may not need to use PWT that often because by default the prompt shows
you the entire absolute path.
OK.
So I have a new shell open here.
You can see it's putting me in the home directory automatically if I type PWT.
It's not that useful because we already see this in the prompt on certain machines other platforms you
may not see the entire prompt by default.
So PWT is worth knowing about but it's not that commonly used.
LS However it's really commonly used.
So again that means list and that just shows the contents of wherever we currently are.
So we haven't seen how to move directories yet.
So I'm stuck in the home directory right now.
I can type ls and I can type PWT to tell myself I am in the home directory backslash users backslash
Colt and I can see what's in there but that's it.
So I will end this video here in the next video though.
We'll actually talk about the command to change directories to move around so we can really start navigating.