Next when a show another way of writing data this will be much quicker using dict writer.
So just like we had adicts reader we have adicts writer and it allows us to write with dictionaries.
And when I said it would be quicker I just meant the video was quicker.
It not necessarily that this is faster than using a regular writer but it is easier to understand what's
going on.
So it really is a personal preference which when you use.
So dict writer is a little more complicated.
You have to specify the field names and set them equal to whatever we want the headers to be.
And then we call right Hetter to actually write a line of headers and then we call write row to write
a row based off of a dictionary.
So let's just look at an example here.
We're opening a file.
We have to import dict writer first opened a file in write mode.
We create a list of headers and then when we call dict writer we pass in the file and we set field
names to be these headers and then we call right Hetter and it's going to use these field names and
actually write that row for us.
And then every time we called right row we pass in a dictionary like this.
Let's just take a look at some code.
This is the old version using writers.
I'm going to comment that out and I'm going to import dict writer as well like this.
OK.
And then down here we'll do our Same with Open.
We'll just work with catch up CXXVI and we'll do w which will overwrite but that's OK for now.
So let's do this gets the SBW as file.
And then the first thing we want to define are the headers that we're going to write in.
So we could do.
I don't know.
Headers equals we had name and age.
Let's go with name breed and age this time.
So we're going to overwrite what's currently in there.
Just completely erase it.
All right.
So then we need to make our CACP writer whatever you want to call this equals dict writer.
And then we pass in the file comma and then we need field names.
This is important and we set it equal to some lists.
You could just put this in line.
But if you have a lot of them just do a variable like that.
Now we're going to call C S rewriter right hatter and it's going to take these letters she passed in
under field names and write them to the File for us and if we just do this now that should be enough
for us to see something every year on the code.
Now we go look at this cat step CACP it overwrote everything because we open the file with right mode
which overwrites everything.
But you can see it wrote those letters for us.
OK.
So that's I mean you do that once right and what's more important is actually writing the row.
So it's See it's rewriter dot right row and it takes a dictionary and we can specify I'm going to do
it on separate lines.
We specify name and we don't have to go in order because we're using unlike with a list where the first
thing had to be name.
Second thing had to be age and they all had to line up here.
I could specify name is and then what do I want name to be.
Let's go with Garfield and then Vrede.
I don't know what he is just short of let's just say orange tabby and age.
I have no idea how old Garfield is to go with 10.
I mean the characters were WAY older.
But let's just say 10.
OK.
Now for on this code and we look at what we get.
There we go.
Name breed age.
Garfield orange tabby and tan.
So this shows us that we can use a dictionary to write all that I would say is that yes this is more
verbose than writing a single row like this where you don't have to specify what we're writing.
This can be nicer if your data.
Obviously if your data is already in a dictionary which a lot of the time you might be working with
dictionaries This is very easy to write data.
It really just comes down to personal preference using writer use of the means less code using dict
writer usually means being more explicit in your code the easier to understand just a preference.
So one more example of using dict reader and dict writer together let's say I want to take my fighter's
data and want to convert the centimeters height to inches or feet.
Would I go with inches for now.
OK.
So to do that the math is easy.
We're just going to multiply.
I have a little function.
CM to inch that takes centimeters.
And this is according to Google.
What we need to multiply by so all I want to do is read in all the data from this file and then I'm
going to write it to a new file and we're just going to take this number in pass it in to that CME to
function and then write that value down and we'll keep these all the same.
All right.
So the first thing we'll do let's do it down here is just with open and the file is fighters Scott cxxviii
as fighter or what am I saying as file.
And then in here we're going to use dict reader.
So we'll do CXXVI reader equals dict reader.
We don't have to use dict reader.
It's just if we're going to use dicts writer it's much easier to keep them in the same format when dictionary
and we can read it in its dictionary write it out as a dictionary instead of having to convert from
a list to a dictionary but it's not impossible.
OK.
And then we just need to pass and file and can just make sure it's working for row and see Reader.
Let's just do even simple print the list version of CSFB reader.
We test it out.
There we go getting a bunch of ordered dicts.
Cool.
So now we have that same question which is do we want to just do a nested solution where we have another
we open up the file we write to inside of this with or do we want to save this data to a variable.
Since we did it nested last time let's do it on separate with statements so a save is too variable.
I'll just call this a fighter's equals list.
C is free read C S V reader and then down here we'll do another with open and ours will be called inches
fighters.
P Y.
And we need that W as a file and then we'll do our C S V writer equals dict writer and we pass and file
but we also need the headers.
OK.
So it's up to us.
But the thing is right now our headers are like this.
So we can just keep that except I'd like to change this to be Heights in inches instead.
Maybe let's just make it right instead.
All right so we need quotes around these.
Maybe there's a better way of doing this.
And then we need to turn it into a list or a tuple and then we'll just do adder's equals that.
And then here we need to do field names equals headers.
OK.
And then we'll do our cxxviii writer.
Right.
And let's run this now.
It looks good and the file that we made of is it called inches fighters let's look for that somewhere
over here.
There we go.
All right we've got the hitters in there.
So now all that we have left is to loop through fighters and we're going to call cxxviii writer.
Right.
ROWE So for fighter and fighters let's just call it let's keep it shorter.
We're going to call cxxviii writer dot right.
Ro.
But this takes a dictionary.
We'll do it on a couple of lines.
And we need to match these headers.
If I guess he didn't show this earlier but if we'd you know messed them up we don't spell them correctly
we would use something else.
Well I'll show you what happens.
We have these ordered dicts right now in fact he just kept them as is and just passed in f right row
f and we run it.
You can see it gives me this problem because the field that they have right now is called height in
centimeters.
And what I wrote down was hights because I want to get rid of that.
So that gives us a slight problem.
We could do is basically loop through each one.
Leave this untouched leaf that untouched and then remove this entirely and add in a new key value pair
for height and set it equal to the inches version.
Or we could just do this instead of trying to write the road directly.
We could write name and set that equal to f of name.
And this is kind of verbose to have to do this but it works.
Country we set to f of countries so those are the same.
And then here we get to height and we set height too.
And then this is the tonic to start.
We could just do f.
What was that Hetter just copy it from here it had the height in CMEs like that.
So that's how they're stored.
If we did this and rerun it and we look at our result.
Oh well I just realized I made this a python file.
That's not what we want really.
Why we're getting that highlighting.
But the syntax is all the same.
What's being written.
But the main problem is that this is still centimeters I want inches.
So before I forget let's make this dot CSFB.
OK.
And down here we're not going to set height to this.
We want to pass this into S.M. 2 inches.
CM 2 inches but there's still another problem which is this is going to be a string and this expects
it to be an int or a number.
So if we get this conversion problem so we could just kind of this isn't necessarily the best way of
doing it because this is called centimeters to inches you would think a function name that would just
take a number.
It shouldn't take a string and automatically turn it to an end.
This is ok we'll just assume whatever we get will turn it into an ant and then multiply it or actually
better yet would be a float in case somebody passing a float.
We won't lose data accuracy.
OK let's test it.
Now let's actually look at the correct file which was inches fighters C S V.
We might want to round but you can see that we're getting data now.
We have named country and height.
We have this new file.
We transfer data from here in centimeters for height over here 2 inches for height.
Everything else is identical.
OK.
So hopefully that makes it clear how we can use dict writer along with dict reader or getting data
into a dictionary.
Usually this would actually be a lot shorter.
But the thing is that I wanted to rename height in cm to now be called height which caused a problem.
If I had left it this height in CM It would have been a lot easier.
Except it would have been a lie because we're working with inches now.
So because of that we have to update this field on every dictionary before we insert it so we can't
just take fighters and loop through each fighter and just add f.
Like I showed you at the beginning that would work for all the other pieces of data like name and country
but it wouldn't work for height because it's not stored underwrite it's stored under height and s.m.
OK.
So you can see there's a lot of choices when you're working with CSB.
Two different ways of reading in and two different ways of writing out to a file at the end of the day.
They all work.
It just really depends on your personal situation what you prefer.
And if you like to be shorter but harder to you know less exposed to it.
Or if you like to be a little longer more verbose but clear and explicit about what code does.