Who.
OK.
So we made it through that long slog of introductions and conceptual stuff in defining terms.
Now it's time to write our first Python class.
Let's say we're making a game poker or blackjack or battleship it doesn't matter.
And we've decided we want to model a user.
So we're going to make a user class as our first simple class and this video we're actually really only
going to go halfway there.
I'm going to show you how to make a new class but we're not going to fill it with data just yet.
So the magic key word is class.
And then a name of a class.
So we'll go with user a couple knows about name naming classes.
We name them in the singular instead of users user.
And we always use camel case you don't have to.
But that's the conventional way.
So we could just to user or poker underscore deck but the convention would be poker deck in camel case.
So most things like variables function names are conventional in Python to you snake case class names
camel case.
OK.
So we could define our class user.
We had a colon and if we just wanted to leave it at this an empty class it did nothing technically right
now.
This is invalid Python code.
And if I try and run this it gets mad at me.
Unexpected end of file.
So if I add pass in here this basically just says OK I'm done there's nothing else in here.
Move on.
No we actually have a working class so we've defined the class just like we defined a function called
ADD and let's just say it returns 3 doesn't actually add.
Well we have to find the function but we're not using it yet.
And to do to use it we have to actually call add with parentheses.
It's no different here.
So we want to actually create a new user.
We have the class to make an instance of it.
We could just go let's call it user 1 equals user with Prince.
So eventually.
OK the next video will be passing in information like a name and an age or I don't know a list of attributes
all these different things you could pass and that will actually instantiate inside the class.
But for now it's an empty shell of a class.
It does absolutely nothing.
But we can tell that it works by doing this if we print user 1.
Let's see what user one is.
OK.
We get this thing.
Main user object.
And that's that's all.
We don't care about this memory address.
So it's a user.
It's empty.
But this is what it looks like for now when we print.
A user will be able to change that come up with a custom representation but we haven't got there yet.
So we've created a new user and it's empty.
It doesn't have any information to any properties no methods but it is a user sort of like create doing
this L equals an empty list or list like that.
And the last thing I'll show.
We can verify for you type user 1 let's call it and it tells us class User main user but this is just
user is what's important.
So just like if we do type of the number 5 it's an int or 5.0 class float or if a dictionary has class
dict we now have her own class user.
So remember this is a class the blueprint for what every user should look like.
Right now they're all identical and they do nothing down here we're instantiating a new user instance
which is a user object an object here and this variable and I could make use one user too and user 3
and 4.
Those are all individual users.
They all look the same but they're not the same thing.
Just like when you make a list we can have four empty lists and they might look the same but in memory
they're actually different.
So if I just print user want a user to go they're both user objects different places in memory.
All right.
So that's a wrap for this video.
You define the simplest use less class called user and we've made a couple of instances of it in the
next video we'll we'll see how to actually add data into this class attributes like username and email
and that sort of thing.