All right.
Welcome back.
So I have another example with inheritance this one a bit more complicated.
So we sell the basics these are how to use super with pet or animal and cat.
Here I have the user class from the last section.
It's a bit more complex.
If you didn't watch any of that section you could just play around with this code download it.
But essentially there's the user.
Each user has a first last name and then age.
We have methods like log out full name which you turn to the full name initials.
A couple of other things we won't use in this video.
There's a class attribute called active users.
It starts at zero.
And every time a new user is created we add one to it and every time log out the instance method is
called on any instance of user.
We remove one or decrement active users once.
OK.
So the goal here and I alluded to this earlier on in the section when I talked about inheritance is
to model a typical permissions set up on a social network or a blog site something like Reddit where
we have a user that most of us are users on the site.
Regular old users we can create comments and a posts but we can't go around just deleting other people's
stuff or editing other people's stuff.
And at our own will.
But then there are moderators and moderators are in charge of a particular community sobre and we're
using the Reddit example like the soccer sub it that's when I go on a lot and the moderators are very
active always having to remove like inappropriate racist comments or things that have nothing to do
with soccer.
And the reason that this is a classic case for inheritance is that moderators are simply users that
they have some additional functionality in them some special things they can do like delete a post or
editing.
I don't know if they can edit.
I think they can just delete a post or hide them into the comments and that sort of thing.
So we don't want to define that functionality on user.
We only wanted one moderator but everything else should be you know fair game.
We want to first name last name age and imagine you know email and password and all that stuff that
a typical user on Reddit has a moderator also has.
So let's start by defining moderator and it inherits from user and then we'll define Arnette and we're
just going to go with the exact same things first class and age
and how about let's go with community.
So this will be like there a section that the moderator enforces like soccer or San Francisco City Segretti
whatever it is.
OK.
And I need a tee over here and colon and then we'll just call super didn't it.
Why am I missing those T's.
And we want to pass in first last and age and then we'll set self-caused community equals community.
So in this case superbe first user calling it appear.
And therefore it should automatically add 1 to active users.
We don't have to do it manually because we're making use of this in net already.
So it's adding one to the active users class attribute because active users and this is how it's structured
right now.
But it makes sense that we want all active users on our site not just the ones who aren't moderators
because a moderator is still a user.
It now is to find a method and let's call it remove post or something.
And let's just have it return a string that says something like Tim somebody removed a post from community
soccer or something.
So we don't have an entire Web site set up or application with a database and everything we can actually
remove anything right now.
But let's just have it say let's use full name just defined up here in the user.
So let's say self dot full name removed a post from.
And then let's do self dot community.
Community.
So Tim blah blah blah removed a post from soccer community.
Yes the soccer community.
OK now let's make a new moderator.
So we'll go with Jasmine equals moderator.
First name is Jasmine.
Last name can be O Connor.
And what else is there.
Age.
She'll be 60 one.
And her community is the piano community.
OK.
So if I do something like print Jasmine dot full name to start and then let's also make sure her community
is set up.
Print Jasmine dot community.
Let's test it out.
What do we get Jasmine O'Connor in piano.
OK.
So these classes are set up correctly.
That's the first thing I wanted to do.
Just another example of how we can save a good amount of typing right.
And we could redefine all of this if we wanted all this functionality and we weren't using inheritance.
We could put it all in here.
But with inheritance automatically every moderator gets all of these built in methods and then by adding
supercontinent we get all this code as well.
So there are a couple of things I'll point out.
The first is if we make a new user just call it the one with the user and this user will be Tom Garcia
who is 35.
And let's start by printing user dot and then what was our method display active users like this end
does that one print itself or does it just return not just returns.
OK.
So let's do this and then do it twice so we'll make a new user.
We'll do it again.
Well make a moderators of three times actually.
So this is a class attribute which is a class method called display actually for users that is referencing
class attribute active users but it's on the user class.
So does creating a moderator impact active users on the user class.
But before we can do that I need to add print here to actually execute that method.
And now we get there currently zero.
And then 1 and then two active users.
So the answer is yes.
This class rable active users is being incremented because we have it being incremented inside of the
user and which we are calling here.
However if we weren't doing that and we manually defined self-doubt first equals first and so on and
duplicated everything then user dot active users would not be incremented because we wouldn't be calling
it.
And if we did want to just keep track of how many moderators there were currently online we could do
total mud's equals zero.
And then just increment could do.
Moderator datt total Mad's plus equals 1.
Every time a moderator is created and we could even steal this exact class method here
and just change it a bit and need this amphoras.
What is this code at Sun and we'll call this display active minds.
There are currently class dot total mud's active models.
OK.
So I just copied and pasted it but I changed this because now it's from ODs and it's referencing the
moderator attribute called Total us.
OK.
So there's a lot to take in there.
Let's just make a couple of users.
So user one user to user or three it's OK that they're all the same and we can print active users.
So let's also make two moderators Gazmin one in jazzmen two and then all will do is print active users
and then print active.
And it's important to note I can't call this with the user dot display active mods.
I do need to call maade that display active mods or moderator that display deflective months.
Now we get there are currently five active users total but only two of them are active moderators.
So the point of all that was just to show you that you know we can separate out functionality where
if we wanted to have a separate class variable for something like that we could put it in the moderator
class and we could have two class variables one keeping track of users on keeping track of moderators
and every time a moderators created both of them are incremented every time a user is created.
Only this one is incremented.
OK.
So that wraps up this slightly longer example.
Hopefully it helps make clear how using inheritance can really help you out.
So you don't have to use it really ever.
You also don't ever have to use o p but it just helps you structure things.
And in this case using inheritance helps us reduce duplication.
Next up we're going to learn about the joys of multiple inheritance which is pretty much what it sounds
like.