All right.
So we've seen stars with a single star.
Now we see another operator with two stars stars star and kw args.
It stands for keyword args and the idea is that it's another special operator.
We can have as a parameter to functions but rather than just collecting any additional arguments.
What this will do is gather remaining keyword arguments and rather then storing them in a tuple it stores
them in a dictionary.
So again it's just another parameter.
You can call this what you want.
Star Star extra stuff Stars star KW ARG args.
It doesn't matter.
Totally up to you.
The standard is KW args though keyword args so let's start with an example and I want to define a function
called fav colors and I want to be able to pass in with keyword arguments something like.
I don't know Colts equals purple.
And then we can have my sister Ruby.
Her favorite is red and Ethel likes teal right now with what we know we could do.
Def can't forget that fav colors and then we could add in Colt Ruby and Ethel and so on.
Or we can use star star and then KW args.
And again this can be whatever people stuff.
But I'll do KW argued arts args.
There we go and let's just start by printing.
KW args just like with Star args we don't actually reference the double star.
It's just the name of the parameter.
After that you start to remember it comes in as a dictionary.
It gathers all the remaining keyword arguments which are these Once again or we have a keyword equals
and then some value a key and a value.
Let's test it out and just see what we get.
So that's going to be Python 3 colors and you can see we get a dictionary and you can trust I won't
make you watch this but if I add something else here.
Well we only had one or we had 100 different key value pairs.
They would all be in KW args.
So suppose I want the output to basically be Colts favorite color is purple Rubeus favorite color is
red.
Ethel's favorite color is teal.
I want to print a line and the print needs to be something like Do an F string and I'll start by saying
person's favorite color is and then color.
But in order for this to work of course we need to have variable's person and color and to do that we
need to loop through KW args But remember it's a dictionary.
And if we need the key and the value of a dictionary we need to use KW args dot items and loop through
that.
So we'll will do for person comma color in KW Armstead item extent.
You know normally we'd have key comma value or K comma V but because this is a special case I know that
these are supposed to be people in their favorite colors.
I'm going to do person common color and then just indent this print person's favorite color is color.
Let's see if it works.
Cool culture colors purple.
Very true.
Ruby's favorite colors red Ethel's favorite color is teal and this works no matter how many we pass
in.
So I can have Ted likes blue or I could have one that only has called a favorite color as let's put
this as royal deep amazing purple Now I run it and we get the first batch right here.
And then there's the next time we called it with four and then the last time with only one keyword argument.
So you can see how this makes our functions really flexible and I have one more example in this case.
There's a function called special greeting and there's only one parameter.
KW args star Starcade w args and they will collect in a dictionary all the keyword arguments.
Or at least the remaining keyword arguments and you can see the way I'm calling it.
In this case is actually just with one key value pair David equals.
Hello Bob.
Hello David equal special.
This is just a stupid little function that will do a greeting depending on the person and their corresponding
type of greeting.
So it checks if inside of key w args there is David so that checks in the Keys and then it checks if
the value of David is equal to special.
So that's checking for this right here.
And if that's the case then we return you get a special greeting David.
Otherwise if David is in KW args but it's not set to special like here then we just return whatever
the value was GW args David.
So in this case Hello David and then else once again we don't need to explicitly say.
Else it's just going to return.
Not sure who this is.
So this is a bit different than the colors example where we're looping through the KW args.
In this case all that we're doing is checking to see if KW args contains David and if it doesn't then
we'll do something and if it does and it also contains a corresponding value special we print special
anyway so let's just test it out and run this and we get.
Hello David then.
Not sure who this is and then you get a special greeting David and that's what we expect.
And just to show if I did comment these all out and do one on its own at the bottom this one can be
print special greeting and will do other equals special comma David equals special and actually rather
than hether equal specialists do hether equals Hello.
So in this case two things are being passed in and both will be stored in the dictionary KW args.
But it doesn't matter because our code isn't doing anything with Heather.
It's only looking for David.
So what do we expect this one to return.
You get a special greeting David because all that matters is that David is in P.W. args right here and
that KW args.
David meaning the corresponding value is special.
So this is true this line.
So we return.
You get a special greeting.
So that's it for star star or keyword args.
I actually can feel weird talking about it because I don't hear many people say it outloud like you
see it online all the time.
I don't know what the actual pronunciation is for this.
I know people say Star args like in this case star.
Well that's our own but Star arge is standard here I'm not sure what people call it.
But more important than the pronunciation is the fact that it just collects all of the keyword arguments.
Unless you know we could have something like if we did Heather here.
KW args is not going to contain this key value pair so it just is kind of sweeping up the remaining
keyword arguments just like this.
Swept up the remaining regular arguments.
Cool so we're done with it.