Hey welcome back.
The next batch of rejects syntax will look at are called quantifiers.
These little characters that you see here all help specify how many times something should occur in
a pattern one or more or exactly 10 times or zero or once that sort of thing.
We make things you know we work with other characters and we manipulate how many times they need to
be there using quantifiers.
So right now what I have back over here I'm just going to change this just a little bit to add in another
word and you'll see why in a second it will just make our example clearer.
I did in kittens anywhere in here.
OK.
So let's say I wanted to match any word that starts with a K and then has anything afterwards.
So I don't want to just match a single K.
I want to match the pattern of a K starting a word.
So if I just type K so a single out you know three K's that i have i like there's a K kittens and Kitty
but I only want to match things that start with a K and then what comes next a word character.
So I could do it like this K and then any word character afterwards.
And you can see it's matching k d k i k I.
But if I want any number of word characters afterwards I add a plus sign there.
It's now going to match something that has a K and then whoops it just changed it and the number of
word characters after.
So we're getting kittens.
We're getting kitty but there's a small problem which is we're still getting this k e that comes at
the end.
We'll see how to fix this later on where we can specify something that needs to start with K.
But with what we know right now I could just do a whitespace character like that whitespace character
then.
And then a word afterwards.
It stills mentioning that space in front of it.
For now that's good enough.
We get a whitespace character.
OK.
It is only lowercase case right now if I change it to uppercase it doesn't match anymore followed by
at least one word character afterwards.
OK so that's plus one or more but we can also specify something exactly a number of times using curly
braces.
So earlier when I was trying to match things that were five letters long I was doing slash w slash w
backslash in at c one two three four five.
I could also just replace this as such w square or curly braces five.
And now it only matches things that are five characters long one two three four or five.
It's hard to see here because it's going one two three four five and then one two three four five and
then one two three for five and then it doesn't get that F I kind of wish it was a little easier to
see where things you know where the actual matches were just bunds them all together.
But this is getting 5 word characters in a row I can change that to be nine.
And it's only going to match that right there.
So this is useful already.
Let's say I had a phone number in here so I don't right now but let's do much redo.
Let's just add some numbers in here 3 1 0 4 6 7 always 3 digits isn't it.
And then there we go.
OK.
And let's say that I want to dash.
This is the syntax that we're going to follow.
If I wanted to match any phone number say I add one more and do it this line I'll change the area code
and just change a couple of digits.
OK.
I want to match that pattern three digits space three digits dash 4 digits using what we know already
I can do.
This is a digit a single digit.
And I want three of them at the beginning.
And then I went to space and then I want what is it three digits again.
So already that's matching only the two numbers the phone numbers.
Then I want a hyphen and then I want four digits ups like that.
And now we're only matching the phone numbers.
So instead of having to do you know slash d over and over and keep repeating it we can take advantage
of the curly braces if we also wanted to have a range of times.
Something could occur.
Let's say I want all I don't know strings of word characters that are between eight and 10 characters
long or let's go between 5 and 7.
I would just do sashed w for a word character five not five on its own matches only five letters but
five comma seven gives the characters or words things that contain word characters that are between
five and seven letters long or the includes numbers 2 and word characters but none of these are five
or seven letters long if I added a number in there.
It's now being matched because it's at least five.
And if we just wanted to do greater then you know four or more times you just add a comma in there.
So if I want to match all series of numbers digits that occur four or more times I can do for a comma.
We don't have any longer.
Let's do three commas so you can see it now matches three in a row as well as five in a row here and
four in a row there.
But it doesn't match two in a row.
We also have a star which means zero or more times.
So this is going to be a silly example but let's focus on this giant string of flutters some I repeated.
If I did a and then B star C see what it matches is there has to be an A.
And then there has to be a C afterwards.
But then any number of B's between zero B's three B's You know if I change this to be 1 b it still matches
if I get rid of it it still matches and if I go back to how it was multiple B's it still works.
So that is the star.
It means zero or more I could do the same thing with C and then put a D afterwards.
And it's going to make sure there's an A in A D on either end and in between any number of BS or CS
including zero.
And then finally there's the question mark which means once or none versus the star which is zero or
more.
This is 0 or 1.
So it's an example let's see I'm going to edit this just slightly.
I like cats and kittens and down here I mean to change the email to be kitten at gmail dot com.
OK.
And if I write you know kitten like this it matches part of kittens and then kitten but if I do s questionmark
it now matches both of them the full word because it says you know I'm looking exactly for Kitten K
I T N and then 0 or 1 s.
So it wouldn't work if we you know we had two s's.
It can only occur once.
So one more example that might be a bit more realistic if I have I was going to copy the same phone
number but instead of a dash or a hyphen I'm going to get rid of that if I want to still match this
as a phone number.
And these other ones I would have three digits then a space and then have another three digits and a
dash and then Opus are missing the digit character and then four.
Right.
OK so that matches these two.
Oh I forgot I added extra digits there earlier on.
But we're not matching this one because it doesn't have that dash.
So if I just add a question mark it now matches because that dash is considered optional but it wouldn't
match.
If we had you know two dashes there you can see no longer counts.
So that's a question mark will do.
That's what all of these things do.
They quantify the number of times that characters or patterns need to appear.