Already Welcome back.
So in the last I guess two videos ago we saw a bunch of different errors we learned about what causes
them.
Then we saw how to raise her own errors.
But really the most important thing in this section is all about handling errors.
Right now if our code gets an error it kind of breaks everything stops execution and everything just
halts and it prints out that error to us in the terminal and we're kind of screwed but that changes
right now because now we're going to see how to actually handle them how to do things if we get an error
if we encounter one type of error or do this if we encounter another type of error do this.
So obviously this is a good idea.
It's strongly encouraged to use try except block to.
That's the magic that we're going to learn here.
The new syntax.
Try and accept.
So here's an example.
This on its own.
Not that impressive but it's a very simple example.
If I just had a file actually let me just copy this and I'll show you paste this into a file and let
me just call FUBAR on its own.
And if I run this what do I expect to get.
You get a name error.
Yep that's kind of review.
There's no variable called foobar no function nothing existing.
So by writing this code as try foobar.
What I'm basically saying is try to do this and then we have this except name error.
Except name error and you can do this as syntax will come back to that.
But let's just actually leave it at the most simple possible thing like this except then print problem
and then afterwards let's do another print down here that just says like after the try.
OK.
So what it's going to do is try this code which is a very silly simple line of code but it will cause
a problem and without trying except our code would break.
This would never run but because it's in a try and except try attempts to do this.
And then if there's an exception this runs instead of the error being thrown and everything getting
messed up.
So let's try it now.
We now get the problem and then after the try.
So hopefully that makes sense what's happening here.
If we just did foobar and then tried to print after foobar we're not going to get anywhere.
None of this will even run if I do this right now.
The very first line ruins everything.
So instead we put it in a try block.
Now this is a very simple example and also is not without its own problems because for example printing
out a problem like this is just not a good idea.
We're not explaining what the problem is we're not actually handling an error in a helpful way.
And also this is very generic.
There could be any sort of error in our case.
This is a name error we know it's an error.
I have a slide actually devoted to this.
You don't want to catch all errors with a blank except like this because what will happen here is anytime
there's an error whether it's a type error a name error anything divide by zero error.
They all will be caught by this except and will always print.
You tried to use a variable that was never declared even if that wasn't necessarily the case.
So what we want to do instead is be specific and we accept particular errors like in this case except
name error.
And that way we're only going to run this code if we encounter a name error.
And if there's another type of error this won't run and we can actually add another except afterwards
and I'll show you that in just a moment.
So let's start by actually building a little function that might be useful.
So you know how we saw this in the last video.
If I define a dictionary like this and we have a name is Ricky like this and then I try and access something
that's not in there we've already seen this before.
What type of error will I get.
Get a key error.
Let's say we want to make function called get and what get we'll do is take in a dictionary I'll just
call it D.
And then a key.
So I would call it like this.
Get the comma city and it should check if city is in the dictionary and if it is it should give us the
value.
If it's not instead of throwing an error or a key error it should.
I don't know.
Return none instead.
Or false.
There's actually already you know dictionary.com get that we've seen.
So we're kind of redefining our own version except it's just a function it's not a method on the dictionary.
So for this to work you need to define our function and the code that we would just run looks like this.
D of key.
So this is a dictionary of the key.
But that could potentially throw an error.
So we're going to try that code and then we want to accept and we can just do all exceptions but let's
do except key error.
All that will do is return None.
In this case Andrew will do.
Return the key so return the value by putting the key into the dictionary.
So if we called Get with the comma name you would tried to access d of name and that should be tricky
but if we tried to do it with something like city as we saw then that will throw a key error.
We will intercept it here and return none instead.
So let me show you how that works.
Now just move this after the function definition.
And now if I call this get the common name and let me print it so we can see the result that we get
we get Ricky All right.
Not surprising that Fred tri city just doesn't exist.
We get none.
So instead of getting an error which is what we would get if we did it on our own like this.
That would give us a key error.
Instead we get the value.
Not so we've now written a function basically mimicking the existing dictionary method d dot to get
where we can pass in city.
This is just our own version so you probably wouldn't do this yourself and build this all out.
But this is essentially what's happening behind the scenes.
It's trying to return the value based off of that key.
But if it gets an error it returns None instead.
I will end the video here.
But we still have a little more syntax to talk about as far as try and accept blocks.
So in the next video I'll show a couple more examples.