OK.
So we've seen how to find out where we are but we haven't learned how to move or change that.
So in this video we're going to learn that command CD which stands for change directory.
It's how we navigate through our files and folders.
So we have a couple of options when working with CD.
We can use an absolute path.
So in this case let's say that I inserted the stuff directory.
So if I typed PWT I would see slashy users slash code slash stuff.
And if I wanted to move to the users directory from stuff I could use the absolute path to find users
so that is slash users and I write CD space and then the path slash users.
And if I hit enter and then I use PWT it will now show me I'm in slash users.
So this is again known as navigating.
Absolutely.
So this is useful but I'm also going to show you another way of navigating in just a moment.
But before we do that let's take a look.
So here we go to my other window or type PWT again can see I'm in a folder called Top Secret.
Let's say I want it to navigate to my home directory which is called Steel.
Well I can do cd space and then the absolute path slash users slash cold steel.
Now if I type PWT I can also see my prompt has changed here.
I'm in my home directory so I can also do the same thing actually to go to my root directory.
I could do cd slash.
And now if I type PWT I'm in slash and you can also see the prompt changed.
And if you want to go back to my desktop Let's say I could do cd slash users slash.
And I'm going to show you.
You can use tab to auto complete.
So if you want to type the whole thing slash desktop and now type PWT and I'm on sosh users slash called
Steel slash desktop so that's using CD change directory.
Absolutely.
But we have another option which is to use it relatively.
So this is what I end up doing most of the time.
It allows you to change directories based off of where you currently are.
So there's a special alias dot dot and that stands for the parent directory or one directory back one
level up from where you are.
So for example if I am currently in the stuff directory and I type PWT I see slash users slash Colt
slice slash stuff and if I wanted to change back one level to the home directory to code I can just
do cd space dot dot and that's the equivalent of saying Take me back one level.
And in this case is the equivalent of if I did it absolutely it would be CD slash users slash code.
But dot dot is so much shorter.
So now for type PWT I see him in slash users slash cost.
So let's do a quick demo of that.
First I'm going to show you there's a clear command.
This just not functionally it doesn't do anything it's not important but I use a lot just to clean up
my terminal and these videos.
So I'm currently on the desktop.
Let me make a new window
and by default I'm in the home directory.
So if I type PWT I get slashy users slash colp.
So if I wanted to navigate to the users directory I could do it absolutely of course CD slash users
or I could make use of dot dot because that is the parent of where I am and if I do that and I had PWT
now I'm now instead of slash users.
So right now we're all missing how to navigate backwards using dot dot but we'll see in a bit how we
can also navigate down into the subdirectories.
Unfortunately right now we don't have a way of seeing what's in this user's directory so we don't know
what folders we can change into.
But again just to quickly wrap this up if I go back.
So let's navigate to my home directory again which is I could do cd slash users slash cold steel and
R-Type PWT can see SAS users slash cold steel and wrap this up.
I'll just show that you can use dot dot more than once.
So if I wanted to go to my root directory I could just CD slash.
That would actually be shorter but it could also do C.D dot dot.
That will take me to users as you can see there.
And then I can do Siddiqa one more time and that takes me to the root directory.
So in this video we saw two different ways of using CD.
You can use the entire absolute path or you can navigate relatively using things like dot dot.
Now in the next video we're going to continue working with CD.
We're going to introduce a new command LS That allows us to look around to see what files are in a given
directory.