Hello hello hello.
So in the last video we saw how to define or kind of define a for loop a version of a for loop.
We're going to go from the opposite direction now instead of working with iterable.
In defining a for loop we're going to define our own iterable sash iterator like a Range class but we'll
call it counter.
OK.
So imagine we have a counter class like this.
And I want to be able to do something like for an encounter from 50 to 55 and then I want to be able
to do print and that should give me 50 51 52 53.
Basically the same thing that I'd get with a range but we're going to define our own class called counter
encounter will take care of everything or return an iterator and the iterator will have a next will
return something when next is called on it.
So let's just get going before I stumble over my words anymore.
First thing we'll do is just define a club or a G is really stumbled well defined innit.
There you go.
And fun read to find the counter will pass in a.
What we need self and then let's just call it low and high like this and then we'll just set self-doubt
low equals low self high equals high.
OK.
Now the very first thing I could show you.
We have to define this death eater like this method and whatever I return in here when we call it her
on a counter which is what this four will do is what will be returned and what needs to be an iterator.
So let me just show you if I come into all this out right now and come at this out as well.
If I tried to do her on counter like I make a new counter let's just call it C equals counters zero
10.
So I tried to do it her see it complaints to me counter object is not an iterable and it means that
it remember something for something to be iterable has to respond to her and return an iterator.
So if we define our hitter method here and we could start with something really simple simple and silly.
Remember that her needs to return an iterator so we can just return's think dumb like a number or a
string like hello but we could return it or hello because remember what this is here and we call it
her on hello.
It's a string.
It's iterable.
This returns the iterator string iterator like we saw in the last couple of videos.
And now if I try it we shouldn't get an error and we don't.
So I actually have enough now to do 4 x in counters zero to 10.
It's not going to do what we want but I could print X and what will happen here is that counter the
for loop is going to call it or on counter when we call it her on counter it calls this.
So this is one of those Dunner methods like length we call Lenn with this the non-dancer function but
behind the scenes it's calling the Dunder Lenn that is defined on a list or on whatever a deck or card.
Same thing here so we define Dunder itor.
And then when we call it or on a counter it's going to it or behind the scenes calls Dondre it's very
confusing.
Ok so here.
What we've done but it just returns the string iterator hello So it's not going to do what we want.
Second to give us numbers from 0 and 10.
It gives us a low but it's an iterator.
It's working.
What we want to do instead is actually return self.
But the problem is if I if I were self right now.
I mean you'll see it's going to try and call next on that.
There's a problem because it's not an iterator just yet.
So we returned to self basically when you call it or on counter which isn't an iterator it just returns
counter which isn't an iterator.
So that's not going to work.
The next thing we have to do is define the behavior of next.
And this is Dunder.
Next Next we call like this.
Like in our previous example here but when we do this next on an iterator it is calling that iterators
dot Dondre next.
So we have to add donder next self and we could do something really dumb like just have it return.
I don't know one over and over and over and if I actually read this right now I believe this would be
an infinite thing because we're not stopping at any point every time you call.
Next we get 1 1 1 1 1 1.
If I did that.
There we go.
OK stop this before I ruined my computer.
So we now have an infinite iterator which That's actually a thing.
But that's not what we want here.
What we want.
We could just return one over and over and over but we want to return starting with low.
And we want to keep adding one in and one over and over and over until we hit high.
So rather than calling this low we'll call it current and I'm going to set it to be low.
So in this case zero then what we want to do.
Well first we should check if self datt current is less than self-doubt.
Hi if if that's true this is where we're going to basically return the number and add 1.
So we would do something like equals self-direct current and then add one self current plus equals one
and then return home.
We need to do it in this order because if we return first it stops the execution.
And so if her turn was appear we would never add one to current and be stuck in that infinite loop.
So the first time through I get zero.
And then it adds one to current.
So current is one.
But then we return to your next time through normal self-talk current some numbers one self-taught current
is now two.
We return one and we keep going until we hit the end.
We're self-taught current is no longer less than the high number.
If that's if that's the case we just want to raise stop iteration just like this.
And that's actually all we should have to do.
OK.
So now what happens.
Let's walk through this.
When we call radio when we have four X encounters year to 10 the for loop is going to call her on this
instance of counter and it returns self.
Earlier we had it return like add it or string iterator or something.
But now this self is actually set up with the next method is able to call next over and over and over
until next your turn to stop iteration.
So if we check it out now there we go 0 to 9 and we could play around with this change it instead of
zero.
Let's go from 50 to 70 also.
So we're not quite at the point of range we don't have a step or we could do negative 1 or something
but that wouldn't be that much work to implement.
Why you would do this exactly.
I'm not encouraging that you need to rewrite range or something this is more to show you that it's possible
in the next video though.
I am going to show you how we can take a deck class.
We wrote a while ago and make it iterable.