All right.
So this video is all about getting data out of a list.
There's a couple ways we've seen how to create them in the last video.
But the data is just stuck in there.
So to get it out we first have to understand the way lists are ordered.
So here's an example a list called friends with three friends.
Very optimistic for my friend's situation.
Let's just say I wouldn't need a list to start my friends.
I could just get away with an integer is Europe.
So we have three strings here.
Ashley Matt and Michael three items in a friends list like ranges lists always start counting at zero.
So there's an order here that's very important and every of there's an order.
The first item is the zero with element that we call it an index it has the zero index than the index
of mad is one index of Michael is to.
So that's really really important.
0 1 2 let's always start at zero.
Then if we want to print out a particular piece of data or we don't have to print it we could save it
to a variable or do something with it.
We use square brackets after the variable name friends and we pass in an index.
So friends square bracket zero is going to go to the friends list and say hey what's the zero with item
which is actually just like if we did two we count 0 1 2 to Michael and that gives just Michael.
And if we tried something like three which doesn't exist we get an index error.
So let's test that out now.
I'll make a list called colors.
Start off with purple and we'll teal and then let's do orange.
OK.
So to get a piece of data out we use a variable name.
And let's start with getting purple colors.
Zero.
That gives us the string purple and we can save it to a variable like the best.
Calls colors zero.
Now if we look at the best.
It's purple.
But it's important to note colors is unchanged.
All this does is retrieve the value.
We're not deleting things we're not extracting it or removing it.
We are just getting the value out.
Just like if we had a variable you know X equals 10 and then I said y equals x.
X is still 10.
What have I done and why is still 10.
OK.
I make some space here.
You've got colors.
So yeah if we wanted to access orange it would be to 0 1 2.
And if we tried something like colors 3 we get lists index out of range.
It's basically Python saying I don't know what you're talking about.
You're trying to go past the worst same thing like we did 10.
So you might think that that would apply to negative numbers as well but it doesn't.
So the way that negative number works is that it's going to work backwards.
So with the same friends list that we have here Ashley Matt and Michael if we did friends of negative
one it starts counting backwards.
So negative one is Michael and Ashley is negative three so negative one negative to negative three and
we get Ashley but if we did negative four we get the same index error.
So just to show that let's do colors of negative 1 which gives us orange.
The last item and to get purple it would be colors of negative 3.
So going backwards we started negative 1 going forward to start at zero.
Of course there's no such thing as negative zero.
So we have to start with negative one.
OK.
So that's the basics of accessing values.
The next thing I'll show you is a little side note if you want to check if a value is in a list somewhere.
There's a really easy way to do it.
We use in so if we have the list I can say Ashli in friends and that gives me true just like any comparison
that we've done before with Boolean operations you know quality capitalization matters.
It has to match exactly.
And if we tried it with Colt is called Friends.
It's false.
So let's hop over here again and do colors and let's see if purple is in.
Friends.
Friends colors.
That's true.
But if I tried purple with capital P it's not.
And so we could do things like if teal in colors if that's the case let's do print.
Do you have good taste in colors.
Get a hit enter and we get you have good taste in colors because inside of colors is teal.
OK so the video here we saw a couple of important concepts the first and most important probably the
most important part of lists in general is that every item has an index.
There's an order and they always start at zero.
The first item has an index of zero.
We can access items out using array brackets.
The square brackets.
And if we try and go past the range we get an error.
We can use negative numbers to start from the end of the array and work backwards to towards the beginning
and then we saw in the very end.