OK in this video let's start by adding the play again behavior.
Right now the game ends after one play through and we have this after a while loop code.
Let's replace this with the code that would basically start the whole thing over.
I'm going to ask the user so I'll do a variable called again and I'll ask the user to know if they want
to play again.
So I'll do something like.
Would you like to play again.
Question mark.
And then just do Y such and an inference with a question mark afterwards.
I think that works better.
And what would be best is if we allow or we check to make sure a user enters one of these or the word
yes or no.
So we could do while again is not in and just do a tuple with y comma Yes and comma no.
Well again it's not in there.
Well ask again.
And all set again to be an empty string or none.
Doesn't really matter.
All right.
So we start off this is kind of the same thing we did with Guess guess what an empty string.
And then that made this part true.
So we then asked for a guess again or started an empty string that makes this entire thing run.
And it's true.
So this is executed because an empty string is not in here.
We'll ask them and we'll keep asking.
And then we need to check if again dot let's do Dalt lower is in.
And I should also do lower here just to be consistent.
If it's yes or no.
If it's one of those.
You could also just say if again that lower is yes or Again lower is why this is shorter.
If that's the case how are we going to play again.
Let's just start by printing.
OK.
You play again and then.
Otherwise let's do an else that just says OK goodbye.
Meaning that they typed and or no otherwise there are traps in this line or they're just asked over
and over again until they type one of these.
All right I have my Colon's.
What else.
Oh this should be in not is in is this for a direct comparison.
We just need in like we had up here.
Now let's test it.
So let's get it right immediately.
William Nicholson paste that in.
You got it right.
Would you like to play again.
Let's type one of the non answers.
All right.
Now I'm going to type Y capital Y we play get but of course it's not actually implemented yet.
So what do we want to happen when we play again.
We have a lot of we have a bunch of ways of actually doing this.
We could put this entire thing.
All of this in a loop and have a variable called play again like while playing with that playing starts
it's true and then down here we can set playing to true or playing to false and start the loop again
or a different approach that we haven't seen before is to put all of this in a function.
So what can I call that function let's call it def start game and let's say it just takes in a list.
Actually let's just call it start game for now that's fine.
Get rid of my wild playing and then indent all of this code all of this is part of start game then what
I'm going to do.
And we haven't really seen this.
If we want to play again we're actually going to call or start game and I'm going to return.
I start game and actually execute it.
So this remember return is going to end execution at this function.
But by returning this kindness it starts it over.
Exactly what it does and it begins again picks a new quote remain and guesses is reset and we go all
the way down through this again.
So we don't have to manage nested while loops.
This is just another approach that allows us to restart.
Otherwise we'll print OK goodbye.
And then that's the end of execution.
The only thing we have to do right now because we move this to a function we have to call start game.
So we'll just put that down here.
Let's see if it works.
OK so let's guess incorrectly and then let's guess Albert Einstein we're getting this correct.
A little hint.
I got it right.
But I'd like to play again.
Yes.
And.
OK.
It was the same quote.
Let's just see if that's a fluke.
That's possible if I just copy and paste I'd like to play again.
OK so now gave us a different quote.
So just happened to pick that same one again.
Let's get it correctly.
I'd like to play again.
Time will tell.
Yes.
Not Marilyn Monroe.
I meant to say J.K. Rowling Rowling whatever it is yes.
This it's a different one by her yes it is to the well organized mind death is but the next great adventure
this one is it says tumbled or that couldn't be any easier.
Come on one more time.
All right.
We are getting diverse ones.
And let's funk out of here.
Incorrect.
Well this is not going to help.
Let's play one more time then.
Guess wrong.
Keep guessing wrong.
One more time.
Sorry you ran out of guesses.
Would you like to play again this time.
No.
And then we're done.
OK.
So that actually is the complete behavior of the game.
Everything works.
We can play again.
We get that correct number of guesses we get the right number of hints.
If you wanted to you could take advantage of this for one of the hints to be more creative.
You could have one hint.
They gave both initials using what we've already done and then do another hint that maybe picks the
first line here or a random line out of the description and removes all instances of Marilyn Monroe
or whatever the author's name is.
You can also figure out the number of characters in the first name and the number of characters in the
last name.
Count those up do the same thing.
If we do a split and then you could call Lenn on the two strings and use those and say and print those
out to a user.
So maybe you can get more creative next let's address this here.
Let's just wrap this in a function called Get quotes or.
Actually it's a scrape of quotes scrape.
Def and then indent all this and then return from it.
Let's move all this stuff.
Well not the base you are.
We are going to need that in conventionally.
We should make this a constant which I'll talk about in just a second.
But let's move all quotes into here and then return all quotes like this.
So then we need to call scrape quotes first down at the bottom right.
There we go.
And we want to save the result to a variable let's call it quotes and then past quotes in to start game.
And it doesn't accept any argument so let's make that variable we call that quotes.
So we need to adjust this to the quotes to match that by calling all quotes anywhere else.
Always good to find that next previous.
OK.
It's all just inside that function which is fine.
So we have this here we will need to in the play again function where we return start game need to return
start game with the same list of quotes.
So we're scraping first and then recalling.
Start game with the quotes that we get back from scraping just to make this a bit more modular so we
can scrape separately if we wanted to.
For example in the next video I'm going to show how to update this to work with the CSP file.
We don't want to scrape every single time we might want to scrape once and then load data from a file
and then maybe scrape you know once every week or whenever it manually or we could learn to schedule
it too.
But that's a whole other thing.
OK.
So back to the base you are.
I'm going to make that.
It's all caps doesn't make a difference.
It's just to show that it's a constant.
This isn't supposed to change.
So then where every reference base you RL looks like we have it here.
Select all of them.
Okay.
And just replace them.
Base you are out in caps.
Otherwise I think we're good to go until the next video where we refactor things let's just verify it
still works.
Local variable you are referenced before assignment yes.
So you are well is assigned up here and then here I'm accessing while you are.
We just want to add that in here that's associated with scrape quotes.
Make sure it works.
Now OK.
It looks like it's going to work.
Who said this quote George Carlin.
That's correct.
The and just restart.
All right.
Let's see if that works.
Let's quit out of here.
Perfect.
In the next video we'll finish up refactoring this to use cxxviii file so we don't have to scrape every
time and we can get the game going immediately.