OK so in this video I'm just going to introduce the less basic rock paper scissors version still is
you know pretty simple game to play.
But now we actually have a computer player.
So it starts off the same rock paper scissors or whatever title card you want and then instead of player
1 and your choice it just says enter your choice because there's only one computer or there's only one
player.
So I entered paper and then the computer picked randomly scissors.
So the computer beat me.
So the AI which is a bit of a stretch to call it that the computer opponent just picks a random move
every time.
Now the thing is we haven't learned how to do that.
How do you pick a random anything.
So I'll give you a hint if you want to try it on your own first.
Otherwise I'll just show you in this video.
Kind of a bonus thing but what you would research is something called Rande at random and it will generate
a number for you.
So for rock paper scissors you basically need three numbers.
You could generate 0 1 and 2 and just pick one of those randomly using Rand int and then you basically
have a conditional that says OK if if the random number was zero then the computer plays rock.
If the random number was one the computer plays paper and so on.
So that's that's the easiest way to do that.
The only other thing I need to say if you are going to venture and do this on your own Rand.
It is not something that you can just use out of the box in Python.
You actually need to import something.
So Google it if you're going to try this on your own.
It's not you know it's a single line that you have to add.
So nothing crazy but it is out of the bounds of what we discussed.
But I encourage you to just check it out.
There's tons of stack overflow posts about generating random integers.
You can find it in the Python documentation.
I highly recommend that you do it.
So here's a quick demo of how it works.
There's two Python three and I called mine.
Version 2.
So let's enter our choice.
We'll do paper and the computer played rock and it beat me.
Let's do paper again.
And played rock again.
Oh my gosh computer's playing rock a lot.
There we go of course right when I'm trying to demonstrate that it is random.
We get three rocks in a row.
But finally the computer play paper and let's do one more.
I need a valid move.
Now we're getting a lot of rocks.
And finally oh my gosh how many later like 15 attempts I finally got the computer to play scissors.
It truly is random.
Well it's as random as computers can be.
That's for a whole other discussion and course it's not true randomness.
But this is more just a freak thing that I couldn't get scissors to work.
OK.
The only other thing I'd mention about it is that I made it case insensitive.
So we haven't talked but how to do that either.
So if you want you could research that.
But it allows me to play rock upper case upper case or in any capitalization that I could come up with
so I could do pay for like this.
And that works as well.
So if you want you can try to add that on your own as well.
OK.
Next video will have a solution.