Welcome back.
So the next thing we have to discuss around functions now that we've seen the basic syntax to define
one is how do we return values from functions.
And before we actually see how we do that to see the syntax.
Let's just talk about what it means to return a value.
So here I have a simple while simple.
It's an empty file.
Very simple.
And I'm calling it returned IPY can call it whatever you want.
Let's define a simple function called print.
Square of 2 the square of 7.
Never again.
So very trivial and silly but if we wanted to do this we could just print seven times seven or we could
do seven squared.
Either way let's do it like this just because it's a bit different.
And then of course I could execute.
Print square of 7 with parentheses.
And what do we expect to see.
Let's run it.
So that's Python 3 or turned up y and it prints 49.
OK.
So that's all great.
That should be review.
But what if we have something like this.
We've seen this all the time.
So we have a list of numbers and we do something like this.
Lanc equals Lenn of names like that where we're actually setting a variable equal to the result of running
a function Letten.
And if we look at link.
It's storing the number four.
So what's happening here is that this function runs.
It doesn't print anything but it's actually returning a value that we're capturing in this variable.
So we see this all the time or you know we do something like pop something off of here so we could do.
Last item equals number pop.
Once again we don't see anything.
And Gnome's is shorter now.
But last item stores the value of four which is what we popped off.
So how do we achieve this with our code.
Let's define another function and we'll just call this one square of seven and you might think oh we
have to do this instead of printing something we're just going to run 7 squared Let's try it and we'll
do a variable called results equals square of seven Whatever comes back when we executed.
And then let's do a print result and all comments out or other print come.
Both of these out.
What happens now if I execute it or I get none.
So what's happening here.
Well the answer is Nothing is being returned still by default.
Just you know running some code doing math whatever we do to finding a string in here that doesn't return
any value out.
And we have to be very explicit when we want them to be returned.
There's a magic keyword which surprise surprise is just return.
So we write a return and then whatever we want to send out of this function.
So we haven't talked about inputs yet.
That's coming up next.
But this is the output side of things.
So this function always returns a square of 7.
Every single time.
And if we wanted to capture it now it should work.
Our result variable will capture whatever has been returned.
Let's see.
Run it again.
There we go.
We've now returned seven times seven and captured in the result variable.
So here's a slide that demonstrates that by returning high string high if we save the result of say
hi the function name the result of executing it in a variable greeting greeting is equal to high.
So a couple of things to know about the keyword return.
It exits the function.
So let me demonstrate that now if I go back here and I do some I'll do a print afterwards that just
says I am after the return just like this.
And we run it you'll see we don't get that print statement even though it's part of the function.
As soon as our code runs.
So the first thing that happens is square of 7 is executed and the first line is returned forty nine.
And that end that ends the entire function.
It's done at short circuits that we never move on to here.
But if we swap them or instead we do another one up here that just says I am before like this and I
run it now we get in before the return then the return call.
Next is the fact that whatever we we place after the return key word is what is returned and we're not
limited to returning a single item.
That's all we'll do for now.
But you can use a tuple to return more than one piece of information from a function.
And finally it pops the function off the calls to cost.
So we haven't talked about the call stack.
We're not going to really in much detail right now but the main idea is that the call stack is sort
of like a To Do list for all the things all the tasks that Python has to do in executing your code.
And every time there's a new function call it gets added to this stack.
It's you know do this and this and this and this.
And by popping it off it moves onto the next thing.
So that's a very very simplistic explanation.
I don't want to get too bogged down in it but you can learn a lot more better at this you Arel or by
Googling it.
But I also recommend that you don't panic about it yet or ever.
It's not really something you need to know.
It's just a good thing to know that happens behind the scenes.
But it's all hidden from view.
OK.
So just to wrap that up.
The return key word is how we actually export or get a value out of a function so we can capture it
in a variable later or we could pass it into another function.
We could do something like print which is itself an other function.
So this runs first.
It returns a value 49 and it's basically the same thing it's just printing 49 which is itself a function
call.
So we'll leave it off here in the next video.
We're going to define a very short function that will help us with coin tosses.
I know not the sexiest thing ever.