Already.
So now that we've seen how to actually parse the HMO and select certain elements based off of their
tag name or attributes or CCS style selectors we're now going to talk about how we extract data out.
So we have these objects we've just been printing them.
So we see you know the string representation.
Well let's say I wanted to go to I don't know the weather some weather site dotcom and grab the temperatures
and the temperatures are always stored.
And does that have a class of temp.
But I don't just want the divs.
I want the text inside.
I want to know the number.
How many degrees we could use get text and this video will discover a couple of methods and attributes.
Get text this one.
Another is name that will retrieve the tag name of a given element.
Adder's is a dictionary of attributes that we can access and we can also access attributes using brackets.
So we'll talk about all four of these things.
All right.
So I'm here in my text editor.
I have a new file I just copied everything over from the previous one.
Same import statement the same multi-line each time string in a variable called HMO.
Same variables soup.
And I've started by selecting all items using select that have the class special and that gives us a
list.
So let's just narrow it down to the first one and I'm going to save this to a variable called El for
element.
So if we just print l we'll just see a string that looks like this.
If I want the inner text for example I can call get text.
So I'll do print l dot get underscore a text it's a method and when I run it you can see we get this
list item is special.
So get text.
Is it going to retrieve the text from that object.
And if I just print l it gives this representation.
Remember though it's an instance of an element class.
So there's a method to just retrieve this and that's useful because a lot of the time what we're going
to do with my weather example we'll go through and just extract certain bits of data usually inner text.
We can also do something like for L in souped up select special print l dot get text and then this should
give us however many items we have to get to in this case.
Give us the inner text and there we go.
Also let's see what happens if I move this on to an element that doesn't have inner text like.
What do we have this right here.
This meta tag you wouldn't really do this with a class at special but let's see what happens it doesn't
have any text.
And I call it and we just get nothing.
And that's the way that get text behaves instead of throwing an error.
In this case there is no inner text it just returns nothing.
Otherwise it will return the inner text.
Next let's continue to work with Special everything that has a cost special.
But I'm going to show you another thing we can access.
So instead of just the text there's also something called Dot name and it's not a method.
So a name should refer to the name of the tag like lie.
So for everything that has class name special we're going to print the name.
And there's three things.
It's and two allies.
Let's test it.
And that's what we get.
Metta ally ally.
Hopefully by now you can see how these these start to work together.
We select things we want on a page.
Then often you'll iterate over them and do something for each one.
Extract the name although more often than not you're extracting the data inside.
I'd say get text is really commonly used.
The next thing I'll show other than name.
Let's also print l dot adder's AT&amp;T r s and this is a dictionary containing key value pairs for the
attributes on each item.
So let's just run it and you can see that our meta tag had char set 88 in a class set to special.
This is a list because elements can have more than one class.
I'll show you that and actually let's give this second item a class of special and also.
I don't know.
Super special you separate them by a space.
If I'd run it again.
Beautiful soup.
Automatically parses that and gives us a list of two classes.
So this is using adder's to access the attributes and so you could do something like.
Print l adder's and then access.
Know class for example which this is redundant because we're only selecting things with class of special
you can see here we get special special.
Actually it's not quite redundant.
This one also had super special and then special.
And speaking of redundant we technically don't need to do this.
Dot dot ATRs if we're trying to access an attribute we can just do this.
Let me actually comment this out and do another example with a single item.
Let's say I want to select this H-3 So that would be soup and we could do it find H-3.
And that way we don't have to do zero or anything because we're only getting one item using find and
then I could do dot adder's if I wanted to access data example like this and type it all out.
Or I can use the square brackets directly on it just do do to dash example and save that to a variable.
Well just call it at her and then print HGT ETR and using that syntax you see if we get.
Yes this is just an arbitrary silly data example or attribute that's called data example we could do
the same thing with a div.
So if I select the first div and then I want to know the ID of that div
is called First which indeed it is.
So we have this syntax this nice shortcut that we can use to directly access attributes to get their
values.
If we have the key but you can also just called Dom adder's to get a dictionary containing all key value
attributes.
OK so we're almost there where we're actually going to start scraping and downloading edged him out.
And you know doing something in a more programmatic way and in the next video we're going to talk a
bit more about navigating between him elements relative to one another.
So not just the tag names not just selecting But once I have an element I might want to select the parent
or a sibling or something like that.
So we'll see how to do that.
To summarize what we saw in this video we saw get text access inner text we saw named to access the
name of a tag the element type and we saw two different ways of accessing attributes.
The adder's dictionary or using square brackets and the name of an attribute.