Next up we get to implement deck and deck is a bit more complex.
So I'm going to just delete that for now.
Copy and paste all of our requirements and then everything that we write will go below the requirements.
We could make a separate file.
Totally works as well.
But I'm going to do it just in the same file to make it easier for the video and for you to see the
solution.
So let's begin we define our deck class
and we need to have our init method take self no matter what.
But we're actually not going to pass anything in because at least the way that this exercise is written
every deck is the same.
There are definitely ways that you could expand on this.
You know I think I mentioned this earlier.
There are games like in Las Vegas.
I think they play with at least two decks sometimes four decks depending on the game they put them all
together and shuffle them together so you could allow this you know to have like number or quantity
or something.
But we're not going to get into that just self.
But what we do need to worry about is instead of that we're going to create a card attribute with all
52 possible instances of card.
OK so we know that self-talk cards is going to be.
But what we want is every possible combination basically between what do we have for the suits.
So that means hearts diamonds
clubs and spades.
And I'll start by just making that into a list and just call that suits I'll fast forward to the next
part.
I wanted to find the values.
OK.
I added the values list.
Now all strings just to be consistent because we have a for Ace K for King.
You could do this but then it would be kind of confusing dealing with it and strings.
So everything is a string.
It's up to King.
And I guess Ace is low in my example.
OK.
So as far as taking these two things and making a new instance of card basically want to do this right
card of ACE Khama hearts.
And then the same thing except ace diamond ace clubs a spade.
And then go to two of hearts two of diamonds.
And we want to take each thing and add it in two cards.
Maybe the first way that might come to mind is to use a nested loop.
So for something like four suit in suits and then we want to double loop for value in values.
We're going to call card.
And then what do we want to pass in passing the value first and then the suit just like that.
And we could just start by doing a print card to see if it all works and to run this I need to do a
deck.
We don't even need to save it to a variable just initializing any deck.
Well run this code and it should print.
I have my parentheses.
So you don't get an error.
Let's see what happens.
All right.
So you can see it goes through it starts with hearts and does Ace through King of Hearts and then it
goes to diamonds and then clubs and then spades.
So here we're just printing them.
So what we could do is take self-direct cards and then instead of printing we could do a append self-direct
cards.
A pen like this and this is perfectly valid.
If this is your solution that's great.
It works.
And at the end you know we can just print cards self-direct cards
and we get this list and the reason we're seeing you know a of hearts two hearts three of hearts instead
of those card objects is because when we printed it full of card objects each card is printed out according
to whatever we defined here in the repr method.
OK.
So this is totally valid solution but we can also do it in a more pythonic way using a list comprehension.
And it looks like this.
So we're going to create a card with value in suit and we'll just do for suit in suits for value in
values.
And you could swap these and do for value in values for suit and suits.
But this is basically doing the exact same thing but in a list comprehension we don't have to append
manually like we're doing down here.
So I'd prefer that way.
And let's just make sure I didn't mess it up let's print self-talk cards again.
Looks good.
OK.
So we've checked off this first syllable a point next.
Nice and easy deck should have an instance method called count which returns a count of how many cards
for main deck.
All right.
So it's an instance method.
So down here we'll just do a def count and we need self in there and all we want to return is what the
self-direct card list we want to know the length of that list.
So it's just Lenn self-doubt cards and that should be it.
So let's now save D2 a variable and just do print the dot count and we should see 52 and we do make
sure it works do the cards pop and run it again and we should see 51.
Perfect.
OK.
So we're done with those first two next decks.
Method should display information on how many cards are in the deck like a deck of 52 cards deck of
12 cards etc..
So we'll do def EPR.
I like to do these up top all the Dunner methods together.
And that also needs self and all we will return again a few using here using the Tommy test that I wrote
then you want to use that format.
It must be upgraded to 3.6.
I will post an announcement about that.
But if they haven't used that format that I'm going to use and F string and all that we'll do is we
could use Lenn of self-love cards but we've already written that here as count.
So I'll just write a deck of.
And then and here we just call self dot count cards.
Perfect.
So now if we make a deck we can just print the deck and we should get a deck of 52 cards assuming I
didn't mess anything up.
And it looks good.
A deck of 52 cards.
OK.
And we can trust because Count was working when we popped one off.
We can trust that it still works just fine.
Nothing is changing count.
All right.
So that's three down.
Next deck should have an instance method called Deal underscored deal which accepts a number and removes
at most that many cards in the deck.
It may need to remove fewer if your request more cards and are currently in the deck.
If there are no cards left this method should return a value error.
OK.
There's a lot of pieces to that.
Let's start by just defining and def deal self and then the number of cards that we want to remove from
self dumb cards.
So the idea is if we call and this is going to be an internal method that we only use We're going to
create deal hand or deal card and deal hand in just a moment that will then call underscore to you and
the first thing we'll start with is just checking how many cards are in the deck.
So let's just make a variable called count because self-deceit count.
And then what we want to do is test this against the number that that's been passed in let's say for
some reason someone wants to remove 53 cards but there's only 52.
So what we want to do is compare the number that's been passed in with the count how many cards are
left.
And basically whichever one is lower we will use.
So if a more realistic example let's say that there's only I don't know I'm going to just represent
each card as a See say there's three cards left and the user wants to remove five cards.
Well we're going to only remove three.
So we'll take the least of them.
So what we can do is use a little builtin function min and we want to find the minimum of count and
numb.
So whichever one of those is lower We'll save it to a variable and let's just call that variable.
I don't know what should we call that actual the actual number we're going to remove.
And let's just add a little print here that says going to remove and then actual cards then it's an
F string in order to work.
OK.
So let's test it out at the beginning.
D is Dirk.
There's 52 cards.
If I try and do d dot even though we're not supposed to call underscore deagle from outside the class
we can just for testing purposes here.
But as developers we should respect that.
Underscore deal and then let's try to get rid of fifty four cards.
OK.
Let's see what happens and we get going to remove 52 cards.
But if I was going to remove five it tells us we're going to remove five cards.
So it's just taking whatevers less.
OK.
So that works.
There is a problem though which is if the count of the cards left is zero and somehow this got called
with number being 0 they're trying to remove something from an empty deck.
Let's handle that case.
So that will just be simple if Count equals zero if there's zero cards left.
And we could actually even just do that at the very beginning.
If there's zero cards left what do you want to do.
Let's raise an error.
And I think the specification is here.
See all the way over here we go.
Value error with the message.
All cards have been dealt
to any value error.
All cards have been dealt.
Perfect.
OK so next we're going to take our list of cards which is self-direct cards and let's say numbers five.
We want to take the last five cards and return those as a list.
But we also need to make sure we're removing them from self-edit cards because the dealer card it needs
to come out of the deck.
We're not just taking the five values and keeping them in there and will always get the same five cards.
We want to remove them from the deck.
And what we can do is actually use a slice.
So if you don't remember the slice syntax what we're going to do here is go from negative actual to
the end.
So actual is going to beat the number of cards for removing.
So let's say we have a list that looks like this.
And actual is going to be three cards.
So we're going to go 0 or back three so this going to be back one back to back three and then take that
slice all the way to the end.
That's what this call signifies.
So then that's going to give us this slice and we'll save that to a variable.
Let's just call it hand equal self-direct cards or actually just go with cards.
Notice it's different than self-dual cards.
It's cards.
And then what we want to do is actually update self-direct cards so that it now goes from the beginning
of the list up until what we just took off even though we didn't take it off.
But what we want to remove is at the end so to do that we're going to do self-direct cards equals self-direct
cards another slice.
We go from the beginning.
That's colon to negative actual.
So now we're going to go from the beginning up to say actual This three to one negative to negative
three.
We go from there to there and that's what self-direct cards is.
And the last step is going to be return cards which is what we took off.
OK.
So one thing I did notice here.
I need those parents after my value error.
Let's test this all out by making your deck.
And then we'll deal.
Let's start by doing three and that's printed.
So we can see what we get back.
And then to verify it's working let's do print the dot count.
OK.
All right.
So we have the three cards that we're dealt returned here and then the count is now 49 instead of 52.
Of course we are getting J Q And K jack queen and king of spades because they are the LAST things.
There is no shuffling just yet.
So we always get the same thing.
And let's just check one more thing.
Let's now.
Well first let's get rid of this print.
We don't need to print those cards in a net anymore.
But now let's try afterwards if we deal all the cards.
So they'll be 52.
And then I try and deal I don't know three again.
Afterwards it goes from here is all 52 count is 0.
Now we get this value error.
All cards have been dealt.
Perfect.
OK.
Moving on along we have shuffle the whole card and deal hand.
Let's go with Deal card and deal hand first because they're very similar down here.
Define deal hand first deaf deal.
Hand or those two card.
I lied and this always just deals one card.
So it doesn't need any parameters there.
And all we return is the result of calling itself underscore deal and then passing in one.
But the thing about where is that deal card it should return a single card.
So not a list.
And right now if we called Deal under square deal with one it gives us a list with one card in it.
So we want to return the zero with element.
This would give us a card rather than a list with a single card.
And then we'll do the same thing.
Def deal.
Hand deal hand side from self.
Also takes a number.
So we'll just call it no.
And it's just going to return self that underscore deal and then we pass in no.
And rather than let's go with hand size I think that's more appropriate for what we're actually dealing
with.
And we want the list because this is a hand of cards.
We want all five cards in a list or three cards or whatever it is.
All right.
And lastly we need to deal with Shuffle shuffle shuffle a full deck of cards.
If there are cards missing the method should return a value error with the message only full decks of
cards which are only full decks can be shuffled.
So to actually do the shuffling I'm going to import random and actually I'm going to do from random
import shuffle.
That's the only method I need.
So import that shuffle method and then I'll define my own shuffle down here.
Def shuffle self OK.
And all we want to do is call shuffle which is not this shuffle it's this one from random and passen
self cards.
But remember we want to add our conditional check to see if let's do if self-taught count is less than
52.
So if it's not a full deck we're going to raise a value error.
And I think I already copied it.
There we go.
Only full decks can be shuffled.
I didn't specify this but it is good practice to return self here even though we don't have to.
So I can just prove to you it works so let's do deck Deedat shuffle and then let's do print D-don't
cards and if we look everything is shuffled before it was all the hearts upfront all the spades and
now everything is mixed up.
We don't have to return self.
It won't actually make a difference.
But if for some reason we wanted to save it to a variable we're now capturing self.
It's just a conventional thing to do.
OK.
So that's a lot of work here.
A lot of code let's just test things out so we can make a new deck.
I'm going to shuffle it.
I'm going to make a hand.
I'll call it.
I'll call it hand a variable and I'll make it equal to d dot deal.
Card let's print hand.
Well I've called that one card print card and then let's do hand equals deal.
Hand of five cards and let's print hand.
OK.
Test it out and it looks like at an executer method here on deal card.
There we go.
So just telling me oh yeah I know that method.
Try that again.
OK.
So if we get a single card five of clubs then we get three of clubs.
Now if clubs Jack Diamond six of spades and ace of diamonds all in a list when we call the hand this
time let's do a hand of 50.
So this should give us one.
I'll take one card away and then we'll do 50 and then let's do one more afterwards and we'll print that
card too.
And then well let's just see what it looks like at the end to a print deck of cards at the very end.
I mean the dark cards not deck.
And we get first card second card and then the fifth here that I'm printing and then an empty burst.
And so if we tried to deal one more card we should get an error because deal card will try and call
deal and deals and I checked if there's zero cards left.
And if that's the case give us an hour and it does.
All right so your implementation might look a bit different which is totally fine depending on how you
want to structure things you know Order of the methods doesn't really matter other than the fact that
I like to put these Dondre methods up top and net referer all that stuff.
And yeah hopefully you're still alive.
It was a long video by now.
Hopefully some of this object oriented stuff makes a bit more sense by how we organize functionality
and pieces of information data into these classes and then instantiate objects using those classes.
If not we have plenty more practice and in the next section we're going to continue with O.P. and talk
about some of the trickier parts some more nuance things including inheritance and fun word called polymorphism
which sounds scarier than it actually is.
See you.