Hey welcome back.
So this section has been all about errors and handling them identifying them raising our own.
But now we're going to talk about the other side of the coin which is when we encounter an error in
our code that is not intentional.
So we didn't raise it.
We didn't expect it.
Something's not going the way we want whether it's a very loud angry error that's actually printing
out an error to our terminal or a silent error meaning or a silent bug.
It's more likely you would hear it as meaning that something isn't working the way we expect but it's
not actually breaking the code.
So that's the most frustrating is when you have code and you expect it to work one way and it doesn't
break.
It just gives you a different result.
The tool I'm going to introduce called PDB will actually help us understand our code and step through
it to figure out where we're going wrong.
So PDB stands for Python debugger.
It's a module just like random that we included earlier on in the course that we have to manually import
in our code with a single line.
And then we have access to it.
So we don't have to install it or anything.
And then by importing it.
And then there's a single method that we'll call which will pause execution of our code.
It looks like this PDB that said trace that wherever we put it in our code on line 1 or on line 100
when Python encounters that line it will pause.
So it doesn't quit it doesn't skip everything else it pauses and then in our terminal we can go and
interact with values or we can step through one line at a time.
So enough of explaining it.
Let me just show you here I have a really simple file and we're not going to debug something you know
mysterious that we're not sure what's happening.
This is super simple I have two variables both strings.
I'm adding them together into a third variable.
Then I make another variable actually called Third and I add that into result and then we print a result.
So nothing groundbreaking but we're still going to use it as just our starter debugging code.
So the first thing we need to do if we want to use PDB is import it.
And we've seen how to import code we saw to import random in the Rock Paper Scissors section.
So we import a module just by name import PDB and then the magic fine.
Is this right here.
PDB does set trace and ninety nine point ninety nine percent of the time when you work with PDB at least
when I do this is what I use.
And we put this wherever we want.
If we actually had something that was breaking I would put it right before the line or the couple of
lines where things were breaking and then that allows you to see a preview of what happens before and
then step through it and then step after it.
But for now let's just put it right.
Let's go right here.
So we're going to define first and then second and then stop.
And when I run this file Python is going to get to here and it's going to stop and then I'm going to
be able to go explore.
So it opens up this new shell for me to start typing in.
And the only other thing I'll point out there are some commands down here and we'll talk about these
in just a second.
But first let me just show you when I run it so this file was called debugging.
OK so look what happened.
Results equals first plus second.
This is telling me this is the next line that it's waiting to execute and going back to these commands
here.
There's this command Oh I can type in if I type L you can see PDB.
So normally we run a python file and it executes.
Maybe it will ask for input or something and it's done in our prompt goes back to normal.
That's not the case here.
It's waiting.
And I'll type L which stands for list which will show me where I am.
Sort of like a map.
And so it shows me that basically this is the last thing to run.
And the arrow is pointing to what happens next.
OK.
So it's showing us that this is next.
And what I can do now is explore some of the values.
So for example if I type First you can see that it has value it's set to first.
If I type.
Second it has a value as well which is second.
That makes sense but if I try to access a variable like Third it's not yet defined because this line
hasn't been run yet neither has this one.
So if I tried.
Result.
Same thing.
Name error.
So if something was going wrong with this code this is exactly what I would do.
I set trace somewhere and I'd check variable values before I'd look at you know results.
Ok it doesn't exist yet.
And then I would use the PDB command to move to the next line to actually execute this line and then
pause here and then I would look at the value after that line executed in the command to do that.
It's in this file.
It's an next line.
So if I type and look at where the arrow is right here or just this is the next line to run I type and
and the arrow has moved down if I type L again for a list you can see this line has run and we're waiting
on this one next.
And if I type results it now has the value of first second.
So by the end of this code it will have first second third.
So and also if I if I look at the value of Third it's still not defined.
This is the last thing to run.
So I can step through with and again.
And now if I look at a third it's equal to the string there first is still the same.
So a second result is only first plus second.
But now if I step through one more time you can see the result.
Now it should be equal to first second third and it is.
And then the last thing to happen when I execute this is for print result to run.
And so I can hit and again and then it prints result which is what we get right here.
So if you can see how this is useful already I should mention to get out of here.
You can use the command Q to quit and it's really not graceful It basically like throws a wrench in
everything and gives us an error message.
That's a two way of quitting.
So there's another way of quitting if I rerun this which is kind of counterintuitive.
The C commander's stands for continue which seems like the opposite of quit but it actually just means
to continue with the rest of the code.
So if this is where he paused just continue with everything afterwards.
And then that will you know in a split second execute our code and we'll be done and it won't quit out
with that hideous message.
So I type C and it runs everything which only prints first second third.
That's really all that happens in our code.
And then we go back to normal.
We're out of that PDB world.
One other thing of note about PDB.
If we had some sort of some code that looks something like this and I'll just paste it in and comment
this out.
The first thing I'll point out is that most of the time at least when I use PDB a lot of other developers
will just do it on a single line import PDB and you need a semicolon here.
Otherwise Python freaks out because it thinks this is all an import.
So this is a way of doing multiple lines on one line import PDB and then use it.
And the only reason for that we'll talk more about imports in the modules section I should've mentioned
that earlier in this video.
Don't worry about modules for now but the main reason is that really this is usually in my code for
five minutes 10 minutes an hour however long I'm debugging something and then I get rid of it.
It's not something you keep in your code with all the other import statements up top.
So it's usually that use like this.
OK.
But the main point I want to make here is that if I have variable names like A B C and D and I save
and I execute this where I'm setting trace here and let's say that I'm calling add numbers 1 2 3 4.
OK let's go back over here.
I run it now.
And let's look where I am.
So we're returning A B C and D and if I try and access the values I can fight type D.
For example I get this newest frame or if I typed a this is giving me basically all values I believe
is what H stands for and it's not actually giving me the value of a self for Type B.
And I think that's a command and free type C that is a command right that quits out as we saw earlier.
So if you have variable names that conflict with the commands like L..
If we had a variable named L. then and each time I typed elf It would just list things instead of giving
us the value of L.
So instead what we can use to print the actual value let's say of C..
I don't want to quit type C it would quit or continue which would effectively quit.
I can type P which stands for print.
So print the value of c and we get three print a and I get one now ABC and D are terrible variable names
so serves me right.
If you use those as variable names but just beware anyway that if you are using single letter variable
names they may conflict with existing PDB commands and I showed some of them here.
These are the ones I commonly use that there are more out there for example as we saw.
So just be careful with your variable names and if something weird happens in PDB and it's not what
you expect.
Check the name of your variables.
You may have a conflict with an existing command.
All right.
So that kind of wraps up what I want to cover in this video.
We import PDB run P-T beat up set trace that halts execution.
I would one thing I should mention in this example we have a function defined in PDB that said trace
doesn't actually run until we execute the function.
So Python goes over this and it's like oh this is a function it's not being executed yet it's just being
defined.
So I'm not going to run Python that PDB that said trace.
But as soon as we execute add numbers then this is executed.
So that makes sense.
Otherwise if it ran right away and I tried to access ABC Indee there would be no values assigned to
them.
So that's PDB short for pretty dang Bewkes useful.
Pretty dang amazing.