A welcome back.
So this video we're going to talk about the different modes for working with files.
We've already seen to that default which is our Which you never actually manually typed but the a default
value which allows for reading from a file and then W in the last value which stands for right.
And that worked to write to a file.
But the problem was that it overwrote whatever used to be in there and the existing contents are erased.
So there are other modes.
And actually if we go to the built in functions on the docks click on the open there is a chart here
that shows you there's quite a few We've already seen.
R and W now we're going to talk about a couple of others just the commonly used ones.
We're not going to talk about things like binary mode but if you are curious just know you can come
to the docks and not only is there a good explanation of open here but it also goes into detail on the
different modes.
But I'll just highlight the commonly used ones.
So first up are we've already seen that doesn't allow you to write to the file to a default value w
writes to a file overrides or overwrites whatever was in the file before.
Next is a stands for append.
So what append will do is allow us to add contents to the end of a file.
It won't overwrite what used to be in there.
It just keeps adding on to the end.
So for example we have this haiku that ticks the file already.
And if I ran this code with w it would overwrite it.
But if I simply change it to the letter A and I run the file.
Now I go back to high kuda to 60.
You can see that this was the existing contents.
Right here up until there and then this has everything new.
Oh no I just messed it up.
There you go.
This was everything new that we added in and so it just appended to the end.
And then this is where cursor stops.
Anything else they add in.
Let's do one more.
Let's do something simple file that right.
Appending later save.
Rerun go back to our file and it's on the same line because we are in append mode and if we didn't want
things to be on the same line like this the better approach.
So we just use the newline character.
But the better approach is to put it at the end here rather than putting at the beginning of whatever
we add next.
It doesn't really matter but ideally we should have done this.
Put that new character there.
Run it go back.
OK so it added to the same line but now our cursor is here and in Python I mean not the bottom cursor.
Now if I did something else like just a simple little happy face.
One more time.
It's on the new line.
So this is append and that works well.
But what if you want it to go back and add something up to the top.
What we could do is use seek right and do something like this file about 6 0 and then let's add another
smiley face up top.
And so what should happen or what we think.
Well OK I'm kind of setting it up here but what you might expect to happen is that our cursor and move
appear.
We had a happy face but because it's append mode it just adds it to the end so we don't actually have
control over where the cursor is.
It's appending always to the end no matter what.
So definitely worth knowing there's a shortcoming to append mode that brings us to our next and final
mode which is our plus.
Read and write to a file and we can use a cursor.
So our plus is really commonly used in my experience at least if you're working with existing files
that already have stuff in them.
If you need to go and make changes or insert things somewhere else in the file rather than just to the
end.
OK so let's test it out.
I'm back in the same file as before.
I have the W version retried.
If the A to append.
Now here I've added r plus.
I should note I kind of messed up a file and accidentally overwrote the existing contents in between
recording the videos.
So I just added a new line says I was here first and now if we use our Plus I'm just going to leave
it like this added using are plus and just a single line open same file our Plus file but right let's
see what happens.
I run the code.
Let's go look and look what happened.
Two things to note.
The first is that it was added at the beginning of the file by default.
I didn't have to specify to seek zero to append is automatically going to or by default.
Actually append only can add to the end of the file.
But if we use our Plus it will start off with the cursor at the beginning at zero.
But we also can move it around.
The second thing you should notice though is that we also overwrote what was here before.
So you do need to be aware of the fact that if you if your cursor is here and you're adding text it's
not just going to insert your text and then shift things over.
It's going to overwrite.
OK.
So if we go back now and delete this and just say I was here first again go back here and we can add
this at the beginning.
Let's do a smiley face lets you smiley face and then let's do file but seek to.
I don't know.
Let's go to position 10 and do a filed out right and do a sad face.
OK.
So we started the beginning at a happy face.
Move to ten.
Move the cursor over and then write a sad face on the code.
Hop on back.
You can see here's her happy face.
And here's her sad face.
OK.
So hopefully that shows the behavior of these different file modes.
So if you are only adding to the end of a file that's all that you're doing and use append.
You don't have to worry about overwriting things you're just always adding to the end.
Obviously if you're just reading you don't even have to specify that if you are solely writing and you
want to overwrite the contents then use W and if you need to be able to update things or overwrite at
will and move the cursor and you can use our plus.
Oh and one last thing if we try and do file that right here let me do one more with our plus to a nonexisting
file.
Like I don't know.
Hello.
T t r plus.
And I just want to write Hello in there like this.
If I run it there isn't a hello to textfile if I run it now.
We actually get an error file not found no such file or directory hello that text t but when we used
w or for use a actually and I rerun that.
You'll see it actually creates hello that text for me.
So that's one thing to be aware of our Plus is only going to work with an existing file.
The idea is that you're updating an existing file but with the plus really means versus a it's going
to end w will both make any file if it doesn't find it.
So just be aware of that.
Oh the joys of file modes.
All right.
So I just added a comment here that says our Plus will not create a file if it doesn't exist and we
are done with this video.