Hey welcome back.
We're almost there.
We just have to talk about how to make your own folders using the power show and also how to make files.
And this video will cover directories.
It's very straightforward.
It's the exact same command as Linux.
M K D are short for make directory.
So you just type make.
DIR followed by the name of the new directory you want to make and it will make that directory as a
child of the current directory.
For example if I'm currently in the stuff directory if I ran the command make dear cat pics that's the
name of the new folder.
It's going to make a new child folder nested inside of stuff wherever I was when I ran that command.
And you can see stuff is instead of code instead of users.
And if I type CD cat pics I now have moved into that new directory I couldn't have done that earlier
because it didn't exist.
Ok so I am in my home directory and my power show.
Let's go to the desktop and if I look at the desktop there's only two folders right now.
I think it can show you that.
There we go recycle bin that counted and then color code and stuff.
So if I type M-K DJR I'm on the desktop.
Let's make a new folder just called which we call it might not cat pics.
So the ATP I see as there does you see it showed up.
So this is Power Shell the command line is like a shortcut to main line into the artery of your computer.
It's allowing us to directly interact with and change files and folders and so on.
This is another interface but it has a few more layers of abstraction to give you the graphical components.
This is the more direct but also a little uglier or a lot uglier version.
So if I type LS I now have this new cat pics directory and I can change into it.
CD cat pics so cat pics is empty if I type.
LS There's nothing in there I could try making another directory inside like I have one cat named Blue.
So I make a directory called Blue CD into blue using tab complete and just to verify if I double clicked
on this.
You can see there's now a blue directory that's empty.
OK so that's all there is to making folders using M-K Diyar make dear.
So if you are partial to the graphical user interface and you want to just make your folders.
Actually don't even know the shortcut of think.
What do you type this.
Yes that makes us a new folder so actually be interesting.
My other cat was named Well she doesn't have a name.
I've been calling her Kitty.
I made a new folder if I type LS from inside of blue.
I don't see anything for CD Back out to cat pics.
I now have a new folder.
So two ways of doing the same thing.
If you prefer.
There's nothing wrong with using this again.
All you need to be able to do is navigate using the command line to find a folder and find a file to
execute with Python.
So if you make that folder file with Python it doesn't matter to me.
It's just.
I personally find it faster for me.
But as a beginner it definitely can be slower but the only way to get faster is to practice.
So I recommend doing it.
But if it's going to discourage you from taking the course or discourage you from working with Python
then absolutely do whatever you're most comfortable with.
To make the new folders and files in the next video will actually see how to make a new file.