OK.
So we've seen a lot of different characters in some of the syntax so far.
We're not done.
We're not going to go over everything but in this video I'm going to focus on one feature which are
these square brackets on this cheat sheet you call some of the character classes section.
It allows us to specify groups of characters or ranges of characters.
So back here if I if I want to select any vowel but say I can't just do a e i o u that's gonna match
exactly.
I or you and we don't have any instances of that.
But if I put it in these brackets A.
Oh you like that.
Now it's going to match any instance any anything where there is one of these characters.
So e o o I want it to match you know double vowels.
I could just add to there.
Now it's finding any time there are two vowels next to one another.
Years and g mail and then this thing here.
And it is case sensitive so we could you know if we put the uppercase A in there.
It's different.
Also I should mention we can use ranges of characters.
So the common ones you'll see lowercase a dash Z.
It's going to be any lowercase letter.
So it doesn't include any of these uppercase letters.
Doesn't include this uppercase s are numbers it's only lower case letters.
You could do a through I don't know f and it only gives us the letters between a NF.
Not that common to do that maybe.
Actually if you're doing hexadecimal if you're familiar with hexadecimal this would work.
Where are the letters that are allowed or a b c d e f.
You can also do uppercase.
So a through capital Z is going to be all uppercase letters.
So that gives us purple if I wanted to select all words that are only you know one or more uppercase
letters I could do.
Plus there will actually one or more but stoops to two or more.
And that gives us purple's the only instance where there's more than one uppercase character in a row.
I add another one.
LR Well it also selects that you could do numbers like this zero 3 9 which we've already seen you know
slashy backslash d to select digits.
The reason you would do this if you wanted lower case letters or numbers is this a dash to see zero
or Dash 9.
So that's all lower case letters all digits.
So you can use the square brackets to specify custom ranges or groups of characters.
One nice thing I'll show you is the carrot character.
If you use it on its own outside of the square brackets we'll see in the next video.
It means something different but inside square brackets it it means not.
So if I had let's say I really hate the letter.
What a way.
I don't really hate anything let's say anything that's not the letter K.
Well if I just do K it's only going to get me.
But if I do not the letter K gives me anything that is in the letter K so any values I put in here.
Let's say anything that is not zero through nine or a vowel so a e i o u.
And that gives me Oh that is including spaces.
So it's also at a space in there and I think and the at sign so you know for trying to only get consonants
which is what my goal was.
We're close although it still includes special characters so we could put any special character in here
to Sarkin to be included now because we have that carrot there.
And if we removed it it's only going to select the numbers and the vowels the spaces and the outside.
OK.
So that is square brackets very useful back in the slides.
You might remember the email example I use square brackets a lot.
So at the beginning we're looking for lower case letters uppercase letters digits underscore period
plus sign in the dash one or more of those it's the plus sign means as we've seen.
So we put them in the square brackets.
Same thing here slightly different use slightly different use here but the same idea where we're selecting
these from a group of acceptable values.
Ok so that is the square brackets.