OK.
So now that we've seen the basics of making GET requests with the requests package as well as sending
search parameters or query strings using prims now we have enough information to make a little program
that does this.
So I called my dad up he Wib it says dad joke 3000 It's the name of our program.
You don't have to do this ascii art with the colors if you don't want to.
But what I do want you to try is ask for a joke.
So give it topic let's do snow maybe.
And then it should print out.
I've got four jokes about snow.
Here's one what did one snowman say to the other snowman.
Do you smell carrot.
So what it does if it gets back.
Multiple results.
Then we're going to pick one at random.
So you'll need to use the random module as well.
And if we search for something that only gives us one result I think fruit only had one result.
I've got one joke about fruit is.
My wife is on a tropical fruit diet.
House is full of stuff.
It is enough to make a man go mango crazy.
Yeah.
Terrible.
And then lastly if we search for something that there are no jokes about like that it should say sorry
I don't have any jokes about it.
Please try again.
So three different scenarios.
We get multiple jokes.
So no matter what you're going to ask the user for input and you're going to send a request to the search
and point of I Can Has that joke dot com slash search query string term equals whatever the user types.
Then depending on what we get back you're going to have to make a decision is a conditional and just
check how many results I get back if results is equal to 1.
Well if results is 0 and doesn't exist then I don't have any jokes if it's equal to 1 print that joke
and if it's equal if it's greater than one randomly sample one or choose one from the list and display
that.
OK.
So give it a shot in the next video.
I'll have a solution when you don't have to do this of course if you just want to watch the solution
and quote along with me that's also an option.
So in the next video I will build this.