Hey welcome back.
This is a video I am really excited about.
I'm going to show you a pretty powerful tool called scrappy slash scrappy.
I've never known how it's actually pronounced.
I just say both internally in my head.
So one of those whatever it's pronounced it is a really really really powerful three release framework
for scraping and write a framework.
It's a it's different than things we've seen so far.
Like the requests module or beautiful soup our single purpose separate entities that we can connect
together and we have a lot of flexibility in how we actually structure our code if we want to write
it class if we want to write just a bunch of functions.
If we don't want any functions at all we can name things whatever we want.
Scrappy skyscraper is very different.
It's a framework for extracting data bundles together the making of the HDP requests along with the
extraction of the data and writing the data to a file and it can very easily change from writing to
a CXXVI file to adjacent file.
It has all of this functionality built in with just a couple of lines.
We can get some really really impressive results if we had to do it on our own.
It would it would take significantly longer.
But the downside is that we have to follow the rules that the framework sets up.
We have to name things a particular way we have to have a special variable called Start you or else
for example because it's going to look for that variable name.
So if we want to use it any framework if you want to use a framework whether it's for scraping or web
development or anything else you generally end up sacrificing flexibility for speed and ease of use.
Like any external module we need to start by running the install.
So Pipp install rapee scrappy.
I already have it on here.
It is a bit of a long install compared to some other things because it's actually installing a lot of
other modules and packages that it relies on.
And then I'm going to make a file.
And let's just call this book scraper why we're going to be working with this same web site.
What's it called books to scrape or to scraped outcome except we're going to work with books.
There are a whole bunch of them.
It's 50 pages of books and we are going to automate the scraping of all of them and get data from all
of them.
I mean it's going to put that you are out here the way that scraper works.
If you want to look at the documentation they have some very good docs.
Unlike a lot of other things in Python where it talks about dependencies but also lots of examples how
you can create what are known as spiders and that's what we're going to create now.
And it's a class that defines how a certain site or group of sites will be scraped including how to
perform the crawl.
So crawl refers to scraping a page and then and then moving onto the next page finding another link
on that site and following that and scraping it and then following a link from that site which is a
really powerful concept.
We're just going to scrape and crawl across the book's data but if you wanted to you know you could
start on one page on Amazon.
Now I recommend you do this and I want to get in trouble.
But if you did scrape a single page on Amazon the front page how many links are on there.
A thousand links something like that.
Maybe a little less.
But if you followed each one of those whether it was a book's link or a shopping cart link or sporting
goods or recently viewed whatever best selling you click or you follow all of them dynamically using
your code and then you scrape all the links on that page and you follow all of those.
Pretty soon you'll most likely have a complete picture of every page on Amazon that you can access without
logging in without credentials.
It's the same idea that powers Google so Google knows about sites that come up.
It's all about links which is why a lot of SEO has to do with links or at least it used to anyway.
We're going to start on a very small scale but you could take what I'm going to show you and apply it
to scraping something much more intense and that's why I'm showing it to you if you want to do some
real intensive scraping scrape you can really be helpful.
First and foremost we need to import scrape.
And then we need to define a class.
And I'm going to call it book spider and it has to inherit from scrape the spider.
So this is some of the framework coming into play.
It works by having us to find a class that inherits from scraping dust spider and then we have to define
a couple of things like well defined a name in here just call it book spider and then we have to define
a list called Start you or else.
So these are the do or else that we're going to start off on like that the first thing to request and
scrape and for us we're just going to start with this one.
You are out right here and that's it.
Next and most importantly we have to define the Parse method and scrape he is going to look for every
spider that we define to have this parse method.
So we'll do death parts and it works like this self Khama response.
So this is how we want to parse the requests are the result of the request.
So it's going to make this request automatically I don't have to say you know requests don't get I don't
have to do any of that.
It does it for me and then it's going to call parse and it's going to parse over and over depending
on how we define parse and I'll show you that in a moment it's going to call it on every single response
it gets back that it's that we want to scrape.
So the response needs to be in there we can call it whatever we want just like we can call self whatever
we want.
That this is standard and response is going to refer to what we get back from the HTP request.
So now we have to go over here and figure out the data we want.
So if we inspect and we look at one of these books what are we going to save.
Looks like each book is in an article.
And I think that's true for all of them.
Just move over here.
That one is also in an article that has a class of product pade.
So we are going to select all of those.
Everything that has article or an article with a class product pod and then will loop through all of
them and to find the price on this one for example.
It's inside of a div with the class of product price.
And actually inside of that we have a classical price color and that's what we're going to want.
Here is the inner text of that.
And then what else.
The title title black dust.
We find that here instead of an anchor tag with we just want to attribute here title title equals black
dust or the inner text.
But I'm going to show you how to get an attribute because the syntax we're no longer using beautiful
soup.
So everything we've seen in this section aside from the concept of how it works everything's going to
be different syntactically.
OK so we saw those classes.
Now what we need to do is first start by calling response CSSA.
And this is the method that we use.
It's sort of like select when we use beautiful soup we had soup out select and then we could tell it
find based off of a class name like Dot.
What was it called.
I don't know what special that would give.
All items are a special class.
We're going to do respond step C S S and we want to look for all articles with the class product pod.
This is CSSA syntax.
If you don't know C S S I apologize.
This is how we specify all articles that have the class product pod and then we're going to do a four
article in that the way this framework works when we create a spider.
We need to use yield instead of return because it's going to continue to go over and over and over.
So whatever we yield here let me just type it out.
Yield and or just can yield a little dictionary that has a price set to something.
So I'm going to just add what we want.
It's not going to work just yet.
So we're going to have a price and then we'll have tidal.
Let's just start with that.
OK.
And so by yielding this it will at the end of the day be taken care of and added to a file this is how
it works on the dock so you can see the Parse method is in charge of processing their response and returning
scrape data and or more year up or else to follow.
So to get the price we have the article ready so we can call article does see assess.
Again this is the special method name C Ss So it's different than beautiful soup.
So it's new and it may be confusing but you can always just look at the documentation and we want the
key.
What was it price color.
And then to get the text we do this here and if we just leave it at this actually you know I just do
this.
This is only going to run right now on the first page here.
We're not moving onto the next pages and continuing to crawl.
And we're just going to have a single dictionary with price and I have nothing else.
This is it.
We're just extracting this information directly executed is a bit more complicated.
We run.
Well what I named this file book scraper.
So we have to run great b space runs spider space dash o space and then the name of the file we want
to save the data to.
If we want bookstore CXVII books that Jason and we do see s v space then the name of the file book scraper
duppy.
And look at all that that happened there.
Let's open up the books file.
OK.
So what we're getting here is you can see we're getting something for each price.
This is what we see.
And this is not quite correct.
What we're getting is the object that is trying to be it's being printed out because when we use Scrappy
just like with beautiful soup each element itself is represented with an object.
So we need to extract the information from that object.
We want to do the equivalent of soup.
Find blah blah blog and then we do get text to get the middle or the inner text out.
The equivalent is a method called extract.
First the docs explain this pretty well.
When we called C S S it's going to return to us Albacete even if it is only one item in and so you could
do this give us the first item dot extract or there there's a built in method called extract first and
that's just going to give us the text or the inner H came out of the first item which in our case there
only is one item.
So we want extract first.
We could do this but extract first is nicer.
So now we called Dot extract first as a method and if we rerun this takes a moment let's go back over
to our CXXVI file.
And I believe that it uses append mode by default.
So it is not overwriting things we have the old stuff but down here you've got all the new prices.
OK so we're getting price just fine.
Let's quickly add the title and so the way we do title is going to set title to the article that says
for each article it's the anchor tag instead of an age 3.
There's probably other anchor tags potentially so we don't want to just say a tag you want to say H-3
within a tag directly inside of it.
And that's not too hard if you know C Ss can just type this anchor tag and you only want anchor tags
with the attribute title and then we'll just call extract first on that.
So as you can see the syntax is very different.
It's not that different but it's different words.
It's the same idea using CSA as selectors might seem foreign but at the end of the day it's just another
implementation of scraping functionality just different method names instead of beautiful soup.
We do it this way which is admitted the foreign to us at this point.
But I think you'll be impressed.
Hopefully already you've been impressed by how easy it is once we add this in here we tell it what to
look for and it takes care of everything else.
We never have to export it to a file that does it for us.
And if we leave this as it is and rerun it with other a different file name sort of boxed up so yes
we just do books to see history and what do we get.
I don't have it open let's do books to awesome and automatically experts to CSB price and title like
that our data is here from one page.
So now all we want to do is update this so that it keeps going.
And it's actually really easy what we want to do is just check if there is a next.
So we're going to do response see SS and we have to identify where that next button is right here.
OK.
So there is an in line with the class of next.
And then there's an anchor tag inside and we need the ref from there.
So that's not too bad.
Assuming I can type response correctly we're going to do see SS and then we want this thing with a classroom
next instead of that in a tag with the attribute ref.
And we just call that extract first.
So calling that to just give us the value of that Tref which is some you know and then we just add this
little bit of logic if there is a next because on the last page we get to there won't be one that will
be the starting point if there is one.
We do another yield it looks like this response does follow.
And then we tell it where to follow which is this link.
This you Arel next.
And then we pass in self up parts.
So inside this function parse we are actually calling parse again.
This is something called recursion which we haven't talked much about but this is how spiders are set
up using scrapin.
So we select you are l next if we can find it if there is one then we yield response stuff follow.
This is all just boilerplate.
We pass on to you or else what to do next where to go and call the same parse.
And so it's going to keep doing this.
So it's going to go through everything on this page scrape all these.
See if there's an X button if there is then it's going to start the whole process over on this page
scrape all these check for next button and it will keep going until there isn't one left and then it's
done and that is the magic of playing by these rules.
If you make the sacrifice of flexibility and you just follow the syntax fill in the blank.
Basically we hit save and run it again.
And they did just append all of this data to the existing file.
Take a bit longer because it's now doing this for 50 some 50 pages wasn't it.
See it's on page 30 32 34.
Keep talking through this.
Oh man this is hard to fill.
All right we finished.
Now if you look at that file this was the beginning stuff and it overwrote it didn't overwrite it appended
to the end and we get a whole bunch more check it out pretty cool.
How easy that was and even cooler is that we can easily change this to be Jason with a single.
I mean what four characters would change there.
Now it's going to write all of our results as Jaison instead of CXXVI and we don't have to do anything
else.
It has a little adapter that it switches over to used Jaison instead.
I personally am a big fan escapee.
I didn't teach it and didn't focus on it because you have to understand how scraping works you have
to understand the fact that you're making requests and parsing them back because it hides all of that
from you.
Now if I open up books today.
Jason here we go.
It's all stored on now.
Is really cool.
This is just the code for the pound the euro symbol of the pound.
It wasn't looking anyway so it's just a little bit of work.
We were able to write this crawler it's a spider.
We have to play by the rules inherit from scraping that spider.
We have to define start you or else we have to define a parse method and the first thing that happens
is that it calls parse.
On this first you IRL or however many you are Elser in here.
And then for each response or grabbing the data we want as well as checking if there is a next page.
And the third is recalling follow which will then called parts and the whole process starts over and
we keep going until we hit a dead end.
Cool.
All right.
That was a lot.
So if this was confusing Don't worry.
This is just a more advanced tool that you can use if you're really interested in scraping and you need
to do it at a high volume or you need to crawl.
Then I highly recommend that you look in discreet be.