OK.
So we've learned a lot about parameters and arguments and some of the cool features that Python gives
us but we have to be very careful about how we order them in a function.
So there is an order we have to follow or else things could break.
And more often than not they will break.
So this is the order in our function declarations.
We put parameters first.
So specifically named parameters then start args then default parameters then start our keyword args.
And this only applies if you need a function that has all four of these.
You might just have parameters and start args.
You might just have default parameters and keyword args but they have to be in this order so whatever
subset of these they need to be in this order.
So let me show you an example I think will make it clearer why you need an order.
So surprise surprise.
I have a file with a trivial example that is useless except to explain why the order matters.
So it's a function called display info and it takes in a bunch of different parameters but they are
all in the correct order so we have named parameters like a and b.
Then we have Star args which will capture any additional arguments.
Then we have a default parameter so instructor is equal to Colt.
And then we have keyword args.
OK so there's a lot going on here and all this function does is return a list that contains A and then
B and then args and then instructor and then keyword args.
So basically it just shows the value of everything that was passed in or in the case of a default value
not passed it.
So when we print display info and we pass in one to three last name Michael Steele job equals instructor.
What do we expect.
So let's just kind of type along here.
So first things first.
A is going to be one right so will have a is one then B is going to be too bright.
And then we have arcs and ARGs will actually contain.
It will be a tuple because remember it will collect anything here.
That remaining and it will be only containing 3 because afterwards we have all these keyword args.
But first we have instructor with a default value.
So instructor is going to be set to colza because nothing was passed in and then we have our remaining
star STARKIE w args key.
I keep saying that KW args and that will be a dictionary right where we have last name is set to steal
and we have job is set to instructor.
Technically this is quote turned into this whole thing is key.
W.
Keep doing that.
KW args.
So hopefully you can see why this order is important for things like args and star star.
KW args which are like the cleanup crews they grab everything else that's remaining.
We have to have the named parameters first the specific parameters definitely and then keyword arguments
always come afterwards.
So let's verify.
See if we're right and just print this out and this is what we get solidest copy this over so we can
take a look.
And we get what we expect.
So we have a is 1 B is 2 args.
Is this tuple 3.
You might be wondering why there is a comma in there.
If we actually just let's just do a print args so I'm not even going to return any more.
Let's just print args.
That's what we get.
This three comma and then lets even go further and do print type of args and we can see if I can get
this to work.
There you go.
It definitely is a tuple.
It's just bizarre because it's a single item tuple and by default Python will add that comma in there
to distinguish it from parentheses because we can put parentheses around any number or around a mathematical
operation or something.
This isn't a tuple.
But that is so it's just what Python does for single item tuples.
OK.
And then we have called which the value of instructor by default is set to code and then we have last
name which is steel and job instructor.
Both were picked up by star star.
KW ARGs in the event that this video made absolutely no sense to you.
All that you need to remember is that there is a specific order we want to follow when using parameters
or when defining functions parameters first that have specific names.
Then start args then default parameters and then start star KW args follow this order.