All right.
Welcome back.
So we have a quick exercise using for loops and ranges.
So the idea here it's based off of an experience I had growing up where I had my mom and my dad often
yelling at me to clean my room and they would say how many times do I have to tell you this.
And so our little program here is going to ask how many times I have to tell you.
And then the user inputs number in this case three and then clean up your room it's printed three times.
So if you don't want to do clean up your room you could just printout Hello X number of times three
times or five times.
But the idea is for taking number in and we're just going to print something out that number of times
are very very simple exercise.
But there is you know a tiny catch that you have to worry about any time you're asking for user input.
So give it a shot pause video and then after this I'll have a solution like I don't know two seconds
from now.
One two.
All right.
I'm back.
So let's go over a solution.
OK.
So I'm going to make a new file here.
I'm just going to call this one repeater.
Why.
And the first thing we'll do is make a variable.
Let's just call it times equals and then we're going to ask for input so input.
How many times do I have to tell you and a lot of space because I always forget that space and it's
really gross and you just have to type input and it just goes on to the end without a space.
OK.
So that will be a string remember.
So let's do times equals inte of times.
Otherwise we would have the string three and we can't use that in a range because what we want to do
is then do a loop for and we'll just call it time in and we can't just say for time and times in some
languages you can do that you could just say for x in 10 or 10 times do this but we still have to have
a range but we can just do this for time and range Times print.
Clean up your room.
So essentially we'll have a number like five so we can hard code five in here and this is a short cut.
Remember for doing this zero to five.
But if we just pass in five it will work just fine.
And just to show that I go run this Python 3 repeater we get clean up room five times and it would be
the same if we had this OK.
So let's now go back to asking for times and remember we need to convert it to an int and everything
should work.
Other than that we're not using the time variable because we're doing the same thing each time through
the loop each iteration.
We don't care if we're on the first or the second or the third.
We don't need that number.
How many times have tell you to clean up YOUR him twice about 10.
There we go.
The only change we could make if he wanted is to just do it in a room and let's do time let's make this
an F string.
And put time right there.
So we get something like this four times zero in every room time one we never hear him.
Time to clean up your room.
And if we wanted to we could shift this over one so we could do time plus one here so that if I type
in five times it says Time 1 instead of time zero.
But really this is above and beyond what we need to do.
The only thing we want to do is just repeat some string a text and a number of times depending on what
the user says and that's it.
So I'll put two solutions to this one.
And the simpler one we started with.
OK.
So next we have a more complex exercise that is hopefully a little bit more challenging.