All right in the last video we saw how to access individual items out of a list.
In this video we'll see how to access all of the items out of a list at the same time.
So suppose we had a list of numbers we could print out each item one at a time.
Print number 0 1 2 3.
There's short comings to this and it's a lot of text but there's also the problem of we might not know
how many numbers are in here.
What if there's 50 numbers or what's a shopping list and a user has added a thousand items.
We're not going to write a thousand print statements.
So just like before when we talked about repeating processes this is the same idea our solution is to
use a loop we can use both a for loop and a while loop.
And in this first example I'll show you a for loop.
It's really nice and simple.
The syntax to do this in Python is really clean especially compared to some other programming languages.
So here we have a numbers list say 1 1 2 3 and 4 and all we have to do is write our FOR loop for number
or whatever item name we want in numbers colon and number is going to automatically have the value of
1 2 3 4 of the piece of data inside of the list.
So let's do an example and I'll actually quit out of Python here and I'll make a new file called for
loop and let's make our colors list those brackets.
Let's do purple again teal and let's do magenta.
OK.
And if I want to print them all out on their own I would just do four and we could call it C we could
call it color.
It doesn't matter in colors.
So just like before we had a range here for a for loop.
If you remember actually really quickly in the loop section said yeah we can use a list but we don't
know what lists are yet.
So another one of those things we kind of have to wait unfortunately.
So here we go we can do a print.
The simplest thing would just be to print color and that's it.
So color is rather than you know when we did for x in range one comment two or something or 4:59 whatever
it is x stored a numeric value.
In this case color will store whatever the value is in that list.
So we could have strings but I could also add afterwards let's add true a boolean and eight point nine.
OK so let's print this out and make some space Python 3 for loop and we get purple teal magenta.
True.
Eight point nine.
So it's really simple to use a for loop to iterate through a list and we don't have to just print things
of course I'll comment this out and we could have another list called numbers and set it equal to just
random numbers if we wanted to.
4 6 2 8 9 7 whatever it is 10 and we could do for numb in numbers let's you print numb times no.
So we'll just square them simple.
And there we go.
We get 60 and 36 down to 100.
Totally.
Well not totally random but random numbers that we're printing out from a list and squaring.
OK.
So that's using a for loop.
So next let's see how to do it with a WHILE loop and using a while loop is a little bit more complicated.
It's a little more syntax that doesn't necessarily make it worse.
And we actually talk about a situation where you would want to use a while loop but let's look at it
first.
So you use a while loop.
We have to basically take advantage of the index of each item in the list.
So we start with a variable that often is called the eye for index or id x or index or I X doesn't really
matter.
And we set it equal to zero.
And what we're going to do is print out the first item number zero.
Then we'll add one to the two I will print out numbers 1 and so on until we get to the end of the list
the last index.
So you can see here our loop runs well is less than the length of numbers.
And notice it's less than not but then are equal to because length is 1 2 3 4.
And if we tried to access numbers square bracket 4 that's out of the list range.
So we need to do less than that Mike.
And then all we do is access numbers and we have to add one to each time through.
Otherwise we get an infinite loop.
So let's go make a file.
This time I will call it while loop IPY and I'll copy over my colors and let's actually add one more.
How about crimson and I lied.
I'll do two more.
Let's do it.
Emerald green OK.
So what we can do now is loop through.
So we can be using a while loop we set up an initial index variable.
I'll call it index that needs to start at zero and thus we want it to start at the end which you could
also do.
Let's start with index zero and then we'll have a WHILE loop.
So while index is less then and we want it to be less than the length of colors.
So while it's less then one two three four or five.
But we don't want to hard code 5.
Because we don't know how many items are in here potentially.
So while that's the case we could just start reprinting colors square bracket index.
And if I left this on it's own right now it could print purple over and over and over because index
is set to be zero.
And we're never changing it.
So we need to increment index plus equals 1.
So let's give it a shot.
Python 3 while loop IPY and there we go.
One two three four five.
So if all we wanted to do is print out data or just access the data directly from inside the list to
do something with it it's much easier to use a for loop.
In my opinion cleaner nicer looking just shorter but sometimes we might want to actually do something
with the index.
So with these colors this is a very silly example.
But what if we want to print out something like zero item or have zero color is purple.
And then one color is teal and so on we need to actually have the index available to us which we don't
by default in the for loop.
So we could do something like this.
We will do a print with an F string.
And let's do instead of here we'll add index colon.
And then let's do colour's index.
So this will give us zero colon purple.
OK so we're going to add the index and interpolate that into the string and then the colors square brackets
index so 0 and then purple one teal and let's take a look and there we go.
Zero purple one teal and so on.
Maybe not what you would need do all the time just printing out a list of colors isn't exactly the most
useful thing either.
But there definitely are situations where you may want to take advantage of the index so you could use
a while loop to do that because you already have the index.
But typically I prefer for a loop if you can get away with it.
It's just so much nicer looking two options so pick the one you prefer.
They both work.