All right.
So it's time for a super quick activity.
Just take a couple seconds of your time maybe a minute depending on how fast you type.
All going to have you do is use some of the commands you've already learned and follow a couple of instructions.
So somewhere on your computer doesn't matter if you're using a PC.
Cloud 9 Mac.
It doesn't matter if it's on your desktop or your home directory.
You make a new directory just somewhere make a new folder called animals and then instead of animals
make to further new folders one called salamanders and one called FROGS.
Then inside of the salamanders directory make a new file not a folder but a new file called axolotl
that takes the really cool animal tell you more about them if you're curious.
After you do the exercise and then instead of the frogs directory add a new file and you know I've typed
this whole thing out.
Just type Pixi frog that TXI.
So two files each in a different directory.
And those two directories are instead of the animals directory.
So quickly do that I should mention from the command line.
Don't cheat and use your mouse do it from the command line and then afterwards all have a quick solution.
But then also some really fun facts about Aksel models and Pixie frogs if you care.
They're pretty cool.
OK.
So let's go ahead and do this.
I'm going to work on my desktop.
So the first thing I'm going to do is CD to my desktop and then from in here I'm going to make a new
directory called animals.
M k d i r so I could CD into animals so you can see it peered over here.
By the way or if I wanted to I could make directory's from here I could do make directory animals slash
salamanders and that's totally valid.
So I could do that or I could CD into animals make directory salamanders salamanders space frogs and
do it in one line.
Those are the two directories you needed.
And if I type LS I now have two directories so I could touch this file axolotl but XTi from inside the
Salamander directory or I could do touch salamanders slash Axel Ladell.
Correctly correctly XTi.
And if I type LS I won't see anything but if I C.D into salamanders and now type Alice I have axolotl
itx.
And then for the frog I'll just C.D into frogs and do it this way and I'll make that pixie frog that
DXi I want do the entire Latin name Pixi frog XTi and that's it.
So we have that file there CD back out let's do ls frogs and salamanders.
Great.
OK.
So I mention I have a couple of fun facts axolotl.
Aside from having a crazy name have a really adorable smile.
You can see here they're from Mexico.
They were once worshipped by the Aztecs.
They have a crazy ability to regenerate not just like typical frogs amphibians you can chop them off
or something that their spinal cord can actually regrow entirely can cut it in half or remove a section
of the spinal cord and they can heal their a thousand times more resistant to cancer than any other
animal on earth that we know about.
And they glow in the dark and pretty cool animals.
They're just so cute.
And on the flipside Pixie frogs.
So my sister growing up really wanted one of be.
She is a special sister and we went to the pet store.
They had one.
She really wanted one till she found out you had to feed it live baby mice a couple of times a month.
So we did not go home with a pixie frog.
But I think it's kind of hilarious that it's called pixie frog and it looks like this.
Anyway they distracted you from the mundane reality of the command line but we're almost a python.