A Welcome Back in this video I'm just going to very very quickly show you a special value in Python
called none.
So none has to have a capital and like this if I hit Enter nothing actually happens.
But if I tried to type it without the capital and Python freaks out gives me an error says None.
It's not defined.
It's looking for a variable called none.
Just like if I try and ask for you know age and it's not defined.
I get the same problem but none is a special case.
Just like true or false.
The purpose of none is just to represent the idea of nothingness.
In other languages you might have come across something called Noel.
If you've worked with other programming languages none is Python's version of No.
If you haven't that's ok I'll show you an example of one you might want to use it.
Suppose I have a very very simple app and I'm asking users for information.
Let's say I'm modeling a person a person has a name and age and then some people have a child.
And let's just say there's you only have one child in this world.
And a little dystopic.
What I can do you know I could ask her name and set it equal to Daisy or something.
Age is 10.
Well OK that might be a bit young for children let's say age 30 and then I might have a variable called
child.
But Daisy doesn't have a child so I'm not going to set it to a name of whatever Daisy's hypothetical
child would be.
There isn't anything.
So instead of not setting it at all because that would be one option.
But then if I tried to access it later by calling child I get an error instead I can set a child to
be explicitly nutten for Daisy and that way when I retrieve child it doesn't show up here.
If I print child whoever can see that it still is none.
It's just the way that this REPL is set up set up.
We don't see none printed out unless you manually print it unlike if I just call name.
I see the string Daisy.
So using this I could then follow the exact same pattern but instead set name to be dusty and Dusty
does have a child and child can now be set to Pamela.
Sure.
So I can call child and I get a value.
So again all known is is a way of representing nothingness instead of me trying to do something like
child equals this an empty string or zero or false.
If I just set it to none.
It's a clear indicator that there isn't a value here but there could be.
I want child to exist as a variable I want a container for child but there's nothing to put in there
yet.
So Python has a special value called Non to do that.
And if I look at type of none.
Excuse me type of child.
It is of none type and there's only one instance of one type which is none.
So it's a very unique situation.
Unlike you no type of name which gives us string.
There's a million while more than a million types of strings.
We could have Dusty Pamela and so on but with non type there's only one.
Which is the exact value.
None Anyway that's none.
I hope I didn't confuse you too much.
I just wanted to see it now with the rest of the values that we're talking about.
It will come up a little bit later when we are making more complex apps and we're doing things like
asking for user input or storing data that may or may not look exactly the same or some data might be
missing.
We'll start off by setting things equal to none.