In the previous chapters, we introduced
graphs, we learnt some terminology, we learnt
how to implement a graph, we can say that we're
ready to start learning about graph algorithms.
Which is what we will do in this chapter,
we will study two very important algorithms:
depth-first search and breadth-first search.
These two algorithms give us the ability to
traverse a graph, a necessary operation that will
be the foundation of many algorithms we will study
later. We will start with depth-first search.
Let me put you in a situation, you are playing
a game, and you want to do all missions.
You start at mission A, you complete it, and from
here you unlocked three new missions B, C, and D.
How would you proceed to complete them all?
Because you cannot do them all at the same time,
you get an idea, you decide to do the
first one and all missions it unlocks,
you go back to your starting point, you go to the
second one, you do it and all missions it unlocks,
you go back, you move to the third one, you do
it and all missions it unlocks, and you go back.
By doing so, you will have finished
all missions. Let's apply this idea,
we go to the first mission, B. You do it, and it
unlocks two new missions. Once again, same idea,
you go to the first one, you go back, you
go to the second one, and you go back.
Let's go to the first one. Now there is
only one new mission to go to, we go to it.
Two unlocked missions now, you go to the
first one. And it doesn't unlock new missions,
you reached the end of the actual path, so you
go back to K, to see if it has other unlocked
missions we didn't complete yet. Now you
have a second mission you didn't do yet,
you go to it. Then you have three new
missions, you go to the first one,
no further missions so you go back, you go to the
second one, no further missions so you go back.
By the way, the red mark on the floor represents
missions you already completed, let's say that
you have a little notebook where you write all
missions you finished, to avoid doing them again.
Third mission now. Only one unlocked mission,
and you can see that it's in red, we
already finished it, so we just go back.
We finished all unlocked missions of this one, we
go back. Same thing here, we go back. Same thing
here, we go back. Now from B we have a second
unlocked mission, F, but we already finished it,
it's in red. No more missions from B, we go
back to A. The second mission unlocked by
A is C, we do it. It doesn't unlock any new
missions, we go back to A. We go complete D,
and it unlocks three new missions: H, I, and J. We
start with H, it unlocks no missions, we go back.
We move to I, it unlocks two new missions. We
go to O, no unlocked missions, we go back to I.
Second unlocked mission, J, we go to it. We can
go to D but we already did D, so we just go back.
We finished all unlocked missions by I, we go
back. D also unlocked J, but it's in red, we don't
need to do it again. We finished missions of D, we
go back to A. We finished missions unlocked by A,
it means that we finished all missions,
congratulations, we finished the game.
You obviously noticed that what you're
seeing on the screen is a graph,
where a vertex represents a mission, and an edge
between two missions means that completing one
mission unlocks the other. And what we did here
is a graph traversal, we traversed all vertices,
which are missions, to complete them. And the way
we used to perform this traversal is: depth-first
search, the algorithm we're learning about.
Now you're wondering, how did it work exactly?
And why is it called depth-first search? At the
beginning we were at A, we completed the mission,
and we had 3 new missions, B C and D. We decided
to go to B. And by finishing B, we had two new
missions E and F. We decided to go to E. E
unlocked one mission K, we decided to go to K.
Etcetera etcetera, what we're doing here is that
we're going deeper and deeper from one path,
until we can't continue further, like when we
reached P, from P we don't have new missions.
This is why it's called depth-first search,
we prioritize the depth, we go as deep as
possible into one path before moving to another
one. What did we do when completing P? We went
back to K to continue from other paths, and
that's the main idea of depth-first search,
we start at a vertex, A in our example, then we go
as far as possible from one branch, we backtrack,
we move to another branch, we backtrack, and so
on until we finish traversing the whole graph.
And because we're working on a graph,
some paths can have common vertices,
which means that if we work naively, we can visit
the same vertex multiple times, which is useless
in a lot of situations. It's the reason why we
used that notebook where we wrote all missions
we completed, so that before going to a mission,
we first make sure that we didn't do it before.
Remembering visited vertices avoids traversing the
same vertices more than once, but it also avoids
something more dangerous, having a program
that never stops. For example we went A, B,
E, K, P, back, L, F. Then here we didn't
go to B because B was in our notebook,
but what if we didn't remember that we already
did B? We would go to B, then again, E, K, L, F.
We go to B again, then E, K, L, F,
and it keeps going like this forever.
Before moving to the implementation, I know that
you may want to see one or two other examples to
better understand, but what if I tell you that you
will be able to visualize millions of examples.
I made a Python program that generates a random
graph then shows you the process step by step,
you will be able to take all your time.
And obviously, if you still didn't understand
something, reach out to me by asking a question.
Let's move to the implementation.
First, let's try to understand
what we did with missions by writing
pseudocode. The initial mission was A,
from where we want to complete all missions, so
we may think of a function complete_missions,
that takes as parameters the actual mission, and
the notebook, where we write completed missions.
Now in the function, we complete the actual
mission, we write in the notebook that we
completed the actual mission, and we move to
unlocked missions. For each unlocked mission,
we first check that we didn't complete it before,
if it's the case, mission not in notebook, we call
the function on it. Yes, it's the same function,
the process of depth-first search is recursive,
we complete a mission and move to unlocked ones,
for each one of them we also complete it and move
to unlocked ones, for each one of them we also
complete it and move to unlocked ones, and so on.
And it's this recursive process that
is handling the action of going back,
remember that when we finish visiting neighbors
of a vertex, we go back to the previous one.
And you need to understand how does it work. You
probably know that when a function calls another
function, the first one stops, waits for the call
to end, then it continues its instructions. And
this is what happens, we have the call on the
mission A, we complete the mission, we write
in the notebook, then we traverse unlocked
missions. The first unlocked mission is B,
so we have a new function call on B, this
is why the call on A stops, waits for the
call on B to end, then continues remaining
instructions, it moves to next neighbors.
And to be able to go back to A, the
call on B stores the return address,
so that once it finishes all its instructions,
it knows where it needs to go back. Anyway this
is something related to recursion, and if you're
comfortable with recursion you should then already
know how the recursive process works, especially
when there are multiple recursive calls like here.
So far, we wrote pseudocode for this
specific example of missions and stuff,
but the general version is this one. We
have a function dfs, depth-first search,
it takes as parameters the graph from where
we will find neighbors, the actual vertex,
and a set visited where we store visited
vertices, it represents that famous notebook.
Then inside the function, we process the
actual vertex, we can print it for example,
we store it in visited, then for each
neighbour, if the neighbor is not visited,
we call dfs on it to visit it, that's
the pseudocode for depth-first search.
If you're wondering where is the base case,
the case where we perform no recursive calls,
which is necessary to stop the
recursive process at some point,
it's the case where we don't
have unvisited neighbors,
in that case we never enter in the condition,
hence, we don't call the function again.
Okay now we wrote the pseudocode,
but how to actually implement it,
in Python for example. First of all, we must know
the graph implementation, is it adjacency list or
adjacency matrix? We will learn to use dfs on both
of them, there isn't much difference but still.
Let's start with adjacency list, we have a
function dfs that takes as parameters the graph,
the actual vertex, and the set of visited
vertices. Inside the function we process the
actual vertex, we can for example print it, then
we add it to the set of visited vertices. Now we
start traversing neighbors. In the adjacency list
lecture, we've seen that to traverse neighbors of
a vertex, we just traverse the array at key
vertex, we write graph.adj_list[vertex], and
it returns that array of neighbors. This is why
we write, for neighbor in graph.adj_list[vertex].
Inside the loop, we first make sure that we
didn't visit the neighbor before, we write,
if neighbor not in visited. And inside
the condition block, we call dfs again,
but this time, we put neighbor, we want to
start traversing from the neighbor this time.
And we got our dfs function, in the
main dfs function we create the graph,
we create an empty set visited, and
we call the recursive dfs() function.
Note that the function we made now is
quite basic, we're just printing vertices,
later we will use dfs for more advanced stuff,
but don't worry, the principle remains the same.
What about the adjacency matrix now? Well, the
function remains the same, only one thing changes,
the way of finding neighbors of our vertex. In an
adjacency list, we have a vertex, let's say 'A',
we go to the key 'A' in the adjacency list, and
we find the array of neighbors. In an adjacency
matrix, we traverse the row to find cells where
there is a 1, by mapping back and forth between
vertices and their indices in the matrix, all that
is implemented in the neighbors() method you will
find in notes of the adjacency matrix lecture.
And we keep the same stuff inside the loop.
Question now. Does depth-first search always
visit all the vertices? The answer is no. In
our example, we called depth-first search on
A, and we've been able to reach every vertex.
The reason behind it is that every vertex
is reachable from A, so we had no problem.
But, it's not always the case, take this
graph for example. We call dfs on A.
You can see that it didn't reach every vertex,
the reason behind it is that some vertices are not
reachable from A, so there is simply no path to
visit them. What's the solution then? The solution
is that in the main function, we call dfs on each
unvisited vertex. Let's do it with this example.
We have this graph, we call dfs on A and it visits
some vertices, A B F and C. Then B, visited. Then
C, visited. Then dfs on D, it visits D H and J.
Then E, it visits E K P L Q. Then F, visited.
Then H, visited. Then I, it visits I and O. Then
J K L O P Q, all visited. Then R, it visits R.
We finished all vertices, you can see that
all of them have been visited with dfs.
In code, in the main dfs function, we just
write, for each vertex in the adjacency list,
if vertex not in visited, we call dfs
on it. And by doing so, we will have
traversed all vertices of the graph, even if
the graph is disconnected or weakly connected.
Last thing to talk about in this lecture,
time complexity of depth-first search.
Once again, it depends on the implementation.
Let's start with the adjacency list. An important
thing to understand is that the function is called
exactly once on each vertex. Why? Because we
have a condition, we're calling the function
on a vertex only when it's not visited yet. And
as soon as we enter a call, we set the vertex as
visited, which means that we won't call dfs on it
anymore, we deduce that it will be done only once.
In this process, we have the cost of traversing
vertices in the main function, and the cost of
traversing neighbors of each vertex. For the main
loop function, we're traversing all vertices,
which costs |V|. And for function calls, we
said that we're calling dfs on each vertex
exactly once, so we just do the sum. But
what's the cost of calling dfs on a vertex?
Let's have a look. We have printing, done
in O(1), then adding to the visited set,
which is in O(1) in average because adding to a
set costs O(1) time in average. Then we have a
loop that traverses neighbors of that vertex. And
remember what we said about traversing neighbors
in an adjacency list, the cost of traversing
neighbors of a vertex depends on its degree,
because in a simple graph, the degree of a
vertex represents the number of its neighbors.
We get that the cost of calling dfs on a vertex
v is deg(v)+O(1), that we can simplify to deg(v).
We're calling dfs on each vertex once,
so the total cost of dfs calls is the sum
of degrees of each vertex. And we have the
theorem that says that in a directed graph,
the sum of degrees is equal to the number of
edges, and in an undirected graph, the sum of
degrees is equal to twice the number of edges. So
in total, we have |V| to traverse vertices, and
|E| or 2|E| to traverse neighbors in all calls.
Which gives O(|V|+|E|) time complexity in both
cases, we can say that depth-first search has an
O(|V|+|E|) time complexity with an adjacency list.
What about the adjacency matrix? Is
it the same thing? Let's find out.
With an adjacency matrix, the only difference is
the way we traverse neighbors. In an adjacency
list, the cost of traversing the neighbors of a
vertex is its degree, but in an adjacency matrix,
the cost is |V|, because we traverse the whole
row of the adjacency matrix. So in the total cost,
instead of having |V| + the sum of the degree
for each vertex, we have |V| + the sum of |V|
for each vertex, basically we multiply |V|
by the number of vertices, which is also |V|.
We get |V| + |V|*|V|, which is |V|+|V|², which
gives O(|V|²), the time complexity of depth-first
search is O(|V|²) with an adjacency matrix. And
we know that O(|V|+|E|) is asymptotically faster
than O(|V|²), so in terms of time, it's
better to use an adjacency list for dfs.
What about space complexity? As extra space,
we have the set of visited vertices, whose the
size becomes |V| at the end of the process,
because we will have inserted all vertices.
And it's a recursive process, so we also have
to take the call stack size into consideration.
The worst case is when there is a path that passes
from all vertices, because when being on the last
one, all calls will still be active, in other
words, they will still be on the call stack.
This is why the maximum call stack size is |V|.
In total, we have |V| for the set of visited
vertices + |V| for the call stack size,
we get an O(|V|) space complexity for depth-first
search, for both adjacency list and matrix.
I think that we're done with depth-first
search, we've seen how it works, an example,
the implementation on both representations we've
studied, and the time and space complexity.
If you're still not comfortable with depth-first
search, it's fine, it's possible to not understand
everything after only one lecture. 5 suggestions
in that case: 1. To use the visualization program
I mentioned before to see how dfs works on more
and more examples. 2. To do the quiz that comes
after this chapter. 3. To ask questions, you can
ask me questions. 4. To focus during the practice
problem we will solve in the next lecture. And
5. To focus during lectures of the next chapters,
because we will use dfs to develop other graph
algorithms. We reached the end of this lecture,
I hope that you understood everything
perfectly, and see you in the next lecture!