Imagine that your company has a bunch of rides
to perform by car in a given day, each ride has
a start and end time. Unfortunately, you may
not be able to complete them with one single
car. Why? Because some rides overlap in time, for
example this one starts at 2pm and ends at 4pm,
while this one starts at 3pm, and at 3pm
the car is occupied by the first ride.
It's clear that more cars are required,
however, cars and drivers cost money,
so a legitimate question is: What
is the minimum number of required
cars to perform all the rides in time, and
what rides should be assigned to each car?
In this example we need at least 3 cars,
here are the rides each car can take,
rides taken by a car don't overlap obviously,
that was the initial goal, avoiding overlapping.
Now we defined the problem, but what about
the solution, how to find that minimum
number of cars given a list of rides? This
is what we will learn about in this chapter.
We're learning about graph algorithms, so we will
obviously represent our problem with a graph.
Vertices represent rides and
edges can represent overlapping,
an edge between two rides u and v means that u
and v time slots overlap. Edges are undirected
because the relation goes both ways, if
u overlaps with v then v overlaps with u.
We want to assign a car to each ride in a way that
two overlapping rides don't have the same car, so
starting from this graph, we want to assign a car
value to each vertex such that if two vertices are
adjacent, then they don't have the same car value.
And this can be done through graph coloring.
Let's first define graph coloring
then go back to this problem.
Graph coloring is the action of coloring elements
of a graph in respect to some conditions.
The simplest graph coloring example is
vertex coloring, the action of coloring
vertices of a graph in such a way that no
two adjacent vertices have the same color.
Note that there exist other forms of graph
coloring, for example edge coloring where the task
is to color edges in such a way that no two edges
with a common incident vertex have the same color.
Also note that even if it's called coloring, we're
not really obliged to use colors, we can use names
or simply integers, the important is that no two
adjacent vertices have the same assigned value.
Where can we use graph coloring? We can use it to
solve problems where some vertices have conflicts
so they shouldn't be in the same color class. And
we can find a lot of examples of this situation.
One of them is the example we used to introduce
this lecture, overlapping rides. We represented
rides with vertices, and here vertices can have
a conflict, when the rides overlap in time.
In that case, they shouldn't be in the same color
class, they shouldn't be assigned the same car.
Another example, let's say that you want to invite
a bunch of friends to a party. But some of them
hate each other, so you don't want to put them
at the same table. This is why you start thinking
about how many tables you need to avoid problems.
Here you think of graph coloring, vertices are
your friends, and you put an edge between two
vertices if those two friends hate each other. Now
you just need to use a graph coloring algorithm
to see how many tables you need, it's represented
by the minimum number of colors required to
color vertices while respecting the condition.
And we can find a lot of other real life problems
that can be solved through graph coloring,
but let's study some terminology. A graph
cannot be colored with any number of colors,
sometimes it's not enough, for example we
cannot color this graph with only two colors.
But if with a value k, we can color the
graph by using at most k different colors,
we say that the graph is k-colorable. And
the smallest value of k, the smallest number
of colors needed to color a graph, is called the
chromatic number of the graph, denoted like this.
For example if we have this Petersen graph, we can
color it with at most 5 colors, it's 5-colorable,
we can also color it with at most 3 colors,
it's 3-colorable, but we cannot color it with
only 2 colors. The smallest value of k is 3,
so the chromatic number of this graph is 3.
With the graph of our initial example, the
chromatic number is also 3, so we need at
least 3 cars to perform the rides properly. And
the chromatic number of a graph has boundaries.
For example we know that it's at least 1. The case
where it's 1 is when we have an edgeless graph,
no conflict between vertices so we can color them
all with the same color, we only need 1 color.
We also know that it's at most
n, the number of vertices.
The case where it's n is when we have a
complete graph, each vertex is adjacent
to all other vertices so its color must
be different from them all. This is why
we need n colors, each vertex must have a
different color from all the other ones.
These are quite weak bounds,
we can find tighter bounds.
For example we know that the chromatic number of
a graph is at least the size of its max clique.
Let's first define what is a clique and what is a
max clique before continuing because we didn't do
it before in this course. A clique is a subset of
vertices of a graph such that every two distinct
vertices are adjacent. It's like a small complete
graph that we can find in a graph. For example
this graph has the clique . It also contains
the clique . Or also this one .
And the maximum clique of a graph is the
clique with the greatest number of vertices,
in this graph it's this one, .
Back to our boundary, we said that the chromatic
number of a graph is at least the size of its
max clique. Which is logical, if in a graph we
have a group of let's say 5 vertices that are
all adjacent to each other, then we will need
a unique color for each one of them, we need 5
colors for that clique. This is why to color the
graph, we will need at least 5 different colors,
at least because it can be more, the chromatic
number isn't always equal to the size of the max
clique, it can be bigger, we just know that
the size of the max clique is a lower bound.
We also have Δ(G)+1 as an upper bound, where Δ(G)
is the maximum degree of a vertex in the graph G,
so the chromatic number of G is smaller than
or equal to the maximum degree in G, + 1.
And we have other lower and upper bounds,
we won't see them all in this lecture.
Another important thing to know in vertex
coloring is that after coloring vertices,
vertices with the same color form a stable.
We didn't define it before, a stable, also
called independent set, is like the opposite of
a clique, it's a subset of vertices of the graph
such that no two vertices are adjacent. It's like
a small edgeless graph that we find in a graph.
Vertices with a same color form a stable, no
two vertices are adjacent. Which is logical
because if two of them were adjacent,
then they shouldn't have the same color.
Okay now we know about graph coloring,
k-colorability, chromatic number, but,
how to actually perform the vertex coloring of
a graph? First of all, we need to clearly define
our problem, do we want to: Know if a graph
is k-colorable? Or find the chromatic number?
The first one is a decision problem, the output
is yes or no. And it's an NP-complete problem.
The second is not a decision problem, it's an
optimization problem, as a result we want an
integer, the chromatic number. It cannot be in
NP-complete class because it's not a decision
problem, however, it's an NP-hard problem. Because
these problems are in NP-complete and NP-hard
respectively, we currently don't know an algorithm
to solve them that is not in exponential time,
which is slow, we deduce that exact algorithms for
finding the chromatic number of a graph are slow,
we had the same problem with Hamiltonian
cycles if you remember. However,
it's still interesting to know a way to solve
the problem, even if it's in exponential time.
A possible way to find the chromatic number of a
graph is to first know how to check if a graph is
k-colorable, then find the smallest value of k for
which the is_k_colorable() function returns true.
Okay but how to know if a graph is k-colorable?
For that, we can use backtracking, we will see it
later in this graph coloring chapter. However,
even if exact algorithms are currently slow,
we have approximation algorithms that are way
faster and give good results that we will see
later in this chapter. Also, you need to know
that when we say that a problem can be solved
in a certain time complexity, it can have special
cases, special types of inputs, where it's faster.
Special types of graphs in this context. For
example checking k-colorability of a graph,
in the general case, is in exponential time.
But, when k = 2, it can be done in linear time.
Because checking 2-colorability of a graph is
in reality checking if it's a bipartite graph.
By definition, a bipartite graph is a graph whose
vertices can be partitioned into two disjoint and
independent sets. This is why a bipartite graph
is 2-colorable, remember that vertices of a same
color class form a stable set, an independent
set. And because we can partition vertices of a
bipartite graph into two disjoint and independent
sets, two colors are enough to color it,
we assign the first color to the first set and the
second color to the second set. So checking if a
graph is 2-colorable is equivalent to checking if
it's a bipartite graph, and checking if a graph
is a bipartite graph can be done in linear
time, as we will see in the next lecture.
Last thing I wanted to talk about in
this lecture is the four color theorem.
First you need to know what is a planar
graph. A planar graph is a graph that
can be drawn in a such a way that no two
edges cross. For example for this graph,
we can draw it like this, and you can see that
there is no edges that cross, it's a planar graph.
However, if we take this graph, which
represents K5, the complete graph of order 5,
we cannot draw it without having at least two
edges that cross, it's not a planar graph.
We can talk about the theorem now. The four color
theorem states that for any loopless planar graph
G, the chromatic number of G is at most 4. In
other terms, any loopless planar graph can be
colored with no more than 4 colors. First of all,
why loopless, why does it work for loopless graphs
only. It's because vertex coloring doesn't work on
graphs that contain loops. The explanation is that
when a vertex u has a self-loop, then there is an
edge between u and u, so u is adjacent to itself.
And in vertex coloring, two adjacent
vertices must have different colors,
while a vertex can only be assigned one color, it
will necessarily have the same color as itself,
which is not allowed in this context. So
the theorem requires loopless planar graphs
simply because graph coloring works on loopless
graphs only. Back to the theorem. Initially,
the theorem wasn't proven, but after several
attempts, the theorem has been proven, we now
know that yes, using four colors only is enough
to color any planar graph, loopless of course.
It's the reason why geography maps you see
can almost always be colored with 4 colors.
Because this type of maps can be represented with
a planar graph such that vertices are countries,
and there is an edge between two countries when
they share a common boundary that is not a corner.
And because four colors are
enough to color a planar graph,
then four colors are enough to color such maps.
We've reached the end of this lecture, we've seen
what is graph coloring, some real life examples,
some terminology, k-colorability and chromatic
number problems, and the four color theorem.
In the next lecture, we will see how
to check the 2-colorability of a graph,
which is same as checking if the graph is
bipartite. See you in the next lecture!