In software development, and in computer science
in general, we have a lot of problems to solve,
some people do that for the whole day. But when
facing a problem, it may seem a bit abstract,
this is why we need to find a way to represent it,
to make it clearer and be able to start thinking
about a solution. For example, we want to suggest
new friends to someone in a social media, for that
we decide to suggest friends of his friends. We
have a list of connections between people, who's
friends with who. But to better visualize them, we
can organize them this way, the circles represent
people, and a connection between two circles means
that those two people are friends, for example red
is a friend of grey. And from here, the problem
becomes easy, we start from the person we want
to suggest friends to, we check circles he's
connected to, they represent his actual friends.
And by checking adjacent circles of those
circles, we can find friends of his friends.
Another interesting example is this one,
we want to travel between two cities,
preferably by using the shortest path between
them. For that we have a list of cities and
distances between them, and we need to find the
shortest path. To better visualize the problem,
we can organize data this way, where each circle
represents a city, and a line between two cities
means that we can move back and forth between
them, the integer represents the distance.
From here, we just apply an algorithm that we
will learn about later to find the shortest path,
we get this one for this example. Last example,
we have a bunch of car rides to perform, we have
the time when each ride starts and ends. However,
we may not be able to realize them all with the
same car, because some of them overlap in time.
And the question is, what is the minimum number
of cars to achieve them? We can visualize the car
rides this way, each circle represents a car ride,
and a line between two rides means that
they overlap, they can't be performed with
the same car. Now to solve this problem, we can
color the circles, each color represents a car.
But we don't color them anyhow, remember that two
adjacent rides means that they overlap, they can't
be performed with the same car, in other words,
they can't have the same color. So to solve this
problem, we will use an algorithm that we will
learn about later to color the circles in a way
that no two connected circles have the same color,
by using as few different colors as possible.
After doing so, the number of used colors
represents the minimum number of required cars,
3 in this example. Okay what's the common point
between the 3 problem examples we've seen now?
The common point is the structure we used to
represent the problem, it's called: a graph.
A graph is simply a set of vertices that
can be connected with edges, that's it.
You can think of a graph as a network
basically. Here is an example.
But even with this simple concept, it remains a
powerful tool that can be used to represent and
solve a huge number of problems. It even has a
whole branch of mathematics, named graph theory.
Graph theory is the study of graphs, the
structure we defined now, it has lemmas, theorems,
conjectures...etc. But in this course we will
focus way more on graph theory algorithms, the
algorithms that will give us the ability to solve
problems by using graphs, for example shortest
path algorithms, graph coloring algorithms,
minimum spanning tree algorithms...etc. And
it's interesting to know how graph theory started,
the first paper on graph theory appeared in 1736,
it was written by Leonhard Euler, it solved
the Seven bridges of Königsberg problem.
The problem says that in the Königsberg's map at
that time, we had seven bridges as you can see.
And the question is, can we find a path
that traverses each of the seven bridges
exactly once? You can take some seconds
to try. Swimming is not allowed obviously.
Did you find one? Hmm, I don't think so, because
it's proven that such a path doesn't exist,
but why? First of all, we can
represent this map with a graph,
where a vertex represents a region, and an edge
represents a bridge that connects two regions.
And this graph has some properties that show
that the path we're searching for doesn't exist,
we will talk about that more in
detail in the chapter about paths.
Now we learnt about what is a graph,
some examples where we can apply it,
but a lot of questions may come to your mind: Are
there multiple types of graphs? Can a graph have
no edges? Can we have multiple edges between
the same two vertices? And many other ones.
Those are interesting questions that will give
us a better understanding of graphs, this is
why in a next lecture, we will focus on the
different types of graphs and some terminology,
to be more comfortable when we start discussing
algorithms. See you in the next lecture!