Welcome to this new chapter where we will
talk about trees, a special type of graphs.
A tree in graph theory is simply an undirected
connected acyclic graph. This definition should
be simple to understand because we've
seen these three terms before. Undirected
means that edges don't have a particular
direction, the relationship goes both ways.
Connected means that there is a path from any
vertex to any other vertex. And acyclic means
that it has no cycle, it doesn't contain a
path that starts and ends at the same vertex.
Here is an example of a tree, as you can see, it's
undirected, connected, and acyclic, it's a tree.
However, for example this one is not a tree
because it's disconnected and has a cycle.
Okay we know what is tree, but what is it used
for, and does it have some special characteristics
compared to typical graphs? We will talk about it
after introducing some trees related terminology.
We just introduced what is a
tree, we move to the forest.
A forest is an undirected acyclic graph.
It has a definition similar to the tree
but without the 'connected' condition,
so this one is a forest for example.
We can think of a forest as a graph
that contains multiple separate trees,
a graph whose connected components are
trees. The term connected component will
be discussed in the connectivity chapter, but
a connected component of an undirected graph
G is a connected subgraph of G, that is not
a part of a bigger connected subgraph of G.
For example for this graph G, this subgraph is
not a connected component because it's not even
connected. This one is a connected component, it's
a subgraph of G, connected, and trying to add to
it any other vertex of G will make it disconnected
so it's not a part of a bigger connected subgraph.
And for forests, the connected
components of a forest are trees,
this forest for example has 4 connected
components, they are trees. In other terms,
if we take a bunch of separate trees and
merge them into one graph, we get a forest.
We also have the polytree. A polytree
is a directed graph such that if we
replace its edges with undirected
edges, we get a tree. Like this one,
we replace its edges with undirected edges, we
get an undirected connected acyclic graph, a tree.
Then we have the polyforest. The definition of
this one should be easy to deduce, a polyforest
is simply a directed graph such that if we replace
its edges with undirected edges, we get a forest.
Here is an example, if we replace directed
edges by undirected edges, we get a forest.
Another important concept to know is the rooted
tree. A rooted tree is a tree but with a vertex
that has been selected as the root, so we take
a tree, we design one of its nodes as the root,
we get a rooted tree. For example here we selected
the node G as a root. Okay but what is a root? A
root works as a reference for other vertices,
and it's kind of where the tree starts from.
We also have a directed rooted tree, it's
a rooted tree but with directed edges.
And we have two special cases for directed
rooted trees, the first one is the most popular,
it's when the orientation of edges
is away from the root, like this,
no path can ever lead you to the root. This
one is called an arborescence, or an out-tree.
The second case is the opposite, it's when
the orientation of edges is towards the root,
like this, all paths lead to the root. This
is called an anti-arborescence, or an in-tree.
And outside graph theory, the tree data
structure, in its popular definition,
is in reality a directed rooted tree with edges
going away from the root, because it has a root,
there is a parent/child relationship from top to
bottom, and we can only move from a parent to a
child and not the opposite, it's an out-tree.
We will talk about it more in detail in the
next lecture and how to convert a graph to a
rooted tree. Okay now we know what is a tree,
a forest, a polytree, a polyforest,
a rooted tree, a root, an out-tree,
and an in-tree. However, we still don't know why
we do we study trees, and how to manipulate them.
Trees are perfect for example to represent a
hierarchical structure, like for employees of
a company. We have the employee with the highest
rank, who is a manager of some employees, who are
themselves managers of other employees, who are
themselves managers of other employees, and so on.
Or with the file system of a computer, we
have the root folder, which contains a bunch
of files and folders, those folders themselves
contain a bunch of files of folders, and so on.
Trees also give the possibility to create a lot
of useful data structures for different uses,
like the binary search tree, the trie,
the heap, the B-tree, and many other ones.
Also, another application that has a whole
chapter in this course is spanning trees,
especially minimum spanning trees. A connected
graph has the property of having a path from
any vertex to any other vertex, which
is a big advantage in some situations.
But some edges can be unnecessary for keeping
this property, for example here we can remove
the edge GE without losing the connectedness
property. And if we keep removing edges, we
reach a point where removing one more edge breaks
the property. And that result is a spanning tree,
a spanning tree of a graph G is a subgraph of G
that is a tree and includes all vertices of G.
A graph can have multiple spanning trees.
And in a weighted graph, we can calculate
the sum of weights of a spanning tree.
And the spanning tree with the minimum sum of
weights of edges is called the minimum spanning
tree, in the next chapter we will see some
applications of it and some algorithms to find it.
Now we know why studying trees can have
applications, but what about manipulating them,
is it different from graphs? Trees are simply
graphs with some properties, so classic graph
algorithms we studied before can be applied
on trees. Most important ones are depth-first
search and breadth-first search, they represent
the foundation of a lot of tree algorithms.
And they can be applied the same
way for trees, here is an example.
However, one noticeable difference, it's that
traversing out-trees doesn't require holding a
set of visited vertices, pause the video
for some seconds to think of the reason.
Remember that we use the set of visited
vertices because a same vertex can have
multiple vertices going to it, multiple
in-neighbours, or when there is a cycle.
Which implies that we may traverse a same vertex
multiple times. Which is not desirable, usually
we don't want to traverse the same vertex more
than once, to avoid repeating the same actions
or worse, being stuck in a cycle infinitely.
But in out-trees, each node has only one parent,
only one in-neighbour, and there are no cycles,
so each node will be accessed only once,
the risk of traversing a same node again doesn't
exist, this is why we don't need the visited set.
Also, in out-trees, we need to call dfs or
bfs function once, starting from the root,
we don't need to remember what vertices we
called the function with. We can still use the
visited set, but we don't need it, we're just
gonna lose some space and time to handle it.
Now we know some trees terminology, where
they can be used, and how to manipulate them,
but one final question before moving to the
next lecture: given an undirected graph G,
how to know if it's a tree?
Try to answer this question.
A tree is an undirected connected acyclic graph,
so we can think of verifying if G respects the
three conditions. For undirected, we already know
it from the problem description. For connected,
to check if an undirected graph is
connected, we just apply a traversal
algorithm starting from any vertex and see if
it reaches all the vertices, in other words,
if the visited set contains all vertices of the
graph. And for acyclic, we already seen how to
check if a graph is acyclic in the topological
sort chapter, we apply one of the algorithms
we've seen and it must return a successful
result, it shouldn't be stuck at some point.
We also have another approach, you need
to know that a tree of |V| vertices,
has exactly |V|-1 edges, because removing
any edge would disconnect the graph,
not a tree anymore, and adding any edge
would create a cycle, not a tree anymore.
So if we verify one condition only, either
acyclic of connected, we don't need to verify
the other one, we just need to verify that
the graph has |V|-1 edges, which is easier.
Checking if a graph is connected is
easier than checking if it's acyclic,
this is why in this approach, we just check
if it's connected and has |V|-1 edges.
What we do is that given the adjacency list of
the graph, we apply dfs or bfs starting from any
vertex while saving traversed vertices and edges.
After it we check that the number of traversed
vertices is equal to the total number of vertices,
and that the number of found edges is two times
the number of total vertices - 1. Two because
remember that an adjacency list has twice the
number of real edges, at least for an undirected
graph. In code, we create a set visited, an array
edges, and we call dfs starting from an arbitrary
vertex. dfs will set the vertex to visited,
then for each neighbor, it adds the edge, and if
the neighbor is not visited, it calls dfs on it.
After filling visited and edges, we check the two
conditions as we just explained. We've reached
the end of this lecture where we learnt about
trees in graph theory, in the next one we will
focus on out-trees and how to convert a graph
to an out-tree. See you in the next lecture!