Now that we know what is a Eulerian
trail/circuit and how to know if
a graph has one, we want to find it in
the graph, not just know its existence.
Which is the goal of this lecture, where we
will learn about the Hierholzer's algorithm.
Imagine that we have this directed graph, and
we want to find a Eulerian circuit or at least
a Eulerian trail. First step, we need to check
if we can find one. First condition is respected,
all edges of the underlying undirected
graph are connected. For degrees,
we have 1 vertex with out-degree - in-degree =
1, and 1 vertex with in-degree - out-degree = 1,
remaining ones have out-degree = in-degree. We
deduce that we cannot find a Eulerian circuit,
but we can find a Eulerian trail, and A will
be the start vertex, and E the end vertex.
Okay there is a Eulerian trail, but how to
discover it? We may think of launching a
classic dfs traversal from the start vertex
and stop when reaching the end vertex.
Let's try it and see if it works. We start from A.
We go to B. From here we go to C. From here we go
to D. From here we go to E, and we reached the end
vertex. But did we traverse all edges? No, and we
cannot stop here because it wouldn't be a Eulerian
trail, a Eulerian trail has to traverse all edges.
Now you may tell me, we got this wrong result
because when being on the vertex C, we should
have went to G before, then F, then back to C,
then D, then E, we would get a Eulerian trail.
You're right, but how could we know? How could we
know the right order of neighbors to visit to get
the Eulerian trail? We could not, there is no
direct way of knowing without moving further.
What to do then to fix our mistake?
We're at E and we have missing edges.
A solution to fix this is to go back and see what
edges we missed and write vertices we forgot.
E has no outgoing edges, so we're sure there's
nothing else to write after E, we can go back.
D has no remaining unvisited outgoing edges,
so we're sure there's nothing else to write
between D and E, we can go back. But from C,
we still have an unvisited outgoing edge, the
one that takes us to G. So after C should come G,
we write it in the current position and go to it.
From G we have an outgoing edge, the one that
goes to F, so we write F after G and we go to it.
From F we have an outgoing edge to C,
we write C after F and we go to it.
Now C has no more unused outgoing edges, we
go back. For F, same thing. G, same thing. C,
same thing. B, same thing. And A, same
thing. We could go back until the beginning,
therefore we have visited all edges, we
got this Eulerian trail, A B C G F C D E.
This is the idea of our algorithm, we write the
actual vertex in the order and we move forward,
then while vertex still has unused
outgoing edges, we take one of them.
And once we finish, we move backwards
in the order before backtracking.
Moving forward and backwards in this context
means moving the blue cursor we were using in
the animation. And writing means writing something
just after the cursor. At the end of the process,
when the initial recursive call ends, we get our
Eulerian trail. Or circuit if it was possible.
However, one problem, as you can notice,
we're writing between elements and neither
at the end nor at the beginning. Which is slow
when working with an array, all remaining elements
need to be shifted. I mean, we could work with
a doubly-linked list and have an O(1) insertion
at the middle, but we have another solution that
uses an array and doesn't insert at the middle,
let me show it to you. A mistake we made in
this approach is to write a vertex before
making sure that it's in the right place,
it's what forced us later to shift elements.
In this new approach, we don't write a vertex
until it has no remaining unvisited outgoing
edges, because by doing so, once we write a
vertex, we will know that we didn't forget
edges after it, it's in the right place when
looking from the end of the trail, I precise,
from the end of the trail, we will build the
trail from how it ends until how it starts.
Let's apply it with our example. We start from A,
but we don't write it yet, it still has remaining
unvisited edges. Then we go to B, but same thing,
we don't write it yet. Then C, same thing. Then D,
same thing, Then in E, we have no remaining
unvisited edges, so we know that E is in the
right place from the end, E will be the last
vertex the trail visits. Which is logical,
E is the end vertex. We go back to D, and it
has no remaining unvisited outgoing edges,
we write it, we know that it will come just
before E. Then we go back to C. We still
don't write C because there is another outgoing
edge we didn't take. We take it and go to G.
We don't write G yet because we can go to F.
We don't write F yet because we can go to C.
And here in C, no remaining outgoing edges, we can
write it, C will come just before D. Back to F,
no remaining edges, we write F, because there's
nothing anymore that can come between F and C.
Back to G, same thing, we write it. Back
to C, also no remaining edges, we write it.
Back to B, no edges we forgot, we write. Back
to A, also no edges we forgot, we write it.
The initial call ended, we got our Eulerian trail,
and that's how the Hierholzer's algorithm works.
You can notice that we have repeated vertices
in the trail, which is fine, because a Eulerian
trail or circuit is allowed to pass from the
same vertex multiple times, the restriction
concerns edges only. This is why we won't use
a visited set of vertices in this algorithm,
the visited set of vertices is used when we
don't want to pass from the same vertex twice.
The example we've seen is too basic, let's see
another example that is more complex before
jumping to implementation. Yes this graph is a
bit scarier than the previous one, we have a lot
of edges and cycles, we even have self-loops
and multiple edges between two vertices.
Let's see if our algorithm will resist. First
step, checking existence and finding start vertex.
Here conditions are respected and start
and end vertex are D and G respectively.
By the way, because dfs uses recursion,
I will also show you the actual state of
the call stack to better understand what's
happening and what else needs to be done.
The first call is on D obviously. From here we
have 3 outgoing edges, we choose any one of them,
let's choose DB. You can notice that we didn't
write in the output yet, you know the reason.
From here we can go to E. By the way, a yellow
semi-transparent edge means that we traversed
it and we cannot do it anymore, remember,
we must not pass from the same edge twice.
From E we can go to J. From J we go to F. From
F go to G. From G we go to K. From K we go to
C. Then we can go to B. Then we can go to C. Then
we can go to G. From here G has no more remaining
outgoing edges, we write G, and we backtrack. We
deduce that G will be the last vertex we go to.
And we knew what vertex we go back to from the
call stack. C, same thing, no remaining edges,
we write C and backtrack to B. B, same thing,
we write B and backtrack to C. C, same thing,
we write C and backtrack to K. From K we can go
to F. From F we can go to K. K has no more edges,
we write K and backtrack to F. From F we can go
to L. From L we can go to F. No more edges from F,
we write it and backtrack to L. Same
thing for L, we write and backtrack to F.
No edges again, we write F and backtrack to K. K
has no more edges, we write and backtrack to G.
G gets written and we backtrack to F. We
write F and backtrack to J. Once again,
follow the call stack to know what's the vertex we
backtrack to when we have no more outgoing edges.
From J we can go to J with the self-loop. J has
no more edges, we backtrack to J. Same thing,
no edges, we write J and backtrack to E. From E
we go to A. From A we can go to D. From D we go
to H. From H we go to E. E has no remaining edges,
we write and backtrack to H. H goes to I. I goes
to D. D goes to H. No edges in H, we write and
backtrack to D. We write and backtrack to I. We
write and backtrack to H. We write and backtrack
to D. We write and backtrack to A. Here we can
go to A. No edges from A, we go back to A. Same
again, no edges from A, we backtrack to E. From
E we backtrack to B. From B we backtrack to D.
D is the initial call, no edges remaining, so
we write D and the process ends here, we finished
the initial call. And we got our Eulerian trail,
D B E A A D H I D H E J J F G K F L F K C
B C G, by using the Hierholzer's algorithm.
Note that here we were writing from the end, but
in the implementation we will start with an empty
array and fill it from left to right, then at
the end we reverse it to get the right order.
Let's implement this algorithm. This algorithm
uses dfs, but doesn't use a visited set.
Not using a visited set can lead to
repeating the same actions, or worse,
being stuck in a cycle. Unless, as we were
doing in the example, every time we use an edge,
we shut it down to not be able to take it
again, which lets us avoid repeating actions.
Because in two dfs calls, even if on the
same vertex, if in the first call we take
a particular edge, the second call won't be
able to take it, it will take another one,
so actions won't be repeated. And we continue
like that until there are no unused edges.
In brief, we allowed traversing the same vertex
more than once, which is sometimes necessary to
traverse all edges as required by the Eulerian
trail, but we also made sure to turn off an edge
as soon as we take it, to avoid repeating
actions, to avoid being stuck in a cycle,
and to respect the condition that says that
each edge must be traversed exactly once.
How to implement that? In our dfs
function, we take as parameters,
the graph, the actual vertex, and the output
where we will write vertices in the right order.
You can see that we have no visited set. Inside
the function, we said that while we still have
unused outgoing edges, we choose one, go from it
and shut it down. We write, while graph[vertex],
the list of edges that vertex can take, is not
empty, we extract an edge from graph[vertex].
But which one? We will shut down an edge by
removing it from the list, and removing the
last element in a list costs O(1) time only, so
we will take the last one. We write, neighbor is
graph[vertex].pop(), the last edge destination
on the list, it also gets popped from the list,
to not be able to take it again. Now we go to
it by calling dfs again but from the neighbor.
After we made sure that we have no
more outgoing edges, we're guaranteed
that nothing will come after vertex from
the end, we can write it in the output.
This function returns nothing as you can see, it
just traverses the graph to fill output array,
the reverse order of vertices we
pass from in the Eulerian trail.
And in the main Hierholzer function, we can assume
that the graph is at least semi-Eulerian. You
can still check if you're not sure by using the
technique we mentioned in the previous lecture.
We get the start vertex, and we
start. We create an output array,
we call dfs function we made from start vertex,
and now we got the reverse order of vertices,
remember that we have to reverse it to get the
right order, so we reverse it, and we return it.
If you want to return the traversed edges
representation of the trail rather than vertices,
you can zip the list output with the same
list starting from the second element,
you get a tuple that contains the
first element with the second,
then a tuple that contains the second
element with the third, and so on.
One small problem, this method modifies the
initial adjacency list, it makes it empty at the
end. To fix this, we can either copy the adjacency
list before starting, or work with the out-degree,
it represents how many outgoing edges are left.
Every time we take an edge, we decrement it,
and if it reaches 0, then we have no more
outgoing edges. In code, we start by calculating
the out-degree of each vertex, we pass the hash
map to the dfs function, where we keep looping
while outdegree[vertex] is not 0. If it's not the
case yet, we decrement outdegree[vertex], and the
edge we take is at index outdegree[vertex].
And we implemented Hierholzer's algorithm.
This implementation works in O(|V|+|E|)
time complexity because we're traversing
each edge once, and even if we're traversing
some vertices multiple times, the number
of traversed vertices is equal to |E|+1, a
trail of |E| edges traverses |E|+1 vertices.
And by the way, the same algorithm is used to
find Eulerian circuit, no problem with that.
Okay but what about undirected graphs? Is it
the same algorithm? Yes, we can use the same
algorithm, but we have one extra difficulty.
In an undirected graph, in the adjacency list,
an edge (u,v) can be found in neighbors of u, but
also in neighbors of v. And if it's bidirectional,
in a Eulerian trail, a same edge between u and v
has to be used only once, whether from u to v or
from v to u. So when using an edge (u,v), from u
to v for example, both u and v must know that the
edge have been used. If we were in a simple graph,
where there is no multiple edges between the same
two vertices, we could just have a set to remember
used edges. But because we can have multiple ones
like in this graph, it's better to use a hash
table where we map each couple (u,v) to the number
of remaining unused edges (u,v). Every time we go
from u to v or from v to u, we decrease the value,
until it becomes 0, it means that there is
no remaining unvisited edge between u and v.
To actually fill this hash table,
where the default value of a key is 0,
we have to traverse edges (u,v) and increment.
In code, we calculate the degree of each edge,
we create edges map, and for each edge (u,v)
in the adjacency list, we increment the value
of the key sorted tuple (u,v). We sort the tuple
(u,v) so that if we have an edge between A and B,
we get one key ('A', 'B') in the table and not
two separate keys ('A', 'B') and ('B', 'A').
And in dfs function, we add an extra parameter
edges. Inside it, while vertex still has unvisited
edges, we decrement its degree, and the neighbor
is in graph[vertex] at index degree[vertex].
Now before taking the edge, we first make sure
that we still have unused ones of that type,
we check that edges[sorted(vertex, neighbor) is
greater than 0. If it's the case, we can go from
vertex to neighbor but before, we decrease the
value in the edges map. If vertex is equal to
neighbor, in other terms, if we have a self-loop,
we decrease by one, but if they're not equal,
we decrease by 2, because when working with
an adjacency list of an undirected graph, the
same edge can be found in both vertices, so its
value will be incremented twice, the value will
be twice the real number of edges so we decrease
by 2. After it, we just call dfs on the neighbor.
And after we finish all edges, we write vertex in
the output before backtracking. And we implemented
the algorithm for undirected graphs, at least
how I implemented it, there may be other ways.
We're done with this lecture, in this one
we learnt how to find a Eulerian trail or
circuit in a graph, by using the Hierholzer's
algorithm, in both directed and undirected graphs.
See you in the next lecture
for a practice problem.