Welcome back to the course, in this lecture we
will talk about out-trees and how to convert a
graph to an out-tree. Out-trees, also called
arborescence, are important to know because
the popular tree data structure you probably
learnt about before is in reality an out-tree,
a rooted tree with directed edges away from
the root. In this lecture we will see how
is it represented, some terminology, and how to
perform the conversion. An out-tree is a graph,
so we can represent it as we were representing
graphs during this course, with an adjacency
list or an adjacency matrix. But we can also
represent it with a recursive Node type.
A node contains an attribute value, it represents
the label of the node, and an array children that
contains all nodes that the node can go to, it's
like the array of a vertex in an adjacency list.
It's called children because in terminology
we have a parent/child relationship.
For example for this node, the value is K,
and its children are the nodes B, L, and F.
And you can see that a node doesn't have the
reference to its parent, so it cannot access it,
this is why it's similar to a directed edge,
we can go from a parent to a child but not the
opposite. If we add the parent it becomes an
undirected edge, we can move back and forth.
Let's move to some terminology. We have the root,
we talked about it before, it's from where the
tree originates. We also have the terms parent
and child. In an out-tree edges are directed,
the node from where the edge goes out is the
parent, and the node where it enters is the child.
And children of a same node are called siblings.
We also have leaves, nodes that are at the
bottom of the tree, they have no children.
And we have internal nodes, nodes
that are neither root nor leaves.
Another important term is levels. An out-tree
can be split into levels, the level k of a tree
contains nodes that are at a distance of k from
the root. So level 0 contains the root only, then
level 1 contains children of the root, then level
2 children of children of the root, and so on.
And you have to know that traversing
an out-tree with breadth-first search
will traverse nodes of the level
0, then level 1, then level 2,
and so on, this is why we say that
BFS traverses a tree level by level.
Another term is the depth, the depth of a
node is simply the level where it's located,
which represents its distance from
the root. We also have the height,
the height of a tree is the length of the
longest path from its root to one of its leaves.
Last one, k-ary tree, it's a tree where each
node has at most k children. For example a
binary tree is a 2-ary tree, each node has
at most 2 children, left and right children.
Now imagine that we have an undirected graph, a
node that we want to design as a root, and we want
to convert it to an out-tree, with a Node type
representation. Our graph is actually represented
by an adjacency list, but we want the tree to be
represented with Node objects, so starting from
values in the adjacency list, we will create
a bunch of nodes and connect them together.
First step, we create a node root
that contains the value of the vertex
we want to set at the root. We also need a
visited set to traverse the adjacency list.
And now, we just apply dfs while for
each vertex we visit, we create nodes
for its unvisited neighbors and add them to its
children, we got an out-tree with G as a root.
How to code this. First we need a class Node,
it contains an attribute val, the value, and
an attribute children, an array of nodes that is
empty by default. Now we need a function dfs that
takes as parameters the graph we want to convert,
the node we're working on, and the visited set.
First dfs step, add the actual vertex to visited.
You can see that here we're adding the value and
not the node itself, because here node is of type
Node, but in an adjacency list we work with the
values of nodes, not nodes themselves, this is
why we add the value of the node to visited.
In the previous example at the beginning we would
add the value 'G' to visited and
not the node with G as a value.
After it we traverse unvisited neighbors.
For each unvisited neighbor, remember that
we need to create a node for it, add it to
children of the actual node, and go to it.
And this is what we do, we create
a node that contains its value,
we add it to children of the actual node,
and we go to it by calling dfs on it.
And in the main to_out_tree() function, we take a
graph as parameter, and the value of the vertex we
want to design as a root. Inside it, we create
the root node, it contains the value we passed
as parameter, we create a visited set, and we
call dfs to build the tree. After doing so,
we return root, the root of the tree we made,
we converted graph to an out-tree. Obviously,
here we assumed that the graph respects the three
conditions, undirected connected and acyclic.
And the algorithm is in O(|V|) time because we're
just applying depth-first search, and in a tree,
the number of edges is related to the number of
vertices, it's the number of vertices - 1. We
reached the end of this lecture, we learnt more
about the out-tree and how to root a tree. In the
next lecture, we will solve an interesting
trees related coding problem to practice.