In previous lectures, we learnt about
two main ways of implementing a graph:
the adjacency list and the adjacency
matrix. We ended with an important question:
which one to choose when we want to implement a
graph? I think that a comparison between them is
necessary here to decide. We will compare them
in terms of time and space resources obviously.
To measure resources used by a graph, whether to
store it or to perform operations on it, we have
two important values to take into consideration,
we have |V|, the number of vertices, and |E|,
the number of edges, we will use them a lot when
measuring time and space complexity of algorithms
we will study. Let's start with space usage.
For an adjacency list, we have a hash table
whose keys are vertices, we deduce that the number
of keys is equal to the number of vertices, |V|.
And for the size of the arrays, I'll try
to make you find the answer by yourself.
Here we have a graph and its adjacency list,
now count the number of edges of the graph,
count the sum of sizes of the arrays in the
adjacency list, and tell me what do you notice.
In the graph, we have 8 edges, and in the
adjacency list, the size of the first array is 1,
the size of the second one is 3, and so
on. If we do the sum, we find 8. We can
notice that the sum of sizes of arrays is
equal to the number of edges, why is that?
It's because every time we add an edge (u,v)
in the graph, we insert v in neighbors of u,
so one of the arrays' size increases by
1, which increases the total size by 1.
And this is why the sum of sizes is equal to
the number of edges, each edge adds 1 to the
sum. In total, we have |V| for the keys, and |E|
for the values, we get a space usage of |V|+|E|.
Note that this is for directed graphs, because
for undirected graphs, remember that when we add
an edge (u,v), we add v in neighbors of u, but
we also add u in neighbors of v. So each edge
adds 2 to the sum, this is why the sum of sizes
will be 2|E| as you can see in this example.
But not a big deal, both |V|+|E|
and |V|+2|E| are in O(|V|+|E|),
we can say that the space complexity
of the adjacency list is O(|V|+|E|).
What about the adjacency matrix now? In the
adjacency matrix, we create a matrix of size
|V|x|V|, which is |V|². This is why the space
complexity of an adjacency matrix is O(|V|²),
the number of edges doesn't affect the size,
whether we have 0 edges or an edge between each
pair of vertices, the necessary space remains
the same, |V|². Which one is better? O(|V|+|E|)
of the adjacency list or O(|V|²) of the adjacency
matrix? You need to know that in a simple graph,
the maximum number of edges is |V|(|V|-1), because
we have |V| vertices, and each one of them can
have an edge with the other |V|-1 vertices,
which is the case with the complete graph.
Look at this example, we have 5 vertices, the
first vertex has 4 neighbors, the second vertex
has 4 neighbors, and so on. So in the worst case,
|E| is |V|(|V|-1), which is |V|²-|V|. We replace,
we get O(|V|²) for the adjacency list, same as
for the adjacency matrix. But in the best case,
we have no edges, |E| is 0, we get O(|V|) for
adjacency list, which is way better than O(|V|²).
The reason behind all of that is that
the adjacency matrix needs space for all
possible edges, even non-existing ones,
this is why it's not space-efficient.
But an adjacency list needs space for existing
edges only, which is better in terms of space.
However, one important detail: A cell in the
adjacency matrix stores the value 0 or 1,
which means that 1 bit is enough. Where a cell in
the adjacency list stores the label of a vertex,
which requires 32 bits if we're dealing with
integers and using an array representation.
In brief, in terms of space, an adjacency list
is more efficient if the graph is sparse enough,
otherwise the adjacency matrix is better.
Next point of comparison, main operations.
We have the operation of adding a vertex.
For the adjacency list, we just add a key with an
empty array, which has an O(1) time complexity,
adding a key in a hash table has
an O(1) time complexity in average.
But for the adjacency matrix, it depends if the
structure is static or dynamic. If it's static, we
have to create a new one from scratch, which costs
O(|V|²) time, because we have to create a new one.
And if it's dynamic, we just need to add a row
and a column of size |V|, which costs O(|V|) time.
Next operation, removing a vertex. With an
adjacency list, we said that we delete the key,
but we also traverse other vertices to delete
all edges going to the vertex we want to delete.
This last operation requires us to
traverse the whole adjacency list,
which has a size in O(|V|+|E|), remember the
explanation when we were comparing space usage.
We can say that deleting a vertex from an
adjacency list has an O(|V|+|E|) time complexity.
And for the adjacency matrix, if the structure is
static, we need to create a new one from scratch,
which costs O(|V|²) time. And if it's dynamic,
we need to swap the ith row with the last row
and delete the last row, which costs O(|V|)
time, then swap the ith cell with the last cell
and popping for each row, which costs O(|V|)
time. So deleting a vertex costs O(|V|) time.
Next operation, adding an
edge. For the adjacency list,
we have to access the array of neighbors of the
source vertex, which costs O(1) time in average,
then adding the destination vertex to the
array, which costs O(1) time amortized.
We can say that adding an edge in adjacency
lists costs O(1) amortized time in average.
And for the adjacency matrix, we just have to put
1 in the cell at row source at column destination,
and accessing an element in an array costs O(1)
time, so adding an edge in an adjacency matrix
costs O(1) time. Next operation, checking if there
is an edge from u to v. In an adjacency list,
we need to traverse neighbors of u, which
costs O(deg(u)) time in the worst case.
For an adjacency matrix, we just check
if matrix[u][v] is 1, it's done in O(1).
Next operation, deleting an edge. For the
adjacency list, we need to access the neighbours
of the source, which costs O(1) time in average.
Then deleting the destination from the array,
and deleting an element from an array costs n,
where n is the number of elements of the array.
And in a graph, a vertex can have at most |V|-1
vertices, so deleting costs |V|-1, O(|V|) time.
We can even be more precise and say that it
depends on the degree of the source vertex,
which can be between 0 and |V|-1 inclusive,
remember that the degree in a simple graph
represents the number of its neighbors.
For an adjacency matrix, we just put
0 in matrix[u][v], which costs O(1).
Next operation, traversing neighbors of a vertex.
For an adjacency list, to traverse neighbors of a
vertex u, we need to traverse the array at key u.
And the length of this array depends on the number
of neighbors of u, its degree, which doesn't
exceed |V|-1, we can say that the time complexity
is O(deg(u)). And for the adjacency matrix,
whether the vertex u has a lot of neighbors,
a few neighbors, or no neighbors at all,
we need to traverse the whole row u,
to find cells where the value is 1, which costs
O(|V|), remember that the length of a row is |V|.
Next operation, building the
structure. For and adjacency list,
we start by creating a key for each vertex,
which costs |V| because we have |V| vertices.
Then we traverse edges to add each one of them.
We just said that adding an edge in an adjacency
list costs O(1) time, so the cost of adding
all the edges is |E|. In total, we get |V|+|E|,
building the adjacency list from a set of vertices
and edges has an O(|V|+|E|) time complexity.
And for the adjacency matrix, we start by
creating the matrix, which is of size |V|x|V|.
And creating such a matrix costs
|V|x|V| obviously, which is |V|².
Then we traverse edges while adding each one of
them. Adding an edge in an adjacency matrix costs
O(1) time, so adding them all costs |E|. In total
we have |V|²+|E|, and we know that |E| is smaller
than |V|², we can say that the time complexity
of building an adjacency matrix is O(|V|²).
Okay now we measured the space complexity of
both structures + the time complexity of main
operations with each one of them. But what is the
conclusion? Which one to choose? As you can see,
both have pros and cons, for example adjacency
matrix is more efficient for adding, checking,
and removing edges, and space
efficient when the graph is dense.
And the adjacency list is more efficient to
traverse neighbors and building the structure
for example, so it depends on the problem. But,
in my opinion, adjacency lists are usually more
preferred, because they're more efficient for
traversing the graph, a very important operation,
we'll see it in the next chapter. This is why
in this course, in algorithms we will study,
we will use almost exclusively an adjacency list
for implementation. Also, in real world problems,
graphs are usually sparse, and an adjacency
list is more suited for sparse graphs.
We've reached the end of this lecture
where we had a comparison between space
and time efficiency of adjacency
lists and adjacency matrices.
Now get ready to start studying graph algorithms,
we will start with one of the most important ones:
depth-first search, aka DFS.
See you in the next lecture!