In the last lecture, we discussed Dijkstra's
algorithm, but it had some problems with negative
weights and negative cycles. What if we have a
graph with negative weights? We cannot find the
shortest path? No, we have alternatives that
handle this, like the algorithm we will see
in this lecture: The Bellman-Ford algorithm.
The way this lecture will be organized is:
We will start by stating the global idea of
the algorithm, see an example, implement it,
then we will see a more detailed explanation, and
we finish the lecture by analyzing complexity. The
Bellman-Ford algorithm solves the same problem as
Dijkstra's algorithm: The single-source shortest
path problem, we're given a start vertex, and
we want the shortest path to all other vertices.
Another common aspect of Bellman-Ford and
Dijkstra's is the use of edge relaxation,
we will use it here also. Edge relaxation
is when we have a map dist where dist[v]
represents the shortest path from source to v.
Let's say dist[C] is currently 24, because we
found a path that takes us from source to v with
a total distance of 24. Then we find an edge (D,
C) such that dist[D]+w(D,C) is smaller than
dist[C], it means that we found a shorter way
to go to C, by going to D then taking the edge
(D, C), here we update dist[C] by dist[D]+w(D,C).
What we're doing here is relaxation. Okay, but how
does Bellman-Ford algorithm work? Imagine that we
have this graph of 8 vertices, and we want to find
the shortest path from A to each vertex. First of
all, in a graph of n vertices, any path has a
length of at most n-1. Which means that here,
the maximum length of a shortest path is 7. I said
the length, the number of edges, not the weight.
What does it mean? Here we have 8 vertices, so
there exist 8 paths that we're searching for,
the one from A to A, the one
from A to B, A to C...etcetera.
And each one of them can have a length of 0,
1, 2, and so on until 7. But you may tell me,
if we have a cycle we can have a path of length
greater than n-1, it can even be infinite.
That's true, but by path we mean ones that don't
pass from the same vertex twice. Because ones
that do, paths that contain a cycle, will not
be in the final result, let me tell you why.
If the cycle has a positive weight, then
it's just increasing our path's weight,
which makes it not the shortest path. If the
cycle has a weight of 0, then it's useless,
we can just remove it and still get the same total
weight. Else if it has a negative weight, it's
true that it's decreasing our path's total weight,
but negative weight cycles are not allowed.
If you understood this, we can continue. The
Bellman-Ford algorithm is based on the fact
that if we relax all the edges k times,
we're guaranteed to have shortest paths
of at most k edges. And because paths lengths
cannot exceed n-1, repeating the operation n-1
times is guaranteed to produce shortest paths
of at most n-1 edges, which is the maximum a
valid shortest path could have in a graph, so it
produces the shortest paths we're searching for.
Let's take this graph as an example. Same
as Dijkstra's, at the beginning the shortest
distance from the source, A, to itself
is 0, and infinity to all other vertices.
Now first iteration, we relax
all edges once. For example for
the edge (A, B, 3), dist[B] is infinity while
dist[A]+w(A,B) is 0+3, 3, smaller, we update.
Same thing for (A, C, 12), dist[C] becomes
12. All other edges didn't have an impact,
because for example for (D, F, 5), inifnity+5
is not smaller than infinity, no update.
We finished with the first iteration, we're now
guaranteed to have all shortest paths of length 1.
But it's not enough, some paths we're
searching for may have a length greater than 1.
Let's move to the second iteration. We relax
all edges. Some edges will not have an impact,
like (D, F, 5) once again, but some edges will. We
have (C, E, 3), it decreases dist[E] from infinity
to 15. Also (B, C, 6), it decreases dist[C]
from 12 to 9. Also (B, D, 2), it decreases
dist[D] from infinity to 5. And finally (B,
E, 11), it decreases dist[E] from 15 to 14.
We finished the iteration, we're guaranteed
to have all shortest paths of at most 2 edges.
But we can find shorter paths by using 3 edges,
let's add an iteration. Let's relax all edges.
Some edges will not have an impact, like
(D, E, 10). dist[D]+w(D, E) is 5+10, 15,
but it does not update, because we already
know how to go to E with less than 15.
But some of them will. We have (D, F, 5),
it decreases dist[F] from infinity to 10,
it's the first path that have been
able to reach F, and we waited until
iteration 3 to find it, it means that we
need at least 3 edges to go from A to F.
We also have (C, E, 3), it decreases
dist[E] from 14 to 12. We deduce that for E,
allowing paths of 3 edges gave us a shorter path
than when we had only 2 edges. With 2 edges,
we can go to E with a distance of at least 14,
but with 3 edges, we can go with a distance of 12.
Let's continue, we may have shorter paths with
4 edges, so we add an iteration. We relax all
the edges. Edges that will have an impact are
these ones: (F, H, 13) will decrease dist[H]
from infinity to 23. (F, G, 6) will decrease
dist[G] from infinity to 16. And (F, E, -2) will
decrease dist[E] from 12 to 8, by allowing paths
of length 4, we found a shorter path to go to E.
We may have shorter paths with length 5, so
let's add an iteration. We relax all the edges,
and the only edge that will have an impact is
(G, H, 4), it decreases dist[H] from 23 to 20.
Let's add an iteration for paths of length 6.
We relax all the edges, and nothing changes,
there is no edge that will give us
a shorter path to its destination.
It means that we're done, we found all
shortest paths, useless to continue,
all shortest paths have a length
of at most 5, and we found them.
We're done, we officially have the shortest path
from A to any vertex. And you can see that they
differ in length, for example shortest path from A
to C has a length of 2, we found it at the second
iteration. The one from A to E has a length of 4,
we found it at the iteration 4. And this is why we
need multiple iterations, each iteration allows
us to find potential shorter paths with one more
edge, until either we do n-1 iterations or nothing
changes anymore. And this is how Bellman-Ford
algorithm works, we keep relaxing all edges
until no update is done in the current iteration.
Let's implement it. We have the
graph, and the source vertex.
We need the list of edges, we extract them by
traversing the adjacency list. Then we create
dist map where dist[v] is the shortest distance
from source to v. Initially we put infinity for
all vertices except the source, for which we
put 0. Then, we gonna do at most n-1 iterations,
so we use a for loop that gets repeated n-1 times,
where n is the number of vertices of the graph.
Inside it, we put a boolean variable changed, to
see if something changes during the iteration.
It's initially false, then if an update
happens, we set it to true. Now we relax edges,
for each edge (u, v, w), as we were doing,
if dist[u]+w is smaller than dist[v], we
update dist[v] by assigning dist[u]+w. And we set
changed to true, to know that an update happened.
After relaxing all the edges, if nothing changed,
we break the loop for an early exit, useless
to continue. After the loop, we return dist.
I know that I didn't talk about reconstructing
the path and negative weights and negative cycles,
I'll do it later. But before, it's possible that
you're not totally convinced of how and why the
algorithm works, this is why I want to explain
to you the dynamic programming aspect of this
algorithm. Okay, we have this graph, and we're
searching for the shortest distance from A to any
other vertex. We have 8 vertices, so the maximum
length of a path is 7. Which means that we're
searching for the shortest distance from A to
any other vertex with a path of at most 7 edges.
We want to calculate all these values,
we want to calculate d(v,7) for each
vertex v such that d(v,k) represents
the shortest distance from the source
to the vertex v by using a path whose
length is smaller than or equal to k.
Let's assume that we have the shortest distance
from A to any other vertex with a path of at
most 6 edges, we have the value of d(v, 6) for
any vertex v, and we want to calculate d(E, 7).
We have multiple possibilities for the shortest
path to E of at most 7 edges: We can either,
take the shortest path to E of at most 6 edges,
which is ABDFE, and change nothing, or take the
shortest path to one of its in-neighbours
of at most 6 edges and add the last edge,
the one that goes to E. E has 4 in_neighbours, B
C D and F. So in total, we have 5 possibilities:
keep ABDFE, take AB and add the edge
(B, E), take ABC and add the edge (C,
E), take ABD and add the edge (D, E),
take ABDF and add the edge (F, E).
How to choose? We simply take the
one with the smallest total weight.
For ABDFE it's 8, for AB + the edge (B,
E) it's 3+11, 14, for ABC + the edge (C,
E) it's 9+3, 12, for ABD + the edge (D, E)
it's 5+10, 15, and for ABDF + the edge (F,
E) it's 10-2, 8. The min is 8, that we can
get by keeping ABDFE, or going to F then to E.
What we did here is that to calculate d(E, 7),
we took the min between d(E, 6), and the min
between d(u, 6)+w(u,E) for each in-neighbor u of
E. Here we assumed that we had those values, but
in reality to get them, we do the same recursive
operation, it's a recursive process. In general,
we have that the shortest distance from source to
a vertex v with a path of at most k edges, d(v,k),
is the min between d(v, k-1), and the min between
d(u, k-1)+w(u, v) for each in-neighbor u of v.
We have a recursive formula, what about the
base case? The base case is when k is 0,
with a path of 0 edges, the minimum distance is
easy to calculate, it's 0 if v is the source, and
infinity if it's not, remember the initialization
step. And we get this recurrence relation: d(v,k)
is equal to: 0 if k is 0 and v is equal to source,
infinity if k is 0 and v is not equal to source,
else it's min(d(v,k-1), min({d(u,k-1)+w(u,v)
| u is an in-neighbor of v})).
We can easily turn this recurrence relation into
code, we take as parameters the transpose graph,
the source vertex, v, and k. We need the transpose
graph and not the graph itself to be able to
traverse in-neighbours not out-neighbours. If
k is 0 and v is equal to the source, return 0,
else if k is 0 and v is not equal to the source,
return infinity. Else, return min(d(v,k-1),
and min between d(u,k-1)+w(u,v) for each
in-neighbor u of v with an edge weight w.
We can also write it this this way if you're
not comfortable with list comprehension,
we set d(v,k-1) as the min, then we traverse
in-neighbors u to see if d(u,k-1)+w(u,v) replaces.
And we return the min distance. What do we
do with this function now? Well, we can use
it to calculate shortest path from source to
vertices of the graph. We have a function sssp,
single source shortest path, that takes
as parameters the graph, and the source.
We create the transpose graph by reversing all
the edges, an edge (u,v) becomes an edge (v,u).
Then, the maximum number of edges of a path is
n-1, so we call the function we made with n-1
on each vertex v, and we store results in
dist map, that we return after finishing.
And we got the shortest distance from
source to any vertex, by using recursion.
Okay then why would we need Bellman-Ford
algorithm?. Well, because this function is slow,
it's exponential, each call may need
the result of multiple other calls.
Let's see why. Let's draw a part of
the recursion tree for one vertex call,
d(E,7). We needed the result of d(E,6),
d(B,6), d(C,6), d(D,6), and d(F,6).
And d(E,6) needs the result of d(E,5), d(B,5),
d(C,5), d(D,5), and d(F,5). d(B,6) needs the
result of d(B,5), d(A,5), and d(F,5). d(C,6) needs
the result of d(C,5), d(A,5), and d(B,5). d(D,6)
needs the result of d(D,5) and d(B,5). And d(F,6)
needs the result of d(F,5), d(D,5), and d(H,5).
Remaining levels of the tree will get
wider and wider, until k becomes 0.
Without even seeing them, we can already notice
something interesting from this part of the tree,
it's that we have repeated recursive calls, we're
doing the same computations again and again.
To avoid this, we use dynamic programming, an
algorithmic technique that optimizes recursive
functions when the same calls are done
multiple times, like it's the case here.
What we want is that when we solve a subproblem,
in other terms, when we get the result of a call,
we store it somewhere so that the next time
we need it, we don't compute it from scratch,
we directly take the result from
the structure where we stored it,
this is dynamic programming. And we have two
approaches: The top-down approach, memoization,
and the bottom-up approach, tabulation.
In memoization we keep the recursive form
of the function, we just add a hash table
where we store the results of subproblems,
the key is what characterizes a subproblem and the
value is its result. And in tabulation, we build
an n-dimensional table, whose the dimension
and the size depends on the shape and number
of subproblems, then we fill it, and we find the
result of the initial problem in the last cells.
Let's go with tabulation, it's more suitable
for this problem because we need to solve all
possible subproblems. Okay but what will
be the shape and size of our dp table?
First of all, here a subproblem is characterized
by two things: The destination vertex, v, and the
number of allowed edges, k. The source is always
the same, A in our example, so we don't count
it. This is why we will have a 2D table, rows will
represent values of k, and columns will represent
the different values of v, the vertices. Paths
can be of length 0, 1, and so on until n-1, so we
have n rows. And we have n vertices, so we have
n columns. Our dp table will be of size n by n.
And dp[k][v] represents the result of d(v, k),
the shortest distance from the source to v by
using at most k edges. So what we're searching
for is results of the last row of the table,
they represent shortest distance from
source to each vertex, all values d(v,n-1).
But to get them, we need to fill the table, how
to do so? Well, we will just use the recurrence
relation. The base case is when k is 0, where
we put 0 if v is equal to source, and infinity
otherwise. We do exactly the same thing to
fill dp[0], we put 0 if v is equal to source,
which is the case for A, and infinity in others.
And for remaining rows, we use the recursive case.
We know that d(v, k) is min between
d(v,k-1), and min between d(u,k-1)+w(u,v)
for each in-neighbour u of v. And here, same
thing, dp[k][v] is min between d[k-1][v],
and min between d[k-1][u]+w(u,v) for
each in-neighbour u of v, very simple.
By applying these formulas to our example,
this is how the table gets filled.
And as you can see, the last row represents
the shortest distance from A to each vertex,
the same result as with
the Bellman-Ford algorithm.
It's because Bellman-Ford algorithm is
based on this dynamic programming idea.
Let's implement this solution. We start by
calculating the transpose graph, we will
need it to find in-neighbours. Then we create
a dp table of size n by n, but for the second
dimension we use a hash map rather than an array
to be able to have the vertex label as the key.
We start by filling the first row,
dp[0]. We traverse vertices v,
and we put 0 in dp[0][v] if v is
equal to source, else we put infinity.
Now we traverse remaining rows, this is why k
starts at 1. For each row, we traverse vertices v.
For each vertex v, we use that formula
and assign the result to dp[k][v].
After the loop, we return the last row of
dp, it's the result we've been searching for.
We implemented the dynamic programming solution.
However, let's change a few things. For example,
we're not really obliged to work with a 2D table,
a 1D table would do the job, we can use only
one row that we keep updating instead of a
whole matrix. The signification of a cell will
slightly change, but we still get the same result.
Also, instead of using min function, we can
traverse in-neighbors and use a condition:
If dp[u]+w is smaller than dp[v], we update
dp[v] by putting dp[u]+w, same result.
Another thing, at each iteration, we're
traversing vertices and for each vertex we're
traversing its in-neighbors, so actually we're
just traversing all the edges at each iteration.
This is why, we can directly traverse all the
edges (u, v, w) and still get the job done.
Notice that we don't need the transpose
graph anymore, but we need the list of edges.
We're just making small changes to the
code that still give the same result guys.
We can use the name dist instead of dp. Another
thing, we can add a boolean variable changed,
to stop as soon as nothing changes during a whole
iteration, to avoid adding useless iterations.
And as you can see, we got our Bellman-Ford
implementation we've seen at the beginning,
we've been able to produce it
by using dynamic programming.
However, two things are missing: Being able to
reconstruct the path, and handle negative cycles.
Because here, we will just have the distance, not
the path itself. This is why we should have also
added prev map, same as in Dijkstra's algorithm.
prev[v] represents the previous vertex of v in
its shortest path. Then if an update happens, if
dist[u]+w is smaller than v, it means that to go
to v, we will pass from u, this is why u becomes
the previous vertex of v, same as in Dijkstra's.
After the loop we return both dist and prev,
and if we want to find the distance we use dist,
and if we want to reconstruct the path, we use
the function we used in Dijkstra's to reconstruct
the path from source to a chosen vertex. We keep
going back and we reverse the path at the end.
What about negative weights? Well, as you could
see in the example, there was no problem with
negative weights, Bellman-Ford algorithm handles
negative weights perfectly. Except when we have
negative cycles, because when we do, it's
not even possible to have a shortest path,
we can always add one cycle traversal to decrease
the total weight. However, we can detect it with
Bellman-Ford algorithm. After the iterations,
we need to traverse edges one more time.
For each edge (u, v, w), if dist[u]+w is smaller
than dist[v], then we have a negative cycle.
How can it be possible? Let's say we allow
passing from the same vertex more than once.
You need to know that if we have a path
from u to v that has more than n-1 edges,
then there must be a cycle in it, it must pass
from a vertex more than once, here is an example.
Our actual shortest paths have a length of
at most n-1, because we did n-1 iterations.
But, can we add cycle to make them shorter?
Well, if it's a positive weight cycle, then it
will increase the weight of our shortest path,
we don't want it. If it's a zero weight cycle,
then it's useless, it doesn't make it
shorter. The only case where it's worth
it is when it's a negative weight cycle,
adding it to our path decreases its weight.
And this is why if we have a path that is shorter
than our at most n-1 length shortest paths,
then it contains a negative cycle, we will
know that the graph contains a negative cycle.
This is why the loop detects them, the loop checks
if there is a shorter path of length greater than
n-1, because if there is, then we have a negative
cycle. Here is an example, we have this graph,
and after the n-1 iterations, we add a last
one to see if there is a negative cycle.
We check the condition with edges, and you can
see that it worked with one, the edge (E, D).
So we have a negative weight
cycle, it's the cycle DFE.
In code, we add this loop that traverses edges
one last time. If the condition is true, we can
for example return null for both dist and prev to
say that there's a negative cycle in the graph.
And we got our full implementation
of Bellman-Ford algorithm.
If you're not familiar with dynamic
programming and this explanation wasn't enough,
I have a last approach to let you understand
the algorithm, I found it on stackexchange.
Imagine that we have a digital door lock with a
four-digit code. And this lock allows not writing
the code all at once, having characters between
characters of the code is fine. For example if the
code is 2749 and we write 32675049, the lock would
still get opened because 2749 is a subsequence.
Knowing this information, you want to open
the door, without entering a lot of digits
if possible. A possible way is to simply type
the 10000 possible codes one after the other,
we're guaranteed to open the lock. But, we'd
need to write 40000 digits, too long. A smarter
way is this one: We write all digits once. Here
we're guaranteed to have all codes of length 1.
But, it's not enough, we want to have all codes
of length 4. We write all digits again. Now we're
guaranteed to have all codes of length 2: 00,
01, 02...and so on. Then again, we write all
the digits. Now we're guaranteed to have all
codes of length 3, you can check by yourself.
Last iteration, we write all the digits. And now
we're guaranteed to have all codes of length 4,
enough to open the door. You can try any code of
length 4 and you will find it here, we've been
able to do that by writing 40 digits only, instead
of 40000, because we avoided repeating work.
It's a perfect analogy for Bellman-Ford algorithm.
We write all the digits a kth time and we're
guaranteed to have all codes of length of at
most k digits, and in Bellman-Ford, we try to
relax all edges a kth time and we're guaranteed
to have all shortest paths of at most k edges.
This is why we try to relax all edges multiple
times, to make sure to traverse all possible
paths starting from the vertex A, while keeping
track of the shortest one for each destination v.
Last thing to talk about in
this lecture: Time complexity.
Extracting edges costs |V|+|E| because
we traverse the adjacency list.
We also have |V| to create dist map, |V| to
create prev map, and |V| to fill dist map.
Then we repeat the same operation c times,
where c is the number of iterations before
the process stops, it's between 1 and |V|-1.
Inside it, we traverse all the edges, |E| cost.
After it, we traverse edges one more time,
|E| cost. In total, we have 4|V|+(c+2)|E|.
In the worst case, we need to perform |V|-1
iterations, c is |V|-1. We replace, and we
get 4|V|+(|V|+1)|E|, which gives a time complexity
of O(|V||E|). But in the best case, c is only 1,
the process stops at the first iteration. We
replace, and we get 4|V|+3|E|, which gives a
time complexity of O(|V|+|E|). So the number of
iterations is important in the running time, we
should try to keep it as low as possible, for that
I think that we need to make the order of edges
traversal start from ones that are closer to the
source, to make more updates in early iterations.
We've reached the end of this lecture, where
we discussed Bellman-Ford algorithm. It's a bit
slower than Dijsktra's algorithm, but it handles
negative values, so we should choose depending
on the situation. See you in the next lecture
to talk about the Floyd-Warshall algorithm.