In the previous lecture, we've seen how to check
colorability of a graph, but with an algorithm
that works with k = 2 only. We want an algorithm
that works with any strictly positive value of k,
this is what we will see in this lecture, we
will check k-colorability by using backtracking.
The process is simple. Let's say that we have k
colors. We can decide to color vertices one by
one following a given order, and if a problem
occurs, we backtrack and try something else.
Because yes, we can have multiple choices
for how to color a vertex, we try them one
by one until finding one that leads to a valid
vertex coloring. But what are these choices?
We have k colors, and the actual vertex may
have neighbors that are already colored,
then we need to choose a color that is different
from them all. We deduce that possible choices
for a given vertex are the k colors minus
the colors already used for its neighbors.
For example we have 5 colors red,
blue, green, yellow, and orange,
and we want to color the vertex F. In neighbors
of this vertex we can find that the colors green
and red are already used. Remaining choices are
blue, green, and orange, we try them one by one.
For the process, we traverse vertices in any
order, we color the first vertex with one of its
possible choices, we move to the second vertex,
we color it with one of its possible choices,
and so on. And if at some point we're
stuck, in other words, we cannot color
the actual vertex because all colors are used by
neighbors, we backtrack and try something else.
And if we get to color all vertices with valid
choices, then we found a k-coloring of the graph.
Let's see this process applied on this
graph with k = 3. First we need an order of
traversal of vertices, because we will color
them one by one and backtrack if necessary.
Orders can differ in efficiency, there are some
orders better than others, some orders that won't
cause a lot of backtracking. There are even
orders that, if followed, we directly get a
valid coloring without ever backtracking, which
is done in linear time. But, because we cannot
know it in advance, we use a random order.
Let's use this order for example, GBIEAHFCD.
We have 3 colors: 0, red, 1, blue,
and 2, green. Let's start coloring.
For each vertex, we'll try to color it with
red, if it's not possible we use blue, if
it's not possible we use green, if it's also not
possible then we cannot continue, we backtrack.
We start with G, we can color it with red. Then
B, we can color it with red. Then I, we can color
it with red. Then E, we cannot color it with
red, because its neighbor, G, is already red.
But we can color it with the
next color, blue. Then A,
we cannot color it with red because B is red, and
we cannot color it with blue because E is blue.
But we can color it with the next color:
green. Then H, red is not available but we
can color it with blue. Then F, red is taken by
I, blue is taken by E, and green is taken by A.
We have only 3 colors and all
of them are used by neighbors,
so we cannot color F with this configuration,
we need to backtrack and try something else.
Back to H, blue didn't work, we move to the next
color. But green is taken by A. We have no other
choices on how to color H, we remove its color
and backtrack, it's important to remove the color
before backtracking to make it like we didn't
come from here at all. Back to A, green didn't
work. And we have no other colors, we remove the
color and backtrack. Back to E, blue didn't work,
next color is green. And it's available, we
color E with green and move to the next vertex.
Next vertex is A, red is used but this time
blue is available, we color it with blue.
Then we have H, red is taken by G and I, and
blue is taken by A, but green is available,
we put green. Then we have F, red is used,
blue is used, and green is used, we backtrack.
Back to H, green didn't work, and we have no
other colors, we remove the color and backtrack.
Back to A, blue didn't work and
green is not available, we backtrack.
Back to E, green didn't work and there
are no colors remaining, we backtrack.
Back to I, red didn't work, this time we try blue.
Then E, red is used, blue is used, we can only
put green. Then A, red is used, we can put blue.
Then H, red and blue are used, we can put green.
Then F, red is available. Then C, red and
blue are used, but green is available.
Finally D, red is used but blue is available. All
vertex have been colored, we found a valid vertex
coloring of the graph by using 3 colors,
we can say that this graph is 3-colorable.
And you can see that vertices of each
of the 3 colors form an independent set.
Basically that's the idea of the algorithm,
we keep coloring vertices by trying available
colors one by one, and if there is no remaining
available colors to try, we backtrack to change
colors of previous vertices. And here's an order
of vertices that produces no backtracking at all,
it walks straightforward, we can get it by
putting vertices sorted by their color number.
But we could not know it since the
beginning because we didn't know the colors.
Let's implement this algorithm. We're using
backtracking, we will have a recursive function.
It attempts to color the vertex i, and it
says if yes or no a valid coloring have
been found from that direction. It takes as
parameters the graph, k the number of colors,
the list of vertices, the index of the actual
vertex, and the color map, because we need a color
map here to remember the color of each vertex.
Initially in the color map, the default value is
-1, -1 means uncolored, we need a default
value to avoid key not found errors.
Also, we won't use 'red', 'blue', 'green', to
represent colors, we will just use integers.
And we have k colors, so colors
will be labeled from 0 to k-1.
When we color the vertex i, we move to the vertex
i+1, so when i is equal to the number of vertices,
we know that we've been able to color
all vertices, we return true because
we found a valid coloring. Else,
we start trying available colors.
We will traverse the k colors, but
to know if a color is available,
we must check if a neighbor has that color or
not. So a good idea would be to identify all
used colors before we start traversing colors. For
that, we traverse neighbors of the actual vertex,
vertices[i], and put their colors in a set to
avoid duplicates and speed up search operation.
In code, we extract the color of
the neighbor for each neighbor
in graph[vertices[i]], and
we put the results in a set.
Now we can start traversing colors. Colors are
integers from 0 to k-1, we write for color in
range(k). If color is not in used, then it's
an available color, we can assign it to our
vertex and move to the next one. This is why
if the condition is true, we assign color to
color_map[vertices[i]]. And we call this function
starting from i+1, starting from the next vertex.
If the call returns true, then we found a valid
coloring from there, we also return true here,
no need to continue. And if after trying all
available colors, none of them returned true,
then we need to remove the color
and backtrack, we assign the color
-1 to the actual vertex to make it
uncolored again, and return false.
What about the is_k_colorable() function?
It takes as parameters the graph, and k,
the number of colors. We start by creating the
list of vertices. We can just take a random order,
so we just put the keys of the adjacency list as
an array. Then we create the color map, it's a
hash map with -1 as a default value. Finally,
we return the result returned by calling the
function we made, we said that it says if yes or
no we could find a valid vertex coloring. You can
see that we've put i to 0 because we want to start
from the first vertex. And we made our function.
Note that if you want the color map instead of
just yes or no, it's possible, you can call the
function to fill the color map, and return it.
For the time complexity, we have n elements,
each one of them has k possible values.
So in total, we have k^n possibilities,
we have k^|V| possible colorings, we get an
O(k^|V|) time complexity in the worst case.
Checking availability of colors reduces
the number of possibilities we try but
it can still be exponential. And
we have faster exact algorithms,
but they're still exponential, we're
dealing with an NP-complete problem.
What about the chromatic number? We said that
we can use is_k_colorable() function to find it.
Yes, we just need a function that keeps
trying values of k in an increasing way
until it finds one with which the function
returns true, it represents the smallest
value of k such that the graph is k-colorable,
it's the chromatic number. But k-colorability
is computed in exponential time, so this
function will run in exponential time.
Fortunately, there exist approximation algorithms
for coloring a graph with the smallest possible
number of colors. An approximation algorithm may
not give the most optimal answer, in other terms,
it may not color the graph with the minimum
number of colors, but at least, it's fast.
Which is useful for large graphs, we simply
cannot rely on an exponential time algorithm
for large inputs, so we may think of
sacrificing some optimization to get
the result in an acceptable time, it's better
than nothing. This is why in the next lecture,
we will learn about the greedy algorithm for
graph coloring, see you in the next lecture!