Welcome back to the course, in this lecture we
will learn about another minimum spanning tree
algorithm: Kruskal's algorithm. The algorithm
works like this: we have a connected undirected
weighted graph G, we start by sorting its edges
according to their weight in ascending order.
Then during the process, we will have multiple
trees that we will keep merging until we get
one single tree: the minimum spanning
tree. At the beginning, we didn't add
any edge to our minimum spanning tree yet,
so each vertex constitutes a tree by itself.
To better visualize, we assign
a different color to each group,
then having nodes of the same color
means that they're in the same group.
Now we start traversing edges in a sorted way.
For each edge (u,v) of weight w, if u and v are
in different groups, we add the edge (u,v) to our
minimum spanning tree and we connect the groups.
Else if they're already in the same group, we
don't add the edge because it would form a cycle.
Let's see it in practice with this
example we used in the previous lecture.
First edge is the one between H and I. H and I
are in different groups, so we add the edge to
the MST and connect their groups, we now
have a group that contains both H and I.
Next edge is between C and D. C and D are in
different groups, we add the edge and connect the
groups. Next edge, between B and D. B and D are in
groups. Next edge is between A and C. Different
groups, we add the edge and connect groups.
Next edge is between I and J. Different
groups, we add the edge and connect the groups.
Next edge is between H and J. And here,
H and J are already in the same group,
so if we add the edge, we will get a cycle.
Which is undesirable, a minimum spanning tree
doesn't contain cycles, so we just skip this edge.
Next edge is between G and H. Different
groups, we add the edge and connect groups.
Next edge is between B and C. Same group, we skip.
Next edge is between G and I. G and I are in the
same group, we just skip. Next edge is between A
and B. Same group, we skip. Then between G and E.
Different groups, we add the edge and join groups.
Then between E and F. Different groups, we add
the edge and join groups. Then between D and E.
Different groups, we add the edge and join groups.
And now our minimum spanning tree has
|V|-1 edges, so we finished making it.
Because a tree of n vertices has n-1 edges,
all remaining edges will have their incident
vertices in the same group, it's useless to
continue traversing edges, we just stop here,
you can verify by yourself. And here is
the minimum spanning tree of the graph G,
it has a total weight of 38, we cannot find
a spanning tree with a lower sum of weights.
Let's write some pseudocode. Our function
takes as parameter a graph, we assume that
it's undirected and connected. We extract the
list of vertices and the list of edges from it.
Then we sort the edges according to their weight.
After it, we create a new graph that will be
our MST, and we create a group for each vertex.
Now we can start traversing edges. For each edge
(u, v, w), if u and v don't belong to the same
group, we add an edge between u and v in the MST,
and we connect the group of u with the group of v.
Last thing to do, if the number of edges of
the MST is |V|-1, it means that we're done,
we break the loop. After the loop, we return our
MST, and this is how Kruskal's algorithm works.
And by the way, same as Prim's algorithm,
Kruskal's algorithm is also a greedy algorithm.
This is just pseudocode, we still need to discuss
how to implement it, especially this part,
create a group for each vertex, check if
u and v don't belong to the same group,
and connect their groups. We can think of having
a list of groups where each group is a set and
elements are vertices of that group. Initially
we have one group of one element for each vertex,
then to find the group of a vertex we
traverse them while checking membership,
and to connect two groups we just move
elements of one set to the other one.
But this implementation is slow, finding
the group of a vertex or connecting two
groups is done in O(|V|) time, we may need
to traverse the |V| groups. Same thing for
connecting groups of two vertices, we first need
to find their group so it's done in O(|V|) time.
To have an efficient implementation, we will use
the disjoint-set data structure. The disjoint-set
data structure, also called union-find, maintains
a collection of disjoint sets, sets that have no
intersection, no common element. And gives the
ability to add new sets, find the set to which
a given element belongs, and merge the two sets
of two given elements. Perfect for Kruskal's
algorithm, at the beginning we add a node for
each set, we can check if two nodes belong to
the same tree with the find operation, and we
can join the two trees of the two incident nodes
with the union operation, because each tree is
represented by a set whose elements are its nodes.
In this lecture, we won't discuss the
implementation of this data structure,
because it's done in detail in this YouTube
video that you should really watch, you can
consider it as a part of this course
and a prerequisite for this lecture.
As said earlier, disjoint-set has 3 operations:
make_set(x), find(x), and union(x, y).
Let's see how to implement Kruskal's algorithm
by using these operations. Our kruskal function
takes as parameters the graph. We start by
extracting vertices and edges. For vertices,
we just read the keys of the adjacency list, they
represent vertices of our graph. And for edges,
we have to traverse all the adjacency list
while adding each edge to our array of edges.
We add edges that go to unvisited vertices
only, to avoid adding a same edge twice.
After it, we sort edges according to their
weight, which is the third element of the tuple.
Now we need to create our MST
and our disjoint-set structure.
For MST, we just create an empty graph that we
will fill later. And for disjoint-set structure,
we use our DisjointSet class we made in the
YouTube lecture, by passing the list of vertices,
because we will deal with vertices in the
structure. Now we can start traversing edges,
but before, we create a variable nb_edges to
count edges we added, to know when to stop.
Then for each edge (u, v, w), we check if u and v
are in the same group. We can do so by using find
operation, if find(u) isn't equal to find(v),
it means that they're in different groups.
When it's the case, we need to
add the edge (u, v) to the MST,
increment the number of edges, connect
the two groups, and check if we're done.
To add the edge (u,v) to the MST,
we're dealing with undirected edges,
so we add v to neighbors of u, and add u to
neighbors of v. We also increment nb_edges.
And to connect group of u and group of v, we just
use union operation of the disjoint-set structure,
union(u, v). Internally, this operation will
find the representative vertex of the set of u,
same thing for v, and it connects them by adding
a link, watch the lecture to better understand.
Last thing, if the number of edges is equal to
the number of vertices - 1, we break the loop,
it means that we're done. After the loop, we
return mst, the result we're searching for.
And we implemented Kruskal's algorithm.
Last thing to discuss, time complexity.
Extracting vertices costs |V|, the number
of vertices. Extracting edges costs |V|+|E|
because we traverse all the adjacency list.
Sorting the edges costs |E|log|E|, because
a generic sorting algorithm runs in O(nlogn)
time for n elements, and we're sorting
|E| elements, the number of edges.
Cost of creating the disjoint-set structure
is linear to the number of elements we put,
and here we're putting the vertices, we
have |V| vertices, so the cost is |V|.
Now we traverse edges, we have a loop
that does at most |E| iterations.
Inside it, we have find and union operations. With
an optimized disjoint-set implementation, their
amortized cost is O(α(n)), where n is the number
of elements in the disjoint-set, and α is the
extremely slow-growing inverse Ackermann function.
Here n is |V|, so we have O(α(|V|)). In total,
we have |V|+|V|+|E|+|E|log|E|+|V|+2|E|α(|V|),
which is 3|V|+|E|+|E|log|E|+2|E|α(|V|).
We have a connected graph, so |E| is at
least |V|-1, we can ignore the 3|V| term.
|E|log|E| is greater than
|E| so we can ignore |E|.
And log|E| is greater than α(|V|), so |E|log|E| is
greater than |E|α(|V|), we can ignore 2|E|α(|V|).
We get an O(|E|log|E|) time complexity.
And in a simple graph like this one,
|E| <= |V|², so log(|E|) is smaller than
log(|V|²), so log(|E|) is smaller than 2log(|V|).
This is why we can replace log(|E|) by log(|V|)
and get a time complexity of O(|E|log|V|).
Now we've seen how Kruskal's algorithm works, an
example, an implementation, and time complexity,
we're ready to move to something else.
Last question, what if the given graph G
is disconnected? In that case, we cannot
have a minimum spanning tree. However,
we can have a minimum spanning forest, we just
take each connected component of G and apply
an MST algorithm on it. Joining MSTs we get,
we can form the minimum spanning forest of G.
You will find the corresponding code for
this operation attached to this lecture.
We've reached the end of this lecture,
I hope that you understood Kruskal's
algorithm, if you didn't, you can ask me
questions. See you in the next lecture.