Welcome back to the course, in this lecture,
we will study the second traversal algorithm
of this chapter: breadth-first search. Let's
take back our missions example. We started
at mission A, we finished it, then it unlocked
3 new missions B C and D. After it we went
to B, we unlocked E and F. In depth-first
search, we've put remaining missions of A
on hold, which are C and D, we decided to
not go to them until we finish all the part
of the graph by going from B, in other words
we kept going deeper and we didn't go back
until we finished our work. But what if we
adopt a new strategy, after completing B,
instead of going to unlocked missions of B,
we just write them somewhere and we continue
unlocked missions of A. So we store E and
F, and we go to the next mission unlocked
by A, which is C. Same thing again, we just
remember unlocked missions, none in this case,
and we continue. Next mission is D, it unlocks
3 new missions H I and J, we remember them.
And now what's the next mission? Take some
seconds to think. The next mission is E, because
now that we finished missions of A, we can
move to missions of B. We go to E, it unlocks
K, we remember it. Next mission is F, it unlocks
L, we remember it. Basically we're just following
the chronological order of missions we were
remembering, so the next one is H. We go to
it, and it doesn't unlock new missions, we
just have no new thing to remember, remembering
means that we need to go to it after finishing
missions that come before it. Next mission
is I. It unlocks D, J, and O, but D and J
have already been unlocked before, so the
only new mission is O, we remember it. Next
mission is J, and it unlocks no new missions.
Next mission is K, it unlocks P as a new mission,
we remember it. Next mission is L, it unlocks
two new missions Q and R that we remember.
Next mission is O, it doesn't unlock new missions.
Next mission is P, no new missions. And same
thing for Q, then for R. We don't have unlocked
missions to complete anymore, we finished
traversing the graph. Okay what just happened
here? This technique of traversing is called
breadth-first search, instead of going deep
into one path, we decide to traverse the graph
level by level. Which is what happened here,
at the first level we had A, then in the next
level we had B C and D, then in the next level
we had E F H I J, then K L O, then finally
P Q R. And it's the idea of breadth-first
search, we don't move to the next level until
we finish traversing all vertices of the actual
level. And to be able to do so, when being
on a vertex, instead of directly going to
its neighbors, we just remember unvisited
ones to be able to go back to them later,
once we finish vertices of the actual level.
And remembering is important, because the
structure determines the chronological order
of elements we still need to traverse, but
it also saves their reference. And having
their reference is crucial, for example here
we went from D to E, which would not be possible
without having the reference of E, you can
see that there is no edge from D to E, so
we need to have the reference of E somewhere
else to be able to jump. In brief, for example
for missions, at the beginning we have only
one unlocked mission, the mission A. After
completing it, we unlock three new missions
B C and D. And we follow this order, B, C,
D, so we start with B. B unlocks new missions
E and F, but as said earlier, we don't go
to them, we just remember them. And to remember
them, we put them at the end of the list of
missions that we remembered before, in our
case C and D. Etcetera etcetera until this
structure becomes empty. By the way, what
structure do we use? You can see that to remember
a mission, we're putting it at the end of
the structure, and the next mission to be
done is extracted from the beginning of the
structure. Basically this structure is organizing
items in chronological order, the first element
that comes in is the first one that goes out,
in other words, the first mission that gets
remembered is the first mission that gets
completed. And what structure works on First
In First Out principle? It's the queue. Because
yes, we're kinda using a queue here, new missions
that enter the structure have to wait until
missions that are already there get completed
before their turn comes, like a real life
queue. Now we've seen how does breadth-first
search work, we've discussed what structure
to use, let's try to write some pseudocode.
Our function needs the initial mission, 'A'
in our example, and the set of visited missions.
Inside the function, we've seen that we need
a queue where we put unlocked missions that
we didn't complete yet. Initially, the only
unlocked mission is the one from where we
start, we directly put it in the queue. And
here we consider the mission as visited as
soon as it enters the queue, even if it's
still not its turn. The reason behind it is
to avoid enqueuing it again. This is why we
put our initial mission as visited. Now we
can start working, we said that we keep looping
while we still have unlocked missions that
we didn't complete yet. We write, while the
queue is not empty. Inside the loop, we extract
a mission, the mission that we will complete
next, for that we just pop from the queue.
We complete the mission, then we need to enqueue
new missions it unlocks. For that, for each
mission it unlocks, we first make sure that
it's not visited, to avoid enqueuing the same
mission more than once. If it's not visited,
we just enqueue it, and we put it in visited,
remember that we consider a mission as visited
as soon as it enters the queue, not until
it gets popped. And we're done, this loop
will perform the process we've seen in the
example, we pop a mission, we complete it,
and we remember new missions that we didn't
unlock before. Let's try to write the pseudocode
with general terms now, not missions. We have
as parameters the graph, the initial vertex,
and the set of visited vertices. We create
the queue where we put the vertex. We set
our vertex as visited. Then while the queue
is not empty, we pop a vertex, we process
it, we can print it for example, then for
each neighbor, if the neighbor is not visited,
we enqueue it, and we put it in visited. That's
it. Once again, if you still can't grasp the
concept of breadth-first search and want to
visualize more examples, I made a code that
generates a random graph then shows you the
execution step by step, you can run it as
much as you want. Let's try to implement this
pseudocode in Python now. Here also, the way
we implement a graph matters, the code will
differ depending on if we use an adjacency
list or an adjacency matrix. But the difference
will be when traversing neighbors only, as
with depth-first search. With an adjacency
list, we have a function bfs that takes as
parameters the graph, the initial vertex,
and the visited set. Inside the function,
we create a queue, we put the initial vertex
in it, we put the initial vertex in visited,
and we start looping. While the queue isn't
empty, we pop a vertex, we print it, then
for each neighbor, we first check if it's
not visited. If neighbor not in visited, we
put it in the queue, and we add it to the
visited set, that's it. And you already know
that to visit neighbors of a vertex in an
adjacency list, we just traverse the array
at key vertex. And for an adjacency matrix,
same code, the only thing that changes is
the way we traverse neighbors, which is done
by using the function we talked about previously.
Now remember that in dfs, we had the problem
of the possibility of not traversing the whole
graph with one dfs call. And it's the same
thing with bfs, if we have this graph for
example and we call bfs on A, some vertices
will be visited but not all of them, because
not all vertices are reachable by A. Once
again, we call bfs on every unvisited vertex.
In code, for each vertex, if it's not visited,
we call bfs on it. Next we have time and space
complexity. For the time complexity, we first
have the cost of traversing the vertices.
We have |V| vertices so the cost is |V|. We
also have the cost of the while loop. Remember
that each vertex enters the queue only once,
so in total, |V| elements will have been in
the queue. And at each iteration, one element
is popped from the queue. We deduce that the
total number of iterations of the while loop,
in all calls, is |V|, each vertex causes one
more iteration. But what's happening inside
an iteration? We are popping from the queue,
costs O(1) time, then we're traversing neighbors
of the popped vertex, whose the cost is the
degree of that vertex with an adjacency list.
When calculating the time cost of a loop,
if the cost of one iteration remains the same,
we just multiply it by the number of iterations.
Which is not the case here, here the cost
of one iteration depends on the degree of
the popped vertex. And we have one iteration
per vertex, so to get the cost, we just do
the sum of degrees of vertices. And we know
that the sum of degrees of vertices is |E|
if the graph is directed or 2|E| if the graph
is undirected. In total, we have |V|+|E| or
2|E|. In both cases, we get O(|V|+|E|), the
time complexity of breadth-first search with
an adjacency list is O(|V|+|E|), same as depth-first
search. And with an adjacency matrix, the
difference is that traversing vertices costs
O(|V|), because we traverse the whole row.
So for the while loop, we have |V| iterations,
each one of them costs |V|, the cost is |V|².
In total, we have |V|+|V|², which gives O(|V|²),
we get a time complexity of O(|V|²) for breadth-first
search with an adjacency matrix. And for the
space complexity, vertices are going in and
out of the queue, so we need to find what's
the maximum number of vertices that can be
in the queue at the same time, to be able
to measure its extra space. In the worst case,
in the queue we can have |V|-1 vertices at
the same time. It occurs when we have a star
graph and we launch bfs from the center vertex.
What happens is that at the beginning we have
only one vertex in the queue, the one from
where we start. We pop it, we process it,
then we enqueue its unvisited neighbors. And
here this center vertex has |V|-1 unvisited
neighbors, they all get added to the queue.
This is why, the size of the queue becomes
|V|-1. And in bfs we also have the set of
visited vertices, which holds all the vertices
at the end, |V|. In total, we have |V|+|V|-1,
which gives 2|V|-1, which gives O(|V|), the
space complexity of breadth-first search is
O(|V|), either for adjacency list or for adjacency
matrix. Now we know about depth-first search,
we know about breadth-first search, but, which
one is better? Which one should we use? Well,
each one has its pros and cons, so it depends
on the problem. For example dfs has an advantage
over bfs when the vertex we're searching for
is probably deep, in other words, in the last
levels of the graph. Why? Because dfs goes
to deep levels frequently, while bfs needs
to traverse all previous levels before reaching
deep ones. And the opposite holds, bfs is
more adapted to search for vertices that are
in shallow levels of the graph, not too far
from the starting point, because shallows
levels are traversed before deep ones. Also,
dfs is good when we want to explore paths
one by one. While bfs works on multiple paths
at once edge by edge, it incrementally builds
multiple paths at once. Another thing, bfs
has an advantage when we want to go from a
vertex to another with the fewest possible
number of edges, when launching bfs from u
and it gets to v, it's guaranteed that bfs
used the least possible amount of edges. Unlike
dfs, it's not guaranteed with dfs. In next
lectures will use them to develop algorithms
and solve problems, which can give you a better
understanding of dfs and bfs and their differences.
See you in the next lecture!