In the previous lecture, we discussed the
greedy coloring algorithm. One of the elements
that was impacting the result is the order of
traversal, at least for non well-colored graphs.
So choosing the order is an important
step, and we may have better ways to
do so than choosing it randomly.
Today we will see two heuristics.
The first one we will discuss is the Welsh-Powell
heuristic. The way it works is simple,
we start by sorting vertices according to their
degrees in decreasing order. Then while we still
have uncolored vertices, we take a new color
c, we traverse vertices in the sorted order,
and we color vertices that are uncolored,
and not adjacent to a vertex colored with c.
Let's take the example we've
been working with to understand.
Here's the degree of each vertex. We sort
them in decreasing order, we get EAHBDFGIC.
We can start working. Let's take a first
color, 0, let's say red for the visualization.
Now we traverse vertices in the sorted order
and see what vertices do we color in red.
E, it's uncolored, and has no neighbors
colored with red, so we color it with red.
Then A, it's uncolored but it's adjacent
to a red vertex, E, so we don't color it,
we cannot have two neighbors with the same
color. Then H, uncolored and no red neighbors,
we color it with red. Then B, adjacent to the red
vertex E, we skip. Then D, also adjacent to a red
vertex, E, we skip. Then F, adjacent to E, we
skip. Then G, same thing. Then I, same thing.
Then C, uncolored and not adjacent to
a red vertex, we color it with red.
We finished traversing the order, but we still
have uncolored vertices, so we start over
with the next color, 1, let's say blue for the
visualization. E, already colored. A, uncolored
and not adjacent to a blue vertex, we color it
with blue. Then H, colored. Then B, adjacent to
a blue vertex, we skip. Then D, uncolored and not
adjacent to a blue vertex, we color it with blue.
Then F, adjacent to A which is blue. Then G,
adjacent to D which is blue. Then I, uncolored and
no blue neighbors, we color it with blue. Then
C, already colored. We finished the traversal but
we still have uncolored vertices, we start over
with the next color which is 2, let's say green.
E, already colored. A, already colored. H, already
colored. B, uncolored and not adjacent to a green
vertex, we color it with green. Then D, colored.
Then F, it respects conditions, we color it with
green. Then G, same thing, we color it with green.
Then I, already colored. And C, already colored.
We finished the traversal and all vertices
are colored, so the algorithm stops,
and we got this coloring, by
using the Welsh-Powell heuristic.
And you can see that this time we
got the optimal number of colors, 3,
unlike the classic greedy algorithm we've seen
in the previous lecture, which used 4 colors.
For the implementation, we start by creating
the list of vertices. But this time we sort it
in decreasing order according to the degree of
vertices. This is why we put as key the degree
of the vertex, which is the length of its
array of neighbors in the adjacency list,
and we set reverse to true to get the result in
decreasing order. Then we create a color map.
We also create our first color, 0. Now while
color map has less keys than the adjacency list,
it means that we didn't color all vertices,
some of them are missing from the color map.
What do we do? We start traversing
vertices in the sorted order. For
each one of them, two conditions to
check before assigning color to it:
First condition, being uncolored, vertex
not in color_map, and second condition,
all its neighbors must not have the current color,
we check that all neighbors are either uncolored,
or have a color that is different from the
current color. In Python we do can do that
with list comprehension and all function, we
calculate the boolean expression on each neighbor,
we get an array of boolean values as a result,
and we check that all of them are true,
that all neighbors respect the condition of
being uncolored or having a different color.
If both conditions are respected for the current
vertex, we assign the current color to it.
After we finish traversing the vertices,
we increment color for the next iteration.
And after we finish the while loop, all
vertices are colored, we return the color map.
And we got the implementation.
For the time complexity, sorting
n elements costs O(nlogn) time,
and here n is the number of vertices, we have
O(|V|log|V|). Then we have a while loop that
does an iteration for each used color, we can say
that it does c iterations, where c is the total
number of colors used by the algorithm. Inside
it we're traversing vertices, |V| iterations.
For each one of them we're traversing neighbors,
the cost is deg(u). So in total we have
|V|log|V| + c(|V|+sum of degrees of vertices). The
sum of degrees for an undirected graph is 2|E|,
we get |V|log|V| + c(|V|+2|E|), it gives an
O(|V|log|V|+c(|V|+|E|)) time complexity. At
least for my implementation, there may exist other
implementations with a different time complexity.
For the efficiency, the Welsh-Powell heuristic
uses at most this amount of colors, the maximum
among the minimum between the degree of
the vertex i + 1 and i for each value i.
Which is usually better than
the plain greedy algorithm.
But we have heuristics that give better results,
we will now discuss another one. Another
heuristic for greedy coloring is DSatur.
In Welsh-Powell, the ordering was depending
on the degree of vertices, in DSatur,
it mostly depends on their degree of saturation,
hence the name DSatur, degree of saturation.
The degree of saturation of a vertex is
the number of colors used by its neighbors,
for example the saturation of this vertex B is 2.
And we will traverse vertices according to
their degree of saturation, in decreasing order.
And if two vertices have the same saturation,
we choose the one with the highest degree.
One difference however, it's that degrees
of vertices is known since the beginning,
we just need to sort vertices and start working.
While the saturation of a vertex is dynamic,
at the beginning it's 0 because all vertices
are uncolored, and it keeps changing during
the process. Which means that we cannot know
the ordering since the beginning. Instead,
we keep track of the saturation of each vertex,
and at each iteration, to get the next vertex
to visit, we extract the unvisited vertex with
the highest saturation. And we apply the same
process as classic greedy algorithm, we
search for the first available color.
Let's apply it with our example. At the
beginning, saturation of all vertices is 0,
we didn't start coloring, the
comparison will be done on degrees.
E has the highest degree, 6, we choose it.
The smallest available color is 0. And now,
we need to update saturation of all its neighbors,
because they potentially have a new color.
Its neighbors are A B F D G I. They all got a new
neighbor color, their saturation increases by 1.
Next iteration, among uncolored vertices, the
highest saturation is 1. But we have multiple
vertices with a saturation of 1, we take the
one with the highest degree, the vertex A.
We cannot color it with 0 because it's used
by its neighbor, E, so we add a new color 1.
And we update saturation of
neighbors, which are B C E F H.
They all got a new neighbor color,
we increment their saturation.
Next iteration, highest saturation is 2, for
both B and F. To decide between them, we check
their degree. Their degree is also the same,
3, then we just choose randomly, let's take F.
Color 0 is used by E, 1 is
used by A, so we take 2.
Its neighbors are A E and I, they all got a new
neighbor color, we increment their saturation.
Next iteration, we have the same scenario,
highest saturation is 2, both B and I,
and their degrees are also the same. Let's
choose I. Color 0 is used, but not 1, we take 1.
Its neighbors are E F and H, but they all
already have color 1 as a neighbor color,
so their saturation doesn't increase.
Next iteration, highest saturation is 2, for
the vertex B only, no hesitation, we take it.
0 and 1 are used, but not 2, we take 2. Its
neighbors are A E and C, let's see which one
didn't have 2 as a neighbor color. A already has 2
as a neighbor color, we don't increase saturation.
Same thing for E. But for C, it didn't have
2 as neighbor color until now, so we increase
its saturation. Next iteration, C has the highest
saturation, we take it. 0 is available, we color
it with the color 0. Both of its neighbors already
had 0 as a neighbor color, we don't increment.
Next iteration, all vertices have
saturation of 1, so we check degree.
Highest degree is the degree
of the vertex H, we take it.
0 is available, we take it. All its
neighbors already have 0 as a neighbor color.
Next iteration, two vertices remaining, same
saturation and same degree, we choose randomly,
let's take G. 0 is used but we can color it with
1. E and H already had 1 as a neighbor color,
but not D, we increment saturation of D. Last
iteration, only one vertex left, D, we take it.
0 and 1 are used, we can color it with 2.
And the saturation of G and H gets increased.
We colored all vertices, we finished the process.
And you can see that we used 3 colors only instead
of 4 like with standard greedy coloring. We even
got the optimal result, 3 is the minimum number
of colors that can be used. With this example you
could perceive the impact of the ordering we use,
by just changing the way we traverse
vertices, we obtained a better result.
What about the implementation? What we need to do
is to keep track of the saturation of each vertex,
and at each iteration, we extract the uncolored
vertex with the highest saturation. If we have
more than one such a vertex, we take the
one with the highest degree among them.
And the suitable structure for this kind of
operation is obviously the priority queue, each
element in the queue is a vertex, its priority
key is its saturation followed by its degree.
And at each iteration, we extract the one
with the maximum priority, it will be the next
vertex to color. And after coloring, we traverse
neighbors to find ones whose saturation increases,
to update their keys in the priority queue. So we
need 3 operations for our priority queue, insert,
to insert our vertices in the queue, extract,
to extract the vertex with the highest priority,
and decrease key, to update the priority
of a vertex. We could simply use an array,
inserting would be in O(1), extracting a vertex
would be in O(|V|), and updating key in O(1).
But a better implementation choice would be
the Fibonacci heap, insertion is in O(1) time,
extraction is in O(logn) amortized time,
and decrease key is in O(1) amortized time.
Before we start implementing, we need
to discuss what key we gonna use,
because as you may know nodes in a heap
are compared according to their key.
At each iteration, the next vertex to color is
the unvisited vertex with the highest saturation,
if there are ties, we take the one with
the highest degree. So the key would be the
2-tuple (saturation, degree), because 2-tuples are
compared this way: The first value is compared,
if they're equal, then the second value
is compared, which is what we want.
But, a Fibonacci heap, at least in the
library we're using, offers a min-heap only,
extracting operation gives us the node with the
minimum key. It was suitable for Dijkstra's and
Prim's algorithm because we wanted the node
with the minimum key, the minimum distance,
but in this one, we want the node with the
maximum key, the maximum saturation or degree.
To counter this, we will switch the sign to use
negative values, because given a list of values,
the greatest value among them is the smallest
value when using their negative form. So the node
with the highest saturation is considered the one
with the minimum key, the one that gets extracted.
Also, for saturation, we need the number of
neighbor colors. Instead of always counting again,
we keep track of the colors used by neighbors of
each vertex, in a set to avoid duplicates. And to
get the saturation of a vertex, we just get the
cardinality of its set, its number of elements.
Let's start implementing.
We first need a color map.
We also need to keep track of the set of adjacent
colors of each vertex, so we create a hash table
neighborhood_colors that maps a vertex to the
set of colors present in its neighborhood.
We also need a priority queue, of type Fibonacci
heap. And we need to have the reference of the
node of each vertex to be able to update key, this
is why we need nodes map, we will map each vertex
label to its node in the Fibonacci heap, same as
in Dijkstra and Prim. Next step, creating a node
for each vertex and inserting it. For each vertex,
we create a node. Its key will contain 3 things,
-saturation, initially 0, -degree, the
number of its neighbors in negative form,
and the name of the vertex, we need to know what
vertex we're working on when extracting a vertex.
We assign it to the vertex in the nodes map and we
insert it in the Fibonacci heap. Now we can start
working, we keep looping while the queue still has
elements. We start by extracting the next vertex.
We get a node as a result, which has a key made
of 3 elements, the third one is the vertex label,
we save it in u to know which vertex we're
working with. Then we need the colors used
by its neighbors. Fortunately, we already have the
adjacent colors map, we don't need to search for
them again. So we search for the first available
color as we did, we start from 0 and keep
iterating until we find one that is not in its
neighborhood and we assign it to color[vertex].
Last step we need to do in the iteration,
we need to update the keys of its neighbors,
for each neighbor, we add its color to adjacent
colors of the neighbor. The good thing is that
if it was already in the set, nothing
will change, the set avoids duplicates.
Also, the saturation of the neighbor may have
changed, we update the key in the priority queue.
Only uncolored vertices are still in the queue, so
we first make sure that the neighbor is uncolored,
by checking if its not in color map. If it's not
the case, we update its key. The saturation is the
length of its set of neighborhood colors. Now we
get its node from nodes map, and for the new key,
it's the saturation in negative form, the
degree in negative form, and the vertex name.
After the loop, all vertices are
colored, we return the color map,
and we implemented DSatur
by using a Fibonacci heap.
For the time complexity, we have |V| for creating
the adjacent colors map. Then |V| for creating a
node for each vertex and inserting it. Then we
have a loop that does |V| iterations. The queue
is storing vertices, and we have |V| vertices,
so extracting costs O(log|V|) amortized time.
We also have finding the color, which costs
deg(u) because a vertex has at most deg(u)
adjacent colors. Then traversing
the neighbors of the actual vertex,
deg(u) iterations, and decrease key in a
Fibonacci heap runs in O(1) amortized time.
The total is |V| + |V|log|V| + twice
the sum of degrees of vertices.
Remember that when we have a loop that traverses
all the vertices and the cost of an iteration is
the degree of that vertex, then the total cost is
the sum of degrees, which is 2|E| in undirected
graphs when using an adjacency list. We replace
and we get |V| + |V|log|V| + 4|E|, which is in
O(|E|+|V|log|V|), we got an O(|E|+|V|log|V|)
time complexity for this implementation.
For efficiency, DSatur usually gives similar or
better results than Welsh-Powell, and it's quite
time efficient. It also guarantees the optimal
result for bipartite, cycle, and wheel graphs.
Now we've seen two heuristics for graph coloring,
there exist other ones obviously, like RLF,
recursive largest first, which gives good
results, but it won't be covered in this lecture.
We've reached the end of this lecture, I
hope that you understood both heuristics,
if you didn't, you can ask questions.
See you in the next lecture.