Imagine that you're playing a platform game where
there are locations that you can move to through
kind of bridges. Each of these locations contains
a key, collecting a key increases your score by 1.
But, once you step on a location, it falls a
few seconds later so you cannot go back to it.
This game can be represented with a graph,
locations are vertices, and bridges are edges.
Obviously, you want to maximize your score, you
want to traverse all locations to collect all
keys and go back to your initial point.
But each location can be traversed only
once because it falls a few seconds later.
So starting from the level's entry point,
you want to find a way to traverse all locations
exactly once and go back to the entry point.
In graph theory terms, starting from a vertex
start, you want to find a path that traverses all
vertices exactly once and goes back to start. And
this is what we will learn to do in this lecture,
get ready to learn about Hamiltonian paths
and Hamiltonian cycles. In previous lectures,
we learnt about Eulerian trails and circuits,
a Eulerian trail is a trail that visits each
edge exactly once, and same thing for Eulerian
circuits but it must return to the initial vertex.
But what if instead of edges, we wanted to
traverse each vertex once, we want a trail
that traverses each vertex once. Such a trail is
called a Hamiltonian path, a Hamiltonian path is
a path that traverses each vertex exactly once.
Same logic for Hamiltonian cycle, a Hamiltonian
cycle is a path that traverses each vertex
exactly once and goes back to the initial vertex.
Here is an example, we have this graph, and here
is a Hamiltonian cycle, you can see that it starts
from A, it traverses every vertex exactly once,
and goes back to A. You can also see that some
edges have not been traversed, but it's not
a problem, the condition is on vertices only.
And for Hamiltonian path, here is an example, we
kept the same graph and cycle and just removed
the last edge, we got a path that starts from
a vertex, traverses every vertex exactly once.
In previous lectures we had
semi-Eulerian and Eulerian graphs,
here we have semi-Hamiltonian and Hamiltonian
graphs. The definition should be easy to guess,
a semi-Hamiltonian graph is a graph
that contains a Hamiltonian path,
and a Hamiltonian graph is a graph
that contains a Hamiltonian cycle.
Note that Hamiltonian paths and cycles can
be present in both directed and undirected
graphs. In directed graphs, the Hamiltonian
paths and cycles must obviously be directed,
we must be able to traverse each vertex
exactly once by considering direction of edges.
For Eulerian trails and circuits, we could
know about their existence by checking simple
conditions, which can be done in linear time. We
can even find one in linear time, by using the
algorithm we learnt about. But, is it the case for
Hamiltonian paths and cycles? Definitely not. The
problem of finding a Hamiltonian path in a graph
is NP-complete, which means that exact algorithms
we currently know to solve it are in exponential
time, we will see one in the next lecture.
Even for knowing if a Hamiltonian
path or cycle exists in a graph,
we may need to actually search for it,
which is in exponential time. I mean,
there are some conditions to say that a
graph is Hamiltonian, but it's not enough.
For example we have Dirac's theorem, it says that
given a graph G, if every vertex has a degree of
at least n/2 where n is the number of vertices of
G, then G is Hamiltonian. This condition can be
easily verified in linear time, and if it's true
then the graph is Hamiltonian. But, if it's false,
it doesn't mean that the graph is not Hamiltonian,
this is why I told you that it's not enough.
Let me show you an example. We have this graph of
6 vertices. Here are degrees of its vertices. All
of them are at least n/2, so by using Dirac's
theorem, we can say that G is Hamiltonian,
which is true, here is a Hamiltonian cycle. Now
let's take this other graph. Not all degrees of
vertices are at least n/2, but it's still
Hamiltonian, here is a Hamiltonian cycle.
In brief, when all degrees are at least n/2,
we know that it's Hamiltonian, but when the
condition is false, we don't know, it can be
Hamiltonian just as it can not be Hamiltonian.
It's different from Eulerian graph where
if the two conditions are respected,
we know that it's Eulerian, and if it's not
the case, we know that it's NOT Eulerian.
We can even find conditions to say that the graph
is not Hamiltonian, for example when a graph has
isolated vertices, then we cannot reach them,
while the Hamiltonian cycle must pass from all
vertices, we deduce that it's not Hamiltonian.
But it doesn't mean than a graph with no isolated
vertices is Hamiltonian, we don't know. And
this is why I told you that it's not enough,
probably the only way of truly knowing if a
graph is Hamiltonian or not is by searching
for a Hamiltonian cycle, which takes exponential
time. Hence, the problem of just knowing if a
graph is Hamiltonian also takes exponential
time. We've reached the end of this lecture
where we learnt about Hamiltonian paths and
Hamiltonian cycles. See you in the next one.