Welcome to this lecture where we will learn to
find a Hamiltonian circuit in a graph by using
backtracking. The process is simple, we start
from a vertex, and we keep trying paths and see
if one of them leads to completing a Hamiltonian
cycle. If the path we're building gets stuck,
we backtrack and try something else. If all
possibilities don't lead to completing a
Hamiltonian cycle, then we have no such a cycle in
the graph. This process is quite simple but lacks
explanation, we need to explain some steps more
in detail to have a clear idea on how it works.
We have to explain what do we mean by start from
a vertex, trying paths, completing Hamiltonian
cycle, gets stuck, backtrack, try something else,
all possibilities don't lead. Let's explain all
of these. Start from a vertex, we know what
does it mean but what vertex to start from?
If a graph contains a Hamiltonian cycle starting
from a vertex, then we can get a Hamiltonian cycle
by starting from any other vertex. For example if
we have the cycle A B C E F D A, then we can just
kinda rotate the path and start from B, we get B C
E F D A B. We rotate it again and get C E F D A B
C. We deduce that it doesn't matter from where
we start, we just choose an arbitrary vertex.
Next thing to explain, trying paths. We try
a path by choosing a neighbor to continue
from and remembering vertices we're adding
to the path, and see what result it gives.
Completing Hamiltonian cycle, we complete a
Hamiltonian cycle by adding the final edge.
To know that we can add the final edge
from the actual vertex, two conditions:
All vertices must be present in the path we're
building, and there must be an edge from the
actual vertex, which is the last vertex we added
to the path, p_n-1, to the start vertex, which is
the first vertex we added to the path, p0. Both
of these conditions are necessary as you can see.
Next term, gets stuck. Remember than we cannot
go back to a vertex that is already in the path,
so when extending the actual path, when moving to
a neighbor, we must verify that we didn't visit
it yet. So if a vertex can only go to visited
vertices and has no final edge, then we're stuck,
we cannot continue. Backtrack, we backtrack by
going to the previous call, for example if F
calls E, we do some work on E, then we backtrack
to F, we go back to the call that called F.
It's what always happens in dfs, every
time we finish a recursive dfs call,
it goes back to the previous call by checking
the call stack, to finish remaining instructions.
Try something else, it means, now that we've
seen that the neighbor we went from didn't
lead to a cycle, we move to the next unvisited
neighbor and go from there to see if this time
we find a positive result. Last term, all
possibilities don't lead. It happens when
all neighbors of the start vertex don't lead to
a valid cycle, when the initial call ends without
returning a positive result before, we deduce
that there is no Hamiltonian cycle in the graph.
Let's see how the process really works with an
example. We can start from any vertex so let's
start from A, we add it to our path. We can go to
B, C, and D, because all of them are unvisited.
Let's go to B, and we add it to the path. From
B we can go to A, but it's already in the path.
Let's go to C instead, it's not in the path. We
add it to the path. From C we have A, in path, B,
in path, D, not in path, we go to it and we add to
the path. From D we have A, in path, C, in path,
E, not in path, we go. From E we have B, in path,
C, in path, D, in path, F, not in path, we go.
From F, we have C, D, and E, and they're all
in path, and we don't have an edge to finish
the cycle, so we're stuck, we cannot continue,
we need to backtrack and try something else.
Important thing, we need to remove F from the path
before we backtrack, it's no longer in the path.
Back to E, we tried all not in path neighbors and
we didn't get a positive result, so we're stuck,
we remove E and we backtrack. Back to D,
we try the next not in path neighbor, F.
From F we can only go to E. From E, all neighbors
are in path, and we cannot finish the cycle
because we don't have an edge to A, so we're
stuck. Back to F, we're also stuck, nowhere to go.
We backtrack to D, also stuck, we tried
all not in path neighbors, we backtrack.
Back to C, D didn't give a positive result
so we try something else, we go to E instead.
From E we can go to D. From D we can only go to F.
But we cannot continue from F, we backtrack to D.
From D same thing, we backtrack to E. Now from E
we try F. From F we can only go to D. And from D,
we don't have a neighbor not in path, but,
all vertices are in the path and we have an
edge to A, so we close the cycle, we found
a Hamiltonian cycle, by using backtracking.
Let's implement this process. Our dfs
function needs as parameters the graph,
the actual vertex, the path, which is an array
that contains vertices we visited in order.
And because we will check if a vertex is in the
path, instead of performing a linear search on
the path array, which is in O(n), we use a
set in_path that contains vertices that are
in the path, which allows searching in O(1)
in average. At the beginning of the function,
we add our vertex to the path from the
end, and we also add it to the in_path set.
Now we start traversing outgoing edges of
the actual vertex, to traverse neighbors.
We have three cases for an edge. First case, it's
the final edge, it happens when all vertices are
in the path and the destination of that
edge is the start vertex. In that case,
we found a Hamiltonian cycle, so we add the start
vertex again to the path and we return the path.
We do so because the path of a Hamiltonian
cycle starts and ends at the same vertex,
we must add the start vertex again to close
the cycle. Second case, the destination vertex,
the neighbor, is not in the path yet. In that
case, we go to it with a dfs call as usual,
and see if it returns a positive result. Third
case, when both of these conditions are false,
then we have nothing to do with the
actual edge, we just move to the next one.
In code, for the first case, we write, if the
length of the path is equal to the number of
vertices, and neighbor is the start vertex,
that we can find at the first cell of the path.
If it's the case, we add start vertex
to the path, and we return the path.
Else if neighbor is not in in_path, we're in
the second case. We go to it with a dfs call
and store the result in a variable.
If the returned result is not null,
then we found a cycle, we return it to stop
here and avoid touching the path again.
We don't need to handle the third case because
nothing happens. And if all edges don't lead to
a Hamiltonian cycle, we need to backtrack, but
before, we pop the last element from the path to
remove the actual vertex, we remove the actual
vertex from in_path set, and we return null.
Now in the main hamiltonian_cycle
function, we take as parameter a graph,
and we choose an arbitrary vertex as start vertex.
We also create an array path and a set in_path.
And we return the result given by the function we
just made, it will do all the work. And we solved
the Hamiltonian cycle problem with backtracking.
But, as said earlier, exact algorithms
for this problem are in exponential time,
and this one is not an exception, it
has an O(n!) time complexity, too slow.
We can optimize it a little bit with dynamic
programming, we get O(n²*2^n) time, but it's still
exponential. However, even if it's exponential,
it remains a solution that we can use at least
with small instances, like with our game, games
like this usually don't have a lot of locations
in a single level. So we just build the graph, and
run our algorithm starting from the entry point,
we get a path that we can take to collect all keys
and go back, if it's possible obviously. We've
reached the end of this lecture, where we learnt
about how to find a Hamiltonian cycle in a graph
by using backtracking, I hope that you understood
the whole process. See you in the next lecture!