With all algorithms we've seen in this chapter,
we worked with weighted graphs. So we may ask
ourselves, what if the graph is unweighted?
We defined the shortest path problem as the
problem of finding the shortest path between
two vertices, where the shortest path is the
one with the smallest sum of weights of edges.
But with an unweighted graph, we have
no notion of weight, so how can we find
the shortest path? How can we compare paths to
take the shortest one? In an unweighted graph,
we can define the shortest path as the path with
the fewest number of edges, so in this graph,
the shortest path from A to K is this one, it
has only 3 edges while other ones have more.
Okay but how to find that path? We can think
of an unweighted graph as a special case of
a weighted graph where the value of all edges
is 1, because moving a vertex to another has
a weight of 1, we're adding 1 edge to
our path. If we think of it like that,
what we can do is to convert our unweighted graph
to a weighted graph by putting 1 in all edges,
and we use algorithms we've studied before.
We can for example use Dijkstra's algorithm,
as it's fast and here all edges have a
non-negative weight so it's safe to use it. We
would get a time complexity of O(|E|+|V|log|V|),
the time complexity of using Dijkstra's algorithm.
But with an unweighted graph, to find
the shortest path, we can use a faster
and simpler algorithm. It's an algorithm that
we studied before, it's breadth-first search.
The reason behind it is that BFS starts by
traversing vertices that are 0 edges away from the
source, then vertices that are 1 edge away, then
those that are 2 edges away, then 3 edges away,
and so on, breadth-first search traverses level
by level. It means that once we reach a vertex,
we're sure that we used as few edges as possible
to reach it, hence, we found the shortest path.
We did something similar in the BFS practice
lecture, we were searching for the fewest number
of edges to go from source to destination,
and return -1 if not possible. But here we
want to also get the path and not just the
distance, for every vertex not just for one.
For that, we will also use a table dist
and a table prev, dist[v] represents
the minimum number of edges to reach v, and
prev[v] represents the previous vertex of v.
With this graph, we create dist and prev,
the queue, the visited set, and we start.
The queue and the visited set initially
contain the source vertex, A in this example.
But in this problem we need
the vertex, but also its level,
because its level also represents the
minimum number of edges to reach it from A.
A is at level 0 because we need 0 edges to reach
it, we're already there. We extract it, and we
check its unvisited neighbors. Its unvisited
neighbors are B C D. For each neighbor v,
we put A as its previous vertex, and we put its
level, which is the level of A + 1, in dist[v].
We also add it to visited, and we push
it to the queue with level of A + 1,
0+1 we get 1, these vertices belong to
level 1, we need 1 edge to reach them.
Next element in the queue is B, its level is 1.
We extract, and we check unvisited neighbors,
we have I. We put B as its previous vertex,
we put 2 as its dist, we add it to visited,
and we push it to the queue. And
the process continues like that.
The queue is now empty, we finished the process,
dist now contains the minimum number of edges to
reach each vertex from A, and prev contains
the previous vertex of each vertex if we
want to reconstruct the path. Let's implement
this solution. We first create dist and prev,
dist initially infinity value for all cells and
prev contains null, same as we did in previous
algorithms. Then we set dist[src] to 0, because
we need 0 edges to go from the source to itself.
We also need the queue and the visited set. The
queue initially contains a tuple that contains
the source, because we start from there,
and its level, the level of the source is 0.
We also put the source in the visited
set, remember that we set a vertex as
visited as soon as it enters the
queue, which is the case here.
Now while the queue is not empty, we extract
the next vertex and its level from the queue.
And the level of a vertex represents the
minimum number of edges to reach it from source.
After it we traverse unvisited neighbors. For each
neighbor in graph[vertex], if it's not visited,
then vertex is the first vertex that discovers
it, we mark that vertex as the previous vertex
of neighbor, it's the one to follow if we want
the shortest path from source to neighbor.
This is why we assign vertex to prev[neighbor].
We also assign level+1 to dist[neighbor],
remember that the level of a neighbor
is the level of the current vertex + 1.
We also add neighbor to visited, and we push
it into the queue, with its level. The level of
the unvisited neighbor is the level of vertex +1,
this is why we push the tuple (neighbor, level+1).
After the loop, dist and prev
are now filled, we return them.
And we use the same reconstruct function as for
Dijkstra's if we want to reconstruct the path.
For the time complexity, we're
just performing bfs, and bfs has
a time complexity of O(|V|+|E|),
so same thing for this algorithm.
If you're wondering where this algorithm can be
used, we can for example think of a grid with
obstacles, we have a start position, and we
want the shortest path to go to end position.
We can use this algorithm by
considering cells as vertices,
and we put an edge between each two adjacent
free cells. And the minimum number of edges
from start to end represents the minimum number
of moves. We've reached the end of this lecture.
If you didn't understand something, you can
ask questions, see you in the next lecture.