In this chapter, we learned
about dfs and bfs algorithms,
and we applied them in explicit graph structures,
we had an adjacency list or an adjacency matrix,
and we've seen how to use the
two algorithms. But what if the
graph structure was not really explicit? Can we
still apply them? Let me show you an example.
A good example is a grid, let's say that we have
a grid made of 0s and 1s where 0 means that the
cell is free, we can walk on it, and 1 means that
there is a wall in that cell. And starting from a
cell we can move to its 4-directionally adjacent
cells if they exist and have no wall in them.
For example from this cell, we can go to the
left, we cannot go to the top because it's outside
the grid, we cannot go to the right because
there's a wall, and we can go to the bottom.
Can we use dfs and bfs to walk
inside this grid? The answer is yes.
The reason behind it is that we can represent this
grid with a graph, where each cell is represented
by a vertex, and an edge between two vertices
means that we can move between those two cells.
Before showing you the result, try to convert this
grid to a graph by yourself on a paper or on a
software, put a vertex for each cell and if we can
move between two cells, put an edge between their
vertices in the graph. You should get this result,
pause the video and compare with what you've done.
And starting from this graph, we can apply
dfs and bfs to solve different problems,
for example we can know if it's possible to go
from a cell A to a cell B in the grid. And to
actually implement this, we can think of creating
an adjacency list, creating a key for each cell,
then for each cell, we check its 4-directionally
adjacent cells, we add to neighbors every one of
them that is inside the grid and has no wall in
it. Then we start working on the graph we created.
But we don't need to do all of this,
we can directly work on the grid.
You need to understand something, to traverse
a graph, we don't necessarily need an adjacency
list or an adjacency matrix, we just need two
things: to know how are vertices represented,
and how to find neighbors of a vertex. Which
are both available in this grid representation.
A vertex is represented by a cell, which is
represented by its coordinates, in other words,
its row and its column, so a vertex is
represented by a tuple of 2 elements,
the first element represents the row
and the second element the column.
And to find neighbors of a vertex, we
traverse its 4-directionally adjacent cells,
we take those that respect the condition,
being inside the grid and not having a wall.
Let's try it now with dfs and bfs. We
want to start from a cell in a grid,
and to move to all other reachable
cells, using either dfs or bfs.
Let's start with dfs. Our function takes as
parameters the grid, the coordinates i and
j from where we want to start, and the set of
visited vertices. Inside the function, we start
by storing the dimensions of the grid in n and m,
then we put the actual vertex in the visited set.
And a vertex is represented by a tuple containing
its coordinates, i and j here, we put the tuple
(i, j) in visited. Then we process the vertex,
we can for example print its coordinates.
Now we need to traverse adjacent cells of the
actual cell, for that we check the 4 directions
in any order, bottom top right left for example.
But how to check the 4 directions? Our cell is
at coordinates (i, j), so the one at the bottom
is at (i+1, j), the one at the top is at (i-1,
j), the one at the right is at (i, j+1),
and the one at the left is a t (i, j-1).
We traverse each couple, and we're
traversing each adjacent cell.
Now we have next_i and next_j, coordinates of the
potential neighbor, potential because we still
need to add a condition. Our cell must be inside
the grid, doesn't contain a wall, and is not
visited, so next_i must be between 0 inclusive and
n exclusive, next_j must be between 0 inclusive
and m exclusive, and grid[next_i][next_j] must
be equal to 0, means that we can walk in it.
If these conditions are respected, then
(next_i, next_j) is a neighbor of (i, j).
But we still have a condition to go to
it, not being in visited. This is why we
add another condition, (next_i, next_j) not in
visited. If all these conditions are respected,
it means that we need to move from (i, j) to
(next_i, next_j), we call the dfs function on it.
And in the main function, we have as
parameters the grid, and the coordinates (i,
j) of the cell from where we start. We create
a set visited, and we call the function.
This was for dfs, what about
bfs now. For bfs, same thing,
a vertex is now represented with a
tuple (i, j), and to find neighbors,
we traverse the 4 adjacent cells and check
those that respect the condition, that's it.
By the way, here in dfs we are checking the
validity of a cell before we call the function on
it, so we have nothing to check at the beginning
of a call, we know that grid[i][j] is valid. But
we can check after calling. We call dfs on each
adjacent cell without checking the condition,
but when entering the function call, we add a base
case, if the actual cell is outside the grid or
has a wall or is visited, we directly exit, it's
not a valid cell to go to. Same thing with bfs,
we can enqueue directly without checking
conditions, we check them when we dequeue
that cell later. And it gives the same result,
it's just another way of implementing dfs and bfs.
That is quite slower because here we first need
to enter the call before noticing that the vertex
is invalid, while in the implementation
we've seen previously we don't even call.
Also, with a grid, we're using a visited set
to store visited cells, which is not necessary,
we have another way to do so. Our
grid actually contains 1s and 0s,
1 means there's a wall and 0 means
there isn't. We can add a third value,
2 for example, such that a cell that has the
value 2 means that the actual cell is visited.
So in our code, when we want to consider
a cell as visited we set its value to 2,
and to check that a cell is not visited
we just check that it's different from 2.
Here we just check if it's equal to 0 because
0 means that it's empty and not visited.
And after we finish everything, we
set all cells with a value of 2 to 0,
to get the original state of the grid. By
doing so, we avoid using extra space for
the visited set, which can be of size n*m in
the worst case, when we visit all the cells.
Okay now we learnt how to apply dfs
and bfs on a grid, how can we use it?
We can use it in a lot of problems, for
example we have the Flood fill algorithm.
In Paint software, we can fill a whole connected
area with the same color, but how does it work?
It uses the flood fill algorithm, it starts
from the pixel where we clicked, and it keeps
coloring all cells of that area with the color
we chose, which can be done with dfs and bfs.
And I made a whole video on
this algorithm on YouTube,
a video that you should really watch, you
can consider it as a part of this course,
you can find the link below, go
watch it just after this lecture.
Second example, we can solve a maze. We can have
a maze, represented by a grid of 0s and 1s, and
we can apply dfs or bfs to find the way of going
from the top-left cell to the bottom-right cell.
Last thing I wanted to mention for this
lecture is that, this lecture is named
dfs and bfs in implicit graphs, the goal is
to understand that graphs we work on are not
always defined by using an adjacency list or an
adjacency matrix, the important is to know how
is a vertex represented and how to access
neighbors. We gave an example with a grid,
but it's not the only case, we will discover other
implicit graphs in future lectures. I hope that
you understood this lecture, and I'll let you
with this animation of dfs and bfs in a grid.
See you in the next lecture.