What is all the hype around the Spring Framework?
Do you already know that you want to learn Spring,
but aren't sure where to start?
Hello.
I'm Bryan Hansen, and welcome to my course on Spring Fundamentals on Pluralsight.
In this course, we're going to be learning about developing with Spring,
and we'll use the various configuration methods to illustrate some of
the common problems we often face in development.
We will develop part of an application without Spring and then show how to
configure that part of the application using Java configuration,
XML configuration, and annotations.
We will also discuss the lifecycle of Spring and how to use beans in a more appropriate fashion.