So, again, what is Spring?
Well,
it is a framework built around reducing the complexities
around enterprise Java development and later also providing
enterprise development without EJBs.
Spring can essentially be used with or without Enterprise
JavaBeans and primarily now is used without them.
This is an important point because Spring enabled us to do enterprise
development without using an application server.
A lot of people don't realize that Tomcat really isn't an application server,
and it's just a web server.
This is one of the reasons that Tomcat has taken over for
Java developments as a standard container.
It's very easy to use, it's lightweight,
and until Spring,
you either weren't using enterprise features or you had to use a more complex,
harder-to-use application server.
I should also mention that it is completely POJO based.
Any code you write in Spring can be written without using Spring at all.
POJO, as you may or may not remember, stands for a plain old Java object.
The Spring Framework really isn't doing any magical thing behind the scene.
It's just helping us write better,
cleaner code and doing things POJO based and interface driven.
So we've already talked about it being lightweight,
but we should also point out that Spring was built
out of the frustrations of JEE, so it's very unobtrusive.
It shouldn't be getting in your way.
If it is, you're using it wrong.
Spring also uses AOP and proxies to apply things like transactions to your code
to get those cross cutting concerns out of your application,
so your code should actually be smaller and more lightweight from using Spring.
One of the most appealing parts of Spring to me is that
it's built around best practices.
We end up having design patterns in our code without us
even realizing that we're using them, things like singletons,
factories, abstract factories.
All of those best practices are built into our code.
Some people may argue that I should know those to get into it.
That's true.
Having that knowledge of patterns will only help increase
your understanding of what Spring is doing,
but it can help make new developers or less experienced
developers come up to speed and use these patterns more
effectively without having that knowledge firsthand.
There's patterns like a singleton in there,
a factory, an abstract factory, the template method.
Spring actually uses template method a lot,
and although it's really not a pattern,
it's a design methodology or a best practice,
there's annotation-based configuration.
If all of this doesn't make much sense to you,
don't be concerned because you can still learn Spring without understanding many of those details.