Before we go any further inside of our application,
there is actually one thing we need to fix inside of our pom.xml,
and this has been the case for every IDE I have ever used.
We need to add a specific build version for our app.
Now you can go look in the Maven course and see why and what.
Suffice it to say that we want to go below the last line of version,
but before we have closed off our project.
So you can see in my example here, after line 9,
I've added some whitespace, so on line 11,
I'm going to add this build section,
and I'm just going to paste it in and walk you through it.
You can add it on your own.
So I have added in here a build section,
and inside of that, there is a plugins section,
plural, and then an individual configured plugin.
And in here,
we have a groupId of org.apache .maven .plugins and an
artifactId of maven-compiler-plugin.
The version is 3.8 .1,
and the configuration is where we specify that we want
Java 11 and a target of Java 11, so the source Java 11 and the target Java 11.
If you don't do this the first time you go to run your application,
it will come back and tell you that it doesn't support Java 5.
Now one thing that I think IntelliJ doesn't do a very
good job of is warning you of that.
Some of the other IDs will tell you that this is
compiling it down to a Java 5 version,
and that's because IntelliJ will compile code as you go using their
internal IDE compiler and not the Maven compiler.
So they're going through and checking code as you go,
and it's compiling it to Java 11, but when you go to run the application,
it will run it with what the default is in Maven,
which, by default, is Java 5.
So this is how you override to tell it to use Java 11. Now that we have our Maven