application that we're going to add,
and it's arguably the most complex piece of the
small app that we're going to do, is the repository tier.
I'm going to exit out of fullscreen mode here,
and you want to navigate down to your source,
main, java directory.
Right-click and say New, Java Class.
And just like before,
we're going to enter in our package structure here of com.pluralsight,
but this time we're going to do a repository.HibernateSpeakerRepositoryImpl,
and click Enter, and that should've created another package.
As you can see over here on the left,
I now have the model and repository package,
and then the class would've been named HibernateSpeakerRepositoyImpl,
so make sure yours looks like mine does here.
And you may argue that I don't like having the implementation in the class name,
and I actually agree with you.
The implementation in the class name can sometimes
be thought of as a code smell,
but the beauty of Spring is is that we code to an interface,
so when this is all done, we're going to have a speaker repository interface,
and that's all our app cares about.
We can swap out these back implementations based upon
what stage of development we're in.
In fact,
this is a good practice to do if I have a database team that I'm
waiting for tables or views or those types of things for.
I can create a speaker repository stub and extract
my interface out against that, and my contract will stay the same.
So let's go ahead and add a method inside of here.
We're going to do a public List of Speakers,
and we want to name this method findAll.
And inside of here,
we just want to create a basic list and return some stuff from that,
so we'll say that we have our Speaker,
and this is going to just be speakers = new ArrayList.
And inside of here, we want to create an instance of a speaker,
so we'll say Speaker speaker = new Speaker.
And I'm going to just use my name.
Go ahead and customize it to yours if you want,
say speaker.setFirstName, and I'll put Bryan inside of here,
and speaker.setLastName.
And here we have our basic speaker object,
and we want to add that to our speakers list,
so we'll say speakers.add (speaker), and then,
lastly, return our speakers, and save that.
There are a couple ways we can extract an interface
or create an interface for this.
One is I could navigate over to my source,
main,
java directory again and go into my com.pluralsight
repository package and create a new interface,
but the easier approach is to just right-click inside of my
class and say Refactor and Extract Interface.
It's going to bring up a dialog,
and it's going to ask me what I want for the class to
extract from and the interface name.
I'm going to change this to SpeakerRepository.
And the package is correct and the target is correct,
and I want to choose the findAll():List Speaker
members to make an interface force,
so it's going to extract those method names out into the interface for me.
I'm going to click Refactor, and if this is the first time that you've done this,
it will show you that it's made changes,
and you say, Yes, I want to proceed.
And we haven't used this anywhere else, so we're good to proceed with that.
And we can open this up and see our SpeakerRepository
with our findAll method inside of here.
So it's just gone ahead and changed our implements SpeakerRepository
signature on our class name and created the interface for it.
Now when we're utilizing this inside of our code,
we can just go ahead and reference it by SpeakerRepository rather than that implementation with hibernate in the name.