How does this all work?
Great, we've seen that it can reduce business focus for us,
but how does it do this?
Well, as I mentioned earlier, everything in Spring is a simple POJO,
a plain old Java object.
Spring itself can be thought of as a glorified HashMap.
It's actually called the application context.
The application context is the configured Spring container
with all of the dependencies wired up in it.
Now I don't want to simplify it too much.
It's doing more than just creating a HashMap and shoving objects in there,
but I also don't want people to be afraid of it because
there's too much going on behind the scenes.
There's too much magic happening with Spring because there's really not.
Spring can also be used as a registry and that's how I'm going to
show you to start with because we're just going to use a little
main method and an application to run it.
But to really get all the benefit of Spring, we'll go through its wiring constructs and use it to autowire our application.