We now have all the pieces of our application built to where we can wire it up,
so let's go ahead and right-click on source,
main, java, and say New, Java Class.
And I am going to use the default package for this.
I just want to enter in here Application and click Enter.
And we're going to create a public static void main in
this file and pass in our String args,
our basic Java signature for a main method.
To demonstrate this, we're going to wire up our SpeakerService.
Just call it an instance of service = new SpeakerServiceImpl,
and we will just do a System.out .println,
a basic happy path testing if you've never heard that term before.
We're going to just test that our application works
exactly how we think it should,
and we'll say service.findAll .get (0) .getFirstName now.
In my instance, I used my name, so this should, when we run it, print out Bryan.
I'm going to go ahead and right-click on main and say Run Application.main.
You'll see it compile here in our build window,
and you'll see that it printed out Bryan down below here.
Now if you get an error here saying that it was compiled with Java 11,
but ran with Java 5, and that's not supported,
it's because you need to go back into the POM and add that
build section that we talked about earlier.
I've seen a lot of people miss that step,
so make sure you've added that in there.
Let's walk through everything that we did here really
quick and what our application did.
So we create an instance of SpeakerService,
it goes to our SpeakerServiceImpl,
so our interface is going to our implementation.
This is going to load our repository tier,
or, in this instance, our fake Hibernate instance,
and go through our SpeakerRepository to that RepositoryImpl where it would
simulate us calling a database and returning a list of speakers.
In this instance, we had Bryan and added that to our list and returned it out. Let's go see how we would now configure all of that using Spring.