In this module,
we will walk through the configuration of your Spring app using just Java.
We're going to take that sample application that we created in
the previous module and wire it up using the Java annotations
and Java configuration loader.
Java configuration is the latest and most preferred method available
now in Spring for wiring up your applications.
It was introduced simply because some people don't like mixing XML
and source code together for a configuration.
We're going to take that sample project,
wire it up with Java and a few basic annotations
just to show you how this works.
So let's talk about the key point of the Java configuration.
Well, the first thing you'll notice about it is there's no XML.
There's no applicationContext file.
If you've done any Spring development in earlier versions,
you'll have an XML file that contains all of your configuration.
With that Java configuration, we have no
[00:00:59]
applicationContext.xml.
We still have a context, it's just not configured in XML.
Earlier Spring development got pushed back for having too much XML,
and all of a sudden people were making jokes about being an
XML developer rather than a Java developer.
Later versions of Spring included namespaces to aid in development,
but developers still wanted less or no XML,
so enter Java configuration.
Almost everything in Spring can now be configured
with just pure Java configuration.
This was not necessarily the case when we first started this course,
but since this is an update,
we've moved to showing Java configuration first because everything is available to be configured this way now.