The singleton design pattern restricts the
instantiation of a class to just one object.
A singleton is the default bean scope inside of Spring.
So if you don't give it a scope,
it will automatically be assigned the default scope of singleton,
which means that there is one instance per Spring container or context.
A lot of people say that means one instance per JVM,
which is technically true,
but you could possibly have more than one Spring container spun up in your JVM.
So, really,
the correct term is one instance per Spring container or application context.
The configuration for adding scope using Java configuration is quite simple.
We simply add the @Scope annotation to our code as you
can see here in our code sample.
And in the previous release of this course,
we weren't using Maven, so you were required to add the AOP jar separately.
Since we are using Maven, this is just a transitive dependency,
and it's already available in our project.
Let's add that scope to our project now and show you how
you can configure that for your beans.
To add scope to our already configured application,
I've gone ahead and opened up our AppConfig.java file.
I'm going to go below our bean definition for our
speakerService and add an @Scope annotation.
Now by default, I did mention earlier that it is a singleton,
and that's implied, but we can explicitly set it,
and there's a couple ways we can do this.
First off, we want to go in here and type value,
and we can type inside of here singleton.
Now I do not like using my own typed out strings for these
values because I could easily forget that n off the end of
there so it's a singleto not a singleton.
So we can use some strings that they have already set up for us inside
of Spring by saying BeanDefinition.SCOPE_SINGLETON.
You can tell by this context-sensitive help tip that
it's just a sting equal to singleton,
but that's what we want and we don't have to define our own.
So a lot of people go ahead and create their own utils.
We'll just go ahead and select value= BeanDefinition.SCOPE_SINGLETON,
and we can save this.
Now to test this, let's go back to our application,
and, right here, we have this SpeakerService service = appContext.getBean.
So we have an instance of this bean where it's going to go
ahead and tell us what object we have.
I'm going to add another System.out .println here,
and this is a very simple way to just see what's
going on behind the scenes here.
And I want to actually just print out service,
and it's going to be the object address for service,
and I want to grab another instance of that bean.
So I'm going to copy this line here, and go down below,
and we'll call this service2,
and I'm going to copy that System.out .println again.
Make sure you change the variable to be the second one.
And this should print out these two different object address instances for us.
So, let's go ahead and run this.
I'm going to right-click on our main method and say Run Application.main.
And when this runs,
you'll notice that it prints out the exact same object address instance.
So down here in our console output,
you can see that com.pluralsight .service .SpeakerServiceImpl,
and your object address will be different just because it's
unique every time you run this through the JVM.
Then it prints out my name,
and it prints out that same object address instance again.
So our singleton is in fact a singleton.
Each time we ask for an instance of that bean from the application context,
it's returning the same bean for us.
Now,
this is the behavior we want because we shouldn't be storing any
state that is unique to that user inside that object.
You can store state unique to that application in there,
but you don't want to store state unique to that user inside that object.
So, this is working as we planned. Let's look at what it means to be a prototype now.