Web scopes are beyond what we're going to cover in this course
since it's just a basic Spring fundamentals course.
They are covered more in the Introduction to Spring MVC
course that's available here on Pluralsight,
and that's simply because we have to set up an entire web application
for you to see how they interact with an object.
The three other scopes that are available are the request scope,
which returns a bean per HTTP request,
which sounds a lot like prototype except it's for
the lifecycle of a bean request, which is fairly short,
but longer than prototype where it's one instance per
every time I ask the container for a bean.
The session just returns a single bean per HTTP session,
and that will live as long as that user session is alive,
so 10 minutes, 20 minutes, 30 minutes,
however long they're alive on that website a bean of
scope session will stick around.
And then there is globalSession, which will return a single bean per application,
so once I access it, it's alive for the duration of that application,
not just my visit to that application.
You could think of it as singleton,
but it's really the entire life of that application on the server until it gets undeployed or the server gets rebooted.