To add setter injection to our project,
we actually have to change a couple of things that we have
hard coded inside of our previous demo.
That's the whole reason we're actually using Spring,
so let's go ahead and open up our service,
and specifically our SpeakerServiceImpl,
and see how we have this new HibernateRepositoryImpl in here?
Let's go ahead and get rid of that hard- coded instance,
and we want to create a setter in here where we
actually wire up this configuration.
So we're going to right-click and say Generate,
and we want to do Setter, and specifically the SpeakerRepository,
and click OK.
And now we've converted our SpeakerServiceImpl to be injected rather
than have hard-coded configured instances in here.
We can save this.
Then we want to go back to our AppConfig.
Now inside of our AppConfig, we can do a couple things here.
We want to start off by creating a new bean for our SpeakerRepository,
so we want to say Bean.
I want to give this a name = speakerRepository.
And if you are wondering why I am kind of fanatic about the names of
our beans is because when we go to do autowiring,
which is coming up here very quickly,
we're going to use it to autowire by name to our variable name,
so these match up and it automatically happens for us.
Let's go ahead and finish out our method signature here,
so we'll say SpeakerRepository, and we'll do getSpeakerRepository.
[00:14: 37.473 ]
Take any no arguments method parameter as well here.
And inside of here, we want to return our new HibernateRepositoryImpl.
And now I want to go back up to our SpeakerService that we
created earlier and reconfigure this a little bit.
So I'm going to just delete this line, and we want to do SpeakerServiceImpl,
not the interface.
We want to do the actual implementation.
We call this service = new SpeakerServiceImpl.
And inside of here,
we want to actually call that getSpeakerRepository bean that we just created,
so we'll say service.setRepository,
and we can call the getter inside of here where we do the getSpeakerRepository.
And we've now configured our service with that repository,
and now we can return our service that we just created.
So now we changed our repository to be injected through
setter injection into our SpeakerServiceImpl.
Now a couple of questions before we proceed just to clear anything up
that you may be a little bit confused on right now.
Why didn't we just create a new instance of the
HibernateSpeakerRepositoryImpl like we did on line 20 on line 14?
Why did we call this getSpeakerRepository?
Because SpeakerRepository is now created as a bean,
and I mentioned this in the previous slides,
but to kind of reiterate that pointer, make it really stick,
the bean is a singleton.
Only 1 of them will get created.
We can call this getSpeakerService method 50 times now,
and only 1 of the SpeakerRepositoryImpls will get created.
So it's implemented as a singleton, and that's a good thing.
That sometimes confuses or concerns people to start with.
This is actually a good thing for us.
So now we've got this configured to use beans.
They're singletons.
It's all wired up.
It's using setter injection.
Let's go to our application now and switch our application to use Spring
because right now we have all this configuration stuff going on,
but we aren't actually doing anything with it yet.
So let's go inside of our main method, and we want to say ApplicationContext,
and we'll call this instance appContext = new
AnnotationConfigApplicationContext.
Let me make this fullscreen so you can see a little
bit more of what's going on here.
And inside of here, we want to pass in the AppConfig.class.
Now this is our AppConfig that we just created,
this file up here where we configured our beans and it's
annotated with configuration on line 8.
This file is what we're passing into our AnnotationConfigApplicationContext.
What this is is this is loading Spring and it's loading the configuration
files that we have out there into our ApplicationContext.
So when line 9 is ran,
it's going to go out and create a basic registry with 2 beans in it,
the speakerService bean and the speakerRepository bean.
As we just changed on line 13 and 14,
it now injects the speakerRepository bean into the speakerService bean,
and then we'll return that back to our application when we call it.
Now to change that, I'm going to change one more line here,
and I wanted to comment out that old one so that you can
see it and kind of compare the two,
so we'll call this SpeakerService service = appContext.getBean.
And we want to use the version that does type casting,
so we want to go in here and, first of all,
we're going to call it by name and say that we want the speakerService
and pass in the class instance of SpeakerService.class.
And save that instance, and we're ready to run our application.
We have Spring enabled it.
We have gone ahead and done the setter injection of our
speakerRepository and our speakerService.
Let's run this now.
When we fire this up, it'll go ahead and compile it,
and you'll see that it actually returns our instance just like we had before.
I've commented out line 11 so you can see what we
had before that was hard coded.
Now nothing inside of our application is actually hard coded.
It's done through our configuration instances.
Just to recap that,
we added the configuration inside of our AppConfig that now signified
a speakerRepository bean that wasn't there before,
and it is setter injected into our SpeakerService.
Our SpeakerService,
we got rid of the hard- coded configuration inside of
here and just added a setter for it,
and then we converted our application to use Spring.
And from this point forward,
we can now inject all sorts of beans and pieces in our application
wherever we would like to do that and not have it hard coded. Let's look at what this would look like using constructor injection now.