We looked at a bunch of advanced bean configuration techniques in this module.
We started off by going through the bean lifecycle,
and the key point with that, there were a lot of steps in there,
you want to pay attention to the init method step.
That's what allows us to hook into that post construct
annotation and add that functionality to our beans.
Next,
we configured a FactoryBean from scratch and implemented
some static code inside of our application,
and that's really one of the main takeaways there is that
when you're needing to integrate some legacy code or maybe
some code with a static initializer,
the FactoryBean and wrapping that is a great way to go
about that and be able to autowire that and still inject
it into your application now.
Then we went through Spring Expression Language and showed how you
could go ahead and interface some other code and libraries and
manipulate the object graph at runtime.
It's a very powerful way for you to go about doing that.
Then we talked briefly about proxies.
Proxies are a very advanced technique.
Just wanted to whet your appetite a little bit with them and show you that
they're out there and make you aware that Spring uses them,
but they're not something that you would use on a day-to-day
basis and you shouldn't be looking for opportunities to
integrate them inside of your application.
The last thing we did was implement bean profiles inside of our app,
and it was a great way to show you that you may have some code in there
that you want to make sure doesn't get into production.
If you use it just for that, it's a great tool.
So what's next for you?
Well, this is the end of this course, and if you enjoyed it,
I would really appreciate if you would leave me a review.
If you liked my course,
there are a bunch of other courses that I've produced out there.
In fact, one of the next ones I would recommend is the Spring MVC intro course.
There is also a great course on Spring Boot fundamentals that Dan
Bunker has put together that is a great course as well.
I've taken it myself,
and I would recommend both of those to you as a next step in your journey
and continue to follow along the learning path for Spring,
on Pluralsight. Thank you.