In this module,
we discussed the various scopes that are available inside the Spring container,
namely singleton and prototype.
We showed examples of how to configure both of
those using the Java configuration.
We then mentioned the web scopes that are available,
but they are outside the scope of this module and of this
course really because we have to set up an entire web
application just to demonstrate them.
Those three scopes are request, session, and globalSession.
We then discussed autowiring.
We showed an example using setter injection and constructor
injection and showed that you can use the component scanner to
wire those apps up or you can do a hybrid.
Our first example we had with this was just a hybrid of
some of the methods being autowired,
but still having our beans defined in that AppConfig.
If that makes you feel more comfortable in using it,
use it that way,
but I will say the more convenient way is to go with full autowiring
using those stereotype annotations that we discussed.
Let's look at what we can do with the XML configuration,
and we're going to run through some smaller examples because it's very similar to Java now.