When I started writing software,
N-Tier and monolithic applications were the defacto standard.
In one single binary web artifact,
there would be a layered architecture with decomposition of
code into more functional components.
There are several disadvantages to N-Tier monolithic application architecture.
Tight coupling of code,
which makes changes hard because a single deployment contains all of the layers,
which causes long testing, building, and deployment cycles.
A big monolithic application makes code reuse and sharing components difficult.
When components are shared in a monolithic application,
it brings about tight coupling.
Due to tight coupling, the smallest of changes can require large scale releases,
which impacts speed to market. This is how TrackZilla would look if it were an N-Tier monolithic application.