Now,
we have a solid foundation for talking about complex
relationships between the entities, ticket,
application, and person.
So what are the relationships between a ticket, an application, and a person?
A ticket belongs to one application,
and an application can have 0 or many tickets.
A person can own 0 or many applications,
and an application can be owned by one person.
A person can be assigned to 0 or many tickets,
and a ticket can be assigned to exactly one person.
In a monolith database,
sharing data and joining data was easy because all of
the data resided in the same place.
The use of microservices changes this.
How do we handle such complex relationships between microservices?
There are a few popular options for sharing data.
We will look at one option called synchronous lookup.
Now when you split data across microservices, joins are much harder to do.
There are several options for this as well,
and we will discuss joining in the client versus a
service that materializes a view.
There are several options for sharing data.
I will demo the option where one microservice makes a synchronous call
to retrieve the data owned by another in real time.
In the relationship, a ticket belongs to one application,
the ticket service will call the application service to
retrieve information about applications since the application
service owns the application data.
This is the relationship between applications and people.
An application has an owner represented by the owner ID.
Now, instead of passing the owner ID back to the calling program,
we want to pass back the name and the role of the owner,
so we use the owner ID to retrieve additional
details like the name and the role.
When you split data across microservices, joins are much harder to do.
There are two options for joining data.
The first option is to join in the client application.
So you have the calling client or application first get an
application using the application microservice,
then query matching tickets for that application via the ticket service.
Materializing a view is where you maintain one or more materialized
views that contain data for multiple services.
The view is updated by a service that subscribes to events from the
application and ticket service about data changes.
For example, first you find applications,
and then open tickets for the applications maintained in a view that joins applications and tickets.