So how does Spring Data REST work?
At application startup, it finds all of the Spring Data repositories.
It then creates an endpoint that matches the entity names.
It then appends an S to the entity name and the endpoint,
and it exposes operations as RESTful APIs over HTTP.
By default,
the HTTP methods to interact with these resources map to the
corresponding methods of the CrudRepository.
GET maps to findById, POST maps to save,
PUT maps to save, DELETE maps to delete.
As a quick tip, in a recent release of Spring,
several CRUD repository methods were renamed; findOne was renamed to findById,
save was renamed to saveAll, findAll was renamed to findAllById,
delete was renamed to deleteById, the second delete was renamed to deleteAll, exists was renamed to existsById.