It's not always desirable to expose the documentation for your entire API.
You can restrict Swagger's response by passing parameters to
the APIs and pass method of the docket class.
Swagger also provides default values in its response,
which you can customize, such as API documentation,
CreatedBy contact email, etc.
To change these values, you will use the API info method.
The API info class contains custom information
about the API that you can modify.
Swagger allows globally overriding response messages of HTTP methods
through docket's globalResponseMessage method.
First, you must instruct Swagger not to use the default response messages.
Suppose you wanted to override the 500 response message for all GET requests.
To achieve this, some code must be added to docket initialization block.
Additional code from this example is excluded for clarity.
So in our demo, we are going to look at the SwaggerUI,
open it, and see operations exposed by the ApplicationCatalog management service.
We will also use SwaggerUI to test our microservices, specifically the ApplicationCatalog operations.