In this module, we've learned a lot about Spring Data REST,
and the topics I'm going to teach you more about during the course.
One neat feature that should stand out to you is that Spring Data REST exposes
data already accessible through Spring Data repositories as a RESTful
microservice without a lot of extra work on your part.
First, we looked at Spring Data REST,
and we talked about hypermedia driven RESTful APIs.
Next, we looked at the learning path.
Now remember, at a minimum,
you need to have a thorough understanding of Spring
Data to be successful in this course, which includes JPA.
Then, we looked at prerequisites and dependent technologies,
remember that you can run Maven from the command line
or within your IDE; and lastly, we looked at our fun case study TrackZilla,
our cool bug tracking application that you will be
working with during this course. Next, I will teach you more about the microservices architecture.