The domains in the TrackZilla application would be application catalog,
ticket management, and user management.
The corresponding microservices architecture would have services
corresponding to each of these subdomains.
So, application management service, TicketManagement service,
and UserManagement service.
For this demo,
we will break up the TrackZilla monolith and create a
ticket management service that allows us to retrieve a
list of tickets for an application.
So looking at this code, this is what we saw at the end of module one,
the TrackZilla monolith with the controller layer,
the service layer, and the data layer.
So let's break it into microservices,
and get it ready to become a Spring Data REST project. So the goal of this demo is to create our ticket management service.