Hello and welcome back to the advance
course on Tableau. We are very close to
the end of the section. We have conducted
all of the required analysis and we are
ready to put our findings into a report
and that is exactly what we're going to
do today.
Now let's see what the best way to do
that is. Alright so we have the box plots
and the box plots they do feel like they
were quite a long time ago.
This is the analysis of competitors. This
is our industry analysis so just in a
general without taking into account per
capita and per capita sales and here
we've got the sales per capita with the
forecast. So there are a number of ways
of presenting this and I'm going to go
with the storyline. So I'm going to
create a storyline and we're going to
say maybe, final presentation here and so
a couple ways you could just show the
box plots and you could just show the
sales per capital as is like this. So I
was thinking of doing that as well but
then the presentation feels a bit weak I
think it feels a bit empty so you want
you want to put in some more steps into
not necessarily more different visuals
but show people like a few more steps
and expand on things a little bit more
and that's why I think what we're going
to do is we're going to add the box
plots, then we're going to show the
industry analysis so we will actually
say this is what the industries
turnovers look like for all. This
industries turnover looks like in a
different state.
However, if we take into consideration
that the populations are growing at
different rates,
this is what sales per capital looks like
and then we'll show this chart but
without the forecast and then we'll
show this chart with the forecast. So
that's our plan for now, so and in this
in this storyline we're not going to add
text, we're just going to have the pictures
and when you're talking, you're
actually presenting you will then say
all the words that requires. So we're
assuming that this presentation has to be
delivered in person rather than the
stakeholders reading through it
themselves.
So let's change this to
maybe yeah why not? Let's change it to a
desktop and I'll expand my Tableau maybe
that's a bit too much so let's expand it
a bit so I just see this whole storyline.
Alright so there we go and this is gonna
be our final presentation box plots so
we got a title here and actually as we
discussed previously we want to first
create dashboards right? So we want to
create a dashboard for every single one,
maybe duplicate the sales per capita and
this one will call sales per capita with
forecast, with forecast and here we're
going to just switch the forecast off,
show forecast
there we go and now we can match the
dashboards to the worksheet and so in
this dashboard and so our presentation
is going to be desktop size we're going
to make dashboards a bit smaller maybe a
laptop size, so because in the final
presentation we've got this bit at the
top right? So we want to leave some space
for it,
laptop, laptop and laptop here. Okay and
now let's just drag our visuals in here
and as you remember dashboards give you
more control you can delete things you
don't want. So that and that is a bit too
wide and the name here box plots that's
why I kind of showed the title here
because that is the same title that you
get here so we can change this to a
competitor analysis and maybe make it a
12 and center it, make
leave it bold, yep! So let's see competitor
analysis, so we don't need this label
because we already see that the
state is here, net profit margin maybe 12
is not the best maybe make it a bit
higher like 20,
there we go that looks better. So
competitor analysis and it is like the
box plot is why that's might not be the
best so what I usually do I take this
like I add in these things on the sides
and that way it fits in nicely and also
just to make sure that the same size, so
that's our competitor analysis if I drag
it in here now,
there it is. So that's our dashboard one
industry analysis same thing just drag
it into here we don't need the colors
because we have the names of the states
right so in this case same thing, so here
we want size 20.
What are we going to call this one? I'll
just keep it industry analysis just keep
it just center it, so industry analysis, we
don't need this label because it doesn't
show us any, it has no use. Here month of date
also same thing, no use from that label
just get rid of it.
Alright so that's our dashboard two, let's
add a new blank point, dashboard two, ok so
industry sales per capita, pretty much
same thing sales per capita, just change
a few things. Change this to a 20 keep it
bold, center it, get rid of state, hide
that, change this to nothing and get rid
of this.
Alright as you can see it's pretty quite
a quick process once you have a plan.
What you want to do?
it's pretty straightforward how to get
there and that's what I really
like about storylines in Tableau,
doesn't take long to put it together and
especially the ones we don't have to
write the text and then sales with forecast
same thing drag it into here, get rid of that.
You can even change the
label here. So well let's make it
nice and neat so maybe actually type it up
sales for capita and then with forecast.
Alright, okay a new blank points. That
alright so I think that looks ok, so if
we go through them,
the only thing we might want to do is
just change the captions here so this
one we're just going to copy it. A
competitor analysis, this is going to be
industry analysis and then if we go here
and steal it from here and then just copy
it here.
Alright, so there we go that's our
presentation. So let's go ahead and save
that and let's have a look through it. So
our story title, forgot the story title,
how could we forget the story title?
Expansion analysis insights and
maybe make it a 22 and center that as
well, maybe make it actually 24. Let's see
how that looks.
So there we go, that is our final
presentation and when we are presenting
it to the executives or the stakeholders
we would just walk through our
investigation and explain what we saw.
So let's have a quick rehearsal at that, in
the first part of our analysis we looked
at the competitors and we saw that out
of all the states, the best business
environment is actually in Victoria and
that is because as you can see the box
plot is quite compact here and the box
part of the box plot is close to the top
meaning that in overall
there's more certainty that how much net
profit margin we can expect to earn in
this state and plus most of the
companies are earning towards the top of
this box plot so means that
even a random company thrown into this
state will have a higher chance of
success and then in the other states.
Then we moved on to industry analysis
and here we can say that all the states
have upward trends for this industry
which is clothing retailing however, if
we take into account population because
as you can see here the turnovers are in
millions of dollars and they are
completely different for all the states
just simply because all of these states
have different populations so if we take
population into account and calculate
the per capita sales then we will see
that the per capita sales are actually
growing only in New South Wales and
Victoria. In Queensland and Western Australia,
the upward trend that we saw previously
are no longer visible meaning that they
were partially attributable to the
growth in population in those states. So
therefore we can make a conclusion that
the actually two conclusions from this
chart, first of all the business
environment in Victoria is a similar to
the one in New South Wales, which we
already have experience with in this
company and second of all we can also
see that the industry itself clothing
and re.. clothing retailing is actually
growing in Victoria just as it is in New
South Wales so the growth that we're
seeing here is not attributable to
simply a growth in population,
actually a growth in people's demands
and their expenditure within this
industry which is exactly what we're
after. So we want to create a expansion
in a business environment which has high
potential for future growth and that in
this case is Victoria, so from those two
stand points Victoria is the place to go
if you add in the competitor analysis
that is a three reasons why Victoria is
the place to be and to finish off we
went above and beyond and we actually
derive some forecasts for
different States and we can if required,
we can supply some information on what
we think is going to be the future of
three years on how the future
two-and-a-half years are going to look
like for Victoria so that when the
expansion is being set up,
we are already prepared and we can already
estimate the revenue for this expansion.
So there we go that is how we put
everything into a storyline and that is
how we present it. I think we've got a
solid case here for the stakeholders
which state to go and that state is
Victoria. Thank you very much for your
attention throughout this section and I
look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, happy analyzing!