To get the materials for the section all
you have to do is open up a browser and
go to superdatascience.com/tableau-
advanced and then if you scroll
down here to Section 2. Groups and Sets
then you'll find a PDF document and an
excel file which is called a 1000
startups. So go ahead and download those
2 and we will pick it up from here.
Alright now that we have got all the
files let's have a look at the challenge
for this section and there it is
section 2 The Challenge. You have been
approached by a Venture Capital Fund. The
Board of Directors are currently
reviewing 1,000 potentially interesting
startups and deciding on which ones are
going to invest in. The criterion for
selecting investments for this fund is a
combination of High Revenue, Low Expenses,
and Top Growth and all of those
parameters are for 2015. Your task is to
assist the Board in identifying which
businesses represent the best investment
opportunities. Sounds very exciting
doesn't it?
I'm getting excited, myself just by
looking at this challenge. So let's have
a look at the data now what has the
Board of Directors supplied us with? I'm
going to zoom in here and the first
thing we should notice is that there's
two tabs so tab number 1 looks like
it's a description and overall summary
of the companies we're going to be
investigated so right away let's check
that there's a thousand rows, there is a
thousand rows then we've got the names
here, the industry they're working in, a
description of what they do
and by the way this is all fake data and
it's all made up numbers and names so if
there is any kind of matching to real
companies in the world then it's,
it's a complete coincidence and here
we've also got the year founded,
employees, state looks like
all of these are American companies, the
city and the metro area.
Alright let's look at the second tab now
financials and in this tab we've
got quite a few columns once again ID
and names so now we know how to join the
two, how to connect the two tabs using
this ID column. Then we've got some 2015
Financials Revenue, Expenses, Profit and
Growth.
Then we've got 14 and 13 and right away
looking at the 2015 numbers and going
back to the challenge we can see that
we'll be working with revenue expenses
and growth so we won't be using any of
those and we won't be using also profit
for 2015.
Now another interesting thing that you
might notice and probably it's a good
thing to like investigate your data
before you start working with in Tableau,
is that here you've got industry for
every single company and there's
different industries here. Now in our
challenge what it says is, The criterion
for selecting investments for this fund
is a combination of High Revenue,
Low Expenses that's that's fine but what is
Top Growth? What does top growth imply? Top
growth could be top growth overall among
the whole thousand or it could be top
growth among the peers of the company so
the company the other companies that are in
the same industry as that company and
quite often that is the case with
venture capital funds because it is hard
to compete again across different
industries because there are certain
constraints and so on. But also sometimes
venture capitalist funds look for top
growth overall, now this is one of the
things that you would go back and you
would confirm with the clients very
important to clarify all of the
conditions of your analysis before you
proceed with it, but in this case we're
going to assume that top growth means
top growth overall, so regardless of the
industry.
Alright so we're done with that, let's go
ahead and load this data into Tableau.
Gonna bring up Tableau here and I'm
going to connect to an excel file,
1,000 startups there it is, perfect
and because we already know how to join
in Tableau we're going to do that right
away we're going to take the overview
tab and then we're going to join into
the financials tab and here you can see
that a join has been created
automatically on the ID field which is
exactly we want. Then we can quickly check
that everything is ok here so one of the
things that you might want to check is
that just take a random name and for a
random row down plus and then just
check that it matches to the name from
the other tab down plus. Ok perfect, now
we go to sheet 1
and here what we're going to do is we're
going to prepare. So today we're going to
quickly learn how to work with folders
in Tableau. So very very easy topic
its pretty much same as working folders
on your computer,
it just helps you organize your measures
and dimensions cause you can see here we
have quite a lot of measures and can get
quite cluttered. This is actually a
pretty simple example you sometimes
you'll have 20, 30 and measures and
dimensions or even up to a hundred so
let's see how we can organize our
workspace. First of all we want to right
click anywhere on the dimensions all the
measures and instead of group by
data source table select group by
folder and now instead of seeing where
these fields came from they're all just
listed altogether so if I'm going to go,
if I go back, you'll see here that you
can see which tab they came from, from the
financials tab or from the overview tab
same thing here. Now we're going to
change to group by folder and now first
thing we're going to do is remove the
fields that are duplicate, so here we are
you know that we joined on this field so
it is a duplicate there's no point in
having this one here. We'll hide this one
and here we're going to hide name as
well because we know it's the same. Now
let's create folders for our financials,
we're going to create a folder, we'll call
it, 2015 financials and we'll take
everything relating to 2015 and we'll
drag it into that folder. Now, we'll create
another folder 2014 financials and we'll
take everything for 2014 and drag it
into that folder and finally let me make
some space, create folder 2013 financials
and drag everything for 2013 to that
folder. So what this does is now you can
collapse these folders and not worry
about them if you don't need the
measures or if your cranium in
dimensions, dimensions which are in those
folder and we know already we're going
to be working between 2015 data so we can just
keep these folders that is as is you
could have of course hit in these fields
like we did with the ones up there but
maybe at some point you might require
them and you don't want to forget
that you actually have them so the best
practice here is just put them in a
folder and collapse that folder. So there
we go,
everything ready. In the next tutorial, we
will start working on our analysis and
will kick off this section. I look
forward to seeing you next time and
until then, happy analyzing.