Welcome back to the advanced course on
Tableau. In the previous tutorial we
created these our beautiful four box
plots and today we're going to learn how
to analyze them, we've got quite a lot of
ground to cover so let's jump straight
into it.
First off, I'd like to make sure that
everybody's on the same page and
therefore let's look at how exactly
box plots work. So I'm going to bring up a
slide that I have prepared very excited
about this.
Alright so let's say you have an access,
it can be vertical, horizontal in all
cases vertical so let's stick with that
and you have a certain number of
observations that you can plot on this
axis so there are 10 observations now in
order to create an a box plot what you'd have
to do is you have to physically count
the number of observations so 1 2 3 up
to 10 and then take the middle between
them so in our case there's an even
number of observations so there is no
one middle observation. The middle ones
are five and six so we're going to put a
line exactly between fit the fifth and
the sixth observation.
Now what we're going to do is we're
going to do the same thing for the top
five. Here we've counted we have five
observations the middle one is number
three. We put a line through that one,
now let's do the exact same thing for
the bottom half 1,2,3,4,5 this is the middle
one over here so we put a line through
it. Now if we replace these lines with
the box we are slowly starting to create
our box plot now all we have to do is
plot the whiskers so the whisker goes
all the way up to the top one over here
and the other whisker goes all the way
up to the bottom one here and elements
of the books plug have their own names.
This is the minimum. This is the first
quartile or the lower quartile. This is
the median. This is the upper quartile,
the third quartile and this is the
maximum and just make sure you don't get
confused here this is not the mean. This
is the median and that's because of the
way we've constructed, so that is how a
box plot gets built so basically it's
about counting the number of records and
breaking it up into four quartile. So
every single quartile has an equal
number of records in it. Now let's look
at another example. Here we've got another
axis. We've got our observations and
let's do the same thing so that's our
median that is going to be our first
quartile that is our third quartile now
for connecting that's our box and now
what we can do here is if we measure the
distance between the third quartile and
the first quartile it's called the
interquartile range.
Well the way we can start box plots is we
want to make sure that our analysis is
not affected by outliers.
So if any observation falls too far away
then we want to exclude from the
construction of the box plot and how do
we determine if and observations too far
away?
Well you need to take one and a half
times the interquartile range and that
is going to be a cut-off point. So if an
observation falls further than that then
you shouldn't included in the box plot
and it's considered an outlier so in
this case our box plot is going to look
like this and that separate dot out there
is considered to be an outlier.
Alright so that's how box plots are
constructed, now let's have a look at a
few sample use cases of box plots. So
here I've got a horizontal axis and for
a change going to be looking at
horizontal box plots and to make things
interesting
let's say we're analyzing sales
representatives and their daily sales so
what would you rather? Would you rather
have your observations plotted like this?
Or would you rather have your
observations plot like this? In both
cases, the median is the same it is a
thousand dollars. Now this is where we
can look at a box plot and if we create
the boxplot for the first example you'll
see that it is quite compact like that.
The second box plot is much more wider,
so what does that tell us? That tells us
that the variance in the first box plot
is lower. So you have a more chances of
being closer to the median, you can only
from the observation that we have you
are only going to be somewhere between
these two whiskers and more likely you
actually going to be inside
the second and third quartiles groups
and therefore you're more likely to be
next to the median here. You have more
room to go up but you also have more
room to go down, so that basically means
that the risk is higher or the
volatility is higher and your sales reps
can bring, they do bring a median back
over a thousand dollars that's a per day
but at the same time it can it can
really vary. It can be anywhere on the
right, anywhere on the left, so you have
more certainty with a more compact box plot,
you have less certainty with a wider
boxplot even given the same median and
the way to think about it or another way
to think about it is in terms of
distribution so this distribution is
narrower this distribution is wider so
if we talk in terms of standard
deviations, standard deviation is here is
all which is also measure of variance
right? So here the standard deviation is
higher or larger, here it's smaller so
you have a more narrow distribution and
you're more likely to actually hit the
nail on the head here whereas here you
can either go left or right which is
more uncertain.
Ok let's have a look at another example,
can you tell me right away what do you
think is this a good box plot or bad box
plot.
Let's say we're also measuring sales and
now its vertical axis and of course
would be better for your great work
compactor like this but is this a good
box plot or a bad box plot and given
that the minimum and the maximum are
fixed and in essence the question we are
asking is is this box plot better than
this box plot and if you think of it in
terms of median the median here is
higher than the median here and it makes
sounds obvious of course this box plot
is preferable to this box plot, so
basically if if your media minimum and
maximum fixed you want your box the part
of the box part of the box but you want
to be as a higher or as closer as more
closer to your desired result of the as
possible so here we're talking about
sales so the larger sales or higher
sales are better, so we want the box to
be higher
not lower but that is the obvious answer.
How do how do we think of it in terms of
distributions and how do we think of it
exactly why this is the case, so if we
plot them out sideways so this is the
good box plot. This is the bad box plot.
Let's plot the observations that make
these boxplots happen, so this these are
10 observations in this case and these
are 10 observations in this case. How
do we see them in terms of distributions?
And for me personally this is the part
that drives this point home.
This is what makes things click, so I'm
going to plot the distribution here and
this here you can see that this is a
right skewed distribution and by the way
right skewed is because the tails on the
right not we don't look at the hump we
look at the tail with the tail is and
that is how we is to define whether it's
a right skewed or left skewed distribution.
So this is a right skewed distribution and if
you think of it in this sense, what it's
telling us is that if you throw a random
observation another one observation on
to this chart then it is more likely to
end up in this area in this more dense
area than it is on in this tale part
right because uh that's how
distributions work. There are more
observations here, so you got your mean
median mode in in this part of the chart
not in this part of the chart so you
throw a random variable here. It is more
likely to end up here and here on
this other side if you throw a random
variable into this environment into this
example then what will happen is it more
likely end up on the right side so this
is a left skewed distribution the tails
on the left but most of the observations
are concentrated over here so if you
throw another random variable it will
most likely end up here and which is
good for us because the sales higher. So
that is how I personally think of box
plots sometimes because you know like
distributions we're used to them and
they've got a lot of mathematics behind
them.
They got standard deviations things like that.
Box plots are also also great but
they're simpler things I think and when
you think of them in terms of distributions
it makes a lot of sense that why a box
plot which is which looks like this is
worse if you want to be on the right of
axis than a box plot that looks like
that.
Ok so that is how box plots work, let's go
jump back into Tableau and see what
analysis we can drive from there.
Alright so there's our chart, what can we
see from this chart knowing that
everything we know now?
Well right away we can see outliers here
and here so what this means is that in
these three states in New South Wales,
Queensland and Victoria. They are companies
that are underperforming in terms of the
overall performance in that specific
state. Then in Queensland there are companies
that are over performing. Also if you put
your mouse over the box plot, you will
get some information which directly
relates to the five points that we
discussed about boxplots so the minimum
the lower quartile the medium the upper
quartile and the maximum and if you use
this information you can compare the box
plots among each other and for instance
we can say that this box plot has the
highest median which is eight percent.
This one is also eight percentage, you can
visually see that see that it's lower
than this box plot comes in a third so
this state has a third median which is
six percent and this one has a four
percent and finally let's talk about the
variance and the sizes of the box plots.
You can see that this box plot here and
this box plot here they are pretty big
compared to these two box plots and
that means that the variance here is
much greater so there's less certainty
that the like a random company thrown
into this one of these states will be
performing at the median net profit
margin and bear in mind when we say
random company we're not taking into
account all the amazing things about our
specific company. We're not taking into
account the product differentiation that
we can offer the amazing customer
service that we deliver and all those
great things. We're just saying if we
throw in a random company that
performs comparability to the companies
in that specific state and you know it's
working its performing about some around
average with sort of certain level
variants where will it end up? So it is
likely to end up in this box but because
the box is so big there is more
uncertainty as to where it will be
performing in this specific state. So
basically we're kind of assessing the
business environment in each of these
states, if in Western Australia once
again there is more uncertainty where
your company will end up in terms of net
profit margin because the box plot is quite
large. Here the box plots are smaller and
as you remember what we just discussed
which one is better?
Let's say here would you rather have
this box here? Would you have it up at
the top? You would rather have it up the
top because a higher profit, profit
margin is better for us. So this is not
the best setup in this specific state,
it could have been better if this box
hadn't had been higher at the top would
have been better on the other hand in
Victoria you can see that the box part
of the box plot is at the top
meaning that the setup in this business
environment is actually pretty good.
You can see that the box plot is quite
compact. Meaning that there is less
uncertainty in terms of where a random
company went end up in terms of net
profit margin and also you can see that
the median well of course the median is
higher than these two other states but
also you can see that the box part of
the box plot is closer to where we want
to be to the top and as we discussed
that's a good thing. It's better than if
this box part was lower,
so there we go that's how you analyze
box plots and what can we conclude from
here. Well we can say that out of these
three states and since we already
working in or the businesses operating
yourself well out of these three states
it's obvious that this state Victoria is
the better one in terms of expansion in
terms of business environment and this
analysis has been performed based on
competitor research. Now that's not the
end of our challenge, we of course have
to analyze the economies of these states
we have to analyze how the industries
are performing
and other populations are growing
things like that so we will definitely
get to that. This was like the very first
stage and what we want to do now is we want
to use the rest of analysis and
hopefully back this finding that the
business environment seems to be best
for this specific industry at this
specific time in Victoria and I look
forward to in the next tutorial.
Until then, happy analyzing.