Welcome back to the advanced course on
Tableau. In the previous tutorial we
loaded up our data, created some
folders, organized our workspace and
today we're finally starting today we're
talking about groups. Now groups are a
feature in Tableau. I wanted to say
powerful feature but the thing is that
in this course and even in this section
we're going to learn much more powerful
tools that we have at our disposal so
let's just go ahead and call groups a
feature because as you'll see they're
very easy
they're pretty straightforward and
they're essential to know and sometimes
use and we will learn all about them in
today's tutorial. So let's go ahead and
get started and right away we've got a
very unique situation. Here, what we can
see is in our dimensions and this might
not be the case for you if you're doing
this tutorial bit later despite might be
different but just observe in that case
what I have in my Tableau right now if
you go through dimensions you can see
they're all blue except for year founded,
it some, for some reason it is highlighted in
green and as you recall from our
standard course in Tableau dimensions
should be blue and measures should be
green so you can see that measures are
in green here and what this looks like
is a type conversion error by Tableau,
type analysis error by Tableau and
obviously if it's something in here it
should be a dimension so that should be
in blue or it should actually be in
measures and if you drag it onto the
chart, you'll see that it's actually in
green and it is being seen as a measure.
So let's go ahead and fix that, we'll just
take your fun and drag it into
measures and now it's in here but we
actually wanted to be a dimension
because these are the years so when the
companies were found we're not going to be
adding them up or anything. This is more like
a categorical variable for us so we now
we're just gonna drag it back and now
you can see that it's in blue. So there
you go that was a very unique situation
that's like I guess seeing a white
rhinoceros.
Alright let's take a year founded and
drag it into columns, now what we're
going to do is we're going to, we want to
find out how many companies
were founded in each of these
years. So let's go and look for number of
records and drag it into rows and right
away we get a bar chart. That's exactly
what we wanted to see, so as you can see
that the venture capital fund is
analyzing a thousand companies most of
which were founded in 2009 and
onwards and it's still a few were
founded in other previous years.
So now what you might want to do is say
that you want to analyze all of these
together like it it's there so
insignificant that there's no point in
analyzing them separately and for the
purpose of your analysis you want to put
them together you want to put them
together in a group and that is when
groups come into play. So groups are ways
you can combine elements of your
dimension so in this specific case we're
looking at a dimension which is called year
founded and we want to group these
elements  1,9 1999 to 2008. So if you
want to group these years into one group
within this dimension. So basically what that
means is you have to have a dimension to
create a group and now if we select them
or actually need to select the years
themselves and then we put our mouse
over it over any one of them. What you'll
see is in the tooltip you have this
paperclip icon and it says group members.
So let's go ahead and click that. Right
away what you can see is that they have been
combined together and the sum, the total
for those years has been represented
here. So if I right-click now and I
change the name so added alias and I say
before 2009 then now I have a new
element in my dimension and in fact I
have a new dimension so if you look here
this is the old dimension hasn't changed
with this is the new dimension so if I
take the old dimension and drag it instead of
the new dimension we still have the old
chart but now I have a new dimension
which no longer has these years which
only has
a year or a category which represents
all these years. If I drag it here you
will see exactly what I mean that we
only have this category here and now
basically we're working with a new
dimension which only has one two three
four five six seven characters. Now let's
say you wanted to fix up this group,
let's say you wanted to include 2009 in
the group and have 2010 onwards
separately. You can easily do that if you
right-click the group and click edit
group, you can expand this group here and
then just take 2009 and drag it into the
group or alternatively if you drag it
out so you can select here you can
select add to this group and will be
added, then you click apply and there you
go now you just have to of course change
the name of the group because it's not
before 2009, it's a before maybe 2009 and
before.
Alright, so that's how you can create a
group using your chart. Now let's look at
another type of group, when would you
want to create a group? Here we'll just
call this years and this one will call
industries. So here let's look at
industry and we'll put it into rows and
we want to see the total number of
columns or let's say we want to see the
total number of employees in each
industry so we click total over there
and let's say we don't want to look at
sum of employees, we want to look at
the average, average number of employees
in these companies and let's sort it by
number of employees like that. So what
when would we want to create a group
here, well let's say that your industries
here we've got IT services, we've got software
and it was one more somewhere here
computer and hardware so we've got three
in industries which are kind of related
to IT in general. So how about we combine
them into 1
industry. We create a group for that, so
we can do it through the chart so once
again if we select them and we bring all
you have to press control just like them, we
bring up on mouse, we can use this icon
over here or we can go to the industry
dimension and right click it. We go to
create and then go to group and here we
want to select the industries that were
looking for IT services, software and
where was other one computer hardware.
Right so we want to group them and this
one will call it information technology,
click enter and then click apply and now
as you can see nothing has changed here
but that's because we've just created a
new group and we still have to drag it
onto our road shelf. Once again, let's
order that and now we should see that we
have information technology and once
again if we want to add another element
let's say telecommunications very easy
to do you just go to industry group and
edit group and then you find the one you
want to add so here we're looking for
telecommunications and then you just add
to your group and click apply.
Alright so we've learned how to create
groups and how they work
let me show you one more quick thing
because this is an advanced course and I
really want you guys to understand
everything to the depths of the depths
that you that how Tableau works so let's
drag average employees onto a label and
let me just format this quickly so we
can see a bit better and a bit more.
Right so those are average employees
right now in each of the industries. Now
when we group there's always when you're
grouping something that is calculating
average is always a risk or concern
maybe the grouping is going to count
average of averages so let's take two
more for example here let's take
construction and environmental services
right so when we, when I group them,
right now if I if I turn them into group,
will this
resulting category would it have the
average of averages all the average be
calculated correctly so what I mean is
right now there might be 10 companies in
this sector and there might be 5
companies in this sector. So the average
for those five companies is this for the
average for those 10 companies is this
when I group them will Tableau take the
average of these two values or will be
able to take the average of the 15
values? The correct approach would be to
take the average of the 15 values,
let's go ahead and see what Tableau does.
So I'm going to click group and I get
61.1 so let me bring up a calculator and
here we will see what would have
happened. So if I click control z and
now I take 57.9 plus 78.0 divide it by 2 so
this is what the average of averages
would be 67.95. Now if you group them,
we get 61.1 so what that is telling us
is that Tableau is smart. It's not taking
the average of those two averages, it's
actually taking the correct average
number of employees for all the companies
in these two industries and that is
important to understand and also
important to know because that will give
you confidence when you are using groups
that what you essentially done just now
what we've done here is not just put
together the result of aggregation of
the two groups who have actually changed
the metadata. We've changed we haven't
changed the data because we can't
actually choose whatever we do here
doesn't change the data set itself but
we have changed the data the Tableau is
working with, so now in Tableau's
perception these two industries are
actually one industry and all the
companies so 5 plus 10 to 15 companies
belong to that industry and any
aggregations that you do will be done
correctly. So that is why Tableau has
61.1 here.
Alright so that's all for today that's
how you work with groups and that's how
you can use them to adjust your metadata
if that is required and in the next
tutorial we will start talking about
sets. I look forward to seeing you next
time and until then,
happy analyzing.