Welcome back to the advanced course on
Tableau. In the previous tutorial we
talked about table calculations and we
had a look at a few Table calculations
that might be handy we looked at the
quick Table Calculations. Today we're
going to proceed with our challenge and
before we do I wanted to say that they
are other quick table calculations that
are present here, percent difference,
percent of total, rank percentile, moving
average and so on. We will look at some
of them throughout this section but I do
encourage you to explore the rest of
them on your own and just see how they
work.
It will be very similar to what we did
with the running total and difference. It
will just give you a good overview of
what quick table calculations are there
at your disposal if you need them and
for now let's save this worksheet as
Tableau
Calyx testing and let's proceed on with
a new sheet. So, for the new sheet what we
want to do is we want to also take date
time and this time we want it to be a
day like this.
So, basically a proper timeline and we
want to visualize tons once again, but in
this case we want to break it down by
machine. So we'll use color to break it down
machine and also we'll drag machine into
the rows so every machine is in its
separate row.
Ok, so those are our machines actually
let's change this or not day but hour so
we actually see what's happening by hour.
So, those are hour machines that's the
actual tons. Let me format this so we can
see a little bit better and make this a
ten and what we have here is all of the
machines that we are working with. Now
let's do one thing so just follow me
when I do this and I'll explain why are
we doing it literally in a few
minutes. So, we're going to take the
capacity and we're going to match it to
the machine so here you can see the
actual tons and then the capacities come
later.
So now let's just drag the capacity for
the right the correct machine above that
machine so here we've got the nominal
capacity for RL1 and there we go to
actual tons for all RL1 and
let's do that the same thing for the
rest of them as well. So, that's RL2
it goes there.
That's reclaimer 2, that's stacker
reclaimer one, stacker reclaimer  four a and
stacker reclaimer six and so let's just
check rl1, rl2 sr1, sr4a, sr6. Alright,
perfect. So, that is exactly what we want
for now and as you can see the nominal
capacity is constant throughout the
timeline and that is because it is a
nominal capacity doesn't change but the
actual tons that the machine processed is
changing and it's varying somewhere
around that nominal capacity. Now what we
want to do next is to start off with for
us to better understand what's going on
which is going to leave these two. So, we
only going to leave rl1, we're going to
leave the nominal capacity and actual
tons using a filter and then we will
return everything after we have a plan
of attack.
So let's take machine again and put into
filters and now select none and then
just select rl1 and rl1 here and click
okay and what you will see here is now we're
only left with our machine rl1. Now, what
can we do here?
How can table calculations help us solve
the problem?
How can they help us find that idle
capacity and check that threshold for
the a day average and the 10-percent and
so on.
So what we have here is a Table. Let's,
let me show you a quick trick so a handy
tip might produce yellow star over here.
What you can do with this visual to see
it as numbers. Sometimes, sometimes
it might be handy to see the numbers. Even
though most of the time we're trying to go
the opposite way turn numbers into
pictures sometimes you might want to
turn pictures into numbers. So all you
have to do to achieve that is right
click on your sheet and select set of
duplicate sheets. Select duplicate as
crosstab and that will bring up the
numbers or turn the pictures into
numbers so like magic or reverse
magic probably in this case
and let's, let me format this one so that
this was a bit bigger because it might be
more important for us to see what's
going on here.
Okay, so here we've got the nominal capacity
and actual tons
just as in this sheet nominal capacity
actual ton.
Their only difference is here it's a picture,
here it's a very long long table for every
single hour in the month of September
2015. What we want to do is we want to
perform a table calculation on our
actual tons. The table calculation that
we've talked about so far they are
always working across your table so from
left to right and let's run one of
those just to see how we go so if
we take, click here in the drop-down we
click add quick table calculation and we
select for instance running total right?
So, you can see that's how the running
total looks like and if I now switch to
the numbers, what it's doing is just
adding these numbers so here's 4200, here
it's in the second day it's this plus this,
in the third day it's the total so far
plus that and it's the total so far that and so
on and the same thing for the top so nominal
capacity. But, we don't want that to be
honest we need something else.
So, let's look at different color table
calculation.
How about we look at difference right? So,
we've already worked with difference and we
remember that this is showing us the
difference for every single bar compared
to the previous bar or for every single
hour compared to the previous hour. So
let's take a random hour from here so
let's look here. What is it doing? It's
taking this value minus this value.
What is the answer and then it's
plotting it. What is then the for the
next bar? For this bar for September
1st, for 2am it's checking. What is the
difference between this and this and
it's plotting it. So we can simply check it
by looking at September first at 3am the
difference over here we can see it's 250
so for September first 2 or 3 am, it
should be 250. Let's go ahead and check
that. So September first 3 am as you can
see here in the pop up it is 250. So,
that's good but that's good but that's
not helping us. What we actually want is
we want the difference I'm just going to
take this calculator quick table
calculation off. So, clear table calculation
and what we really want is we want the
idle capacity and to get to the idle
capacity the first thing, the first step
would be to find out the difference
between our actual tons and the nominal
capacity so how different is the actual
tons to what it should be and we have a
nominal capacity here and where we have the
actual tons here all we have to do is
somehow find a way to subtract what we
have here from what we have here right?
So far all our table calculations are
going from left to right.
How do we do a table calculation and
goes out from bottom to
top? Because if we look at the table,
these values are in fact in one table.
All we have to do is subtract, instead of
subtracting this from this or
looking for the difference between these
two we have to look for the difference
between these two and then for these
ones these chance on. So we just have to
change the orientation of the way the
table calculation works. And in order to
achieve that, Tableau has a very very
easy functionality. All you have to do is,
so quick table calculation right so same
thing difference right now is doing not
what we want but instead we were going
we're going to say compute using table
down. Right? So right away this disappears
because as you remember the first it has
nothing to compare there's nothing above
it but this whole row is now being
compared to the values above it and
let's have a look in our example just to
make sure that this is what is happening.
So let's have a look at for instance we
could look at here September first at
3am so remember what it used to be 250
because the difference here is 250 but
now the difference should be 0 because
it is actually working at its capacity
the Machine process 4200 tons which is
its maximum so let's check that again. So
September first 3am September first 4am,
3am, so there you can see. Where was that?
there we go September first 3am you can
see that the capacity or the
difference in tons between the actual
tons and the nominal capacity is zero
you can see that in the pop-up. So that
is exactly so here you can see that the
difference is zero. So that is exactly,
what we want as you can see the table
calculations been run from top to bottom.
So let's explore that a little bit
further, if we now go into the drop-down
and not just use these quick controls
but go into the edit table calculation
window. What you will see here is that
you have the same controls but they're
all nice see together and here what it's
telling us is we used to have a cross
difficult apply. Once again you see that
old visual where it's calculating like
that but now it's calculating down. So
it's taking the difference from the
previous. Some not from the next, not from the
first, not from the last, but from the
previous and in this case because we
arranged it remember this is this is the
answer to why we arranged it that way. We
specifically put the nominal capacity
above the actual capacity so that when
we do this table calculation the nominal
capacity is the one that's being
subtracted for the correct machine of
course. So, that is what we're doing table
down. Now let's go ahead and will close
this for now but we'll return to it in a
second now we're ready to return
everything we had right so let's get rid
of this filter and i'm just going to
drag it out of here and what you will
see now is all of the values are back
now this might look a bit confusing so
to start off with let's take this
table calculation and clear table
calculation. So once again what we have
is nominal capacity for the machine
actual tons, normal capacity for the
second machine actual tons and so on.
Now what we want to do is return a table
calculation so quick table calculation
difference and we want you can view
choosing table down. So, now what it's doing
is it's taking same thing as we have,
we want.
It's taking the actual tons and
subtracting the nominal capacity that
was above then for this one same actual
tons minus nominal capacity,
actual ton minus normal capacity that
reason why the nominal capacity looks weird
right now. Well first one here
obviously because there's nothing above
it but then for the nominal capacity the
same thing, same calculation is being
performed. The nominal capacity, the value you
see here the picture the visualization
is representing the difference between
nominal capacity for machine to minus
actual tons machine one. Which
doesn't make any sense right? So, there's
no point in subtracting the nominal and
actual for two different machines and
that is a side effect of these table
calculations because sometimes in your
table you might not need this result and
that's not a problem for us because we
don't need to look at these nominal
capacities anymore with use them in our
table calculation and now we can get rid
of them and all you have to do is select
the nominal capacities all of the rows
with nominal capacity using control so
holding down control your keyboard and
if you right-click and don't click
exclude because that way you will
exclude them from the whole calculation
and you'll exclude them from the table  and that
will mess up this table calculation,
which is being run downwards through
your table. What you want to do is hide,
so you want to simply hide them. There's
they're still participating in your
table calculation the only thing is that
they are no longer visible.
That's all, and what we have in front of
us now is the difference that we were
after. So this is the idle capacity is
not really expresses in a percentage not
yet, but it is expressed is a idle
capacity in tons. So you can see, how much
idle capacity in every single hour each
single one of the machines had. So that
is a great start, that is our very first
step towards our goal and in the next
tutorial we will continue on from here. I
look forward to seeing you next time
until then, Happy analyzing.