Hello and welcome back to the advanced
course in Tableau. Now that we've talked
about theory of level of detailed
calculations. I hope that you can see
that they are very, very simple even
though this sounds like a very complex
topic and that it's a challenging
skilled monster Tableau in reality level
of detail calculations are not that hard
we've already talked about the theory
and now we're going to move on to the
practical side of things so that you
will also see that they're very easy to
create in Tableau and my goal is that by
the end of this section you should very
easily navigate across these level of
detail calculations and that you should
be able to create them even without
looking into any sheet, sheets or looking
up formula. So that you'll know on an
intuitive level, how each one of the
level of detail calculation that you
want to create, how it should work. So
let's get straight into it.
In this case, we've got a map at the
level of granularity of the state, so
let's save it here as a map and which is
going to duplicate this sheet and now
we're going to in this sheet we're going
to actually going to call it LOD,
level detail calculation, include. So
we're going to talk about the include,
type of LOD here and what we're going to
do? Well what we want to do,  is we want to
get, we want to keep the visualization at
the level of aggregation at, at state so
that is our bottom line that is our
foundation of what we're building here.
The visualization has to stay at this
level of aggregation we cannot go down
or up in our aggregation, but at the same
time we want to perform some sort of
calculation at the level of granularity
or aggregation of a city. So we want
to perform a calculation at this level
but our visualization has to stay at
this level and the calculation and we
want to perform is, so let me just go
back here, the calculation we want to
perform is we want to take all of the
profits for each city so for all the
orders and all of the items that was
holding any given city for example here
and we want to sum it up and then once
we've got sum so as we can see here
this is actually what we're after we're
after the sum of the profit and then we
want to take the average across each of
the states. So for instance in North
Dakota the final number that we want to
see for that state is an average of 2678,
4400 and minus 76. So
these three cities,
that's the sum of profit for that city.
That sum of profit for all of the
orders all the items in that city and by
the way don't forget that here in this
data set we've actually got many, many
years. So we've got order date and if you
put that in filters and look at years
you'll see that we've got four years
here.
So in reality what this 4,400 represents
is that is the sum of the profit for
every single item in every single order
for every single year for the City of
Mandan in North Dakota, same thing here, this
is the sum of all every single item in
every single order for every single year.
This is the summer for every single item
for every single order for every single
year. So that's the sum of profit and
What we want as a final number is the
average for the State. The same thing
here Colorado, same thing for Wyoming,
same thing for Utah for every single
State we want to average out. The sums of
profits that were incurred in the cities
of that state. So there we go now we know
what we want.
How do we create that? So we have to be
at the State level and the first thing
that pops to mind is how about we just
take instead of sum of profit. We take
average of profit. So let's change this here
to average, let's change this here to
average. Now if you've been following
along with the logic, so this could be
changed this font to 12 and bold so we
can see better, if you've been following
along with logic you will notice that
this is not what we want. The average of
profit is taking the average of
profit for every single order. So let's
say in North Dakota, it is taking the
average of all of the orders inside
North Dakota. So let me open up
the data set here and so let's say we
were sort of by City actually by state
where the State? Must be somewhere here
State, so let's find North Dakota, Ok
North Carolina, North Dakota so what it
is doing currently?
What it's doing currently is it's taking
all of these orders is quite a lot of
them here is taking all of these orders
for North Dakota that's North Carolina
again, let's go back there it is, so it's
taking all the orders for North Dakota,
which we can see are over here and it's
taking the average of all of the profits
so there's a profit column taking the
average of these profits. That's not
what we want, we want these rows to be
broken down into City. So we want the sum
of these rows for Dickinson, the sum of
these rows for Grand Forks. The sum of
these rows from Mandan. We want to
aggregate at the level the city first,
and then we want to take the average. So it
will be the average of the City profit.
Right now we're seeing the average of
the item profits,  so it's not even at the
order levels at the item level and that
is where it's going wrong so but at the
same time we're going to keep this
visualization so we can compare the
final result. So I'm going to crew
duplicate this map, I'm going to hold
down longitude, hold down control and drag
it to the right and that duplicates the
map, creates a dual-axis chart for these
maps and now what we not a dual-axis
chart it actually creates two charts
side-by-side for a dual-axis. We need to
click to dual-axis here, but like this is
just two charts side-by-side, two maps
side-by-side, so that's a handy little
trick and what we want is we're going to
keep the one on the right which is so
here you can see there's two drop down, so
the one on the right we're going to keep
it without the LOD calculations so we're
actually going to add a annotation here.
We're going to click area annotation
we'll say without LOD calculation, make
this bold, make this 22 in size, make
it red,
and let's make it like this.
There you go and here we'll also change
will format it so right click format,
border, give it a border, a thicker border, make
it rounded, there we go.
So that's what followed to LOD
calculation. This one we're going to
change and we're going to include an LOD
calculation, so let's get to it this is
the fun part.
So what do we want to create? Want to
create an LOD calculation for the profit
of the City. So we're going to click here,
we're going to click create, calculated
field, we'll call it LOD usually would
say something like LOD city profit but
in our case we're going to explore
different types of LOD's and we're
learning so I'm just going to add some
additional information for our own
benefits. I'm going to call it LOD include
City profit. So we know that this is an
LOD of the type include for the city
profit. Again you don't have to do that
in your actual work all the time but
this is just for learning purposes and
here we're going to write off formula
and the way these formulas work is is
actually very very straightcforward. You
first thing you need to do is you
need curly braces and that is your level
of detailed calculation, is going to go
inside the curly braces and here you
need to first specify the cure, so it's
either going to include, exclude or fixed.
So in our case we want include. Then
you want to specify that dimension that
you want to include. So in our case we
already have state, we want to add a two
from where we are now remember the
absolute and relative paths. So we're
creating a relative kind of relative
path if we take thinking folder terms
which is our little analogy to remember
these things in terms of parts we're
creating a relative path we want to go
down a level to Cities. So we want to
say here in square brackets, we want to say
City and then you put a cold one, so this
is your condition. You want to include
city and then you're going to say here
what you want to do. So you once we get
to the level of city, we want to sum up
at the level of granularity of city, we want
to sum up. What you want to sum up? I want
to sum up profit right and that's all
there is to it so you can see the
calculations valid so here we want we
want to sum up profit at the level of
granularity which is our current
visualization plus we want to include
city in our current visualization so
bear in mind that if you change your
visualization this result might also
change because you might go up include
some other view aggregations and so on
so this result is dynamic it changes with
your visualization, but in addition to
all of the measures that you have in
your visualization already
it will include an additional one which is
called the City. Alright so we click OK
here and there is our LOD include so
let's make some more room here so that
they fit in and now instead of so in
this in this map not in this map in this
map instead of average profit.
We're going to do an average, so here is
doing sum that's not wonder what
we want average of the LOD so the full
of profit to some profit for the City so
again we want here average and so now
I'm going to add an annotation area and
so here I'm going to say with LOD
calculation, size again 22, there you go 22 whoa see that
again doesn't want that way, Alright
22, color red.
Okay and make some room, like that and
now we're going to format it as well so
make it border red nearly there around
it.
There we go so that's with LOD
calculation, that's without LOD
calculation and let's have a look at the
result. So here you can see that this for
instance for North Dakota it doesn't
stand out at all and what are these
other states Louisiana and Nevada,
they don't they don't stand out here.
They they're kind of like
everything else but here right away they
stand out very clearly because the
average profit per City is different to
the average profit so that the average
profit across cities in each state is
different to the average profit across
all items in each State. So here's only
57.4 dollars but actually it is much
higher than the across in than in other
States, it's the average profit across
the cities of North Dakota is actually
2,334 and that is what we were after.
So as you can see the results are
different here and not only are they, they are
proportionately different. You can see
that this visualization gives us
additional insights on top of this
visualization or that you actually gives
us the insights that we were after.
So hopefully that makes sense and
hopefully that gives you some
understanding of how to or an idea of
how to use level of detail calculations,
the main thing we're after here is
the syntax so let's have a look at it
again so we'll edit it. So it's very simple,
so curly braces include then the
dimension or dimensions and we'll talk
about this further down in section that
you want to include in addition to your
current visualization the colon and then what
you want to do there. So this is
specifying the level of granularity
which you want to get to, as if you
were going to change your visualization
but you're actually not this is all
happening in the background and this is
what formula you want to apply at that
level of granularity and then this whole
thing will bring you back that result. So
it's very very simple this is.. was our
very first LOD calculation. We talked
about include and further down the section
we're going to discuss the other two.
Hope you enjoy today's tutorial and I
can't wait to see you on the next one
make sure to spend some time to play
around with this try some other
dimensions, try to include some other
dimensions just so you have some
practice because practice is what leads
to mastering and see you next time.
Until then,
happy analyzing!