In the previous tutorial, we applied the
data source filter and you can see that
it's applied here because there's a
number one here and that will allow us
to work with a smaller data set so
less rows and do all the pre-work and
then when we're ready we'll remove this
filter and then all the rows will go
through the same visualizations that we
have prepared. And today we're going to
do a pivot, we're going to create a pivot
for our columns. So as you can see the data
set is not in the best format for
machines and we're going to fix that, so as
we are used to we're going to select all
the columns that we want to pivot and
there's a lot of them this time we'll
click this drop-down and select pivot
and there we go
everything has been done. So let's make
some more space here and of course we
want to rename these so this is pivot
field notes for now, we won't to name this
one. We'll rename this one, so we rename it
to turn over millions of dollars because
remember we remove that row telling us
that this is in millions of dollars.
Alright, so now what is this column
contain. Well it's got the word
turnover which is kind of useless to us
because we already know that we're
dealing with turnover there but also has
the state and it's got the clothing or
it's got to the industry and now we want
to separate that information so how do
we do it? Well we already know it's very
simple we click the drop-down and we
just select split and there we go now we
have our columns and they have been
split, so here you've got the state and
here you've got the industry and that's
exactly what we want. So you can see
Tableau's actually smart
it's not even included a column for the
word turnover separately because it
would have been the same for every
single row. So now we can hide this
column because we don't need it anymore
and we can work with these two so let's
rename them this was going to be state
as instead of Australia and this one's
going to be industry. And there we go,
that is all we needed to do. Our data set
is now ready for analysis and we'll jump
straight into it in the next tutorial. I
look forward to seeing you next time and
until then happy analyzing.