Hello welcome back to the advanced
course in Tableau. In the previous
tutorial we discussed the first level of
detail calculation which was include
level of detail calculation. I hope you
enjoyed the tutorial and you picked up
quite a few new things from there and
most importantly I hope you had the
opportunity to revise what we learned
and to some additional practice and
today we're going to have a very quick
tutorial which will allow us to
understand the attribute function or the
ATTR function in Tableau and we'll find
out what it's for because in the coming
tutorials when we talk about the exclude
and the fixed level of detail
calculations we will actually need that
function in our work we'll be using it so
it's a good idea to quickly revise or
learn what it does.
Alright so let's get straight to it, I'm
going to take the map that we have here
I'm going to duplicate sheet and move it
here and I'll just call it
ATTR Investegation and so as you
can see we're kind of not even bothering
with the level of detail calculations at
this stage we just want to understand
the ATR and what it does.
So let me show you first what I'm
talking about, if I take for example city
here and I drag it into color or that's
a bit too much here let's say into
detail then what will happen is it will
change my visualization, right? It will
change the level of granularity of
visualization if I can do the same
thing, I can do well let's try color so I
was able to drag city into color as you
can see it's again so if I take city if
I remove city,
let's just remove it this way if I
remove city we're back at the previous
level of granularity added to color and
now it's my level of granularity has
changed again or I can do the same trick
let's just do this field map
and now if I do city and or actually had
profit here so let's put profit on to
color and for this city and put on the
size, you can see that that changes again
my level of granularity. So basically I'm
showing you that all these options, all
of these boxes that you can select from
they will change the granularity of your
visualizations, so will the columns and rows.
What won't change is the tool tip over
here, so if I take city and drag onto
tooltip it won't change the level of
aggregation but it will add the city
dimension into your tool tips. So if you
go over any state you'll see and you
call a new line appear here which says
city, and in this case it says just star.
So this is what we're going to talk
about, why does it say star and what is
this
ATTR over here what is this function?
What does it do? So in order to give us
some assistance we're going to bring up
the Tableau help so you can just go to help,
open help or click f1 and then brings it
up in a browser and now we're here at
the top we're going to search for ATTR.
We're going to go to aggregate functions
and there is ATTR and then expression,
so what does it do? It returns the value
of the expression if it has a single
value for all rows.
Otherwise, returns an asterisk, null values
are ignored and so what what does this
mean and how do we work with this?
Well let's think about it, if we added 80
we added city to our map right but if we
know that in every single state there is
there are multiple cities so there's no
way that Tableau can just pick one of
those cities for instance in North
Dakota we know that there's three cities.
How is Tableau going to pick one of the
cities and split over here for us? It
can't do that right so that's why it's
specifying a star because it there's no
unique city in the city in that state is
not unique it cannot do that for us it
cannot just pick around the city, it's just
the star is telling us that there are
multiple options and you can just apply
one of them, whereas if we take this out
and let's say for example we take
country and we put country into the
tooltip, now we know that in every single
state or across the whole database
actually we have only one country which
is United States and so therefore the
country's working fine the country
dimension and our tool tip is working
fine because there isn't Tableau doesn't
have to make a choice even know that
there is a certain aggregation that is
happening and rows of our data set out
being aggregated to this state all of
those rows have the same country and
therefore Tableau can apply that same
another country here. That is exactly
what that Tableau help illustrate for us.
Returns the value of expression has single
value for all rows.
Let's try another one, let's remove
country and let's say we'll try region.
So region is not part of our
geographical hierarchy but same time
region is you know west or east of
central and so on so let's add it to our tooltip.
Let's have a look here, so you can see
region west, region west, region central
region central, region south, south and
region east. So it is working because it is,
the data set instruction such a way that
all of the social take any given state if
you take where are we? Where are the state? You
take any given state there, for example
Alabama you'll see that every single row
in that state has the region south so and
that would that is what the ATTR
function does. The way to think whether
the way I think of it is
ATTR, it applies or it pastes a certain
value from your rows onto your
aggregated mark. So here we've got states,
that's we've got 49, you can see on the
left here, we've got forty nine marks and so if
there's an opportunity to do so,
ATTR will paste
the mark on to your or it will paste the
value that you're after on to your state and
ATTR doesn't have to be applied just with
the tooltip. You can apply you'll see it
to come up here and there, not
just the tooltip in other calculations
and that's what we'll see inside this
section but it's just quickest way to
demonstrate this function is through the
tooltip. Alright so hopefully that makes
sense, so ATTR basically if the values
are unique it all if there's only one
value for all of the rows that are being
aggregated it will use that value if the
values are different so if there's at
least two different values for the
aggregate rows for instance in
California there's many different cities
it will just give you a star indicating
that it couldn't the function can be
applied properly. So that's how the ATTR
function works and we'll be using it in
this section of the course. I hope you
enjoyed today's tutorial and I look
forward to seeing next time. Until then,
happy analyzing.