Hello and welcome back to the advance
course on Tableau. Now that we've
prepared our data set and our connection
we can go ahead and create the main
visualization that we'll be using for
this data. So let's go ahead and do that,
we're going to create a new sheet and
this one we will call industry analysis.
Alright and what do we want to see here.
Well to start off with, let's visualize
the month of the year. So first of all
let's rename this column to something
else,
so let's say date and now let's
visualize this date column here but
we're going to look at rather than
looking at years because our data
at month level we're going to just like
this month the green one.
So we get timeline, now we're going to
look break our data down by state. So
there we go, that's every single state we
have here and be careful there is a
total for states so we'll get back to
that but just take a mental note of that
there's a total and then we're going to
take industry or throw it in here as
well and so here we've got the
industries and they're broken down by
states and all we have to do is add the
turnover and also bear in mind that
there is a total for industries here as
well. So now let's take the turnover and
add it to our visualization. We'll put it in
here as you can see it's not showing as
anything. It's completely flat, if you
scroll down you'll see why and that is
because sometimes it's not flat and that
is mostly for the total. So the totals
are much greater and therefore they're
completely overwhelming the rest of the
visualization that is because every you
can see that every single chart here has
the same axis range and to fix
that we have to give them independent
axis so that they wouldn't
have they wouldn't calculate the axis
range based of the most volatile I
guess call a row that we have, so right
click click edit access and select set
automatic, select independent axis
range for each row or column click ok
and there we go that's what we wanted
what we wanted to see. One more thing,
let's take industry hold down control put
it into color and there we go much
better.
So what we're seeing here is for the
years that we specified in our data source
filter, we're seeing the turnover for
every single industry so there you go
that's clothing and retailing that's
department stores that's electrical and
electronic goods and so on and also
broken down by state. So now this is
great. This is our visualization but as you
remember we applied a datasource filter
to simplify or expedite our analysis to
get us to this point and now it's the
time to remove that filter. If this was a
very quick journey for us we got here
quickly in other cases you might want to
keep the data source filter for longer if
your visualization is more complex but
for us it is a good time to get of the
filter, so let's go ahead and do that. You
can go to the data source and get rid of
it there or you can right-click your
data said here or connection here
and click edit data source filters select
the filter and click remove, click ok and what
you'll see is that all of the missing
rows have been added back and now our
data set is, our visualization is being
presented
be for the whole period between 1982
and 2015. So these nulls are just
nulls in our data set because some you
scroll down you'll see some industries
didn't have information for a certain
period of time so we're just going to
click that and are actually going to
right click and click hide indicator so
it's not bothering us. There we go so
those are our industries and as you can
see this is already a very exciting data
set.
I'm going to what I'm going to do is I'm
going
to actually I was going to make some
more room for the visual but there isn't
anything that we can actually take out.
Anyway so it is a pretty exciting
data set because you can select an
industry and you'll see how in that
state it is it has it has been changing
all the sales or the turnover in that
industry how they've been the dynamics
how they've been changing between 1982 and 2015
and this is all actual real data
taken off the Australian Bureau of
Statistics website. So let's let's play
around with this and let's see what we
can find just have fun insights from
this real-world data. So there's a
Australian capital territory and the Australian
capital territory isn't a big
state so what would want to do right
what we would want to do is we'd either
want to look at a big state like
New South Wales or we'd want to look at
Australia over all right? And normally what
you would think to do to get a straight
overall you just take the state out of
your visualization right so I'll just
take a drag someone here to get rid of
it and that would add up so because we
have sum here to add up the turnover
for all the states right so and that's
not make sense you add up the turnover
for let's say what I say household goods
and retailing you add up a turnover for
all the states and then you get the
total but here this would be a mistake
and in reality the turnover is not that
great for this industry and that is
because as we saw previously what I
pointed out is that we have the totals
in this data set so this data set
contains totals for all the states so
let's take the state column back and put
it in here and what you'll find is if
you scroll down so you gotta straighten
capital territory over there so if I
keep scrolling down, you got New South Wales.
I might make this a bit bigger so
you can see. There we go, we've got New
South Wales there so if I keep scrolling
on Northern territory Queensland, South
Australia, Tasmania and you've got
total so this is not even though this
this is a more states down there like
Victoria, Western Australia but here
you've got total set and be careful that
sometimes statistical data especially it
contains already the total so if you
were to take out the state column and
think that's a total you'd be double
counting so we don't want to double
count and we'll just look
explore our data for this state
which is total so for the whole Australia
basically so you can see that cafes and
restaurants have been growing, cafes and
restaurants and take away food sources
growing as well there you know it's a
lower-level actually 3 billion
dollars the turnover is like monthly
turn over 3.3 and here it's only 2.1 so
clothing and retailing that's
very interesting right so what can you
see here this is this pattern right what
is this pattern and this is and you can
see it's it's evident in a lot of
industries this kind of like a saw. It's
going up and down up and down and it's
obviously a seasonal pattern and what
what is happening here why is it always
this spike what's going on?
So that's very interesting and this
knowledge actually might be able to some
sometimes, something apply in your future
work if you look at the pattern you'll
see that the peak always occurs in
December right? So that's when people are
preparing for Christmas for new years,
they're buying presents and they're
spending a lot of money because
everything's on discount, you've got
boxing day, you've got lots and lots of
reasons to spend money and where is
always the troll right? Where is it? And
the the bottom it's always in February
so February and this is, this is actual,
this is actually how it is in reality
February is the worst month for retail
and if you work or any of you working
the retail industry you will be able to
confirm this. February is the worst month
not January but February and why is that
and that is because that is when people
have our help paying off their credit
cards for the purchases that made in
December so that is when
all that the time has passed and the
time has come to pay off credit cards
and people are very conservative for
their spending. So that is a very
interesting pattern and you can actually
see it here from real data so if
you're a retail store and you just open
up. Be prepared that February is going to
be your worst month and that is because
everybody spent their money in December.
So that's not only retail, you've got
whatever got a department electronic,
food retailing, similar
patterns right? So liquor household
goods retailing another interesting
thing is disruption so we can observe
through these parents or through this
data how we visit visualize that we
can observe actual destruction of whole
industries and here you've got an
example a newspaper and book retailing.
So what happened as the technology is
progressing you can see that book
retailing was growing up until the early
nineties so in the nineties already
started flooding out computers got,
personal computers got introduced still
growing a bit and then in 1995 like it
start flattening out there was a bit of
growth here,newspapers and so on and
now since 2010 boom it's going all the
way down right? So there is destruction
of an industry happening in real time
and that is you know all the iPads,
iPhones. How internet's taking over so
newspapers and books are not selling as
well anymore it's going down so that's
an interesting insight as well. So feel
free to play around with that and have a
look at this data that's really
interesting look at the industry's maybe
you'll find an interested you work in an
industry you work in or your
friends working or an industry you're
interested in and have a look and see
what you can find what interesting
insights you can derive from here and we
will continue on with our analysis in
the next tutorial and until next time, happy
analyzing.