Hello and welcome back to the advanced course
on Tableau. In today's tutorial we're
going to continue with the level of
detail calculation which is exclude and
we're actually going to drive some
insights or change this visualization to
be useful to drive insights.
Alright so let's have a look what do we
do we have so far? So far we know that
we've been able to bring the profit for
the whole state down to the level of
this granular and aggregation which is a
city. So as you can see the value for all
the cities here is the same within each
state, but now how can that be useful?
What we can do is we can take the profit
for the state and city which we know we
can calculate and then divide it by this
value that we brought back and that will
give us the proportion or the portion of
the profit that that city brought into
the overall profit for that state.
Alright so here it's a good, it's good
that we have this visualization on the
side so let's first of all duplicate the
sheet and we'll call this LOD exclude
part 2 and it's good that we have this
on the side here so I'm going to zoom
into North Dakota and actually I'm going
to go to all here and change the label,
size make it 12 and bold and so here you
can see that we've got the profit for
the state we've been able to
successfully bring it down to this
higher level of granularity which is the
city and here we have the actual profit
for each of the cities. So which is just
a simple sum profit, as you can see
there and what we want to do is want to
take this number and divide by this
number for every single city and
visualization and what that will give us
is it will give us the portion of the
profit that each city contributed to the
total profit of the state right so let's
do that. Again we're going to only work
with the visualization on the left and
let's get straight into it. So ready to
go open it up
and here so we no longer want that value
right? We actually want
let's say, let's take profit for now and
we'll drag it into label and here we
just double-click and do a calculation
right inside this item we're going to
say divide that by as you remember we
had the ATTR function because we need
some sort of aggregation and then we're
going to do
LOD exclude state profit. That's what
we want.
So let me just expand this bit more so
we can see it.
These are very handy is a very handy way
to do calculations just that ours is
quite long so we got sum profit and
we're dividing it by ATTR and so we need
ATTR we discussed that previously, dividing it
by this value of the state profit that
we're bringing from a different level of
aggregation. Click OK and now we also
drag this into color and we can actually
drag it into size as well. So there we go,
so this is the start. This is a good start
actually let's get rid of the second
chart because we don't need it.
There's nothing to compare to in this
case. So we're going to take this and
remove it and that way we only have this
one chart left so now if I look at what
we have here it's a good start because
we can already see like for instance
0.382 right. So I can take the profit
and just added into somewhere where you
can add it if I added into the tooltip
for example, just sum profit in the
tooltip, here I can see that profit is
2,678 and also let's take the state
profit and put into the tooltip as well.
I know this is getting quite large but
it should all make sense so we've just
got the state.
We've got the calculation as a label, the
calculation as the size, the calculation
so that a ratio that percentage as the
color as well and then we've got the
calculator and then we're going to some
profit as the tooltip and the sum
profit of the state as a tooltip so if
we take the city for instance here.
Dickinson we can see that the state
profit is 7,002 the profit is 2,678 and so the
sum of profit divide it by the sum of state profit is
thirty-eight percent three-eight-point-two
percent which seems about right.
So 2,678, 2,678 let's bring up a calculator,
let's just check this right, 2,678 divide it by 7,002
38.2 yeah so that's that's correct and
that's also correct and then if you add
these up then you should get a total of
one which also seems to be the case
which is good. The thing that is not exactly
right here or is a bit misleading on
this visualization like visualization is
pretty much completed this is what we
are after but the thing there's a few
misleading things on this visualization
so going to move this here so we have
some room.
What's misleading number one is that
Tableau is creating this size legend
base starting from like it's taking
negative values has very low and in size
and then going up to high values which
is going up to like all the way too high
values and by the way it is normal that
we can have like a value greater than 1
because we can have negative values and
the cancel each other out but what this
isn't what we want we want to see so
even if it's a negative profit we want
to see it as a big circle rather than
tiny circle which won't be able to
notice right? We'll we'll be able to tell
that it's negative because of the color,
but we don't want it to be also very
small so let's go to correct that so we
need to correct this one over here which
is which contains the size and so how
we're going to do that? Well we're just going
to double click in here
and we're just going to add another
formula here we're going to say abs for
the absolute value of this so the ratio
might be negative but then if you take
the absolute value it'll be positive always so
if you click that now the visualization
is much better right so now big circle
is a big percentage regardless of
whether it's positive or negative and
then the color will tell us if it's
positive or negative.
This brings us to the second misleading
thing that we can see here is that let's
say if we have a state, so if we go to states
here, the state has a positive profit so
never like North Dakota or California
you can see that yes it all makes sense
this is positive and then this one is
negative.
Let's look at, I'm gonna let's look at
another one that's a that's the Arizona
here right so it's got a positive profit
685 and here so you've got the negative
has an orange color and any positives
has a blue color right? So that that
makes sense but now if we take a state
which actually has a total negative
profit so great examples Wyoming right
so zoom into Wyoming and let me have a
look at the map so here you can see it's
minus 3,655 so it's a total negative
profit and if you look at this at the
colors here you can see that the 1.533
if you look at the profit, it's negative but
the color is blue so the value that
affect the value is positive that's good
that just means that this city
contributed 153% of the total
profit of Wyoming and this city
contribute minus fifty three percent so
in total it's it's a solid one that's
fine but what is concerning is that this
color is blue so it's kind of hinting at
that Rock Springs had a positive profit
which is not the case, Rock Springs had a
minus style and 5600 dollars profit
whereas this city I hope I'm pronouncing
this right,
Cheyenne had a positive profit so why does
this happen? Well let's look at the
calculation for color what we're doing
here is we're taking now
we're taking the profit right so we're
taking a profit for the city and we're
dividing it by the profit for the state
so in the case when the profit for the
state is positive so in that case if the
profit for the city is positive then
it's going to be positive and going to
be blue if the plus profit for the
city's negative is still negative
divided by positive is still going to be
part of negative is going to be red
orange, but in the case when the profit
for the state is negative everything
reversed, so if this is negative then if the
city profit is positive then you have
positive divided by negative gives us
negative and if the city profit is
negative that's negative divided by
negative and gives us positive and
that's reversal of what we want. So here
what we want to do is we want to take
this and want to correct it we want to
multiply this whole thing by the sign of
this value there you go, those too many
brackets so I'm just going to take this
whole calculation and so let's bring up
a word document and I'm going to copy
here and so we're going to discuss it
what's going on here so this part we
discussed already so we've got sum
profit divided by the ATTR of so the sum so
basically the profit of the city divided the
profit of the state and it should make
sense by now how this can be when the
state profit is negative how this is all
mixed up.
Well this sign basically plus or minus
of the state profit fixes
everything, so if the state profit's
positive, this is a one and nothing
changes which is good if the state
profit is negative then it will again
reverse everything and will give us the
final result that we want.
So a bit of a trick here and therefore
as you can see now we've got the good
colors now in Wyoming. This is orange
meaning that this city had a negative
profit and this is blue meaning ahead
positive product and there we go so that
is how we actually leveraged a level of
detail.
They should exclude to bring information
from a higher level of aggregation so
from the level of aggregation of state
protect this way from here
don't don't mind these colors this is
just because I messed up the
visualization right now so I mix it up
and I just, just to illustrate that we
brought this report values from here
into this chart and that's what we're
after and moreover we were able to use
those values to create these ratios and
colors and sizes which will now show us
which cities in their respective states
had the biggest impact. So this is a way
to kind of normalize our analysis right?
So even though cities might have
different actual values so for instance
here 48.5 percents or nearly fifty
percent of the total profit is actually
only 332 dollars whereas let's say
here
thirty-eight percent even less in top as
higher 2,678 but that's because the
state profit is higher, seven thousand
dollars and here it's only 605 so
basically we're normalizing by state
profit and then now we can compare we
can say regardless of the absolute
figures in relative terms which of these
cities are performing really well in
their respective states or really badly
in their respective states. You can see
this city's performing really bad. This city is
performing bad. This city is performing well.
This city is performing really
well, very well as well so it's this
visualization shows us which cities to
focus on and then which ones to leave
alone or to try to even further improve
on or which cities like little ones
maybe they're not doing anything so that
there's there isn't much demand for our
products in those season maybe that's
the point of concern or something so
this is a very, very powerful
visualization and it does combined
calculations from little different
levels of aggregation. So there we go,
that is the second type of level of
detail calculation as you can see this
one is a you even though it's
conceptually simpler in this case we
were able to create a very complex
visualization I'll say using this level
of detail calculation. I highly encourage
you to take some time before you go to
the next tutorial to actually practice
these things to maybe you try recreates
again just for practice sake for use some
of the other dimensions that we have
other measures to practice creating
another level of detail calculation of
the type exclude just so that this
knowledge sinks in and after that I look
forward to see you in the next tutorial
and until then happy analyzing.