Hello and welcome to the Data Structures and
Algorithms Using Java course. My name is
Tim Buchalka and I'm the instructor in
this course. Now I wanted to make this
video because you'll probably be
surprised when you go onto the next
video and see that there's another
instructor who's created the videos the
reason for that is fully explained in an
announcement that I sent out towards the
end of January 2019 because there's a
link to that announcement in the
resources section for this video that's
at the top left so click on that if you
want to find out the full details but I
just wanted to make it clear very
quickly that the bottom line is I've now
taken over the course and I'm going to
be releasing new content moving forward
in this course as well as updating it
now if you've seen a good portion of
this course already I suggest you go
down towards the end of the
course, the last section and there's a
lecture there with
a link to a survey and that survey will
alone enable you to give me some
feedback on what you like and dislike
about the course what you'd like to see
added updated etc. If you could take a
moment to update that once you've seen a
good portion of the course or some of
the course that would be great because
then I could start working on this new
content I'm really committed to making
this the best possible course on Data
Structures and Algorithms using Java
that I possibly can so with your help we
can actually do this together
so in terms of support nothing else is
going to change I've got another person
who's helping me, Goran, he's going to be
helping me as a co-instructor and
answering the questions
you have in the
course in the Q&amp;A section so look out
for him as well and we're here again to
teach you everything we can about data
structures and algorithms so that's it I
just wanted to give you a bit of an
update as to what's going on with the
course for now though, proceed to the next
video and you can get started
I look forward to seeing you as we work
forward in the next coming months updating the content
Cheers for now.