Alright so now we're going to handle
the case of deleting 2 children
and because we have a recursive method
it's easy to do.
It's actually longer to explain what we're doing
than it is to implement it.
So let's add case three.
The left child is null, we've handled it here.
If the right child is null, we've handled it here.
If both of these conditions fail,
that means that we have a node with two children
and so down here we're gonna handle that case.
So case three node to delete has two children
and of course because we return in both of these blocks,
we won't make it down here
unless we haven't returned from the method yet.
And so what do we want to do?
We want to do what we discussed in the slides.
So we want to find the minimum value in the right subtree
and we can do that just by calling the min method,
that's why I wanted the min method,
to just return an int.
Here's the min method down here.
And so what we're going to do is
we're going to say subtree route.
Remember at this point subtree route
is the route that we want to delete
and so what we want to do is we want to replace the value
in the subtree root node with the
smallest value from the right subtree.
Because if we replace it with
the smallest value from the right subtree
we know that everything remaining in the right subtree
will be greater than the subtree root
and so the characteristic of the
binary search tree is preserved.
And so we're not actually going to rewire any nodes,
were not gonna physically take
the replacement node and move it in the tree.
Instead we're just going to set the data
of the existing node to the value of the replacement node
and then we're going to delete the replacement node.
And so we're going to say subtreeRoot.setdata
and we want to set it to the minimum
value in the right subtree
so we're going to say subtreeRoot.getRightChild.min.
And so this finds us the minimum value in the right subtree
and we're going to replace the value
of the node were deleting with that value
and then we have to delete the replacement node.
So how are we going to do that?
Well we're going to use our delete method.
I mean we know the root of the subtree
that we want to search for the value,
we have it right here.
It's actually the subtreeRoot.getRightChild
and we know the value we want to delete.
It's now the subtreeRoot.getData.
And so all we have to do is say subtreeRoot.setRightChild
and we're gonna call our delete method,
that should be subtreeRoot,
and we're gonna call
our delete method and we're gonna pass it
our subtreeRoot.getRightChild
and the value we want to delete is subtreeRoot.getData.
Replace the value in the subtreeRoot node
with the smallest value from the right subtree
and then delete the node that has
the smallest value in the right subtree
because obviously, conceptually what we're doing is
we're moving the node with the smallest
value in the right subtree, we're moving it
to the root of this subtree
and so we need to delete it from its old position.
And so what we're doing here is
we're not actually physically moving the node,
we're just replacing the value with the minimum value
and then we need to delete the node
that contains that minimum value
and we're just gonna do that by calling our delete method.
And so we're going to replace the right child
of the node that was the deleted node,
we didn't physically delete it of course,
but we're gonna replace it's right child.
Now if this subtree has a lot of levels to it,
then this will end up being a redundant replacement
but if we have a situation where the node
that is the smallest value is the immediate child
then this will actually result in the
right child being set to something new, and that's it.
That's all we need to do to handle the case of 2 children.
And so now that we have a delete method
that's handling all the cases,
let's go to the main method and try this out.
I'm going to comment these out and
I'm actually going to bring back these two lines
so that we can see what the tree looks like
before we do any deletions
and let's say intTree.delete and let's do
the cases we went through in the slide.
So I think we deleted 15 and then intTree.delete
and I think we did 20.
Did we do 20 or 27?
Let's do 27.
I can't remember if that's what we did
but let's do it anyway and then let's delete the root.
So we'll delete 25 and in fact let's do these separately
so that we can see the results of each delete.
So I'm going to copy these two lines.
And so the first node we're going to try deleting is 15
and we know from the slides that
15 has one child, 17 so let's run.
So that'll be case one.
So let's run this and we'll see that before the deletion,
we have 15, 17, 20 et cetera and after the deletion,
15 is gone and our in order traversal is
still working properly, still printing out
the numbers in ascending order.
So that's the case one.
Let's delete 17.
So let's change this to 17 because that would be case zero.
We know 17 is a leaf so let's run that
and 17 is gone.
So we have 15, 17, 20 before the deletion
and now we have 15, 20, 22 et cetera
and everything looks OK.
So for the case of 2 children,
well we know the route has 2 children so bye bye root.
So root is 25, let's run.
And 25 is gone.
So we've got 15, 17, 20, 22 25 before the deletion,
15, 17, 20, 22, 26 after the deletion
and everything looks good.
So it looks like our 3 cases are working.
Let's try 8888 just to make sure that that one's working
and hopefully our tree won't fall apart.
And you can see that there's no deletions
and we're not getting any nasty exceptions.
So if we try to delete something that's not in the tree
it's essentially a no-op and so that's delete.
It turns out that it's longer to explain case to
than it is to implement it
when we're using recursion.
If we were to use an iterative implementation,
the code for deleting a node with 2 children
is actually goes from 2 lines of code
to 30 lines of code.
So that's it for delete.
I'll see you in the next video.