(soft electronic music)
(keyboard clicking)
So for our second challenge
I want you to change the implementation of insertion sort
that we went through in the insertion sort video
so that it's a recursive implementation.
So I want you to sort the usual example array,
and in the resources section for this video
you'll find a starter project that essentially
will contain the code that we covered
in the insertion sort video.
So if you need to review the video on recursion,
and of course the video on insertion sort,
if you need to review that as well.
So essentially the challenge is to take
the iterative implementation and change
it to a recursive implementation.
Good luck, and I'll see you in the solution video.