(upbeat music)
If you've been working with Java
for any length of time, you'll be familiar with array list.
It's pretty much the go to class
when it comes to storing a collection of objects
that you'll want to iterate over sequentially.
So let's take a closer look at them
by going over to the Java doc.
If we scroll down and we read the documentation
written by the developers of this class,
we'll notice that it says this is
a resizable array implementation of the list interface.
Meaning that the data in the list
is being stored in an array.
And this array is called the backing array.
Now this tells us a few things based
on what we learned about arrays.
If we know the position of an item in the list,
accessing will be efficient.
In fact, it'll be all of one or constant time
because we know that if we have the index
of the item that we want,
then accessing the array element is all of one.
So array lists are great if all you're going to do
is iterate over them.
Because in that case you're always going from
index zero to the end of the list.
So you know the indices of
the items that you want to retrieve.
But if you want to add a lot of items to an existing list,
this will be slow if the size of the list
isn't large enough to accommodate the new items.
In other words, if the backing array is already full
and you wanna add more items to the list,
then you're going to have to resize that backing array.
Well, you won't but the implementation
of the array list class will.
And also, removing items will be slow
because we're gonna have to shift the remaining items
to remove any empty space.
So if you're going to be adding
a lot of items into an array list,
you want to have some idea of how many items
are ultimately going to be on the list
so you can create an array list instance with
a capacity that will accommodate all the items.
Otherwise, the array that's backing the list,
that's actually storing the items,
will have to be resized when it gets full
and you wanna add more items to the list.
Now as I said, you can ensure that the array
will be large enough by specifying the capacity.
And if we go down to the constructors,
you'll see there's one that lets you
specify the initial capacity.
And it says it constructs an empty list
with the specified capacity.
What it's actually doing is
the backing array that it creates
will be of length initial capacity.
Now when it comes to array lists,
it's important to understand the difference
between size and capacity.
Capacity is the maximum number of items
that the list can hold before it's gonna have to be resized,
the backing array.
The size is the number of items
that are actually in the list.
So if you create an array list
with the capacity of 20 and you add three items to it,
then the capacity is 20 and the size is three.
And you'll notice up here, if you don't pass a capacity,
you're gonna get an initial capacity of 10,
which isn't a whole lot.
So if you're gonna have more that 10 items on the list,
you're better off specifying the capacity.
Okay, so let's go over to the IDE
and play around with array lists.
So I've created a project
and I'm putting, or I've put the code into
academy.programming.arraylists.
And I'm going to create an employee class,
employee, so that we have something interesting to add to
our lists that isn't just integers.
So under the same package, I'll create a new java class
and I'll call it employee.
And we'll add a
first name field,
a last name field and we'll throw in an ID field as well.
And now we can get the IDE to help us generate
all the boiler plate code.
So if I right click anywhere
or where I want the code to go
and I click generate,
you'll see there's lot of choices here.
So first of all, add a constructor.
And I want all three fields to be handled by the constructor
so I'll select them and click OK.
And now we have our standard constructor
that just takes the parameters it's passed
and assigns them into the number fields.
And of course we want sets and gets for these
'cause they're private.
So once again, we'll right click,
we'll say generate and we want getter and setter.
And once again, I want getters and setters
generated for all the fields.
So I'll select all of them and click OK.
And now we have the standard sets and gets.
And finally,
I'd like a two string method generated.
I wanna override the default because when we print
an employee instance, I'd like to see
first name, last name, and ID.
I don't just wanna see the object reference.
So I'll right click,
go to generate, and I wanna a two string method.
I want all the fields and here we go.
We have a nice two string method.
And so the IDE gave us quite a bit of help there.
Just by right clicking and go to generate
we can get all the boiler plate code that we need.
So now that we have this class,
let's go back to our main method.
So we want a list so I'm gonna say list employee.
Now the reason I'm saying list rather than array list
is by using list, if I decide later
that I want to use a different type of list,
it's easy to change the specific implementation
of list that I'm using.
So I'm gonna call this employee list
and I'm going to create a new array list.
And I'm not going to specify capacity
because I'm only gonna add four employees
and as we saw, the default capacity is 10.
So I'm not gonna worry about the array having to be resized.
So I got a couple of errors here.
First of all, there are multiple possibilities for list
because there's more than one list class.
So IntelliJ wants me to tell it which one I want
and I want java.util.
And here it's telling me that diamond types aren't supported
at language level 1.6.
And if you get something like that,
it means that right now for some reason,
I'm not sure why it does this because I've specified
the JVK is Java nine,
it thinks I'm using Java 1.6.
So to get rid of that,
click here and say set my language level to seven,
'cause that supports the diamond.
And so now all the errors are gone.
So if you get something like that,
just wait for the light bulb to come up
and then have it set the language level
to a higher language level.
Okay, so getting back to why I use list here,
if I decided I wanted to use a different type of list,
I could just replace the specific class
that I'm using when I create the instance
and this will still work.
Because as long as the class that I'm using
implements the list interface, the compilers happy.
Okay, so now that we have our list,
let's add a few employees.
So I'll say employee.add, this is how we add
an item into our list.
And I'll say new employee.
Our first employee will be Jane Jones.
And she'll have an ID of 123.
Let's add another one.
And we'll say John Doe.
And his ID is 4567.
We'll add
Mary Smith.
And her ID will be 22.
And finally we'll add
Mike Wilson.
And he'll have an ID of 3245.
And I think I'm missing a parenthesis here
so I'll just add that.
So as I said, what's happening under the covers
when we call the array list constructor
is creating a backing array of 10.
'Cause we saw that the default capacity,
if we don't specify one, is 10.
So we only have four employees so that's okay.
It means that when we added our employees,
the backing array didn't have to be resized.
And let's go look at the add methods.
I'm gonna select it, right click
and say go to the declaration.
And this is actually on the interface.
I want to go to the implementation
so I'm going to come here and click on the I
and I'm going to select the arraylist.add implementation,
because that's what we're using.
And so here we are in the actual code.
And now let's go to that implementation.
And so this is where the work's actually done
and we'll see that the first thing it does
is checks to see whether the backing array is full.
And so it checks to see whether the number of items, S,
that's in the array are equal to the array's lengths.
Because if that's true then the array is full
and so it needs to grow the array, it has to resize it.
And then after it's done that,
it'll assign the item
and then of course, it gonna increase the size
because as I discussed earlier,
the capacity is the maximum number of items
that can be stored in the array,
basically the array's length,
and the size is the actual number
of items we've added to it.
Okay, so an array list is backed by an array.
So why don't we just use an array?
Why are we using array list?
Well, because array list has a bunch of methods
that let you work with the list items.
And so the code to do this has been written for you.
You don't have to directly work on the array.
Also, array list implements the list interface
and so as I mentioned earlier,
you can swap to another type of list
that uses the list interface
without too much disruption of the existing code.
So let's go back to our main method
and look at some of the methods that array list offers.
We've seen how we can add items,
let's print the items on the list.
So we can say employeelist.foreach
and then we'll say employee
system.out.printlineemployee.
And now it wants, I have to move up
to language level eight because it wants lambdas.
We need Java eight for lambdas.
So this is a lambda expression
and for each employee in the list,
we're going to print that employee out.
Now I could've just used a loop
and loop through the list
but this is more concise.
So if we run now.
Here are employees
and we're getting the nice print out
because remember we used the IDE to override the two string.
So here are our employees
and it was easy for us to just go ahead,
call one method and iterate through the list.
So let's now get the second employee in the list.
And so just like with arrays,
the index is zero based when we're working with array lists.
And that's surprising because we now know array list
is backed by array.
So if we want to print out the second employee,
we just say employeelist.get1
because the second employee will be at index one.
So we'll run and we should see John Doe come up
and John Doe does.
These four are from the four each col
and then we have John Doe being printed out from here.
And as we know, because an array is backing the array list,
this get col, when we actually access the employee,
is done in constant time.
Because an array is backing the list,
random access like this, where we just provide an index,
is done in constant time.
The time complexity doesn't depend on the size of the list.
So array lists are great when you want to load
a bunch of data and then access it like this.
Now we also can check to see if a list is empty.
So we can say
system.out.printline
employeelist.isempty.
Now we expect false because the list isn't empty
so let's run,
and sure enough, we get false.
Okay now another thing we can do
is we can replace the employee at a specific position
with another employee.
So lets replace John Doe with John Adams.
So to do that we just have to say employeelist.set,
so we're not gonna use add here.
And the first parameter is the index
of the employee that we want to replace
and we're gonna replace John Doe with a new employee John
Adams.
And John Adams has an ID of 4568.
And now if I comment out,
I'm gonna comment out all of the prints we've done so far.
And I'm going to copy the print that prints the entire list.
And let's run.
And we'll see for the second employee is now John Adams,
it's no long John Doe.
So if you wanna add an employee to the list
or add an item to the list
and it's always added to the end of the list,
you use the add method.
If you want to replace an item in the list,
you use the set method.
Now because random access is all of one setting,
an employee will happen in constant time.
As long as you're providing the index,
whatever operation you're performing will perform
with a time complexity of constant time over the one.
Now if you want to get the number of items in the list,
that would be the size, we can do that.
So we'll just say employeelist.size.
And remember, this won't give us the capacity,
the capacity is the total number of items this list
can currently hold.
That's the length of the backing array.
This will tell us how many employees
we've actually added to the list.
So let's run.
And we'll see four, which is what we expect.
'Cause we have four employees on the list.
Now as I just said, the add method
adds items to the end of the list.
What if you don't want that?
What if you want to add an employee at a specific position?
Well, if you wanna do that you can also use the add method
but you have provide more parameters.
So if we wanted to add John Doe back in
but we wanted to add him at index three,
so we wanted him to be the fourth employee,
we'll say employeelist.add
and this time we need to provide an index
as well as the instance we want to add.
So we'll say John
Doe and 4567.
And if we now print our list again,
so I'll grab this.
And copy it here, let's run.
And we'll see that John Doe has been added at index three.
Now you've provided an index
but because in this case you're sticking him
in the middle of values,
some values are gonna have to be shifted up.
So the worst case for this would actually be o of n
because the worst case would be
you'd want to put him right at the beginning of the array
and then all the other elements have to be shifted.
And let's go to the source code to look at that.
So we'll saw go to
the declaration and I want the implementation
for array list.
And you'll see here, this is the array copy,
this is the shifting.
So depending on where you want to put him,
elements are gonna have to be shifted in the array.
And that's what causes this particular operation to be
a linear time operation.
Alright, back in our code,
if we want the array, let's say we have a list
and we're saying okay, well give us that backing array.
Give us the array that's holding the employees,
we can get that by calling the to array method.
But we're not going to get an employee array.
We'll get an object array.
So we'll say object
employee array equals employeelist.toarray.
Now if we want an employee array,
we can get it but then we have to tell
the compiler that that's what we want.
And to do that, we pass an array of the type we want.
So instead of just calling the to array method
and not passing anything, we would change this call
to say new employee and the length that we want
is employeelist.size because the size method
will return how many employees we actually added.
And so we just needed an array of that length.
And then when we get that array back,
let's print out
the element.
So we'll say for employee,
employee in the employee's array,
or employee array, rather.
And I'll change this to employee now
'cause we can do that.
We'll just print the employee.
So let me comment out the other print
so we don't get confused with what we're looking at.
And let's run this.
And I think there must be one more print,
yep, here it is.
Let me comment that out, run again.
And now here's the print coming from the employee array.
And so we get the five employees that we had in the list
but we now have them in an employee array instead.
Now if you want to know if the list contains an instance,
you can call the contains method
to check whether the list contains an employee.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So that's system.out.printline
and we wanna check employeelist.contains
and we have to pass
the object we're looking for.
Now we don't have that instance because
we didn't save Mary anywhere
so we'll have to ask for Mary again.
And her ID was 22.
And let's run.
And you'll see that we get false.
Now maybe we're expecting true, maybe you weren't.
And the reason you get false is because
we haven't implemented the equals method
in the employee class.
So because there's no equals method,
what this method is doing is actually checking
to see if they're the exact same instance
because that's what the default equals method does.
The one that's all the way back in object.
And they're not the exact same instance.
We created an instance here
and we created an instance here.
So there are two distinct instances.
Now they're structurally the same,
meaning that all their fields contain the same values
and so we think they should be equal.
That if we're looking for an employee
with the first name Mary, the last name Smith
and the ID 22, we know we have an employee like that
in the list but we have to implement the equals method
in the employees class so that it's going to compare
the individual fields against each other.
So let's go to our employee class
and I'll just put the code here.
And once again, we can get the IDE to do this for us.
So I'll say generate.
Now it's going to create the hash code method for us too
because whenever you override the equals method,
you should really be overriding hash code as well.
So that's fine.
We can just accept all the defaults here.
I'm gonna select these two
and say first name and last name should never be null.
And now we have an equals method.
So if we go back to our main method and run again,
we should see true.
And we do.
Because now the equals method in the employee class
is actually looking at the values in the fields.
Now that we have the equals method,
we can make use of the index of method.
And this will look up an employee in the list
and tell us what index that employee is occupying.
So let's look at for John Doe.
So let's say system.out.printline
employeelist.indexof and once again,
because we didn't save a reference to John Doe,
we'll just create an instance with the values
and his ID is 4567.
And because we implemented the equals method,
this should find John Doe.
It'll find the employee that has
the same values in the fields.
And it does.
It says he's at index three and we know that's true
because we specifically added him at index three.
Now the contains and index of methods
are only as good as the search algorithm
being used to search the array.
In other words, when we're looking something up in the list,
the method that we're using has to search the list.
And the way it's searching the list
will determine whether the index of
and contains method are fast or slow.
And we'll be looking at search algorithms
later in the course.
Alright, so the last thing I want to show you
is how to remove items from the list.
Let's remove the third employee,
that's gonna be Mary.
So we'll say employeelist.remove
and we're gonna pass two
because we wanna remove the third employee.
We could also pass an instance of her if we wanted to
but this is actually faster
because we're providing the index.
And once we've done that, let's print out the list.
I'll comment this out so we're not printing out
a bunch of stuff from the array.
And I'm gonna copy this line,
that prints out our list.
And let's run.
And we'll see that Mary is no longer in our list.
We just have four employees now.
Now because we're dealing with an array in the background,
remove can be expensive because elements
after the one we removed have
to be shifted down one position.
So if we take a look at that,
if we go to the source code
and I want the source code for array list,
we'll see here that this is an array copy
and that's what's doing the shifting.
If it has shift elements down to occupy
the empty space left by the one that we removed.
Okay, so there are a few more methods
in the array list class
but I'm going to leave you to explore them on your own.
For a lot of you, this may have been a review
but I just wanted to show some of you the methods
and operations you can do on array lists.
So array list is good for random access
if you have the index
and it's good for iterating over the items in the list
but it's not so good for inserting items into
the list in any position other than the end.
It's not so good for deletions, removals.
And it's not so good for accessing an item in the list
when you don't have it's index.
So remember, it's backed by an array
and so if you have the index,
the operation will be able to be performed in constant time
but if you don't have the index
or if you're inserting or removing elements
from somewhere in the middle of the array
or at the beginning of the array,
elements are gonna have to be shifted around.
And so because an array list is backed by an array,
it has the same problems and advantages that arrays have.
Okay, that's it for array lists and in the next video
we're gonna take a quick look at vector, the vector class.
I'll see you there.