(bubbly music)
(keys typing)
In this video we're going
to implement the bubble sort algorithm
that we just went through using slides in the last video.
So I'm gonna start by creating a new project.
Now I'm gonna go through this one more time
and then from this point forward,
I'm going to assume that you understand
how to create a project so when we start a video
I'll already have the project created.
But, for one last time, we go up to file,
new, project,
and I want a Java project,
so I'll make sure Java is selected on the left-hand side,
and we don't need to check any of these boxes.
I have my project SVK set to Java nine.
I'm going to click next.
I want the IDE to create the main method for me,
the main class and the main method
so I'll select that and click next.
And I'm gonna call this project bubble sort.
And I'm going to change the package
to academy.learnprogramming.bubblesort.
And I'm gonna click finish,
and because I have a project open,
it's asking me if I wanna use the same window
and I do, so I'm gonna click this window.
And there we go, we have our new project.
Fine to move this over a little to make some more room,
I'm going to delete this comment.
And this is a rather simple algorithm
so we're just gonna do the implementation
within the main method.
Now before we do that, I'm going to write a swap method.
As you'll see, a number of the sort algorithms we'll look at
swap elements at some point,
and that's true of bubble sort.
It swaps elements, so I'm going to write a swap method.
So I'm gonna say public static,
it has to be static because we're going to be
calling it from the main method.
Void swap, and this method's going to take three parameters,
it's going to take the array that we're sorting,
and it's going to take two indices.
And these two indices are the indices
of the elements we want to swap.
So if we want it to swap elements three and four,
we pass the array in, and we pass
three for I, and four for J.
So the first thing we're gonna do in this method
is check whether I equals J.
Because if I equals J, there's nothing for us to do.
So I'll say if I, I equals J,
we'll just return.
Because essentially if I equals J
we're saying we wanna swap element two with element two
or swap element three with element three,
so there's nothing for us to do.
There's actually no element to swap.
But if I isn't equal to J, then we do
have elements to swap and so what we're going to do
is we're going to create a temporary int variable
and we're going to say array I
into that variable.
So temp will now contain the value at array I.
And then we're going to assign the value
at array J to array I.
Equals array J.
Now it's okay for us to do this.
We've overwritten the value that was at array I,
but that's fine because we've saved it in temp.
And so the final thing we have to do
is assign temp to array J.
So we'll say array J equals temp.
So we assign what's at I to temp,
we assign what's at J to I,
and then we assign what's at temp to J.
So, when we exit this method,
what used to be at position J will now be at position I,
and what used to be at position I will now be at position J.
Alright, so now that we have a swap method,
let's create our intArray.
So I'll say int, intArray equals,
and we'll use the same values we used on the slide,
20, 35, -15, 7,
55, 1, and -22.
And now we wanna use the bubble sort algorithm
to sort this array.
Now, the implementation that I'm going
to show you is one implementation.
There are other implementations of this algorithm,
there'll be a different implementation
to sort in descending order.
Some of the implementations expand
the sorted partition from left to right
rather than from right to left.
I'm going to implement what I showed you in the slides.
And so we're going to say for int,
last unsorted index
equals array.length
minus one, that should be intArray actually.
So remember that at the beginning of the algorithm,
the entire array is unsorted, and so the last unsorted
index will be the last valid index in the array,
and that's intArray.length minus one.
So that's what we're initialising that to.
And then we're going to do this as long
as the last unsorted index is greater than zero and
after each iteration we're going to
decrement the last unsorted index.
Now remember that because we're bubbling
large values to the end of the array,
the sorted partition is growing from right to left.
And so the last unsorted index starts at six
and after the first iteration it's now
going to be five because whatever's here
will be in the sorted partition.
And then after the second iteration it'll be four,
because then these two elements will be sorted.
And three, two, et cetera.
And so the index is going to go from six to zero,
and once we hit zero, we can stop.
Because at that point, the entire array is sorted.
So that's the outer loop.
For each iteration of the outer loop,
we want to traverse the array.
And we want to bubble the largest value that's unsorted
into the sorted partition.
So we want to bubble the largest value
to the end of the array.
So that's what the inner loop is going to do.
So we'll say for int, I equals zero
because we always start at the beginning of the array.
I less than the last unsorted index,
because we don't need to go into the sorted partition
because we know that those, the values
in the sorted partition are already sorted.
So in the inner loop, we start at zero
and we keep going until we hit the last unsorted index.
And we're gonna increment I,
and then what we wanna do, is you saw in the slides,
is we wanna compare the value at I
with the value at I plus one.
And if the value at I is greater than
the value at I plus one, we wanna swap the two values
because we wanna bubble the largest values
up to the end of the array.
And so we're going to say if intArray I
is greater than intArray I plus one,
well what do we want to do, we want to swap them.
And we can use our swap method to do that.
So we'll pass at the intArray, I and I plus one.
And that's it, that's our implementation
of the bubble sort algorithm, as I said
this is not the only implementation,
it is a implementation, or should that be
an implementation.
So we're sorting in ascending order,
and we're bubbling large values to the end of the arrray,
and we are growing the sorted partition from right to left.
We're starting it right at the end of the array,
and after each iteration of the outer loop,
the sorted partition grows by one.
And so it starts out being basically nothing
in the sorted partition, and then it,
after the first iteration, the element at position six
is sorted, so that's a sorted partition,
after two iterations, the elements at positions
five and six are sorted, so that's the sorted partition
et cetera until we get right down
to the beginning of the array.
So let's print out this array after we've sorted it.
So for int I equals zero,
I less than intArray.length,
I plus plus, and we'll just print out
the value in the arrays, so intArray I.
So this should work.
And when we run, these values should be sorted.
Let's give it a shot.
And sure enough, our values are sorted.
22, -15, 1, 7,
20, 35, and 55.
I'll just close the console here, and so that's bubble sort.
Now, I said in the last video that the time complexity
of bubble sort is O to the N squared, it's quadratic.
So the absolute worst case is it will take N squared
steps where N is the number of items we're sorting.
Now you might look at the code and say
well it's not N squared, it's actually less than that
because the sorted partition is growing
after each iteration of the outer loop
and the inner loop doesn't cross
into the sorted partition.
So the inner loop is actually doing less work
as the algorithm progresses, or at least
as this implementation progresses, and you'd be right.
But remember that when it comes to determining
the time complexity of an algorithm, we're not doing math.
We don't want the absolute precise expression.
What we're trying to do is get some sense
of how the number of steps grows
as the number of items we have to sort grows.
So we kind of want a general idea.
We want to be able to say this is a linear algorithm,
or this is a quadratic algorithm,
or this is a logarithmic algorithm,
or this is a constant algorithm.
It doesn't grow as the number of items
you're dealing with grows.
And so we're looking for approximations.
The algorithm grows in a quadratic way
as the number of items increases.
The pattern isn't linear, it's not logarithmic,
and it's certainly not constant.
And so we still consider bubble sort
to be an O to the N squared algorithm,
and in fact this implementation
has a little bit of an optimization.
Strictly speaking, bubble sort wants us
to traverse the entire array every single time.
It doesn't really pay attention to where
the sorted partition is.
This implementation does pay attention
to where the sorted partition is,
and it doesn't cross into the sorted partition
because it doesn't have to.
Those elements are already sorted.
One tip when it comes to determining time complexity
is to look at how many loops there are.
Because normally each loop corresponds to N,
and so if you have only one loop,
then it's linear time complexity.
If you have two loops, then it's N times N.
And so that's quadratic time complexity.
And here we have two loops, and so just at a glance
we can kind of guess that this is
O to the N squared time complexity.
Alright, so that's bubble sort, not very complex.
As I said upfront in the theory video,
this algorithm is one of the least efficient algorithms.
In fact there are some computer scientists
that think we shouldn't even teach it anymore,
but it is a classic sort algorithm that is usually taught.
And it's gotten us warmed up for some of the faster
algorithms that we'll look at later.
So I'll see you in the next video.