(inspiring music)
(clicking)
In the last video
we went through the characteristics of general trees.
In this video, we're going to go through
the characteristics of a binary tree
and then we're gonna move onto binary search trees,
which is what we're going to look at
for the remainder of this section.
So a binary tree is a tree
in which every node has zero, one, or two children
and that's why it's called a binary tree
because the maximum number of children
a node can have is two.
Now remember when we looked at general trees,
a node could have as many children as it wanted.
It could have three, five, 10, 50, whatever.
But in a binary tree, every node can have zero
which means it would be a leaf,
one or two children.
Now because each node can have at most two children,
when we're working with a binary tree
we refer to the possible two children
as the left child and the right child
and in practise,
we don't just use a regular old binary tree,
we use a binary search tree
and we'll look at those later.
And so here's a binary tree, and this tree,
every node only has zero, one, or two children
and the left child of 15 would be 22
and the right child of 15 would be four
and this is how they're usually depicted
with going to the left and going to the right.
The left child for four would be 18
and the right child would be three.
22 has a left child, 19,
but it does not have a right child
and 18 has a right child, 14,
but it does not have a left child.
Now a binary tree is complete
if every level except the last level, has two children
and on the last level,
all of the nodes are as left as possible
and so this is a complete binary tree,
all of the nodes have two children except leaf nodes,
that's a last level, and four.
But you'll notice that the children
are all to the left as much as possible.
If three was a right child
and we had an empty spot here,
this would not be a complete tree.
So with a complete tree,
every level except the last level
and this is the last level,
is completely filled
and so all of the interior nodes
have to have two children
and then on the last level
all of the nodes have to be to the left
as much as possible.
Now a full binary tree
is complete tree as well,
but with a full binary tree,
every node other than the leaves
has to have two children,
and so this is not a full binary tree
because four doesn't have two children,
it only has one,
but it is a complete tree.
This tree if full and by definition it's also complete
because every node in the tree
except for leaves, has two children
and as I said,
full binary trees are also considered
to be complete binary trees, right?
Because is we go back up to the complete binary tree,
the definition of a complete tree is,
every level except potentially the last is filled.
And with a full binary tree,
every level is filled including the last.
So full binary trees are also complete trees.
Now it's fine to have incomplete binary trees
if we go up to the tree we looked at, at first,
this is incomplete because we're missing a node here
and the nodes at the bottom level
aren't to the left the most.
So it's completely fine to have incomplete binary trees.
Now this is not a binary tree
because four has three children
and so this tree is not a binary tree.
A binary tree, every node has
zero, one, or two children
and the root also has three children in this one.
So this is a binary tree.
This is not a binary tree.
In practise, we generally don't use
just any old binary tree.
We use what's called a binary search tree
and the reason that binary search trees are popular
is that we can perform insertions,
deletions and retrievals in O(logn) time.
They also have faster searching than unsorted arrays do,
but equivalent time complexity to sort it arrays.
Remember when we search a sorted array
using the binary search algorith
we can do it in O(logn) time,
so it has the equivalent search time.
When we're dealing with a binary search tree,
the left child always has a smaller value than its parent
and the right child always
has a larger value than its parent.
And this means that everything to left of the root
or to the left of a parent
is less than the value of the root or the parent
and everything to the right of the root or the parent
is greater than the value of the root or the parent
and because of that,
it's really easy to do a binary search
on a binary search tree
because we look at the value of the root.
If it's equal to the value we want, we're done.
If it's not, and it's less than the value at the root,
then we know to go look at the left subtree
because everything to the left of the root
is less than the value of the root.
If the value we're looking for is greater than the root
then we know to go to the right subtree
because everything to the right of the root
is greater than the value of the root
and so right away, just by checking the root,
we cut the number of values we have to search in half
and then we rinse and repeat,
so we'd, if we were gonna search the left subtree
we'd move down to the left child of the root
and we compare the value against that.
If it's less than the value, we go to the left subtree
if it's greater, to the right subtree.
So essentially,
binary search trees are ideal for doing binary searches
and that's why they're called binary search trees.
And because of that characteristic as well,
we can do insertions, deletions and retrievals.
That's searching for a value, so that's obviously O(logn).
We can do those in O(logn) time
because it only ever takes us O(logn) steps
to find the insertion point
or to find the value we want to delete or retrieve.
And so this is a binary search tree,
so the root is 15.
Everything to the left of the root is smaller than 15
and everything to the right of the root is larger than 15
and this has to hold true for every node in the tree.
So if look at three,
three has one child, two,
and two is less than three,
and so two has to go to the left.
If we put two here, this would not be a binary search tree
because it would violate the rule
that everything to the left has to be less than,
and everything to the right has to be greater than.
22 is greater than 15, so it goes to the right.
18 is less than 22, so it goes to the left.
19 is greater than 18, so it goes to the right
and 25 is greater than 22, and so it goes to the right,
and so this meets the requirements of a binary search tree.
Now let's say we came in and we wanna find the value of 18.
So we'd come in, we compare 18 to 15,
while 18 is larger than 15
so we know it has to be to the right of the root,
so we go down to the right child.
18 is less than 22,
so we know it has to be to the left of this node
because everything on the left is less than 22.
So we come down to the left child, 18 equals 18.
Boom, we're done,
we found 18 in just three steps,
and so it's called a binary search tree
because it's naturally organised
so that you can do a binary search
just by comparing values against a node
and then depending on the result,
going to the left or going to the right
and so each time, you're cutting the values in half,
the values you have to search.
Now what about duplicate values?
How do those work in binary search trees?
Well there are a couple of approaches to this.
Some implementations just say they're not allowed
and so if you try to insert a duplicate value,
it's not allowed and that takes care of the problem.
If you want to allow them,
one way to handle them is to always store duplicates
either in the left subtree or the right subtree.
You have to choose one and stick with it.
A third approach is to have a counter with each node
and so rather than adding
a separate node for a duplicate value,
you would just increment a counter,
so if we were doing it that way
and we came in and wanted to insert the value 22,
rather than going, is 22 less than or greater than 15?
It's greater than, so we go to the right
and then we hit 22 and rather than saying, is 22?
Oh, it's equal,
well, we're gonna insert it to the left or the right.
Instead, you just increment a counter in here to two.
So that's another way.
Okay, and here's another binary search tree example.
So this time 25 is the root.
Everything to the left of 25 is smaller than 25
and everything to the right of 25 is larger than 25
and that will hold true of every node.
So for 20, 15 is to the left cos it's smaller.
22 is to the right cos it's larger.
For 27, 26 is to the left.
30 is larger than 27
and 29 is less than 30
and 32 is greater than 30.
Okay so how would we build this tree?
What insertions did we do to get this tree?
Now the order in which you insert the nodes
is gonna influence how the tree ultimately looks
and you'll understand this a little better
as we go through this insertion.
So the first node we're gonna insert is 25
cos that ended up at the root
and when you insert a value into an empty binary search tree
you always put it at the root.
So as I said, the order in which you insert items
can influence what the tree looks like
because if we started with another value
the root would be a different value
and then the comparisons would be different obviously
and we wouldn't be comparing against 25.
Okay, so next we're gonna want to insert 20.
20 is less than 25 so we put it to the left,
then we insert 15.
15 is less than 25, so we go to the left.
15 is less than 20, so we go to the left
and we hit an empty spot and so that's where it goes.
For 27, 27 is greater than 25, so we put it to the right.
Now if you haven't realised this already
when we're doing insertions,
we always insert the node into the first empty spot we find.
So where do you think 30's gonna go?
Well 30 is greater than 25, so we're gonna go to the right.
30 is greater than 27, so we're gonna go to the right
and so 30 ends up getting stored as the right child of 27.
For 29, 29 is greater than 25,
so we're gonna go to the right.
29 is greater than 27, so we're gonna go to the right.
29 is less than 30, and so we're gonna go to the left.
For 26, that's gonna end up here
as the left child of 27
because 26 is greater than 25, so we go to the right.
26 is less than 27, so we go to the left.
Can you figure out where 22 is gonna end up?
Well, 22 is less than 25, so we go to the left.
22 is greater than 20, so we go to the right
and finally for 32, can you figure this one out?
32 is greater than 25, so we go to the right.
32 is greater than 27, so we go to the right.
32 is greater than 30, so we go to the right
and that's how we built our tree.
Now if we mixed up the insertion order of these values,
we shuffled these,
then we'd end up building a different tree
because a different value's gonna go into the root
and our comparisons may end up putting 20 over here.
If we ended up with 15 as the root,
then 20 would end up in the right subtree
and so the order in which you do insertions
will influence what your tree looks like
when you've finished building it.
Now one really important characteristic
to note for binary tree,
is you can get the minimum value in the tree
just by following the left edges
all the way down to the leaf
and so the minimum value in this tree is 15.
Cos if we follow the left edges until we hit a leaf,
we hit 15
and if you want the maximum value in the tree
you do the same thing with the edges on the right.
So you follow the edges down and we hit 32
and 32 is the maximum value in the tree
and so when you have a binary search tree
you can get the minimum and maximum values very quickly.
You just travel all the way down the left
for the minimum value
and all the way down the right for the maximum value.
Now this may sound counter intuitive
but if you insert sorted data into a binary search tree,
you're gonna end up with this situation.
Now in this case, the data is sorted in descending order
and so we insert 25.
20 is less than 25 so we're gonna put 20 here.
15 is less than 20, so it's gonna go to the left
and 10 is less than 15, so it goes to the left.
If we had them in ascending order,
we'd get the same situation but to the right.
So if we put 10 first and then we put 15,
15 would go to the right and then we put 20,
20 would go to the right
and 25 would go to the right.
We end up with this situation
when we insert data that's already been sorted
and this is not a good situation.
This is essentially a linked list
and so rather than having a binary search tree
and we can search it in O(logn) time,
we end up with a linked list.
This is essentially a linked list
and if you search this you're not gonna get O(logn) time,
you're gonna get linear time, O(n).
Ideally when you're building a binary search tree,
you try to keep the tree as balanced as possible
and that means that the heights of the left subtree
and the right subtree, don't differ by much.
And so there are binary search trees
that are self balancing binary search trees.
After every insertion or deletion,
they look at the tree
and if the tree is starting to get out of whack,
they rebalance the tree by shifting nodes around.
We're not gonna look at them in this course
because they're more advanced
but I just wanted to mention that they exist.
Two common ones that you'll here about
are AVL trees and red-black trees.
So with that out of the way,
let's implement a binary search tree.
I'll see you in the next video.