(chime music)
(keyboard clicking)
I said in the last video that we could improve
on the implementation of our queue
and I asked you to think about the case where
we add two employees and then we remove one,
we add one, we remove one, add one, remove one
and we keep alternating like that,
because in that case we never have
more than two employees on the queue.
And so if we've created a queue of length 10
or of length five,
the queue should never need to be resized.
Because we always have fewer employees
than the size of the queue.
But will that be the case?
So I've created a new project
and I've got the exact same code in here.
(mouse scrolling)
And this is the code we're going to update
to improve the implementation.
But first let's demonstrate what's wrong
with this implementation.
So back in the main method,
I've added the code for doing
the alternating adds and removes.
I'll just uncommit that code.
Underneath, I have our old code
that we did in the last video
and what I'm going to do here is I'm gonna say;
"Array queue queue equals new array queue".
Array queue
And I'm gonna make it five
so we don't have to do a tonne of adds and removes.
So down here I'm adding Jane and John
and then I removed Jane
I add Mary,
I remove John,
I add Mike,
I remove Mary,
I add Bill,
I remove Mike
and then I add Jane again.
And so because after the first two adds
I'm removing, adding, removing, adding et cetera,
we never have more than two employees on a queue
and our queue has a capacity of five.
And so we shouldn't expect
this queue to be resized.
So let's go into our array queue class
and I'm going to put a break point
right here.
And I'm gonna run the debugger
and we're gonna see if when we run the main method
if this break point is hit.
Because if it is, it means we're resizing the array.
So to run the debugger instead of hitting the green arrow
I'll hit the little bug here.
So let's run.
And boom, we hit the break point
which means we're trying to resize our array.
Now if we go back to the main method,
so I'll go to the,
here's our call stack that we've talked about.
So right now we have main and add on here
I'll go main and you'll see that it's when
we come to add Jane Jones
that we're trying to resize the array.
So before we do that,
we've added five employees
and sure we're doing a sixth add.
And our capacity is five,
but we never have more than two employees
on the queue so there should still be room,
but apparently there isn't.
And I'll tell you why.
If we come down and look
at the fields for this class.
And we look at the queue field.
We'll see that the only employee
on the queue right now is Bill End
which is what we expect from this code.
Cos we've, the last remove removed Mike
and so all we have is Bill when we come to add Jane.
And he's at position four
and here we have the line saying
"Not showing null elements".
So that means that positions zero to three
in the array are null.
But if you look at our front and back fields,
our front is four and that's right
because Bill's the only guy on the queue
and he's at position four
so he's at the front
and the front is four.
But the back is five.
And if we look at our add method
we're checking whether
back equals queue dot length and it does.
Because it's five and the length of our queue is five.
We specified a length of five back here.
The problem is there's all this space
at the front of the array.
And so our queue isn't really full.
What we've done here is we've just hit the end of the array.
And so even though 80% of our queue is empty,
we're doubling the length of the array
and then if we keep doing this add remove thing
at some point we're gonna double it again
and double it again
and double it again.
Now our array was only started at length five.
What if you started an array at length 1,000?
And you kept doing this add remove stuff.
By the time you get to the end of the array,
you're gonna have over 990 empty spots
in the front of the array
and you're still gonna go ahead
and double the size of that array to 2,000.
So it would be nice if we could use
the empty space at the front of the array.
And we can if we wrap the back of the queue
to the front of the array.
And when we do this,
this is called a Circular Queue.
And we're going to update our implementation
to do that.
So rather than incrementing back to five,
we'll wrap it to the front.
And so our queue will actually...
The front part of the queue will
be at the end of the array
and the back part will start filling up
at the beginning of the array.
And that way we can make use
of all this empty space
and our queue won't have to be resized as often.
So I'm gonna close this off but before I do
I'm just gonna stop the debugger
by hitting the stop button here.
And now I'll close this off
and for now I'll remove the break points
so it's not distracting.
So lets go ahead and update this implementation
so that it's a circular queue.
We don't have to touch the constructor,
front and back are still gonna start at zero.
But we are gonna have to do
a different check here because now,
just because back equals queue dot length
as we've seen
doesn't mean the queue is gonna be full.
There may be empty space at the front of the array.
And so we're gonna use size here.
And we're gonna say
"if the size
of the array
is equal to queue dot length minus one".
Okay so that's resizing.
Now obviously because we're wrapping the queue,
we've got to change some code down here as well.
We're still always going to assign
the employee we're adding,
into the back of the queue.
That doesn't change.
But we don't necessarily want to just increment back.
Because we might want to wrap back
to the front of the queue.
So we're gonna say
"if back is less than queue dot length minus one".
In that case we can just go ahead and increment back.
I'll remove that increment from here.
Otherwise, we're gonna set back to zero
which means we're gonna wrap it.
Alright so lets take a look
at what this code means for our case.
So I'm gonna add some comments in here to help.
So if we add Jane to position one
and then she's gonna be the front.
And then we come ahead and add John
and then we come in and we add Mary
and then we come in we add Mike.
Now at this point there's a position four
and right now it's the back position.
So I'll just put this out here.
So after we've added Jane, John, Mary and Mike,
the front of the queue is still position zero,
the back of the queue is currently pointing to four.
It's the next available position.
Now we want a circular queue.
So if we come in here
and we add Bill,
we can't wrap back to the front
because that's not the next available position.
When we add Bill in here,
we want the next available position to be five
and that means that we're gonna have to resize the array.
And so in this case the size which is four
is equal to queue dot length minus one, right?
Because queue dot length,
which is five, minus one is four,
and that means that we've got our size is four,
they're equal, and so we need to resize
the array because we want to be able
to add Bill in here and increment back to five.
And so once we've done that,
we'll assign Bill in here.
So assign Bill.
So we're gonna put Bill in here
and because we resized the array
we're now gonna have five,
six,
seven,
et cetera,
up to nine.
And so when we do this test here
we're gonna say
"is back less than queue dot length minus one"?
Well yes it is because the new length of the queue is 10.
And back is less than nine
and so we can just safely go ahead
and say we've added Bill.
And now here's the new back position.
And so this is why we have to resize
the queue when we're one element short
of the length of the array.
And that's why this test down here is good.
Because once we've resized the queue
we know that back will be
less than queue dot length minus one
and we can just go ahead and increment it.
But now let's take these guys out
so we can look at the case where we're doing
the alternating adds
so we can see what other situations
we can get into.
And so again we're back to zero, one, two, three.
So in this case we add Jane at the front
and then we're adding John
and after we've added John
we have this situation right?
And then we come in and we remove Jane.
And so our front's gonna come here
and I'll take this out
and then we add Mary
cos we're doing these alternating adds.
So Mary comes in here
and our back position gets incremented by one.
And then we're removing John
so our front comes here.
And then we come in and we add Mike
and our back get incremented.
And then we remove Mary
so our front is now here,
and now we want to come in
and we add Bill.
That's all cool.
And we're not gonna resize because
when we do the test here
we've only got one employee, Mike,
when we came in.
And so we don't need to do a resize.
We're gonna add Bill into back which is currently four.
And then we do this check, and we say
"if back is less than queue dot length minus one".
Well this check fails because
back is four and queue dot length minus one is four.
So it's not less than queue dot length minus one.
And so because of that we drop into this part
and we wrap back to the front of the queue.
And so this here will be the new back position
which is correct.
Because then when we add Jane for the second time,
we can come put Jane in here,
and increment back.
Alright, so lets keep going with this example.
Because as you're gonna see
we have one more change to make to our add method
and you might've caught that already.
So let's say that we go ahead
and add back John and then
we increment back to here.
Well when we come in and add let's say Mary again,
there's room for Mary here,
but we can't increment back.
So we are going to meet this condition
because we have four items in the queue.
And so this condition's going to be true.
And we're going to ahead and resize the array.
But if we just copy in the elements exactly
as they are, that obviously won't work.
Because if we add Mary in here,
it doesn't matter if we've added elements at the end,
we can't increment back
so we have to change how we're resizing the array.
When we resize the array
we're going to unwrap the queue,
so basically we'll copy the elements
from the front of the queue
to the back of the array
into the front of the resized array
and then we'll add the remaining elements
in the queue to the end.
And so after we've resized,
our front will be reset to zero
and the back will be the size
will be the number of elements
because that will be the next available position.
So in this case
after we resize the array
we're gonna end up with the following.
So we'll have Mike at position zero
because he's at the front of the queue.
And then at position one,
we'd have Bill
at position two we have Jane,
at position three we have John
and then at position four
that'll be pointing to back
and then we'll have,
if we double the length of the array,
we'd have positions five up to position nine.
Because we would have doubled the array.
So we're gonna have to change the code in here
so that if we're butting up against the front
after we've wrapped
when we resize
we start the queue from the beginning again.
And as you can see we're in the same situation
here as we were if we added four employees
and then wanted to add a fifth.
Here we've added four employees
when we've wrapped the queue
and we still get into the situation
where we can't increment back
because if we do,
it's gonna be pointing to something
that's already occupied.
So when we have one fewer items in the array,
then the length of the array
it doesn't matter whether the remaining free spot
is at the end of the array
or somewhere in the middle of the array,
we still have to go through the resizing
because we have the same problem
of not being able to increment back
or in the case of at the end of the array
we can't wrap back to the beginning of the array.
So let's change our code in here
to resize the array and copy the elements in such
that we'll take the elements from the front of the queue
and copy them to the front of the resized array
and we'll copy the elements in
so that when we're finished
our front is reset to zero
and the elements are in the order they were added
and the back will be a the end.
So essentially in here
we're not just resizing the array
we're also moving the queue
we're unwrapping the queue potentially
and moving it to the front of the array.