(playful melody)
(typing)
All right, so let's talk about traversing trees.
Now, there are four ways you can traverse a tree,
one isn't used very often and the other three are.
So the first way which isn't used very often,
is called a Level Traversal.
And what we do is we visit nodes on each level in order,
starting from the top.
So we'd visit the root, 'cause that's at level zero
and then we visit the nodes at level one
going from left to right and then we'd visit the nodes
at level two from left to right, et cetera,
until we've visited all the nodes in the tree.
The second way is called Pre-order,
and with Pre-order we always visit
the root of every subtree first.
And so we're gonna visit the root
and then we're gonna visit the root of the left subtree
and the root of its left subtree, et cetera,
and until we get down to the first leaf.
And then we visit the leaves of each subtree
working back up the tree, and don't worry
I'm gonna show you an example of this in a minute.
With Post-order traversal we do the opposite,
we visit the root last.
And so instead of starting at the root,
we travel all the way down to the tree to the first leaf
and that's where we start our traversal.
And then there's In-order traversal
and that means that we visit the left child first
and then we visit the root
and then we visit the right child.
So this is one case where pictures
will hopefully make this clear,
so let's go to the next slide.
And we're gonna look at the level traversal here.
And for the level traversal we start at level zero
and then we move to level one
and we move from left to right,
and then we go to level two and we move from left to right,
and we go to three and we move from left to right.
So we visit 25, then 20 and 27,
then 15, 22, 26 and 30
and then 29 and 32.
So that's a level order traversal
and it's not used very often.
So now we have pre-order, and with pre-order
we always visit the root of a subtree first.
And so we're gonna start at 25
and then we're going to go to 20,
and then we go to 15.
15 doesn't have any children and so we go back up
to the root which we've already visited and we visit 22.
So the order so far is 25, 20, 15,
22 and then we go back up, we visit 27
and then 26, we go back to the root and visit 30
and then 29 and then 32.
So each time we look at a node,
we visit the node before we look at its children.
So we visited 25 before we looked at 20.
We visited 20 before we looked at 15 and 22.
And then we visited 27 before we looked at 26 and 30.
And we visited 30 before 29 and 32.
So that's pre-order.
Pre meaning the root is done first.
Okay, so with an in-order traversal,
we completely visit the left side and then we visit the root
and then we completely visit the right side.
And so we don't start with 25, we don't start with 20,
we start with 15, because that's the left side.
15 doesn't have any children,
so at that point we move up to the root and visit 20,
then we visit the right side which is 22.
And then we are finished with the complete left side
for the root, and so now we visit the root.
And now we do the same thing on the right side,
we wanna visit the left side first
then the roots and then the right side.
And so we don't visit 27 yet
because it has 26 on the left, so we visit 26
then we move up to the 27
because now we can visit the root for this subtree.
And now we wanna do the same thing with the right.
And so we don't visit 30 yet because 30 has a left child,
and so we visit 29 then we visit the root
and then we visit 32.
So with in-order, it's always do the entire left side
then the root, then the entire right side for every node.
And so it's 15, 20,
22, 25, 26, 'cause we need to do the left side first,
27, 29, because we do the left side first,
30 and 32.
Now notice something here, the data is sorted,
15, 20, 22, 25, 26, 27, 29, 30 and 32,
and that's why it's called in-order.
And so because of the characteristics
of a binary search tree, if we do an in-order traversal
the data is sorted.
And so it's really easy to get the sorted data
once you've inserted them into a binary search tree.
You just have to do an in-order traversal of the tree.
If you wanna sort an array for example,
you could insert the values into a binary search tree
and then traverse the tree.
And that would actually be faster
than some of the sort algorithms we looked at.
And so that's in-order, for every node
you visit the entire left subtree first
then you visit the node and then you visit
the entire right subtree.
And finally, we have post-order.
We had pre-order back here where we visited the root first
or the node, and then the left and then the right.
In post-order the root goes last,
and so you visit the entire left subtree for a node
and then the entire right subtree for the node
and finally you hit the node.
And so we're gonna start here at 15,
'cause we have to visit the entire left subtree
and right subtree for the root first
and then we have to visit the left or right subtree for 20,
so we get 15 and then 22 because we do the subtrees
before the node.
And then 20 and then we have to do
the entire right subtree before we do the root.
So we're gonna go 26 and then we've gotta do
the entire right subtree for 27 first
and then the entire left and right for 30,
so we're gonna go to 29, 32, now we can do the roots,
30, 27 and 25.
So in pre-order you visit the root first or the node.
So if we have the concept of a current node,
you're gonna visit the current node first
and then its entire left subtree
and then its entire right subtree.
And so we visit 25 and then we're gonna do
its entire left subtree and right subtree.
So we visit 20 and then we're gonna do
its entire left subtree, its entire right subtree.
And so we get 25, 20, 15 and 22
and then we do the same thing on the right side,
we do 27 and then we do its left subtree 26,
and then its right subtree.
So we're gonna do 30, its left subtree
That's pre-order, the root goes first.
In in-order it's left, root, right.
And so when we're talking about roots
we're talking about the root of every subtree.
And in post-order, it's left, right, root.
And so in this case we do 15, go to the right,
22 and then we do 20,
and then we don't do the root yet,
because the root goes last.
So we come here, 27 is gonna go last,
so 26 and then we go to the right,
30 is gonna go last, 29, 32 and then we can start
going back up, 30, 27, 25.
And so those are the four ways that we can traverse trees,
level, pre-order, in-order and post-order.
And so let's go back to IntelliJ now
and we're going to write a method
to do the in-order traversal of our tree.
And so here I am back in IntelliJ
and I'm going to go to the tree node class,
because as we saw in the slides,
each node can be a root of a subtree.
And we're gonna add the traversal method in here.
So right here, I'm gonna say, public void
(typing)
traverse in-order and I don't need to pass anything,
'cause we're just gonna start at this node.
And remember, for in-order we visit the left child
and then we visit the root
and then we visit the right child.
And so we're gonna say if the left child
is not equal to null, well, we need to traverse
the left child before we wanna traverse this node.
And so we're gonna say leftChild.traverseInOrder.
Then we wanna visit this node and so we'll say,
system.out.println and we'll say data equals plus data.
And in fact I'll make this print
and I'll add, change that to a semicolon first,
keep hitting L instead, and I'll add a comma here,
so plus comma equals.
And then finally 'cause we're doing in-order traverse
so we wanna visit the right child.
So we'll say if right child is not equal to null
visit the right child.
(typing)
And that's it, that's our traverse in-order for the node.
And so when we're doing this node
we wanna do, we're examining this node and its subtree.
And for in-order we wanna do the left child,
visit this node and then do the right child.
And by left child and right child,
of course, they can have children.
So this is saying we're gonna visit the left subtree
of this node first, then we're gonna visit this node
and that's when we print out its data
and then we're gonna visit the right subtree.
And so back in our tree class we need a method for this.
So we'll say public void, traverse in order
and all we wanna do here is traverse the root.
So if the root isn't null, isn't equal to null.
(typing)
Then we'll traverse the root, and that's it.
And so when we call this with the root
we'll check whether the root has a left child
and if it does we're gonna handle its left subtree first
and then we'll visit the root,
and then we'll handle its right subtree.
And so keep in mind that for in-order
as we saw in the slides, every node's left subtree
will be printed out before we actually
print out the data for the node
and then every node's right subtree.
So let's go back to our main method and call this now.
So we'll say inTree.traverseInOrder
and we should see these values printed out in sorted order,
because remember, when we traverse a tree in-order,
we actually end up with the values
coming out in sorted order.
So let's run.
It will probably be easier actually, looking at that,
if I didn't do this, if I just had the data and a comma.
So let's run that again,
and there we go.
So 15, 20, 22, 25, 26, 27, 29, 30 and 32.
And so our nodes were inserted,
one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine
and we have one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine values
and they were inserted where we expected
them to be inserted and our in-order traversal is working.
Because when we traverse in-order we'll get
the values in the tree in sorted order.
Okay, so now that we can build a tree and we can look
at what's in it, we should write a method
for finding a value in the tree.
And we'll do that in the next video.