(gentle music)
(typing)
Alright so I ended the last video
by saying that we have
a bug in this code or at least the implementation
has a bug and that is
that when we remove employees
we set the position to null
but that means that when we're doing our linear probing
we're not going to be able to find
some of our items for example Mary Smith.
When we put Mary Smith into the hash table
Jane Jones was occupying position 5
and Mike Wilson was occupying position 6
and so we had to use two probes to find position 7
but then we delete Jane and Mike.
And so when we come to get Mary
and we're doing our fine key
in this loop here we drop out of the loop
as soon as we hit a null position.
And we're gonna hit that null position right away
and so that means we can't find Mary anymore.
And so there are two ways that you can solve this problem.
You can on a remove you can rehash
all of the items that are already in the hash table.
So you can say okay
we're gonna start with a new hash table
so you'd create a new hash table
and then you're going to loop through
the existing arraigned you're gonna rehash all the values
because after we've deleted Jane
that would move Mary into position five right?
Because when we do the rehashing
when we come to Mary we're gonna hash her key
which is going to end up being five
and in the new hash table position five would be empty.
So that's one way of doing it.
Of course it means that on every remove
you're going to have to iterate
over all of the remaining elements and rehash them
and there's a performance hit
and of course that means removes
will no longer be done in constant time
even if the employee you're removing
is out the position you expect them to be at.
So for Jane Jones for example
she would be at position five
and boom we find her in position 5 right away
we're still gonna have to iterate over the entire
array and rehash everything
so it has its disadvantages.
The second way that we could deal with this problem is
instead of nulling out the employee
or the position in the array
instead we could add a feel to the stored employee class
that says whether an employee has been deleted or not.
Now how would this help?
Well it would let us distinguish between
positions that have always been empty
meaning nothing has ever been added to them
and positions that used to have something in them
but that something was deleted.
And so in that case when we did our find key
when we were doing this loop the position
of deleted employees would not be null
and so when we delete Jane
we wouldn't remove her we just set her
deleted field to true
and when we deleted Mike we wouldn't actually remove him
we just said set his deleted field to true
and so when we came looking for Mary
positions five and six wouldn't be null
and we'd be able to find her.
Now of course this has disadvantages first of all
you're going to end up with a polluted hash table
because you're gonna have a mix of live and deleted values.
The other thing is it means that
even though you're deleting items your load factor
isn't gonna change?
And it means you're gonna have to be doing
a lot more linear probing
because when you go to add an item
if it collides with a deleted item
then you have to do linear probing
and so in the first solution
you're gonna be hit when you do or remove
'cause you're gonna have to rehash the entire table.
With the second solution you're gonna be hit
when you do ads because
there's going to be more collisions
and you're gonna have to do a lot more linear probing
because you never remove anything from the table essentially
and so as usual it depends on
where you're willing to take the hit.
Do you want to take it on get?
So do you want to take it on removes.
I would rather take it on the remove
I would rehash the table.
And so let's try doing that.
So once again to remind you of what the problem was
If we run this now
we'll see that we can't find Mary.
So rather than using this let's put a marker in here
I'm going to rehash the table
because that will keep the table clean
and it means that it will reduce the number of collisions
and the load factor will be helped by this as well.
So when we remove an employee
rather than doing this line here
this hash table I'll just comment it out.
Okay so first we'll save our current hash table
into a temporary variable.
So we'll say stored employee
old hash table equals hash table.
And now we're going to create
a new brand new stored employee array
that's going to be the same size as our old hash table.
And so we've got our existing old hash table saved off
and hash table here now contains our new hash table.
So if we call
get or put or whatever at this point
it'll be operating on this new hash table.
So then we're going to say four into I equals zero
I less than bold hash table dot length I plus plus
and we want to hash all the values in the old hash table
and put them into the new hash table.
Now we have to check for null values obviously
so we're gonna say if old hash table I is not equal to null
then we want to rehash it
and we're gonna just do that
by putting it into the new hash table.
So we're gonna say put old hash table I
dot key that's gonna be the key we wanna use
and the value is gonna be old hash table I dot employee.
And that's it that's our rehashing
and so because here we've assigned our member variable
with the empty hash table
went the first time we call put
it's using that new all of our methods in here
we'll be using that new hash table.
And this should result in Mary being moved to position five
because if we've removed Jane
then Mary what will have been moved to position five.
Now I've said this is work
it means every time we do a removal
we're gonna be rehashing but if we don't do the work here
we're gonna create a lot more work
for ourselves up in the put method and in the get method
because it means we're never gonna remove
anything from the hash table essentially
we're just gonna mark it as deleted
and that's gonna result in a higher load factor
and a lot more collisions.
Now we could have code for resizing the array
and a robust hash table implementation would have that
in the put we'd be checking the load factor
and if necessary resizing the array
and when we do the resize I mean we'd rehash everything
but that would mean that
because we're keeping a lot of deleted items around
we could potentially be using a lot more memory
and it's all because we never get rid of anything.
So there's always advantages and disadvantages to everything
but I like the rehashing better
for this simple implementation.
So let's go to our main method now.
And so we're gonna add four employees
retrieve two of them and then
we're gonna remove Mike and Jane
and then now we should be able to get Mary.
And in fact when we print the hash table here
Mary should be at position five.
So let's run.
Alright so these are our results
and this does not look right to me
because in the second printout
we still have Mike and Jane in the array
so we're getting Mary back
because we haven't actually deleted anything.
So let's go over and look at our code
and that's because I commented out the line
that's actually knowing out the employee
so when we rehashed everything
the employee we deleted was not null.
So let's run this again.
Okay and this time
things worked the way we're expecting
so we have Mary in position five
and John in position three
and we're able to find Mary.
So this printout
is after we've added the four employees
and then if we look at our main method
we then retrieve
Mike and Mary and that works fine
'cause nobody's been deleted yet
and then we delete Mike and Jane
and then we try to retrieve Mary
and after we delete Mike and Jane
we're printing out the hash table again
and as you can see
now only John and Mary are left
and Mary is now in position five
because when we did the rehashing
after we deleted Jane position five was free.
And then when we go to retrieve Mary Smith
we can now get to her.
And so as you can see when you use linear probing
there's a lot more work involved.
In the best case using linear probing
is still constant time
if the position you're you want to work with is empty
and so if you're adding an employee
the position is empty and if you're getting an employee
If the key at the hashed position
is the one that you're interested in
that's constant time.
Now If you actually have to use probes
then the worst case is a linear time
because it's possible that you might have to traverse
the entire array before you either find an empty position
in the case of an ad
or before you find the key you're interested in.
Now does this mean that linear probing isn't good
to use to deal with collisions?
Well no!
Because with a decent hashing function
and if you are resizing the array occasionally
so you're keeping the load factor reasonable
you're never gonna have to use that many probes
in the average case you won't have to use a tone of probes.
You're not gonna have to traverse the entire array.
But as I've said many times the hashing function
and keeping the load factor reasonable
Is what's gonna make or break your hash tables performance.
So if you have a hash function that produces
tones of collisions all the time
or your hash table is really full
and you don't precise it very often
your performance is gonna suffer.
Now before we leave linear probing
one variation is quadratic probing.
And when you use quadratic probing
instead of incrementing the hashed value by one
you increment it by some constant squared.
So for example you start out
by incrementing the hash value by one squared
and then you'd increment it by two squared
and then three squared et cetera.
Alright so that's linear probing in the next video
we'll take a look at the second strategy
for dealing with collisions
and it's a strategy that's called chaining.
I'll see you there.