(gentle music)
(keyboard clacking)
Alright, so let's go ahead
and start implementing delete.
Now, normally, we've been putting a method
in the TreeNode class and one in the Tree class,
but for delete, we're gonna do everything in the Tree class.
And so, I'm gonna go over to Tree,
and I'll add the delete method after the get method.
So, I'm gonna say public, void, delete,
and we want the value that we wanna delete,
so we'll say int value.
And what we're gonna do here is call a second method
that's going to be a recursive method.
And we're going to say the root equals
delete
and we're gonna pass the root and the value.
We're getting an error right now
'cause I haven't written this second delete method yet.
What we're doing here is we're passing,
as the first value, we're passing the root of the subtree
that we want to search for the value.
And so, when we first call this method, of course,
we wanna search the Tree.
We don't know which direction to go in yet,
so we're passing the root and then we're passing the value
that we want to delete.
And what we're ultimately going to return is
the root of the Tree.
Now, this might not change, but if it turns out
that the root is the value we wanna delete,
then the root will change.
So, let's code this method,
'cause things will probably become clearer at that point.
And so, I'll say private,
because we don't need to expose this method
to the outside world.
They would call this delete method with the value.
So, private
TreeNode.
This essentially returns the replacement node.
If a node doesn't have to be replaced,
then you just get the same node back.
And so here, if the root wasn't the one being replaced,
we'd just get the same node back for the root.
Delete.
And for this one,
we need the subtreeRoot.
And so this is the root of the subtree we wanna search
and when we start out, we wanna search the entire Tree
because we don't know which direction to go in yet
and so we're passing the root of the entire Tree,
and we need the value that we wanna delete.
And when I say search, of course,
we need to find the value that we wanna delete,
so we know which node to actually delete.
Okay, so the first thing we're gonna check
is if this is null
and that would be the case of the Tree being empty.
So we're gonna if subtreeRoot equals null,
then we're just gonna return subtreeRoot.
I mean, if it's null, we're essentially returning null.
We could put null here.
And so basically, we'd just being assigning
null to root again.
And root is already null, so that's fine.
In the case of a subtree,
that would mean that we've decided that we wanna
look down the left or the right subtree
and there's no child there.
And so this would stop the recursion essentially.
So at this point, there are three possibilities,
either the root of the subtree
is the value we're looking for,
so that's the node we wanna delete,
or we've gotta go down and search the left subtree
or the right subtree.
And so we're gonna say, if value
is less than
subtreeRoot.getData,
then we wanna search the left subtree.
And so we'll say, subtreeroot.,
now remember, this method returns the replacement node.
And so we're gonna say, set the left child with
whatever this method returns
because we're gonna call this method in here.
So we're gonna say delete,
subtreeRoot
.getLeftChild
and the same value that we're searching for.
And so what this is saying is
if the value is less than than the root
of the subtree we're searching,
then we wanna move to the subtree's left child.
And at the end, we're gonna replace the subtree's
left child with whatever the result of the delete is.
Now it's possible that
this means this will be replaced,
the left child, because the left child
is gonna be the value that we actually delete
or it's possible that it won't change.
And if it doesn't change, we'll just get the same node back
that's already the left child.
So that handles the case of if the value is
less than the subtreeRoot.
So now, of course, we wanna check if the value is greater.
I'll see if value is greater than subtreeRoot.getData.
In that case, we wanna do the same thing,
but we're gonna go to the right.
So we'll say subtreeRoot.setRightChild
delete
subtreeRoot.getRightChild,
and the value.
It's the same deal here,
we're now gonna look down the right subtree
and if it turns out that the right child
needs to be replaced,
what will be returned is the new node,
and so we'll set the right child to that new node.
If it doesn't need to be replaced,
we'll just get back the same node.
Now if the value isn't less than the root
and it isn't greater than the root,
that means it's equal to the root.
And so that essentially means that we have found
the node that we want to delete
and it is the subtreeRoot.
And we're gonna say else.
And we're now gonna handle the first two cases
that the subtreeRoot has no children,
or the subtreeRoot has one child.
So we're gonna say, if
subtreeRoot
.getLeftChild
equals null,
now there are two possibilities here.
Either this is a leaf
and so the right child is also null
or it has a right child.
And so what do we wanna replace this node with?
So if this node has zero children,
meaning that the left child is null
and the right child is also null,
then we just wanna lop off the node.
And so the replacement node is nothing, it's null.
If it has a right child, then the replacement node
is its right child.
So what we're gonna do is return subtreeRoot.getRightChild.
Because this works in both cases.
This TreeNode is returning the replacement node
and so, if this is a leaf,
then the right child will be null and that works
'cause we're saying the replacement node is null.
And so what that will do ultimately
because of the recursion,
is the appropriate child of the parent will be nulled out
because here, as you can see,
we're setting the left and right children
with the result of the delete.
And so, if we're returning null,
that would mean the left to right child
is being set to null.
And so in the case of a leaf, we'd return null,
meaning we're telling the parents,
"Set your left or right child to null
"because I'm gone now."
If it does have a right child, then we want that right child
to replace subtreeRoot.
And so we want the right child to replace
the left or right child of this node's parent.
Now we do the same thing for the opposite case.
Else
if
subtreeRoot.getRightChild
equals null,
then we're gonna return subtreeRoot.getLeftChild.
And that does the same thing.
We're saying, okay, if I don't have a right child
and I don't have a left child, then just lop me off,
so return null.
And then up here, when the recursive call returns
and we're handling the parent,
the parent will set its left of right child to null.
If it does have a left child, then we want the parent.
We want the left child to replace the node we're deleting.
And so due to the recursion, the parent
will set its left of right child
to the left child of the node we're deleting.
And then what we're gonna return at the bottom,
now this is, cases zero and one.
Let me put this in here.
So
cases
zero
and one.
Node to delete
has
zero
or one children,
zero or one child, children.
Make that grammatically correct for the one child case.
We haven't handled case two yet.
We're gonna do that in another video,
but down here, once we're done,
we're gonna return the subtreeRoot.
And so as I said, if we make it down here,
it means that this node is not the node we wanna delete.
And so we just, the subtreeRoot
isn't the node that we wanna delete
and so we just wanna return it.
And so that's why this works,
because we're always returning the replacement node
and if this isn't the node we wanna delete,
then we just want the same node.
Essentially, the node will be a replacement node
for itself if it's not the node we're deleting.
And so when we return to the parent
and we're setting the left and right child,
we'd be, essentially be setting the left and right child
to the existing value.
All right, so that's it for
the first case.
And the second case,
I guess cases zero and one, I think I'm doing arrays here,
cases one and two.
Okay, so that's the cases one and two.
We have the third case to do.
We're not gonna test this until we've added the code
for the third case.
And the third case, of course,
is when the node isn't a leaf
and the node doesn't have just one child,
but the node has two children.
And so let's move onto how to handle that case.
I'll see you in the next video.