I've mentioned the term priority queue
a few times in relation to heaps
and that's because a really common use of heaps
is to use them as what's called a priority queue.
Now remember queues are usually first-in, first-out.
Items are removed from the queue
in the order that they're added.
But what if we wanted to change that slightly
and say that we always want to access
the highest priority item.
And so, rather than always removing
the items in the order they were added,
when we add an item we assign it a priority
and when we go to remove an item
the highest priority item is the one that's removed.
So it's not gonna be first-in, first-out or FIFO anymore.
It's whichever item has the highest priority,
kind of like it's not FIFO when you go to an emergency room.
If you've ever gone to an emergency room of a hospital
that uses triage,
they don't see patients in the order they come in.
Somebody who's having a heart attack
is gonna be seen before somebody who perhaps needs stitches.
So it's the same idea for priority queues,
when we take an item off the queue
we always want the highest priority item first.
So if the values in the nodes indicate the priority
and of course they can, then a max-heap
is an ideal data structure for this
because the value with the highest priority
is always at the root of the heap.
And so, when you want to remove the highest priority item
from a max-heap, you just remove the root
and that can be done in constant time.
Now since heaps are usually implemented as arrays,
that just means that we're always removing
the item at position zero.
And then once we've removed the highest priority item
and we fix the heap,
that means that the next highest priority item
is now at the root.
And when we want that we can remove that at constant time.
And if we add a new item into the heap
that has a higher priority, after we fix the heap
that highest priority item will be at the root.
And so we can always get the highest priority item
in constant time.
And so a priority queue is an abstract data type
that's commonly implemented as a max-heap.
Every item in the heap has a priority
and we build a max-heap based on the priority value.
So if we're dealing with integers themselves
like we were in our code in the implementation that we did
then the integers themselves have their priority value.
But more commonly, you're gonna be dealing with
other types of objects
and there will be something in the object
that indicates what the priority is for that object.
So when it comes to priority ques
the common operations are, insert with priority,
remove the highest priority item
and that's called Poll, and peak,
which will return the item with the highest priority
but, it won't remove it from the heap.
This is the same as peaking at a stack or a queue.
Now when we remove the highest priority item of course,
we might have to fix the heap
but when we peak at the heap we don't.
Because we don't actually remove anything.
So Java has a priority queue class,
that's what's on the screen,
so there's no need to code your own
but of course if you did you'd just be coding a max-heap.
And we'll see that this is an unbounded priority queue
based on a priority heap.
And so that means there's no limit
to the number of items it can hold.
Now one interesting thing about this priority queue is
it's actually a min-heap.
The head of this queue is the least element
with respect to the specified ordering.
So the lower the number, the higher the priority.
If you're number 999, you're a lower priority
then somebody who's got a priority of 10.
It's an array implementation.
We can see here it says a priority queue is unbounded
but has an internal capacity governing the size of an array.
And so they're resizing the array
if you try to add something
to a priority queue that's already full.
This is not synchronised
so if you want to use it for multiple threads
you should use priority blocking queue instead.
It's only been around since 1.5
so it's a fairly recent addition.
Okay so let's go over to the IDE now
and give this class a try.
Alright, so here we are in the IDE
and we'll just use the JDK priority queue class
and we'll use it with integer
just to demonstrate some of the methods.
So let's create a priority queue.
So, priority queue and we'll have an integer priority queue
and I'll just call it pq equals new priority queue.
And let's just add some items to it.
So we'll say pq dot add 25.
Pq dot add
Let's add minus 22.
Pq dot add 1343.
Pq dot add 54.
Let's add zero.
And we'll add another negative number.
So it'll be negative 3492.
And pq dot add 429.
So now let's see what some of the methods give to us
when we call them.
So we'll say, system dot out dot print line.
And let's peak at this priority queue.
So we'll say, peak.
And let's run this right now, see what we get.
And we'll see that we get the lowest number on the queue.
Remember that this implementation is a min-heap.
And so the minimum value is going to be at the root.
And so the lower, in this implementation,
the lower your number, the higher priority you are.
So minus 3492 is still on the heap
because peak doesn't change the heap in any way.
So let's now remove the item with the highest priority.
So we'll say pq dot remove
and let's peak after we've done that
to see if the heap is changed in any way.
And of course it has.
So, before we removed minus 3492, that was at the root.
The remove method, actually returns the item it removed
and so we see minus 3492 again
and then after the removal, minus 22 is now at the root.
So we get that with the peak.
And that would be the next item
with the highest priority.
So now let's call poll.
So we'll say, system dot out dot print line pq dot poll
and let's peak at the queue after we've done that.
So we'll run and we'll see that when we polled,
minus 22 was returned and then when we peak
we're getting zero.
Poll and removed are the same thing
so they both remove the highest priority item
and return that.
And so minus 22 gets returned and then zero
will now be at the root of the heap
because it's now the minimum value.
Now if you wanted to, you can remove
just some random number.
So we'll say system dot out dot print line pq dot remove
and we'll just remove 54, let's say.
And now if we peak again
we should still see zero at the top.
So let's run and you'll see that here
we got a true back.
It doesn't return the object you removed
because you're actually passing what you want to remove
so it would kind of be redundant
to return what you want to remove.
Instead it says, yes, I successfully removed this.
So if this was false,
it would mean that it couldn't find this in the heap
and zero is still at the root.
And so for a final call here let's add another value
and we'll add something
that's higher priority than the root.
So zero is the root, so we'll add another negative number.
So we'll say, pq dot add and we'll just add minus one
and then if we peak at the queue after doing that
we should see minus one at the root.
So let's run again
and we do, we see minus one at the root.
So the difference between poll and remove,
when you pass it a value
and in fact remove when you don't is,
if you call remove without a value
or you call poll, it always removes the root.
If you pass it a specific value,
then it doesn't remove the root
instead it removes that value.
Now if you wanted to build a priority queue
using instances that aren't integers,
of course that would be fine,
as long as the class implements the comparable interface.
So the priority queue can compare instances.
You can also provide a comparator
when you construct the queue.
There is a version of the constructor
that let's you pass a comparator.
Now we can get the array from the queue
and so the way that we do that is
we would call the two array method.
And so let's do that after we've removed 54,
just to see what we get.
So we'll say, object and we're gonna get an array,
int equals pq dot two array
and we'll say, for object num int
system dot out dot print line num
just to see what we get.
So let's run that.
And I guess that's not very helpful
'cause we can't really see where it starts.
So, I'm going to comment out all the other print lines
so that we just see
the array after we've removed 54.
So let's run.
And we have negative 3492, zero, minus 22,
54, 25, 13, 43 and 429.
So since I commented out all the prints,
that's where we're actually removing things,
so we're basically getting the entire heap
after we've added the items.
And you'll notice,
if you remember how things are stored as an array.
So we have minus 3492 and then zero
and minus 22 as it's children
and so this guy is less, remember this is an in-heap,
he's less than zero and minus 22.
And the zero's children would be 54 and 25
and zero is less than both of those.
And minus 22's children would be 13, 43 and 429
and of course, minus 22 is less than both of those.
Let me go up now and comment out the line of removing 54
just so we can see 54 disappear.
And if we run again we'll see that now 54 is gone
and we got this true here from the print line.
This class is pretty straight forward
and know what a queue is already,
even though this is a different type of queue.
You know what a heap is.
So it's just a matter of exploring your documentation.
But if you do need a priority queue in Java
you can take a look at this implementation in the JDK.
Just remember that it's a min-heap.
Now you might be thinking,
well what if I need a max-heap?
Well, don't forget you can provide
a comparator to the class.
So, you could provide a comparator
that will get you the behaviour you want
and builds a max-heap instead of a min-heap.
And so you'd need a comparator
that will look at the two values
and whenever you have one value greater than the other
you in fact want to return that that value's less.
You'd want to flip things around
so that this class would actually be building a max-heap.
So if you want a max-heap, you're gonna have to
provide a comparator to the class to get that behaviour.
Alright, that's it for heaps.
See you in the next video.