(music)
Alright, now that we know about Hash tables
and more importantly we understand
what hashing is, we can look at another
sort algorithm called Bucket sort.
Bucket sort uses hashing
and it makes assumptions about the data,
like radix and counting sort do
and because of that it can achieve linear time.
It performs best when the hashed values of the items
being sorted are evenly distributed,
so there aren't many collisions.
So when it comes to bucket sort,
we are hashing the values that we are sorting.
So there is no concept of keys and values.
The important thing when it comes to Bucket Sort
is the values that we are sorting are hashed.
And so how does it work,
it starts out by distributing the items
that you wanna sort into buckets
based on their hashed values
and this is called scattering.
After the scattering is done,
it sorts the items in each bucket
and then after every bucket has been sorted
it merges the buckets,
this is called the gathering phase.
And because all of the items in every bucket
have been sorted, you can just basically
concatenate all the buckets one after the other.
And so in the third phase you're gonna be
copying the items in the buckets back into
the original array.
And, this is actually a generalisation of counting sort.
Because if you remember counting sort,
we went through the values
and then we distributed the values
into the counting array
and then in the final phase we just
traversed the counting array
and for each value we copied how many we had back
into the original array.
And so, bucket sort is doing something similar
except its distributing the items based on
their hashed values and then it has to sort
the items in each bucket.
But, then it goes over the buckets
and copies them back into the original array.
Now, there is one important thing here.
In order for this third step to work,
the gathering step, the values in bucket X
must all be greater than the values in bucket X-1
and less than the values in bucket X+1.
And so what does this mean,
well in the merging phase we are
going to write the values in bucket 0
back to the array and then we are gonna follow
those by the values in bucket 1
and values in bucket 2 etc...
That means that the values in bucket 0
all have to be less than the values in bucket 1.
Otherwise only write the values in bucket 0
back to the array and follow them by bucket 1
and they are not gonna be sorted.
If values in bucket 1 can be less than the values
in bucket 0 we are not gonna have a sorted array.
And we will see this in a minute.
So what this means is whatever hashing function you use,
it has to make sure that the hashed values
it produces meet that requirement.
And so, if you have a hashing function,
if you are sorting the values one, two and three,
you can't have a hashing function that would put three
into a lower bucket than one.
That wouldn't work, because when you copy
the values back into the array,
three would be copied back before one is.
And so your hashing function has to hash
the values so that this requirement is met.
So that if it puts a value into bucket 5
then that value has to be lower
and when I say the value in this case
I mean the actual value not the hashed value.
That value has to be lower than the values that
would put into bucket 7.
And so let's take a look into an example here.
Let's say we are gonna sort the array at the top.
So, we are gonna sort 54, 46 etc...
What we are gonna do is you will see
in the implementation video is, we are gonna sort
them into buckets based on their ten's position.
And so, the hash function the way it's gonna hash
these values is it's going to hash 54 to five.
It's gonna hash 46 to four,
its gonna hash 83 to eight.
And so, in the buckets and this would be our bucket array.
46 and 43 are gonna end up in same bucket.
54 will end up in the bucket for the 50's.
66 will end up in the bucket for the 60's etc...
And so this meets the requirement
that all of the values in the lower bucket
have to be less than all of the values
in the higher bucket.
So, this is the scattering phase.
Then we do the sorting phase
and so we are gonna sort all of our buckets.
And so, here we can 46 is coming before 43.
But, we sort that and the same thing with 95.
Here, 95 is coming before 92.
After we have sorted, 92 comes before 95.
And then the final phase, the gathering phase,
is to traverse over all our buckets and copy
them back into the original array.
And so we are gonna copy 43 and 46,
54, 66, 83, 92 and 95.
Now, if we did not have that requirement
that values in lower buckets be less than the values
in higher buckets this wouldn't work.
I mean if 92 and 95 could be in this bucket
when we copy the values back to the array
and we do that just by traversing
the array in order, the bucket array in order.
If we didn't have that requirement
and had values greater than 43 in front here
when we copied back we would have values
greater than 43 appearing before 43.
And so obviously, our array wouldn't be sorted.
And so bucket sort is not an in-place algorithm.
It uses extra memory that depends on the number
of items in the array that you are sorting.
And the stability will depend on what sort
algorithm you used to sort the buckets.
So back here, we are gonna obviously sort
each bucket and you can use
any algorithm you want to do that.
And so if the algorithm you use is unstable
then bucket sort will end up being unstable.
If it's stable then bucket sort will be stable.
Now, to achieve linear time, you would have one
value per bucket.
Now, insertion sort is often used
to sort the buckets, because insertion sort
is a really fast algorithm when the number
of items is small.
Like, we are not gonna use insertion sort
we are going to use the sort method
and the Collections class in the JDK
and it uses a an adaptive merge sort algorithm.
But I wanted to make you aware
that insertion sort is a popular
algorithm to use for bucket sort.
Alright, so now that we know how bucket sort works,
let's implement it.
I will see you in the next video.