Hi.
My name is Kevin Jones from Pluralsight,
and this is the Hot Deployment module from the Java Virtual
Machine: Class Loading and Reflection class. In this module,
we'll take a look at how class loaders can give us the ability
to reload classes dynamically.
This means that we can, for example,
ship new code to an application and have that application load that new
code without having to fully reload the application.
This is the sort of thing that web servers do.
So, for example, Tomcat, if you ship a new version of a server into Tomcat,
we don't need to reload Tomcat. Tomcat just detects that this
new version of the server that shipped and is able to reload all
the classes that make up that particular application, that
particular web application. This gives us great flexibility in the way we can configure our applications.