So I'd like to cover a couple of things just before we start writing code.
First of all,
there's a method on Class called forName, and forName allows us to
load classes based on the class name. By default, forName takes the
name of the class and a Boolean parameter,
specifying whether to define that class or not.
But there's a three‑parameter version of class.forName.
There's a third parameter,
takes a classloader, and class.forName then uses
that classloader to load the class.
So it looks something like this.
We create,
for example here, a new URLClassLoader, call it ucl, call
Class.forName, passing the name of the class, and then as
the third parameter, passing ucl.
In this case,
the class is loaded by the classloader defined using the
URLClassLoader we created, not the application classloader that
was loaded when the application started up.
This makes it slightly easier to use classloaders and provide some isolation.
So something else we've mentioned and something I'd like to emphasize is
the idea of using interfaces in our code while using base classes to
allow us to make calls on classes that we load.
So, for example,
here, we're using Class.forName to load a Rocket class, and we're
passing this thing a classloader. The ucl is a reference to a
URLClassLoader. But when we call newInstance,
we cast this to be of type Rocket, but Rocket here, the type
Rocket, is visible to the application's classloader,
and that really defeats the purpose of using the
URLClassLoader to load the class in the first place.
Instead, we do what we've already done in our demos.
We still use the URLClassLoader to load the class Rocket.
But now, when we call newInstance, we cast this to be of type Rocket interface.
So Rocket interface is visible to the application's classloader
delegation, but Rocket is only visible to the URLClassLoader's
delegation. So we could load Rocket using one URLClassLoader and
cast it to be of type Rocket interface.
We could then load another copy of Rocket,
a different version using a different URLClassLoader, but
cast it to the same Rocket interface.
So we did a previous demonstration where we use a
URLClassLoader to load a class file.
This code is similar,
except here, we're using Class.forName, and we're passing the
URLClassLoader as the third parameter to Class.forName.
So in this case,
com.pluralsight.Quote where we load it as a class from the
location specified in the URLClassLoader,
which is simply
demos/ClassloadingWithItf/out/artifacts/Implementations_jar/Implementations.jar.
If I take this code and duplicate it, but just change the name so we have url2
rather than url1 and classloader 2, but we still do Class.forName, we keep all
the locations the same, so we're still loading from Implementations.jar for
both URLs, I can create an instance here using clazz1, and I can create an
instance using clazz2. And these are both cast to be of type IQuote.
And we know that Quote, com.pluralsight.Quote, indeed
implements IQuote. And then at the end here,
I'll print out two checks, a check to see if something of type clazz1
is equal to clazz2, and I also call quote1.getClass and
quote2.getClass and check to see if they are the same.
So at the command prompt, if I run this code, so again,
just pointing my application classpath at the interface's JAR file and
the location, out\production\Client, where the main classes are held and
then run com.mantiso.Main, we see that clazz1 == clazz2 is false and
quote1.class == quote2.class == false.
So here, clazz1 and clazz2 are not the same.
So the class loaded here and the class loaded here are not the same,
which is sort of unusual. As you saw that when we create a class,
that class should be cached by the classloader.
So in this case,
we might expect clazz1 to be the same as clazz2. When we call
Class.forName here, we'd expect the same class instance to be
returned in the clazz1 and clazz2,
but as we're using different classloader delegations,
that's not the case.
So here, our URLClassLoader created on this line will load clazz2 and the
URLClassLoader created on this line will load clazz1. So they can't be
the same. And the same for the calls here.
It's the same for the second check. When we check to see if
quote1.getClass is the same as quote2.getClass, quote1.getClass
returns clazz1, and quote2.getClass returns clazz2. So we'd
expect to see the same result.
So using this technique, we get a degree of isolation.
So the class is loaded by this classloader delegation here. Using one
URLClassLoader can be different to the classes loaded by this
delegation here loaded by a second URL classloader.
That lets us load classes in isolation and, therefore, to load different versions of the same class at runtime.