To demonstrate the use of the CLASSPATH in Java,
we are going to write two simple Java files,
Helper.java, which will have a getMessage method that'll return a string,
and Main.java, which will have a public static void main,
and this will simply use the helper.
The Helper class will be a public class called Helper,
and this class will have one method,
which will be a public string method called getMessage,
getMessage, and this method will return a string,
something like Hello from helper, and we can save that.
Main.java will have a class, again a public class, so public class Main.
And this class will have a public static void main
method that takes a string array, capital S,
of course, all args.
Inside here, we'll create a helper, and helper is in com.mantiso,
so com.mantiso.Helper helper = new com.mantiso.Helper.
And then we'll simply do System.out.println,
and we'll output Helper.getMessage, all very simple.
To compile this, we'll go to the command prompt.
And at the command prompt, we'll run this command to compile the Helper class.
What we're seeing here is they compile the source files
from src\com\mantiso\Helper.java,
and I'll put the class file into the classes directory.
If we do that, first of all, for Helper.java and then again for Main.java,
what we end up with is a classes directory. And,
in the subdirectory of classes,
we'll see that we have com\mantiso and com\pluralsight.
In com\pluralsight, we have the Main class,
and in com\mantiso, we'll have the Helper class.
To run this code from the command line,
we'd use Java directly to execute the class files.
We need to tell it what class files to execute.
So you'd think we might be able to do something like java
classes\com\pluralsight\Main.class, but that's simply not going to work.
The class is not called classes\com\pluralsight\Main.
The name of the class is com.pluralsight.Main.class.
So maybe we could try java classes and then say com.pluralsight.Main.class.
And again, this doesn't work.
It simply doesn't find the classes there.
So we have the tell Java where to find these classes,
and there are two ways of doing this.
We could set a global CLASSPATH,
and we do that by setting the CLASSPATH environment variable.
And in this case,
we can say set CLASSPATH=classes as classes is the
directory that contains our Java classes.
If we do that,
I can then say java com.pluralsight.Main, leave the .class off the end,
and the main code runs. We get Hello from helper.
If I unset CLASSPATH,
so I'll just say set CLASSPATH= and try that again. Again, that's not
going to work. It can't find com.pluralsight.Main. Setting the global
CLASSPATH is generally not a good idea,
however, as this will affect every Java application on the system.
If you have an application that uses a JAR file that contains classes, and
that JAR file or another version of that JAR file is installed elsewhere
on your system, and that elsewhere is on the CLASSPATH, then you might
find that you end up using the wrong JAR file. So a better way to set the
CLASSPATH is to set it when we actually run Java itself, and we do that by
saying java ‑cp or java ‑classpath and just specify where the CLASSPATH
is. And we can say java ‑cp classes, and again we can do com.pluralsight,
pluralsight.Main. And again, it will find the code for me.
If we have more than one location to load classes from,
we can provide multiple locations on the CLASSPATH.
We can do that if we're on Windows by separating the locations with a semicolon.
If I'm on a UNIX‑based system, we do it by separating the locations with a colon.
So at the moment, we have a classes directory, and this directory, as we've
seen, contains a com\montiso and a com\pluralsight subdirectory. And it's
the montiso directory that contains our Helper class. What we'll now do is
move our Helper class into a JAR file.
So if we change into the classes folder and then from here,
we can run this command.
This says to create a JAR file, call helper.jar and include
the file called com\montiso\Helper.class.
If we do that,
it creates the file for me. So if I do a dir, there's the
Helper.jar. And I'll then move that file up one layer into
a folder I created called lib.
So if I go back to the root and do a dir, you can see that here now, we have
our classes folder, our lib folder, and our src folder.
The next thing I need to do is to delete the Helper class. So I can
just do del classes\com\montiso\Helper.class.
So now we have a main class that's in the classes directory,
but we have no Helper class there.
So if I try and run java ‑cp classes
com.pluralsight.Main, this will try and execute,
but it will now try and load the com.montiso.Helper
class, and that class doesn't exist.
We get a NoClassDefFoundError. So we need to tell Java where to find that class,
and that class lives in the JAR file. So on the CLASSPATH,
we can now specify a semicolon‑separated list of locations,
and one of those locations could be the JAR file. So I can say
lib\helper.jar and run the code.
Sure enough, it finds the class file again, and the code
executes correctly. So on Windows,
we'd have classes;lib\helper.jar; anything else. On a
UNIX‑based system, we'd use colon, so it would be classes:lib\helper.jar: anything else beyond that.