To show some of the aspects of reflection, we're
going to use a fairly simple class,
this one here called Car, and this class has a couple of constructors. It
has a default constructor and a constructor that takes an int. It has a
method called drive, a method called accelerate, which is a private
method, and a method called selectDrive, which is a private method. These
are just two helper methods.
So what can we do with reflection?
Well, we know we can create instances, so I can say Class cls = equals Car.class.
Then I can say cls.newInstance, and I can create an instance
of the car, and that is used in reflection.
We're creating the object,
using its type at runtime rather than using the new keyword
and discovering its type at compile time.
And if I run this code,
we'll see that an instance is created. There's no error here.
If I go back into the Car class, though,
and remove the default constructor and run the code
again, now we got an exception.
We got an instantiation exception,
which tells us that it can't find com.pluralsight.Car..
Init is the constructor.
It's looking for a constructor with no parameters to try and call, but we
don't have one currently, so let's put this back as it was.
So that's about the simplest thing that we can do.
However, once we have class of the type we are trying to examine,
we can discover a whole bunch of information about that class.
So, for example,
we can say cls.getMethods, and this returns an array of method types,
and this gives me information about each of the methods on the class.
So in here, for example, we could write a for loop.
We could say for (Method method: methods). And inside
here, we can print out the name of the methods. We say
%s\r\n and then do method.getName.
And if I run this code now, we'll see the name of the
methods on the class. So notice in this list,
we get methods from the class itself, and method from object is the methods
that we derive from. So by my calling getMethods, that returns a list of the
public methods on the type and the methods of any types that we derive from.
Notice as well, we get three wait methods, and that's three different
overloads of the wait method. And we can see that by printing out the number
of parameters for each method.
So each method type has a function called getParameterCount.
We're going to assign this to an int count, let's say. We
can then do something like System.out and print out the
count. Let's put this in brackets,
and so %d for the count is going to be an integer, and say
count here. At the end of this, we'll do a print line, and
we'll remove the new lines here.
And then if we run the code again,
we'll see that there's a version of wait with no parameters,
there's a version of wait with 1 parameter, and there's a
version of wait with 2 parameters.
So getMethods returns all the public methods of the class or any
classes or interfaces that we derive from or implement.
We can also get the private methods of this class by using a similar method.
Rather than calling getMethods, we can call
getDeclaredMethods, so we're tidying this up slightly.
If we say getDeclaredMethods here, we'll put an empty line here just
to separate the two, and if I run the code again,
we get the list of methods here, and then following that,
we get the declared methods, and these include drive as it was here.
That's the public method with two parameters.
Now we also get selectDrive, which is a single parameter, and accelerate, and that's a private method with 0 parameters.