So in the previous module we saw that we can use a classpath and
place classes somewhere and that classpath.
And the classpath can reference a directory, or the classpath can reference a
JAR file. In this module, we'll see how we can make use of the inbuilt class
loaders in Java and how to write our own class loader.
So first of all, we'll take a look at writing and using a URLClassLoader.
So we have a Main class here, and in here we're going to create a
URLClassLoader and use that to specify a location to load classes.
So we do that by defining a URLClassLoader. And this is in java.net.
We can just call it ucl. We create a new instance of that
URLClassLoader. And the constructor to this takes an array of URLs. So
we need to define a URL, so we're going to say URL url,
and we'll end up wrapping all of this inside a try‑catch block. And
there will be a few exceptions that we have to handle.
So for now we'll just do try‑catch, and we'll add the exceptions in a moment.
So inside the try block we'll say URL = new URL, and we'll need
to pass this the location of our classes.
So for this example,
we've created a file called Quoter.jar that contains a quote class.
So here we need to specify where that file lives.
Now for this example,
we've got to hardcode this location, and we need to specify a URL.
The location is on c:\demos\lib\quoter.jar. So that will be in URL
format, c:/demos/lib/quoter.jar.
And then to make this a URL, we'll need to say file:///,
and that should give us access to this URL. And this is
complaining that we need to add a catch,
so we add a catch clause to this and get rid of the empty one here.
And we can now catch the exceptions thrown when we create the URL. To the
class loader we pass an array of URLs. So here we can say new URL and into
here initialize that with the URL we created above.
So just like the classpath, we can pass as many URLs to our class loader as
we need to use. That code will simply load the class.
So once the class loader has been created,
we can then use that to load up a class. So we can say something like
Class clazz = ucl.loadClass. And to loadClass we pass the name of the
class we'd like to load. Now I know that in Quoter.jar there's a
class called com.mantiso.Quote.
So that should load that class for me.
And again, IntelliJ's complaining.
We need to add a catch clause. We'll add a ClassNotFoundException in this place.
Once we have the class in place,
we can create an instance, so I can say Object o = clazz.newInstance.
And again it wants to throw an exception, in this case an
InstantiationException, an IllegalAccessException.
Once we have that,
we'll print out just the information about the class. We'll call
o.toString and print that message out, which,
in this case,
will just print out the hash code of the class. Once that's all in place, so
if I compile this code, let's go to Build and Make project,
go to a command window, and in here run the application.
Our IDE has saved this to a location called out\production\demos,
and we have com.pluralsight.Main. And from here,
if I run the code,
then we just print out the hash code of the class. We
show the class has been loaded.
If we change the name of the class, for example,
here and build the code and then run this again,
we'll get a ClassNotFoundException. So of course,
the problem with this example is that when I call newInstance,
I only get back something of type object.
Now I know I'm actually getting back something of type com.mantiso.Quote,
but I can't use that type directly here because if I do that,
that defeats the whole purpose of me using a class loader. Because
by using this type directly inline in the code,
then in that case we'll simply use the application class loader.
So if I need to access the methods on the quote type,
I need some other way to do that.
And the way we do that typically is to break this down into
using interfaces and implementations. So we have a slightly more complex example to show that.