So we've just done a fairly basic introduction to class loading.
So we've seen that we can set, for example,
a global class path, and we've seen the biggest set a class path
when an application runs. In the rest of this class, we'll cover
some more classloading basics.
So we'll talk about the Bootstrap class loader and the extension class
loader. We'll talk about classloading delegation and how we can see
the delegation within the class loaders.
We'll take a look at how we can write our own class loader
and we can use that to load classes, for example,
from a database.
We'll see how we can use classloading delegation to our
benefit so we can isolate class loaders.
Use this to do things like hot deploying Java code.
So you're running application and you want to update the application while
it's still running, we can do that by using class loaders.
This is the sort of thing that Java web applications do
when you want to deploy a new service,
for example. And finally in the class, we'll take a look at Java
reflection and we'll see how Java reflection works.
And then we'll use reflection to implement a simple IoC container,
an inversion of control container, to get a really good handle on
how we can use reflection to create instances of types and to load those types at runtime.