What about the built‑in classes?
We've seen that we can use the extensions directory to contain libraries,
so we put helper.jar inside the extensions folder.
But in my code here,
I've now created a new string and passed it the text Hello World,
and I simply print out that string.
If I go back to my command prompt and compile our code,
so again we're just saying compile the code from the src path src,
and I put it to classes.
And that should compile okay.
And I take that code and run it, again just
specifying the class path of classes, we get Hello from the helper,
and we get Hello World.
So the string class is coming from java.lang.String,
and that's part of the standard Java runtime.
Now suppose we try to write our own string class.
We can write our own string class and put this into a package called java.lang.
So here, inside Sublime, if I do File, New File,
and then do a File, Save As, and go to the src folder.
Inside here, we'll create a new folder called java.
Inside there, we'll create a new folder called lang.
And inside here, we'll save this class as String.java.
So inside my String.java file,
if we create a class and we call it public class String
and save this, we put this in a package.
So we'll put this into the java.lang package.
We'll save it.
And then if we go back to our command prompt and compile our code,
we'll find that the code tries to compile.
So it tries to compile the String class.
So it does find java.lang.String on the class path.
So in this case, our class doesn't have the correct constructor,
so the compilation fails.
So how about we modify the code so that it compiles.
So here we just to String message = new String, no parameters.
In my String class, we have a default constructor.
And I've also added this helper method,
so getValue, and this returns the value 42 here.
And if I go back into Main.java and put in a call to getValue
and just print out the value we get back,
and if I make sure both of these are saved and then
go back to the command prompt, in here we can compile the code,
and the code compiles.
So we have this weird String class with a call to
getValue that's compiled correctly by javac.
However, as soon as you try and run this,
so we just do the same thing as before, we do java ‑cp classes,
and that will point at the classes folder that contains the
java.lang.String and com.pluralsight.Main and try and run the code,
then the code now fails.
Now it fails with a method telling us that the getValue
method can't be found on java.lang.String.
So it seems that while javac will happily compile any class,
so java.lang.String, when we try and run this from inside Java,
something fails.
So here we get this NoSuchMethodError as the loaded
java.lang.String class doesn't have a getValue method,
and the loaded class is coming from rt.jar.
So what happens here is we have something called a bootstrap class loader.
And the job of the bootstrap class loader is to load the bootstrap classes.
These are the main classes that make up the Java runtime.
So it's the bootstrap class loader that loads classes from rt.jar.
So one last thing to be aware of.
We can actually also override the bootstrap class path,
at least on the Oracle Java virtual machine.
So if I do java ‑X,
this will print out extension flags that we can pass to the Java runtime.
And if I scroll back top the top here, you can see that some of those flags
include bootclasspath. So we can say ‑Xbootclasspath and specify a set of
directories, and the Java VM will look in these directories for the path, \a to
append directories to the built‑in set of classes and \p to prepend a set of directories to the build‑in set of classes.