So when a user wants to find an instance inside the
map, they'll call the resolve method.
This resolve method takes the type to resolve and returns the type it's
mapped to. So the type to resolve will typically be an abstract type, and
the type to map to will be the concrete type. And this resolve method
goes through five steps and has to find the type we've been asked for in
the registrations map.
It looks inside that type, and it finds the constructor
with the largest number of parameters.
So we need some rules to which constructor to use.
So if the type is multiple constructors, basically it will be pick the
largest one. That has to resolve all of those constructor parameters,
and they will do that by calling resolve on the type, so we come back
into this method until we have all the constructor parameters that we
need. It then looks at the mapping and the constructor parameter mapping
from the configuration and looks for any arguments defined in that
mapping, and it will use those to fill in any gaps inside the constructor,
and, finally, we can use this constructor to recreate the
type and return that from this call.
So this is the container code.
So the container gets passed the name of the path that contains our config file.
It creates a loader, and it asks that loader to load up the registrations
from the config file, and it calls this helper method called
registerConverters that we'll come back to a little later.
What we look at now is the resolve class.
So the first steps of the resolve method are pretty straightforward.
The first thing we do is to reach into the registrations and
check that the type is registered and then get back the
registration object for that type.
The registration object also contains a list of the constructor
parameters for the type that's being registered.
So once we have the registration information for the type,
we can use that to get the constructor parameters.
Once we have this information,
we now want to try and create an instance of the type.
What we have here is something like this.
We have a registration that says I want to map
IMeetingService to MeetingService.
So the application has asked for an IMeetingService and our
configuration says map IMeetingService to MeetingService.
So we need to get the class object for whatever the mapTo is and
then find the largest constructor that this MeetingService type
here actually has, and then we create an instance of that type.
So one step at a time,
our config.json contains a mapTo field that gives us the
name of the type that we are mapping to.
This is the concrete type we want to create. And our registration
helper has a registration.getMapTo call, and that getMapTo call
returns the name of the class here.
Once I have that,
I can then get the class object for that class. So I can say a Class.forName on
the registration.getMapTo value. Given the class, I'm now going to call a helper
function called getLongestConstructor. GetLongestConstructor will return me a
constructor object that references the constructor of this class returned by
getMapTo. It's the constructor that has the largest number of parameters.
GetLongestConstructor is pretty straightforward. It gets the constructors from
the class, by default, sets the longestConstructor to be the first one from that
list, it writes over all the constructors, getting the parameter count for them,
and if the parameter count of the one it's currently selecting is larger than
the parameter count of the current longestConstructor, then it simply resets
longestConstructor, and just returns that value to us.
So back here at this point,
we now know what the longestConstructor for this class is. Now what we
need to do is to go away and resolve all the parameters for that
constructor, and we need to do this iteratively.
So if we find a parameter that's being registered,
it's a registered type in our config, we need then to resolve that and then do the same thing for its constructor and so on and so forth.