Java class loaders support the delegation model when it comes to loading
classes. Typically in an application, there are more than one class loader. For
example, there's the class loader that needs load extension classes and the
class loader that needs to load the base classes.
And these class loaders typically exist as a hierarchy. And each
of these class loaders has a parent apart from the base class
class loader. That's the top of this hierarchy. And a class loader
may delegate to its parents.
Now we say may.
Typically,
this is the behavior. And if you use the built‑in class loaders and
if you derive from the built‑in class loaders,
this is the behavior you will get.
However,
there's nothing to say that when you write your own
class loader that you have to delegate.
You can do anything you want to in your own class loader.
When a class loader delegates to its parents, then that
parent may load the class. And again,
the parent does not have to load the class. There are some rules
however. If a class loader loads a particular class once,
it must load it in the future.
And typically,
class loaders load a class once. So once the class has been loaded,
it's cached. And the same instance of that class is returned
when it's asked to be loaded a second time.
And again, if you use the built‑in class loaders,
this is the behavior you'll get.
So, for example, if you load a very basic Java console application,
you'll end up with three class loaders.
You'll end up with the application class loader whose job it is to load
your classes and any classes loaded from the local classpath site,
you'll end up with the extension class loader that we've seen already
loads from the extension directory, and you'll end up with something
called a bootstrap class loader.
Now the bootstrap class loader in the Oracle Java VM is written in C,
so it's not actually written in Java.
The other class loaders, the extension class loader
and the application class loader, however,
are written in Java. And typically what happens is this.
The virtual machine asks the application class loader to load a
class, and the application class loader will delegate.
They will delegate to the extension class loader,
which will delegate to the bootstrap class loader.
At this point,
the bootstrap class loader may load the class. So if it's
java.lang.String, the class will find the String class, load it,
and return that data back down the delegation.
However, it may not be able to find the class,
in which case that load will fail and come back to the extension class loader.
And the extension class loader will know try and load the class
itself. So it will look in its set of JAR files and its set the
directories to find the class.
And again, if it finds the class, it will load it.
If not,
it will fail. And that gets passed back to the application
class loader. And the application class loader at this
point again has the same option.
It will try and load the class from its set of directories,
its set of JAR files and, if it succeeds,
loads the class, or it can fail. We'll get our famous NoClassDefFoundError.
Each time one of these class loaders is asked to load a class, it will,
first of all,
check to see if it has previously loaded that class and, if it has, just
return the same class from the cache. So in this case,
when we load the class up, we only ever get one instance of the class in memory.
So the class type for the class is essentially a singleton, or at
least you can think of it that way. And we can write code to see this delegation, and we'll do that now.