So we've seen throughout this class that class loaders and reflection give
us masses of flexibility when writing Java applications.
We've seen in this module in particular that we can write an
application using something like an inversion of control container
to give us a large amount of flexibility in the way we configure our
applications, in the way we allow our applications to build objects
and to build instances.
Once you have an inversion of control container in place, and I'd recommend
finding a good open‑source one to use or a commercial one to use, then that
gives many advantages inside the applications.
For example,
it allows us to make our code far more testable because we can now inject
interfaces everywhere and at test time replace those interfaces with our own
mockable versions. So IoC containers, dependency injection, is a highly recommended practice in your Java code.