So reflection is a very powerful aspect of Java.
It might not be something you use every day. When
you need it, you really need it.
As we've seen,
we can use reflection to get details of classes at runtime. These are
classes that we don't have any compiled information about.
We can also use them to dynamically get values of instances at
runtime to extract data from types. Again, without having any
compartment information about this,
we can reach into an object and pull out its data,
including accessing private data within the type.
We can also update these objects. We can set values on the objects.
As you've seen,
we can create instances of these types, so there's a
constructor type in java.line.reflect, and we can use that
constructor to create objects, again, things that we haven't met during compilation.