So what about in Java 11? So Java 11 is similar,
but there are some clear differences between Java 8 and Java
11. So we still have the core classes.
However, this is now modularized, and we'll see this in a moment.
So,
whereas previously there was an rt.jar, instead now, these
classes are kept inside a module, and the internals of that
module are not documented.
However, you can still list the classes inside that module,
and we'll see what that looks like in a moment. And
gone are the extension classes.
Instead, we now have something called the platform classes.
So in Java 11, if you run an application and the application starts up,
if it finds an extensions directory, then the application will fail immediately.
So what are these platform classes?
So as Java grew, classes were added to it that weren't really part of the core.
But those classes are still expected to be there. In Java
11, these are the platform classes.
So these are things, for example,
like classes in the java.compiler package or the java.covar
package or the javax.xml.bind package.
And these are now loaded by the platform class loader, and this is in
place of what used to be the extensions class loader.
We still have delegation,
but the delegation is now different in Java 11. And we can still
display that delegation, but we can't display the same information in
the delegation that we could display in Java 8.
So in Java 11, we have the application class loader still, we have
the platform class loader in place of the extensions class loader,
and we have the bootstrap class loader.
But beyond this, the behavior is the same.
So we ask the application class loader to load the class.
That delegates to the platform class loader. That delegates
to the bootstrap class loader.
And again, if this fails,
it fails all the way down, and eventually the
application class loader will load the class.
The other thing we can't do in Java 11 that we could sort of do in
Java 8 is to replace things in the core classes.
So in a previous demo, we saw we could do things by
compiling against our own java.lang.String class, although
that wouldn't work at runtime. In Java,
11 you can't even compile against these classes.
Java 11 has a check to make sure that packages aren't split across modules.
Java.lang is in one of the core modules, so if you tried out of class
in the java.lang package, that's going to fail as that java.lang
package can only be in one module. Okay, so let's take a look at how delegation works in Java 11.