Hello everyone,
and welcome to the Advanced Numbers lecture.
In this lecture we're gonna go over
a few more representations of numbers in Python
and then a few of the built in methods
that have to do with numbers in Python.
Should be a pretty brief lecture, but an interesting one.
Just going through the Jupyter notebook,
we're gonna look at hexadecimal,
representation of numbers, binary representations of numbers
and then a couple of built in functions for numbers.
In case you're not familiar with hexadecimal formatting
or binary formatting, I went ahead
and linked the Wikipedia pages for both those formats,
and you can check them out, as far as the
descriptions and how they actually work here.
So, I won't be teaching you what
hexadecimal numbers actually are,
what binary numbers actually are,
you can go ahead and read about that
on the Wikipedia page yourself.
I figured these two topics are
only useful if you're familiar with
the computer science topics or in your math classes
and were curious on how to do it in Python.
Quick overview on how to do them in Python,
for hexadecimal numbers, you call it, hex,
built in function and it will convert
numbers into the hexadecimal representation of numbers.
For instance, if I call 12 there,
it returns the hexadecimal, a representation of that number
and let's just do another one such as, 512
and there's another representation of it.
If you're interested in binary representation in numbers,
you can use the bin function and
that will return the binary representation of some numbers.
For instance, we just go for some classics,
just 128s or 512, you can see those
in the binary representations of those numbers,
if you're familiar with binary representation.
Okay, now let's go over some more common built-in functions,
so we know that we can call to the power
using two asterisks, but there's also a function for that,
so you can code, pow and it will do the same thing.
If you put in three arguments,
such as this, what will happen is,
the third argument will be treated as mod,
so with two arguments, it's the equivalent
of x to the power of y, x and y are your
first and second, respectively.
But with three arguments, it's equivalent to
x to the power of y, mod z and
this just has to do with some efficiency cases.
In case you're interested in why there's
a whole built in function for that.
Now, there's also an absolute value function,
which is abs, which will return the absolute
value of a number that you put into it.
There's also the round function,
and it'll round the number to a given precision
in decimal points, and by default, it's zero,
so following it to around, let's say 3.1,
it will round it off to zero decimal points.
For instance, to make it clear,
if I also put in just three, it rounds it off
to zero decimal points, or if I put in 3.9,
it rounds it off to zero decimal points here, to just four.
Okay, interesting to note though,
it always returns a floating point number,
which is why you're seeing that point zero there.
You can also specify how many digits you want
after decimal points, so for instance,
if you had the longer representation of pi,
let's say, you only wanted to see
two decimal places past the points,
you can add that in as a second argument.
Okay, that's really all there is for the advanced numbers,
should have been a pretty brief and straightforward topic,
main takeaways are, there's the hex and bin functions
for you, in case you're interested in that.
There's also these built in functions, abs,
round and also pow, for power
and Python also has a built in math library,
which maybe useful to play around
in case you're ever in need of
some more mathematical operations.
Okay, and as always, here's the Jupyter notebook
because that goes along with this lecture,
for you to check out.
Alright, thanks everyone, I'll see you at the next lecture.