Hello everyone, and welcome
to this lecture on the collections module.
So the collections module is actually
my personal favourite built-in module
and it implements a bunch
of specialised container datatypes.
So we'll be learning about these various datatypes
and there are going to be counter, defaultdict,
ordereddict, which is just an order dictionary,
we'll look a little more into
equality with an ordered dictionary,
and then we'll also look at some namedtuples.
Alright, so let's go ahead and get started.
As always the Jupyter notebook's available for you
in case you want to read the notes along,
but we'll go ahead and get started with the live code.
Okay, so let's start off with counter.
So counter is basically a dictionary subclass
which helps count hashable objects,
and let's see how it can be used.
So the first thing we're going to do
is say "from collections import Counter".
Okay, now that it's imported what we're going to see
is that inside of the counter it's elements
are stored as dictionary keys and then the count
of the objects are stored as the value.
So let's go ahead and make a list here,
I'll call this list "l".
And I'm going to put in a bunch of numbers,
most of them repeated,
doesn't really matter here, but you'll see
how counter works when I call it on that list "l".
So now what counter does is it counts
the number of occurrences of each of these objects,
or elements, in that list.
So two showed up five times, one showed up four,
four showed up four, three three,
five three, twelve once.
Okay, so that's how you can quickly count
the number of elements in a list
and it basically acts as a dictionary.
So let's look now at counter with strings.
So I'm going to make a string,
"s", and it's going to be a bunch
of random letters here that I'm quickly typing,
and then I'm going to call counter on "s",
and what that's going to do is count
again the number of elements in this iterable here
which is a string, so s shows up nine,
a shows up six, b shows up six times, v shows up four.
Okay, now let's work with counter
and the words in a sentence.
So let's say you wanted to count
how many times each word shows up in a sentence.
So I'm going to make a string
and say "how many times does each word
"show up in this sentence word word shoe up",
well "shoe up" put in "show" and then we'll stop that there.
Okay, so if I wanted to count the number of words
and how many times they showed up
I could do this, I could say "words", we could
go ahead and split that string by white space
and then call counter on the words,
object that I just made.
And now the counter's going to be this dictionary
and has counted up the amount of times
each word has shown up.
So that's gonna to be really useful if you ever
find yourself trying to parse through some sort of text
or even doing natural language processing techniques.
Okay, now let's look at methods of counter.
So if I say, "c" is equal to counter of words
I can actually call various methods on it,
so I can say, "Hey what are the most common words?",
and then I can pass in an argument here.
So I can say, "Show me the two most common words",
and it'll return this list of tuple pairs.
And I can even ask for the three most common words etc.
So I'm going to hop over to the Jupyter notebook
and walk through some common patterns
that you might be using when you use the counter objects.
So, one of them is just the sum
of the values, so you'll get the total of all counts.
So if I go back here and ask for the sum of c.values
that'll tell me the total words in that string.
We can also do some other methods
that I actually won't implement here
because they might interact with each other.
You could reset all the counts
by calling the "clear" method on that counter object.
You could call "list" on that counter object
to get a list of the unique elements.
You could call "set" to convert it to a set.
Sometimes you may just want to convert it
into a normal dictionary.
You could call "items" on the counter object
and that will convert to a list
of these elements and count pairs.
You can also call the dictionary
on list of pairs and counter, and that basically
will convert from a list of element count pairs,
instead of "to" it'll convert "from"
so you'll have basically this list of pairs
which you get out of c.items.
You could call dictionary on it and call counter on it
and this is just the inverse of the c.items.
Then again, like I mentioned, you have "most common",
and you can actually use string indexing
to get the least common elements
with this sort of notation.
So this notation will allow you to get
the "n least common elements",
so you can plug in whatever number you want there for "n".
And then finally, you can also remove zero
and negative counts by using this notation here.
Okay, so that's it as far as the counter object.
Up next in this section what we're going to be
learning about is the default dictionary.
Alright, thanks everyone
and I'll see you at the next lecture.