Hello everyone,
and welcome to the Final Capstone Projects.
First of all, a huge congratulations to you
for making it this far into the course.
You should be super proud of yourself
for everything you've learned.
And now, what we're gonna do is take all your knowledge
and put it into a final capstone project.
So what you're gonna do,
is click on the folder in nbviewer
called final capstone projects.
And then, click on final capstone project ideas,
Ipython notebook, or Jupyter notebook.
And here, you have a list of capstone project ideas.
So, your capstone project is actually totally up to you,
and what I want you to do is
pick a simple project at first
that you think you can finish in a day.
So, here I have listed about a hundred project ideas,
some of these we've actually already done
such as a Fibonacci Sequence generator,
or even the FizzBuzz problem is also in this list.
So, I want you to choose one of these problems
that you think you can finish in a day.
They're organised by section,
so there's a numbers section,
there's the classic algorithm section,
a graph section, data structures, text, networking,
classes, threading, web, files, databases,
graphs and multimedia, security.
So there's a lot here.
So choose one of these projects
that you think you can do in one day.
Once you're done with that,
what I want you to do is
either pick a project from this list,
or think of your own project,
something maybe at work,
that you want to fix using Python.
Or maybe you have a hobby
you want to explore more with Python.
Anything that you want,
it's up to you.
But try to make it so it's gonna take you more than a week
to finish that project.
Remember, just have fun with this.
If you do decide to use one of these projects here
as your capstone project,
what I want you to be aware of,
that if you go back to the folder
Final Capstone Project,
there's a folder within that folder
called Projects Solutions.
And there should be a Solution Links.md,
and if you click that link,
it'll take you to GitHub read me page
where I have links to a bunch of other solutions here
that other people have done in Python,
to a lot of these problems.
So you can click on any of these links,
and it will take you to an example solution.
So for example,
if you were deciding to try to find Pi to the Nth digit,
you've googled around,
you want to make sure your program's right,
you want to compare your code to someone else's,
click any of these,
I open the link in a new tab,
and it will take you to an example solution by someone.
Okay, so that's it.
Remember these capstone projects are totally up to you.
Do something that interests you,
that you find fun.
The only thing I suggest,
is that you start off small,
and then grow larger and larger with your code base.
Alright, other than that,
huge congratulations for making it so far in the course.
I cannot stress this enough.
You've learned so much if you've made it this far.
Congrats.
And make sure you have fun in your Python project.
Okay, thanks everyone.