Hello everyone.
In this video, we'll be going over
the Objects and Data Structures assessment solutions.
Okay, so the first question was, "write a brief description
of all the following Object types and Data Structures
we've learned about."
So for the full answers, all you've gotta do
is review the Jupyter notebook.
So if you go to the solutions notebook,
I've put links so you can go ahead and
check out the introductions of each of
those Jupyter notebooks where described in layman's terms
numbers, strings, lists, tuples, and dictionaries.
So let's go ahead and move on to the numbers section.
First thing I wanted you to do is write
an equation that uses multiplication, division,
exponent, addition, and subtraction to equal
this kind of arbitrary number.
So your answer's probably different,
all I did was work backwards.
But this was just so you made sure you understood
what minus, to the powers, parenthesis,
division, multiplication all look like, and how they worked.
So this is what I did, and that equals a 100.25.
Next I wanted to explain what
the cell would produce, two divided by three,
and what can you do to change it so the answer's correct.
So if you notice, we have two divided by three
and we have a zero there.
And remember that's because Python 2
performs classic division for integers,
and you need to use floats to perform true division,
such as 2.0 divided by three.
We also discussed on how to use import from the
future module to also change that.
Or you could just use Python 3 and you
wouldn't have to worry about that.
Next, answer these three questions without typing code,
then type code to check your answer.
So you can go ahead and check your own answers here,
but this was just to make sure you understood
order of operations in Python.
What was the type of the result of the expression here?
The answer's gonna be a floating point number,
as long as there's one floating point
number in the entire equation your
result will be a floating point number.
After that, what would you used to
find a number's square root, as well as its square?
You can just use two asterisks in a row
to do a power, and then use a fraction to do a square root.
There's also a math module in Python that will
allow you to do square roots and we'll
talk about that later on in the course.
The string section, basically I just wanted you
to play around with indexing,
so writing out commands to grab letters from strings,
making sure that you understand
that indexing starts at zero, reversing strings,
again with slicing and indexing, and then given the string,
give two methods to print the letter O.
First one was just going in reverse with negative one.
Second one I just went straightforward with index of four.
After that it was lists, and I wanted you to build
the list 0,0,0 two separate ways.
One way is just the standard,
write out the lists in between brackets.
The second way you could have done it was
by doing a list of zero and multiplying
it by three to get three of those.
After that I wanted you to reassign "hello"
in this nested list to say "goodbye."
So the index to reach that item was [2][2],
because it was a list nested inside of a list.
After that I wanted you to sort this list,
and you could've done that with a sorted function
or with the method "sort."
Then for dictionaries, this was basically
just keys and indexing to grab "hello."
First one was just pretty simple,
you just had to do this simple key.
The second one a little trickier,
had to do two keys because there was a dictionary
nested inside another dictionary.
Third one, pretty tricky, this is
actually harder than I expected.
It was the key, an index, nest key,
and then two indexes later to get "hello".
This one was a little crazy.
It was a key, an index, a key two, index,
the key "toughie" and then two indexes
to reach "hello" there.
After that was "Can you sort a dictionary? Why or why not?"
No you can not sort a dictionary,
because normal dictionaries are mappings, not sequence.
So they don't remember what order you put in items in.
Now later on in the course we'll talk about
something called an ordered dictionary,
which is a sub-class of dictionary in Python
in a specific module called collections,
so you'll learn about a specific type of dictionary
that you actually can remember order.
Moving along with Tuples, "What's the major difference
between tuples and lists?"
Hopefully you were able to answer this,
which is tuples are immutable, that's the big difference.
"How do you create a tuple?"
Remember it's just parenthesis and then commas,
just like a list but instead of square brackets
you're using parenthesis.
For sets, "What's unique about a set?"
Remember they don't allow duplicate items.
So to use a set to find the unique values,
you could just cast that list with the set function.
For booleans, don't worry if you didn't
fully understand this, there's a whole section
on comparison operators coming up next.
But I just wanted you to get kind of a sneak peek.
You can go ahead and check out these various pieces of code.
They should have been hopefully pretty straightforward
if you already knew some math notations.
This is two greater than three,
or two less than or equal to two, et cetera.
So you can run those cells and check your answers.
Final question was, "What is the boolean output
"of the cell block below?" Right here.
So it's gonna be false, and we can check
that through indexing.
So l_one, index two, zero, would have been,
if we look here, that would have been this list,
first item, so that's three.
So then you're basically asking, "Is three greater
"than or equal to?"
And we fill out that second list it's gonna be index two,
key one, so four.
So is three greater than or equal to four?
That's false.
Okay, great job on your first assessment,
and I'm excited to continue on with the course,
and I'll see you at the next lecture where
we talk about Python comparison operators.
Great job everyone.