Hello everyone, and welcome to this quick
introduction to Python statements.
As always there's a Jupiter notebook that is associated
with this lecture, and it's also called
Introduction to Python Statements.
So what are we gonna do in this lecture?
In this lecture we are gonna get
a quick overview of Python Statements.
And what we're really gonna try to do is emphasise
differences between and Python and other languages,
such as C++.
And there's two main reasons for taking this approach,
this comparison approach.
And that's because, reason number one if you're
coming from a different language,
this is going to really rapidly accelerate
your understand of Python.
And then number two if Python is your first language
learning statements in this fashion will allow you
to read other languages more easily in the future.
So, you'll be able to jump from Python
into Java, or C++, or another language much quicker
if you learn about Python statements
through this comparison context.
So, let's look at Python verses other languages.
What we're gonna do is create a simple statement that
says if a is greater than b,
so if a variable a is greater than a variable b,
assign the number 2 a and the number 4 to b.
So let's take a look at what this would normally
look like in another language.
So, a lot of times the syntax for other languages
would look something like this.
It would say if, and then you'd have your check case
a greater than b within some sort
of parenthesis or brackets.
And then you'll have curly brackets
with statements on what to do.
So if in parenthesis this case is true,
you might have a bracket here,
and then you'd have lines with semicolons afterwards,
separating each statement.
What does this look like in Python?
You'll notice this syntax is a lot cleaner
and a lot simpler.
This is one of the main beauties, and what people
really enjoy about Python.
So, you'll notice here we just have a direct statement.
If a is greater than b, colon.
You'll notice some white space here which we'll make
clear in a couple mores slides in the future.
You'll see it resents a is equal to 2,
and b is equal to 4.
So, what are the differences here,
let's go ahead and compare them.
What Python does is it gets rid of these parenthesis
and these curly brackets by incorporating
two main factors: a colon, and white space.
So, in Python your statements are ended with a colon here.
So if a is greater than b, colon.
And then white space is used, this indentation here,
to describe what takes place in case of the statement.
So in Python you'll notice white space is extremely
important, and it's fundamental to your code.
And as we learn about statements throughout this section
of the course, we'll really emphasise good practises
and good indentation throughout your code.
So what are the other differences here?
Another major differences is the lack
of semicolons in Python.
So, a lot of times in other languages semicolons
are used to note that a statement has ended,
but in Python the end of a line,
so once you stop typing on a line,
is the same as the end of a statement.
In other languages you're required to put in a semicolon,
but in Python that's not the case.
Another reason why Python is so nice and so clean.
And lastly, just to end this brief overview of the
differences, lets take a closer look at the indentation
syntax in Python versus other languages.
So, in other languages you might some syntax
that looks like this.
If you parenthesis x, if parenthesis y,
you'll have a code-statement and a semicolon,
else, another code code-statement, semicolon.
But in Python, you have this very clear structure
that's driven by code indentation,
and the use of white space and these colons.
So that means codeword ability is a really core part
of the design of the the Python language.
And that's why you'll feel that Python is a
very easy language to learn in comparison to other languages
because its readability is driven really at the core
of Python, with white space and indentation
and this sort of colon, Python statement syntax.
Okay, so that's it for this quick introduction to
Python statement and how they compare to other languages.
What we're gonna do now is start coding out
different Python statements
and learning about various statements we can do.
And we'll get a better understand that way.
Okay, so thanks, I will see you at the next lecture
where we'll start coding some Python statements.
I'll see you there.