Hello everyone, and welcome to the if,
elif, and else statements lecture.
So this is gonna be our first lecture in the statements
portion of this course.
So, we're gonna go ahead and hop over
to a quick presentation to kind of just explain
the basics of an if statement.
Here, I have opened the Jupyter Notebook
and we're just gonna be going over this quick introduction.
Alright, let's go and hop over.
Okay, so if, elif, else statements.
So if statements in Python allow us to tell computers
to perform alternative actions based on a certain
set of results.
So verbally, we can imagine as if we're telling the computer
hey, if this case happens, perform this particular action.
So we can then expand on this idea a little further
with elif and else statements, which elif kind of
you can think of it as else, if
so, it's basically telling the computer
hey if this case happens, perform some action.
If another case happens, then perform some other acton.
Else, if none of the above cases happened,
perform this action. Et cetera, et cetera.
So let's go ahead and hop over the Jupyter Notebooks
so we can get a look at the syntax format.
So here in the Jupyter Notebook we can see that
the syntax for if, elif, else statements
looks a little something like this.
So you have if space case,
so some sort of Boolean check, see something's true
or greater than or equals to, et cetera.
Then perform a particular action
so a certain piece of code.
Then elif will be another if case
to perform some other action
or else, if neither of these cases occurred
you can have more than just two elif statements
you can have as many as you want.
Then finally perform the third action.
So, we're gonna go and walk through some quick examples
and in this case, we're just gonna
be using straight Booleans as the check statements.
So let's go ahead and start a very simple example.
So I'm gonna say if space true colon
and if I click enter, notice how there's an automatic
indent done for me, which I can just do a tab.
So, start thinking about that white space
we'll cover it more when it comes to for loops
and things like that
but this white space is actually necessary for Python
to understand what you're typing.
So I'm gonna say if true, print it was true.
So it was true, so that makes sense.
So what if I say, if false print it was true,
nothing happens because it's false,
it doesn't let you do anything.
That's only gonna happen when the case is true.
So now to take this example a little further
I'm gonna add some else logic then.
Let's go ahead and say X is equal to false.
And we're gonna say if X, 'cause remember
we're doing some sort of Boolean check here.
And we'll say print X was true.
Else, so in any other case where X isn't true
I'm gonna say print...
Let's see, I will print when...
X is anything not true.
Okay.
So right now we have this print statement going.
I will print when X is anything not true,
so since X is false we had the else print.
So let's go ahead and change this to true
and see what happens.
And you notice X was true was printed out here.
Okay, so let's go ahead and break down
what's going on right now and I'll go
over a little bit more on formatting and syntax.
So I set X equal to true and I said if space X,
so some sort of Boolean check has to occur on this line.
colon, and notice how when I start my next line I indent,
so that lets you know that whatever
is going on here occurs with that if.
So if we hop over back to the syntax here
notice that we have our statements,
some colon, an indent, and that tells Python
perform anything that's indented here
underneath that if statement.
And then elif goes back and lines up with that if
and else also lines up with that if.
And then the indented actions perform
only when the case above it takes place.
Okay, so then we have an else and then it says
print and depending on what X is, if it's true or false,
we'll get a certain print statement out.
Alright, so to get a fuller picture of how
far if, elif, and else and take us,
we're gonna write out a nested structure.
So take careful note of how if, elif,
and else line up in the code.
And just a quick note, I say ee-lif,
some people say el-if, so feel free
to say it however you want.
So now we're gonna introduce a little bit
of comparison syntax for Python.
So I'm gonna go ahead and say loc
is equal to Bank, so I'm saying
loc, that variable, is equal to bank
and that's gonna stand for location in my code.
So I'm gonna say if loc, which is for location,
is equal to, and notice how I'm putting double equals signs.
So we went over some comparison methods before earlier
and the double equals sign is just to check
if loc is equal to something.
If you use a single equals sign, that means you're
trying to reassign something which won't work in this case.
So I'm gonna say if loc is equal to auto shop,
print...
welcome to the auto shop.
And then I'm gonna say elif loc is equal to,
let's say the bank, colon indent,
print welcome to the bank.
And in any other case, which will be my else statement,
note how I don't have any Booleans there
because I'm saying in any other case that wasn't
predefined, I want to just print
a question, where are you?
And in this case when I ran that cell
it said welcome to the bank, so that makes sense
because my location was bank.
So if I set this equal to auto shop
it says welcome to the auto shop.
If I set this to something else such as mall,
since neither of these if statements get activated as true,
the else occurs and asks me where are you.
So it's important to note how the nested
if statements are each checked until a true
Boolean causes the nested code beneath it to run.
And you should also note that you can put
as many of these elif statements as you wanted
so we could also have put in an elif loc
double equals sign to mall,
and then said print welcome to the mall.
Okay, and if we ran that then we say welcome to the mall
since right here this occurred as a true Boolean.
So let's just create two more simple examples
of the if, elif, and else statements.
I'm gonna say this person, some variable
called person is equal to Sam.
And I'm gonna say if person,
double equals sign Sam, let's say print
Hi Sam, whoops.
And then else print...
Let's say what's your name?
Now notice what happened here, I have to use
double quotations since I'm using a single
quotation with the 'what's' in order
for that string to work properly.
Alright, so if you've noticed here
have person equals Sam, if person is equal to Sam,
hi Sam what's your name.
Since person was equal to Sam then this Boolean
check right here, person equal to Sam,
and I'm gonna go ahead and copy and paste that,
so person equals Sam that's gonna return true
since that variable is equal to the string Sam.
And since this happened to be true then the nest
of code beneath it will run.
So just a quick note on indentation,
it's important to keep a good understanding
of how indentation works in Python
and it really maintains the structure
and order of your code.
We're gonna touch in on this topic again
as we go through all the different statement
types in Python and we're really gonna
hone in on it when we start talking about
building your own functions and methods.
So right now just keep in mind that I'm indenting here
whenever you see a colon.
So that says based on what happens up here,
indent space, right here this code's gonna run.
Alright, so just a quick overview of what we went over here.
Quick and a brief overview of if, elif, and else statements.
So those if statements in Python
allow us to tell the computer
to form alternative actions based
on a certain set of results.
This is what the syntax looks like,
you have if, a bunch of cases that check for Booleans,
once one of those is true,
then you perform one of the actions.
Then you can have an else statement that says
if none of those happen to be true,
then perform some final action.
Okay, there's a couple more examples here in the Jupyter
Notebook you can check out, but other than that
we'll go ahead and move on to the next lecture.