Hello, everyone and welcome to
the lecture on for loops.
So in this lecture, we're just gonna learn about
for loops and you can see here I have the Jupyter Notebook.
And the for loops are gonna help us iterate through
any items that are a sequence in Python
or really, any items that you can iterate over.
So you can see here, I have the Jupyter Notebook.
We're just gonna go through a bunch of examples
and we'll introduce two new topics along the way.
And these are all the examples we're gonna work through.
So let's go ahead and cut to a very brief presentation
just to break down what a for loop is
and then we'll get started with some live coding
and the for loops.
So let's go ahead and jump over to the presentation.
So for loop statements.
So a for loop can act as an iterator in Python
and what it does is it goes through items
that are in a sequence or any other iterable item.
So if you remember these objects we covered in the
objects and data structures section,
that we learned about that we can iterate over,
those items include strings, lists, tuples,
and then we can also iterate over the built-in iterables
in dictionaries, such as keys or values.
And we'll break down that topic later in this lecture.
So the general format for a for loop in Python
is gonna look a little something like this.
You're gonna say for item in object colon.
Next line, you're gonna indent
and say statements to do stuff.
Now if you're in NEID or if you're in Jupyter Notebooks,
this sort of indentation is taken care of
automatically for you.
So again, the format is gonna be
for item in your iterable object colon
and then you're gonna have some code to do stuff.
So that variable name that I used, item,
is actually completely up to the coder.
So you're gonna be able to just choose a name
that makes sense to you and hopefully,
you choose one that you're gonna be able to understand
when you're revisiting your code in the future.
And then that item name can also be referenced
inside of your loop.
So, for example, if you wanted to use
if statements to perform checks.
So that's the presentation, let's go ahead and hop
back to the Jupyter Notebook.
Great, so we're back
and we're gonna go ahead and get started
through a very simple example.
So now we're gonna start with some live coding.
I'm gonna make a list and this list is just gonna be
the numbers one through five.
So I have my list, l.
So l's equal to 1,2,3,4,5.
And now I'm gonna say a for loop.
Let's say I wanted to print every element in that list.
I could say for element in l colon
I'm gonna click enter.
It's automatically gonna indent for me.
I'm gonna say print element.
Shift+Enter to run that cell.
And you'll notice, it went ahead and printed
each of those elements.
And to drive the point home that we can actually name
this item, that variable name, whatever you want,
I'm gonna go ahead and switch it here.
For num in l, print num.
And you notice, it's the exact same thing when I run it.
So what's nice about this is within your for loop,
before it, you don't have to worry about
pre-defining that num and you can then reference it
inside of your for loop.
Okay, so let's go ahead and do
something a little differently here.
What I'm gonna do is I'm gonna say
for num in l, print something.
So what this is gonna do is you're gonna tell Python
Hey, for every number, for every element in that list,
I want you to do the code below, which is print something.
So it should print something then five times.
And there you have it.
So you could imagine we could have lots of code here
in this space and it'll do it for
every element that's in that iterable or that list.
Okay, so that's our simplest example.
So we're gonna build on top of this
and we're gonna write an if statement within that for loop
that can check for even numbers.
So in order to check for even numbers,
I'm gonna introduce a new concept called
the modulo, which is spelled M-O-D-U-L-O.
And what this is gonna allow us to do
is get the remainder in division
and it uses the percent symbol.
So I'm gonna show you an example.
So imagine I have 10 divided by three.
So what would the remainder be?
Well three times three is nine
and so three goes into 10 three times, remainder one.
So that means when I type this in,
10 modulo three, or sometimes called mod three,
one is my remainder.
So I have three remainder one.
And let's say I wanted to do, just another quick example,
18 modulo seven.
So seven can go into 18 two times with a remainder of four
cause there's gonna be 14, seven times two is 14,
and then in order to get up to 18,
you have a remainder of four.
So that's what we output there.
And let's just drive the point home with
four mod two, so two actually goes in evenly into four,
so you have no remainder, zero.
Okay, so go ahead and make sure that this makes sense to you
by typing in examples,
but basically all that modulo is doing
is it's just giving you the remainder that's left.
Which remember, that's not equal to the decimal point
after the number, that's just the remainder
as in a super-basic kind of elementary division.
Alright, so moving along, we can notice that if this number
is fully divisible with no remainder,
then the result of the modulo call is zero.
So that means we can use this test for even numbers.
So we can think that if we get a zero output
from this percent sign or modulo two,
if that's equal to zero,
that means it's an even number, right?
Cause if two goes into your number evenly,
then you know that number is even.
And if it outputs a one,
then you know you have an odd number.
So let's go ahead and go back to that for loop
we were doing.
So I have l which is 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
I'm gonna go ahead and say for num in l colon
and then I'm gonna have an if statement.
I'm gonna say if num modulo two is equal to,
and notice how I have two equal signs
because I'm making a comparison statement here,
so I'm saying if that number is absolutely equal to zero
colon, print the number.
So let's go ahead and break down what this is gonna do.
It's gonna go through each of those items in that list
and it's gonna say okay, grab that item,
which in this case is a number, perform modulo two on it,
check if it equals zero, and if that's the case,
then print that number.
So go ahead and see if that works.
Awesome, so you notice we only printed the even numbers.
And so what would happen if we set this equal to one?
Let's go ahead and find out.
We only print the odd numbers.
Excellent, so let's go ahead and build on top of this
and add an else statement.
So I'm gonna set this back to zero,
so it only prints odd, or even numbers, excuse me.
And I'm actually gonna change this.
I'm gonna say print Here is an even.
And remember this sort of print statements
are for Python 2.
And then I'm gonna say else print Odd number.
So take a moment, make sure you understand what is gonna
actually output from the cell and then check if you're right
by running it.
Okay great, so let's go ahead
and do one more edit to this code.
So I'm gonna say,
let's say I want to actually print the number
if it's even, so I'm just gonna print the num here.
And then if it's odd, print an alert That was an odd number.
Let's go ahead and run that cell.
And you notice I get
Odd number, 2, Odd number, 4, Odd number.
Keep this in mind cause on your test,
there's gonna be a question that kind of uses
this sort of logic.
It's gonna be called the fizz buzz question
and it's actually a really common
interview programming question
as one of the first screens you do.
Okay, so moving along,
we're gonna go with a totally different example now.
So another common idea during a for loop
is keeping some sort of running tally
during the multiple loops.
And, for example, what we're gonna do is create a for loop
that sums up that list.
So let's go ahead and make a list.
Actually, we already have our list, l, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
And I'm gonna make a variable called list_sum
and I'm gonna set it equal to zero.
Okay and then I'm gonna do a for loop that says
for num in l take my list_sum
and I'm gonna set it equal to the current list_sum
plus that number.
And then after the for loop has run,
I'm going to print list_sum.
And notice how this statement right here is
outside of the for loop
cause it's not indented inside of it.
Okay, let's go ahead and run that.
And I get 15, so that makes sense.
So basically what happened is
one plus two plus three plus four plus five
is gonna be equal to 15.
So let's break down what's going on in this cell
so we really understand it.
I'm setting a variable, list_sum,
and I'm setting it equal to zero outside of the for loop,
before the for loop takes place.
And then I'm saying for every number in that list,
go ahead and take the current list_sum
and then add that number to it
and reassign list_sum.
So it's doing this code again and again
for each of these numbers.
And you'll notice, list_sum is then acting like a
current running tally for your current sum.
Okay, great.
So read over that cell,
make sure you fully understand what's going on
and something I want to note that we've gone over before
is if we're editing a variable by itself,
we can also use this sort of notation, this plus equals.
And you'll notice if I run that cell,
it's gonna equal the exact same thing.
Okay, great.
So let's go ahead and move on to another example.
So we've already looped through lists
and now we're gonna loop through a string.
So I'm gonna say s is equal to this is a string.
Okay, perfect.
So remember when we index strings,
Python thought of them as a sequence.
So now when we iterate through them,
we'll also be accessing each of those items in the string.
So I can say for item in s, that string, print item.
Shift+Enter and you'll notice it's going along
the zero, the one, the two, the three,
almost as if it was indexing it
and then it's printing every single item
in that sequence, this is a string.
Great, so right now if I was to do this in my own code,
I would have called this something that makes sense to me.
So for instance, letter makes a lot of sense,
since I know I'm going through the letters.
And I'm gonna say for letter in s print letter.
And you notice the output is exactly the same.
Okay, so now let's go ahead and look
at how a for loop can be used with a tuple.
So I'm gonna make a tuple.
I'm just gonna call it tup
and remember tuples are with parentheses
and I'm gonna use 1,2,3,4,5 and I'm gonna say
for t in tup print t.
So you notice it's iterating it
just like as if it were a list.
It just cares that it's a sequence
and we can also, again, call these whatever we want.
Okay, great.
So something that's interesting about tuples,
and this is where we're gonna get a little more advanced
than in a typical lecture,
we're gonna learn about something that's called
tuple unpacking.
And to fully show that,
what we're gonna do is create a list of tuples.
So I'm gonna redefine l to be equal to a list
and what I'm gonna have it do is
create some tuple pairs in that list.
So is gonna be an element in that list.
, so you notice I'm kinda nesting these tuples
inside of that list.
And then .
Okay, so what's going on here?
I have l which is a list of tuple pairs.
And to show you what that looks like,
let's go ahead and index the zeroth item.
That's gonna be that pair, that tuple.
And I can again, if I wanted to, index again
and say that's just 2, so zero zero.
And then I could say one, grab 4.
So let's say we wanted to grab 10,
hopefully this is familiar to you,
that would be the second index of that list
and it's gonna be that first item
and there we have 10.
Okay, so now that we have that sort of logic down,
we can actually do what's called tuple unpacking.
So if you're iterating through a sequence
that contains tuples and the item actually be
the tuple itself.
So during the for loop, we will be unpacking that tuple
inside of a sequence
and we can access the individual items inside that tuple.
So I know that was a lot,
so let's just go ahead and show you an example.
So first, I'm gonna say for tup in l print tup.
Okay, so that makes sense, right?
I'm printing every element in that list.
And now, I'm gonna show you how to do it with unpacking.
So if I know what my data structure looks like inside that
and it's a tuple, I can actually write something
that looks like this.
I can write that item that I'm iterating with as a tuple.
And I can say for this tuple in l print,
let's just want to print the first ones,
the 2, 6, 10.
And now, this is called tuple unpacking.
So with tuples in a sequence,
we can access the items inside of them
through this unpacking.
And the reason that this is really important is
because a lot of objects
will deliver iterables through tuples.
And what we're gonna do now is start exploring
iterating through dictionaries
so we can take this concept a little further.
So just to break down what we did,
we said for tup in l we printed tup and that will output
the entire items in that list,
but if I state that item to look like a tuple,
this t1,t2, and remember I have to match it up exactly
to what all those items look like in the list,
so the items have to be uniform,
then I can print things from that actual tuple.
So I could do something like this as well.
Or then I could perform operations on it.
So I could say maybe I wanted t1 minus t2
and I get -2 for all of them.
Or let's say I wanted the sum of them,
six, 14, 22 etc.
Okay, so let's go ahead and expand on that idea
by working through a dictionary.
So I'm gonna say d is equal to,
let's go ahead and make a quick dictionary here.
I'm gonna make three keys, k1, k2, and k3.
Great, so now I have my dictionary,
1, 2, and 3 with three keys, k1, k2, k3.
And I'm gonna say for item in d, that dictionary
print item.
So what do you think's gonna come out?
It's actually just the keys
and notice how they're also out of order.
Remember dictionaries are mappings.
So what's gonna happen here is
that this is only producing the keys.
And what do we do if we want to get the values
or both the keys and the values?
So we're actually gonna have a Python 3 alert.
So let's go ahead and jump back to the Jupyter Notebook.
Okay, so jump back to the Jupyter Notebook
to fully discover this Python 3 alert.
So if you're using Python 2,
the method that we're gonna use to iterate through the items
is called .iteritems.
So if you're using Python 2, you should use .iteritems
to iterate through the keys and values of a dictionary.
So what this does is basically creates a generator
and we're gonna learn about generators
later on in the course and that's gonna generate
the keys and values of your dictionary.
So to see it in action,
I'm just gonna walk through the code here.
I have d.iteritems
and we can see that this creates a generator.
So calling the items method returns a list of tuples.
And then you could iterate through that list
of tuples of the keys and the values.
Now if you're using Python 3,
what you want to use is .items.
So .items for Python 3 is gonna be the same as using
iteritems in Python 2.
It's basically a really similar change as
when we were learning about range and xrange
which we'll cover in more detail throughout this course,
but a lot of the changes in Python 2 to Python 3
were turning things into generators
so you want to store things in lists.
Okay so you might be wondering why this worked in Python 2
and that's because of the introduction to generators
in Python during its earlier years.
So go ahead and read this in the Jupyter Notebook.
Hopefully, you already have before coming to this lecture.
But it's just a little more of a breakdown
as to what's going on here.
But let's go ahead and say
a quick tuple unpacking for a dictionary.
So I'm gonna say for k,v in d.iteritems ;
print k, print v.
And there, I'm printing every key and every value.
And it actually doesn't matter
whether or not you have these parentheses in there.
It's gonna work the same,
so that's actually up to you.
I just put them in there cause
it might be a little more clear
that you're doing tuple unpacking.
But if you're reading someone else's code,
more than likely, you're gonna read it like this,
just without any parentheses, the k and the v,
or whatever the items happen to be in that tuple.
Alright, so that's it for this lecture.
Go ahead and make sure you go over
all of the examples in the Jupyter Notebook.
They're really similar to the ones we did
in this lecture, but just make sure you understand
the context of a for loop
and how to make your own for loops.
Alright, thanks guys.