Hello everyone,
and welcome to the second lecture
in the collections module part of this section.
So what we're gonna be learning about now,
is the defaultdict,
which is a dictionary like object
which provides all the methods that come from a dictionary,
but also takes on a first argument as a default data type,
and I'll show you what I mean by that in just a second.
The most important thing to note,
is when you're constructing a default dictionary,
it will never raise a key error.
If the key doesn't exist,
then it will get the value returned
by the default factory condition that you provide.
So I'll show you what I mean.
Let's go ahead and start by importing it,
so we'll say from collections
import defaultdict.
There we have it.
Alright, so let's see what happens if we start
with the regular dictionary.
So I'm gonna make just a normal dictionary,
gonna have a k1 string key,
with a value of one.
So there's our normal dictionary.
If I call k1, I get the value one out.
Let's say I call a key that's not in there.
Let's say I ask for key 2, or k2.
Notice we get an error,
and we get a key error.
So now let's see how that would work
with a default dictionary.
So the way I would create a default dictionary,
I'll again call it the variable d.
I call defaultdict,
and here I'm gonna pass in object.
Whoops, defaultdict.
Okay, so now, if you notice,
if I were to put in a key
that doesn't exist in this dictionary yet,
and remember this dictionary d,
for default dictionary d,
doesn't have any keys.
I haven't assigned it any.
And I call one,
it will assign whatever the factory condition
here for that value is.
And in this case, it's gonna be an object.
So if I say for item in d
print item,
notice we do have a key there of one now.
So we can also use this to initialise default values,
and you can usually use that in conjunction
with a Lambda function.
So I can say d equals defaultdict.
I'm gonna pass in a Lambda function
that will take in any arguments,
and just return zero.
So it actually doesn't even really take in an argument,
it just always returns zero.
Okay, so that means, if I assign a one here,
without actually putting an equal sign there,
that will automatically assign,
using the Lambda function, a zero there.
And if I put in another key that says, let's say two,
then that also works.
So now, if I print out my default dictionary,
I have a default dictionary,
has this function, which is the Lambda expression,
which always returns zero,
if there is no assignment for that key.
So two has two since I assigned it.
Since I didn't assign one, instead of throwing a key error,
it goes by the default that you pass,
which in this case was just return a zero.
I hope you can see now
why the default dictionary is so powerful
since it won't ever respond with a key error,
it will just create one
with whatever the default condition was
when you passed it.
Okay, so that's it.
Go ahead and check out
the documentation for default dictionary
in case you wanna learn more,
but the main takeaway here,
is that it won't throw a key error.
Instead it will initialise the default value
that you place when you create the default dictionary.
Okay, up next,
we'll learn about order dictionaries.