Hello everyone, and welcome to the lecture on
the Statements Assessment Test Solutions,
so let's go ahead and take a look at them.
I'll do a brief overview of the solutions, and you can
check out the Jupyter notebook to take a more detailed look.
First up was use for, split and if to create a statement
that will print out the letters that start with S.
So what I did was say for word in this string,
call the split method on it, and that will return a list
of all the words because I'm splitting by the white space,
and then I said if word index of zero,
so the first letter of that word is equal to S,
go ahead and print that word.
Next up, use range to print all the even numbers
from zero to 10.
So I said range, go from zero 11 remember,
'cause indexing starts at zero and it goes up to 11,
but not including 11,
and then I did spacing by two,
where that was my step size.
Next, for list comprehension to create a list of all numbers
between one and 50 that are divisible by three,
I've just said X for X in range 50,
if X mod three is equal to zero.
Equal equal because it's a bullion check.
After that, I wanted you to go through the string below
and if the length of the word is even, print even.
And I'm gonna refresh this real quick to show the answer.
Okay, I refreshed, so sorry if there was a jump
or a glitch there.
But now I have the solution.
So for going through the string below,
and checking if the length of a word is even,
I said for word in ST split, if the length of that word
mod two is bullion check equal to zero,
print and you could've printed whatever you wanted here,
I just printed the word plus this arrow saying
has an even length, FizzBuzz.
You can go ahead check out this answer,
should have been pretty similar to what we discussed
in the lecture,
and then, at the end, I wanted you to use list comprehension
to create a list of the first letters of every word
in the string below.
So what I did was say word, index zero for word
and ST.split.
So go ahead and check out this Jupyter notebook and
check out the details of the code in case you're confused
on anything.
And as always, feel free to start a discussion question
in case you want more clarification.
Alright, thank you, and I'll see you at the next lecture.