Hello everyone
and welcome to this quick lecture
on the functions and methods homework.
So in this lecture we're just gonna quickly go over
the assignment and what to expect.
Okay, so let's go head and get started.
So your first question is write a function that computes
the volume of a sphere given its radius.
And for pretty much all of these function homework
assignments, I've given you just the basic code cell
to fill in.
So there's your def vol.
It's gonna take in a radius,
and then you're gonna have to return the volume
of the sphere.
Second question, write a function that checks
whether a number is in a given range.
So that's inclusive of high and low.
So there's two methods for this.
You could either say def ran_check,
and you could have a print statement that says
yes, it's in the given range,
or you could just do a Boolean check.
And I want you to fill these in both.
So have one function say it prints out a statement
saying whether the number's in the range,
and another one that just returns the Boolean.
Okay, after that, I want you to write a Python function
that accepts a string and calculates the number
of upper case letters and lower case letters.
So, for example, you have an input string that says
Hello Mr. Rogers, how are you this fine Tuesday?
And I want you to have the output print something like
this, number of upper case characters,
number of lower case characters.
And if you feel ambitious, you can use the
collections module to solve this problem,
but you actually don't need it.
Okay, after that, I want you to write a Python function
that takes a list and returns a new list
of the unique elements of the first list.
Remember, I want you to return a list.
So it's gonna look a little something like that.
Okay, after that, I want you to write a Python function
to multiply all the numbers in a list,
as so, def multiply.
Then, I want you to write a Python function
that checks whether a passed string is a palindrome or not.
So remember, a palindrome is a word, phrase or sequence,
that reads the same forward and backward.
So like madam or nurses run,
those are examples of palindromes.
Okay, then finally, I have this hard level question,
and what it's gonna do is I want you to write
a Python function to check whether a string
is a pangram or not.
And note that pangrams are words or sentences
containing every letter of the alphabet, at least once.
So for example, the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog
contains every letter in the alphabet.
And I put a little hint for you,
and you're gonna use the string module.
So you're gonna put this line, import string.
And this is gonna allow you to save time
from having to write every letter of the alphabet.
So if you import string,
and then say string.ascii_lowercase,
that will actually output the alphabet.
So to give you an example of what that looks like,
after you import string,
you're gonna say string.ascii_lowercase,
and that's just gonna output this long string
of the alphabet.
Okay, so that's it.
Basically have a lot of fun with these.
There's multiple ways to answer a lot of these functions.
See if you can try the most readable and simple
solutions you can.
And I forgot you can go ahead and check out
the Jupyter notebook that has the solutions.
Okay, that's it and good luck.