Hello, everyone, and welcome
to the functions lecture.
So, in this lecture, we're gonna be learning about functions
and getting our first introduction
how to actually make our own functions.
So, we've seen a few functions in the past,
such as L-E-N, remember that length function,
and now we're gonna learn to build our own functions.
So let's go ahead and get started
with a quick introduction to functions.
So, what are functions?
So, formally speaking, a function
is a useful device that groups together a set of statements
so that they can be run more than once.
And they can also let us specify parameters
that can serve as inputs to the functions.
So you can remember the range function
allowed us to put in parameters
such as start, stop, and step size.
So, on a more fundamental level,
the functions allow us to not have to
repeatedly write the same code again and again.
So, if you remember back to that lesson
with strings and lists, when we were
using the function L-E-N to check
the length of a string or of a list,
if that's something you're gonna wanna do a lot,
you're gonna wanna create a function,
so you don't have to repeatedly
write out manually some sort of count for loop.
Okay, and then, finally, these def, or D-E-F, statements.
So, def is a built-in keyword telling Python
that you're about to create a function.
And, instead of going through the syntax
here in a PowerPoint presentation,
we're actually just gonna hop in
straight to the code and check out the full syntax.
So let's go ahead and hop over to the Jupyter Notebook.
Okay, so, we're back at the Jupyter Notebook,
and now, we're gonna go ahead and hop over
to some live code to check out the syntax.
So, how do you build out a function in Python?
So you first start off with the D-E-F, the def keyword.
And if you're using an IDE that highlights
the correct syntax in Python, you should see it highlighted.
And then, you do a space, and then
you enter the name of your function.
And the rules as far as naming your functions
are gonna follow the same rules of naming variables.
So, I'm gonna say
name_of_function.
So, space, the name of your function,
you can name this whatever you want,
and then, parenthesis, colon,
enter, and right now, this is
gonna be a super simple function.
It's just gonna pass.
It's not gonna do anything.
And that's your very first function.
Okay.
So, now, I can actually call this function,
and if you're using Jupyter Notebook,
so you can do tab to autocomplete.
And I won't pass anything, since
it doesn't take any arguments.
Shift + Enter, and nothing will happen.
Okay.
So let's start building on top of this.
So, we began with that def, and then a space,
followed by the name of the function.
And, remember, we're gonna try to keep the names relevant.
So, for example, L-E-N is a good name
for that length function.
But you also wanna be careful with names.
You don't wanna call a function
the same name as a built-in function in Python.
And if you go to the Jupyter Notebook,
I actually have a link here that goes
to all the built-in functions.
So if you open this link, let me zoom in a little more
so you guys can see it, Python has
a bunch of built-in functions,
such as the L-E-N function right here, length.
And we'll be exploring these as we continue on throughout
the course, but you wanna avoid any of these names.
So, instance, like abs, all, any, basestring, et cetera.
Usually, just make your function name
more specific than it has to be,
and you'll be unlikely to overrwrite
any of these built-in functions.
Anyways, continuing on, we have our function,
name of the function, then came a pair of parenthesis,
and that's where you're going to input arguments.
And you'll separate the arguments with a comma.
So you remember, when we're using the range function,
you inputted the start, the stop, and the step size,
and they were separated by a comma.
And then, finally, you have a colon there.
And then, you start a next line, and you have to indent.
So, this indentation is actually important for Python,
since Python makes use of what's
called a whitespace to organise code.
A lot of other programming languages don't do this,
so keep that in mind, that this whitespace
and this spacing and indentation is actually
one of the most important parts of
organising your code in Python.
Okay, so, let's build up on top of this.
Let's actually pass in some arguments.
And I have to label them here,
so I'm just gonna label them arg1, arg2.
And, again, pass.
I'm not gonna do anything with those functions,
or, excuse me, with those arguments.
And if I run that cell again, notice now I get an error,
that the name_of_function takes
exactly two arguments, and I'm giving it zero.
So it's required now that I input two arguments.
So, if I input one and two, I don't get an error,
but, again, nothing happens.
So, let's build out the function even more.
We wanna do something.
So let's go ahead and rename this function.
Let's call it
my_addition_func.
This is a really long name, but hopefully
you can guess what we're gonna do.
We're gonna say,
print arg1, arg2.
Whoops.
We wanna print them being added together.
And I'm gonna get rid of that pass now,
since we actually wanna do something with them.
So now, if I run that cell to save that function,
name_of_function, now I'm gonna change this to
my_addition_func.
And notice how I use tab autcomplete for convenience there.
And now, if I run this cell, it actually
takes in the arguments and does the code
that's indented beneath the colon there.
So, something else you might see for functions
is something called a docstring.
So, if you remember the range function,
if I clicked Shift + Tab, a docstring came out
that had some information.
Range stop, list of integers.
So you might be thinking, well,
where's that information actually saved?
So, to create a docstring, you create
a comment
using triple quotations marks to enclose it.
And then you say, here is whatever you wanna
say in your docstring, since this is just a giant string.
Here's my docstring.
I'm gonna click Shift + Enter to run,
and now you'll notice, if I click Shift + Tab here,
my docstring is actually recorded in Python.
So, if I call help on that function,
that docstring's gonna help you.
So, right now, we're gonna avoid docstrings,
just so our code is a little cleaner,
but as your functions get more and more complex,
docstrings are gonna become increasingly important.
So you remember what a function actually does.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and get rid of that.
And we're gonna start off and back up a bit,
and start with a really simple example of a function.
So let's go ahead and make a function
called say_hello,
parentheses, colon, indentation.
And then, all this is gonna do is this is gonna print
hello.
Now, if I, whoops.
Now, if I run
say_hello, I don't pass any arguments,
because it doesn't take any.
It goes ahead and says hello.
So, now we're gonna create a function
that greets people with their name.
So what do we wanna do here?
I wanna say D-E-F, space, and let's go ahead
and make a function called greeting.
And it's gonna take one argument,
and I can actually call the arguments whatever I want,
just like, if you remember, when you're
iterating through a for loop, you can
call those items whatever you want.
I can call these arguments whatever I want.
And I'm gonna say, def greeting name,
and what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna print hello,
space, and then I'm gonna concatenate,
or add on that name.
And let me...
I should've used two double quotations,
that's why that was being highlighted.
Okay, so, what is this gonna do?
It's a greeting function.
I have def, space, greeting, and then it takes name
as an input argument, colon, and the indented code
is what's gonna run once we call that function.
So it's gonna print hello, and then, plus name.
So it's gonna concatenate the string
that we put into the name into the whole phrase.
So I'm gonna run that cell to save my function,
and then I'm gonna say def greeting,
and let's just put in a string, and I'm gonna put in Jose.
So I should expect a hello Jose to come out.
And notice I have invalid syntax.
So what's going on here?
Well, what's going on is I accidentally called D-E-F again.
So, remember, when you're calling your function,
you just call the function name.
You don't actually call D-E-F.
D-E-F is what you use to define
your function when you're creating it.
And then, later on in your code, you don't call D-E-F again.
And so, that was just to throw that in there.
So I'm actually just gonna call greeting,
just like were using print hello.
Greeting, Jose, hello Jose is the output.
Okay.
So now, we're gonna introduce the return statement.
So let's go ahead and see an example
of using a return statement, and then
we'll break it down a little further.
And what return is gonna allow us to do
is return a result that can then be stored as a variable,
or used in whatever manner the coder, or you, want.
Okay, so let's head back and create
an addition function again.
I'm gonna call it add_num.
And what it's gonna do is it's gonna take in two numbers.
I'm gonna call it num1 as an argument,
and num2 as an argument.
Colon, click Enter, my indentation
returns, or, it's automatic.
And I'm gonna introduce a keyword called return.
And what return does is whatever is put in front of return,
that's what your function is going to output.
So, remember, range outputted a list.
And that's because it returns the list.
So now, I'm gonna return num1 plus num2.
So note, I am not printing the addition
of these two numbers, I'm returning it.
So now, what happens is I can say,
x is equal to
add_num, and let's say
we'll pass in the arguments two and three.
So two is that num1, three is that num2.
And it's returning the sum of them.
And now, I can set that sum to a variable.
So let's go ahead and run this cell.
And if I call x now, it's gonna be equal to that sum.
I can also just say print that value,
and it would work the same.
Okay, excellent.
So let's break it down a little further,
and ask ourselves, what happens
if we were to input two strings into this function?
So we have our add_num, but remember,
we're just specifying this with a plus sign.
So if we were to put in two strings,
let's say one and then two,
what it's gonna return is
one concatenated with two, since they're strings.
Onetwo.
And I can even set that equal to a variable.
And then, if I print x, I get the concatenation
of those two strings, basically them being stuck together.
And why is that happening?
It's because we don't declare variable types in Python.
So, if you're familiar with other languages,
a lot of times, you have to do something like
call a V-A-R, and declare the variable
to be some sort of integer, et cetera, et cetera.
If you're learning Python as your first language,
it's really nice, because you don't,
actually, you don't have to worry about that.
But one of the issues with that is,
is, for this kind of function,
we could pass in strings and integers
or floating point numbers, et cetera,
and still get results out, maybe even
if we didn't want that to happen.
So, later on, we're gonna learn about
adding in checks to make sure a user
puts in the correct arguments into a function.
So, now we're also gonna start using break,
continue, and pass statements into our code.
Remember that we introduced these
during the while lecture, and now
they're gonna come back again.
So, let's go ahead and go over a full example
of creating a function that checks if a number is prime.
And this is kind of a common interview exercise.
So we're gonna head and go and break it down for you.
So I'm going to clear this cell.
I'll clear this cell as well.
Clear this one as well.
Okay.
So, let's go ahead and start with D-E-F.
That tells Python we're making a function.
And I'm gonna say, is_prime.
And there's my function, and I'm just gonna say pass.
So right now, if I call is_prime, nothing happens.
Okay, perfect.
So let's start building on top of it.
I want is_prime to take in a number, right,
'cause we're gonna take in a number,
and then check if it's prime.
So, save that.
And now, is_prime is going to take an error,
or give out an error, since it needs an argument there.
So I'm gonna go ahead and pass in a number, two,
and we don't get an error, perfect.
So now, let's keep building out a little more.
So we'll start with that docstring,
which, remember, is the triple quotes
way of writing a comment.
And I'm gonna say this is a quick
description of this function.
This function
checks for prime
numbers.
That's one way of writing a docstring.
Sometimes, some people write docstrings
with kind of this sort of format.
And they'll label it INPUT, OUTPUT
so users know, let me zoom in a bit for you guys,
so users know what's gonna be inputted and outputted.
So, we know we're gonna input a number,
so I'm gonna say input a number,
and we are going to output
a print statement
whether or not
the number is prime.
Okay, so, let's zoom back out real quick, so you saw that.
So now, we have this docstring.
I'm gonna save it.
Is_prime with that two runs fine,
and if I click Shift + Tab, now
my docstring is actually pretty clear.
So, input a number, output a print statement
whether or not that number is prime.
Okay.
So, I'm gonna dive into math a little bit,
but we know a number is prime if that number
is only evenly divisible by one and itself.
So what we're gonna do is write a function
to check all the numbers from one all the way to that number
and then perform modulo checks.
So I'm gonna say,
for n in range,
and let's start from two, since we know one
will always go into a number.
We can say, from two to num,
if the number we put in
divided by any of the numbers from two
all the way up to that number is equal to zero,
then we know it's not prime.
And then, we're going to break out of this loop,
because we don't need to check anymore.
And I'm gonna head back one.
So, let's say, after we go through all those numbers,
none of them had a mod zero, that means,
no numbers from two all the way up to the input number
go evenly into that number itself.
Then I'm gonna say, else,
so if mod number zero occurred, whoops,
I'm going to print
the number is prime.
Okay, now, let's see if this works.
Let's go ahead and input a number
we know is prime, 13, okay.
And now let's input a number that we know is not prime, 12.
Perfect, so we know this is working.
So, there's other ways to do this exact same function.
And there's actually better methods of checking for primes.
And I'm gonna kind of leave it
to you as a homework assignment to go ahead and try to use
either the math module to check,
or use your own Google abilities
to check out what's a better method
of checking for prime numbers.
And, just to give you a quick hint,
if you scroll down to the bottom of this Jupyter Notebook,
the better version is the example for you there.
But let's go ahead and break down
exactly what happened here, so we understand
all these various pieces that kind of
really build out your first true function, that brings in
a lot of what we've learned in the past together.
So, let's break this down completely.
So we're checking if a number is prime.
So I'm making a function using the D-E-F
to tell Python I'm about to make a function.
I'm gonna say, is_prime is the name of my function,
parenthesis, num, that's the argument it takes in, colon.
And then I have my docstring, which is basically
a description of what's going on in the function.
After that, notice all the code is indented at least one,
so it lines up with that name.
That means all this code is going
to run when I call that function.
And now, what I'm doing is I'm going for
every n, which is gonna be a number,
from range two to num, and remember, since I'm in Python 2,
I could've also done xrange to not create a list.
If you're using Python 3, you can only use range,
which is gonna be the same thing as xrange in Python 2.
But that's a small detail, don't worry about it.
So I'm saying for n in range from two to that num.
So, what is that doing?
If I were to just to check it outside of the function,
let's say, two to 12, it's creating
a list of all the integers from two up to that num.
Actually, up to but not including that num,
which is important, since we're checking for primes.
And then, I'm gonna say, if the number itself,
so, in this case, if 12, divided by any of these numbers
leaves you with a remainder of zero,
then I know it's not prime, right?
So, if 12 is divisible by three,
evenly, with no remainder, then I know it's not prime.
And then I'm gonna print Not Prime,
and I'm going to break, which is gonna
break out of this for loop, and end my calculations.
Else, if that never occurs, and then I know
the number is prime, and I'm gonna
print the number is prime.
Okay.
So, that's our first lesson in functions.
And functions is gonna be something
we come back to a lot during our code.
And it's gonna be one of the basic
building blocks of our code.
So you'll see it over again and again.
So, go ahead and check out the reading
and this Jupyter Notebook, and make sure
you fully understand at least how to read
and understand how a function is built out in Python.
Okay, so, thanks for watching this lecture,
and I'll see you at the next one.