Hello everyone, and welcome to the
Nested Statements and Scope lecture.
So we've gone over writing our own functions using
lambda expressions, et cetera, but now it's important
to understand how Python deals with the variable names
we actually assign.
Before we start this lecture, what I want you to do is
read and code through the entire Jupyter notebook
for this lecture.
This is a super important topic for fully understanding
the more advanced Python programming features,
so what I want you to do is read through the entire
Python Jupyter notebook, read through all the code,
code it out yourself, make sure you understand it,
and then come back and we're gonna
explain those ideas further.
Okay, so let's go ahead and get started.
Through a quick introduction, so like I mentioned before,
we've written our own functions, now let's understand
how Python deals with the variable names that we assign.
So when you create a variable name in Python, that name
is stored in what's called a namespace.
And variable names also have what's known as a scope.
The scope determines the visibility of that variable name
to other parts of your code.
So, let's see a quick example of this.
Here, we have the cell block that was in
the Jupyter notebook, so as I mentioned before, you should
have gone through the Jupyter notebook already
and typed out this code yourself.
So, we have the cell block, we have X equals 25,
and then we have this function printer,
which sets X equals to 50, and then returns X.
So what do you imagine the output of printer is,
and what do you imagine is the output of print X?
So the output of that print X statement is 25,
and the output of print printer is 50.
So if you notice here, you basically have two different X's
one for printer, and one in a more global scale or scope
which we'll learn about in a second.
So what we really want to figure out is how does Python know
what X to refer to in your code.
And this is where scope comes in,
so Python has a set of rules it follows to decide
what variables, in this case X, you're referencing
in your code.
And what we're gonna do is break down some of those rules.
Okay, so this is what I just said,
let's go ahead and break it down through name assignment.
So name assignments will create or change local names
by default.
And name references search, at most, only four scopes.
The four scopes are local, enclosing functions, global,
and built-in.
So let's go ahead and start with a quick definition
of all these scopes.
First, local scopes.
So names assigned in any way within a function,
such as a def function or lambda expression,
and not declared global in that function.
That has a local scope.
So if we go back real quick, that X equals 50,
it's defined within a function, printer,
so currently that has a local scope, which is why
when you call printer, it returns 50.
Okay, next, if it couldn't find it in local, it looks for
enclosing function locals.
So, the name in the local scope of any and all enclosing
functions, such as def or lambda, from inner to outer.
And we'll see an example of that in a further slide.
After that, it checks for global.
And those are names assigned at the top level of the
module file, or declared global in a def within a file.
And we'll talk about the global statement in just a second.
After that, it checks for built-in names in Python.
Those are names that are preassigned built-in names
in the Python language, so such as open, range,
SyntaxError, et cetera.
So let's go ahead and break down a few examples
of all four of these.
So first, local.
So for instance, if we have a expression here,
X is local to that lambda expression, or any function.
Next, enclosing function locals.
This one's a little different.
So here I have an example
which you've already coded through.
I'm assigning name is equal to this is a global name,
outside of any function.
Then I crate a function called greet,
and name equals Sammy.
And then, this is something a little new that we
haven't seen yet, I put a function within that function,
I enclose it, and I have a function called hello,
and it prints hello plus name.
Then, I call hello in my greet function,
and then at the end, I call greet.
So if you notice it prints Hello Sammy.
So what happens here, is if we work inside out,
we have this hello call,
and if we look at the function hello,
it says def hello, print hello name.
So what Python's gonna do is it first looks for local scope.
Is name defined anywhere within this hello function?
It's not.
Okay, then let's go to enclosing functions.
Is hello enclosed within another function?
It is, it's enclosed within this greet function.
It looks for the name variable there, and here it is:
name equals Sammy.
So now that it's found it, it brings it back here.
It won't actually go all the way out to this global,
because it's found it already in the enclosing function.
Alright.
Next up, global.
So, globally if I were to just say print name,
since I defined it earlier here
with outside of any function,
this is a global name, it'll print this is a global name.
And then built-in, we've seen a tonne of examples of these,
such as len, which is the function length, et cetera.
So you're gonna want to be careful not to overwrite
any built-in names.
Alright, so moving along, local variables.
When you declare variables inside a function,
they are not related in any way to other variables
with the same names used outside the function.
So variable names are local to the function.
And this is called the scope of the variable.
And all variables have the scope of the block
they are declared in starting from the point of definition
of the name.
So we kind of just went over this, but let's go ahead
and break it down a little further.
So here's one more example, I have assigned here
X is equal to 50, this is a global variable,
it's global in scope.
Then I have a function, func, which takes in X,
it prints X is, X, resets X equal to two,
prints change local X to X,
then we're gonna call that function and print X is still.
So what happens here?
I say, X is 50.
So that's this line right here, print X is.
So the function takes in 50, it says X is 50,
locally it changes X equal to two.
It does not change the global variable.
Which then it says, change local X to two.
But outside the function, even after we call the function
if I were to print X, it still stays 50.
So it only affects that change on a local level.
Now what if we wanted to change that on a global level?
So, if you want to assign a value to a name defined at
the top level of the programme, not inside any kind of scope
such as functions or classes, which we'll learn about later,
then you have to tell Python that the name is not local,
but it's global.
And we do this using the global statement.
So let's see what that looks like.
So here, it's the same code you've gone through before
in the Jupyter notebook.
I have assigned X is equal to 50, and now, this is
where it gets interesting, within my func,
my function here, I say global X,
and this basically tells the function, hey, I'm looking for
the global name of X here.
I'm, whatever, whatever changes I do will affect X globally.
So then I print this function is now using the global X.
Print because of the global X is print out X,
resets X equal to two,
print ran func, changed global X to X.
So, outside of the function, what I first do is I print
before calling func, X is, so let's see the output.
Before calling that function, X is 50.
Then we call the function.
And this function is now using that global X.
Because it's global, it knows X is 50.
It resets the global X to two, and then,
even after calling the function outside of the function,
X is now equal to two.
So with that global statement, I can affect name changes
to variables that have a global scope
using that global statement.
And I'll use that a lot throughout the project of the
black jack game that you'll see later on in this course
to really nail it in that global statements allow us to
take in global variables.
Okay.
So in conclusion, one last thing I wanna mention is that
you can use globals, a built-in function, parentheses
and locals, another built-in function, to check what you
current local and global variables are.
And another thing to keep in mind is that everything
in Python is an object.
So I can assign variables to functions just like I can
with numbers, or any other type of objects we learned
about in the first section of this course.
So we're gonna go over again this whole idea that
everything in Python is an object a lot more in the
Decorators section of this course.
But I just want to mention to you now so you have a feeling
of what to expect.
Okay, so let's hop over to the Jupyter notebook
really quickly.
So again, you should have gone over this entire notebook
before seeing that slide presentations, and go over
this code and make sure you really understand
what's happening here.
So the things that are important to understand.
It's important to understand for this cell block
why X is printed as 25 here with this command,
and why it's printed as 50 here with this command.
That's crucial for your understanding of how variables
and nested statements and scope works in Python.
Once you have a good feeling of why that's happening,
you need to make sure you have a good feeling
of why this is happening.
Why is hello Sammy being printed, instead of hello,
this is a global name.
Make sure you understand that, and then finally,
make sure you understand these last two examples.
This one right here, why X equals two,
is printed only when you call that function,
and then X is still 50 globally, and then you also need
to understand after reading all this, this example here
why X is 50 and why, since we've called global,
X is equal to two resets the global X to two,
even outside of the function.
Okay, once you understand those examples, you pretty much
have a full understanding of scope in Python,
and you're ready to go.
So take your time with this lecture,
this should take you about a whole day if necessary
to really understand what's going on.
But make sure you take your time to really understand
nested statements and scope.
Okay, thanks everyone, and I'll see you at the next lecture.