Hello everyone
and welcome to the strings coding lecture.
In this lecture we'll be learning about strings.
Right now I have opened the live coding notebook
and, as always, there's an entire
corresponding Jupyter notebook for this lecture.
For a quick overview of the notebook,
it goes over creating strings, printing strings,
some differences in printing between Python 2 and 3,
string indexing and slicing, string properties,
string methods, and then some print formatting issues.
Here's what the notebook looks like.
You can go ahead and check it out on your own
and everything in this notebook
is what we're gonna be going over in this lecture.
Okay, great.
Let's go ahead and just jump right in
and get started with some coding.
Alright, so strings in Python are used to record,
usually text information, such is the name.
The way you can create a string
is by using single quotes or double quotes
in the most basic format.
So I can put in a single quote here
and then say, hello, and end it.
Close it off with another single quote.
Shift, enter to run that cell and now I have a string there.
You can also do an entire phrase, like a sentence.
So I can say, this is also a string.
Close it off and you have a string that way, as well.
Now something important to know in Python
is that what Python realises here
is that this string is a sequence
and we'll go over that further in just a little bit.
But the way Python is thinking about this string,
if you will, is that it's seeing every single letter, here,
as part of a sequence including the spaces.
When we learn about indexing and slicing strings,
that will become a little more clear.
Something else I wanna note
is we've been using single quotes,
but we can also use double quotes to create a string.
Here I have a double quote and I can say,
this is a string.
As you can see that works just as well.
Now, why would you use double quotes versus single quotes?
The reason for that is let's say you have a string
where you want it to say, I'm a string.
Now, if you notice here, I'm using a single quote
in this I'm, so that's gonna return an error
because of an invalid syntax.
So that's one of the instances where you're gonna want
to use double quotes, if you have
a single quote within your string.
Now that will be fine.
You can also do the opposite.
You could, let's say this is a quote.
As you can see that double quotes
are now within this string.
Great.
Now let's learn about printing a string.
Because we're using this Jupyter notebook setting,
if we just run a cell that only has a string in it,
it will automatically output the strings.
But the correct way to display strings in your code,
if you're using Idol or another Ide
that we've gone over before is through printing a string.
So we can decare a string, such as hello world
and let's say we wanted to put in multiple strings,
so I say hello world 1 and hello world 2.
If you notice here, in this Jupyter notebook setting,
only the last string was displayed.
The correct way to output these strings
is using a print statement.
The way that works in Python 2 is by writing the word
print, space, and then whatever string you want to print.
Here again I'll do it, print, space, and then the string.
Now, you'll notice here, it's actually printing the string
and these quotes, these single quotes that we saw earlier
have gone away and this is the main way you want
to output or display strings in your code.
Alright, some other things to note
is that there's special backslash characters we can use,
in order to print certain things.
What I mean by that is let's say I wanted to print
a new line, such as a space or something.
The way you can do that is by using a backslash n notation,
so I'll show you what that looks like in practise.
I'm gonna put a string that says, here is a new line
and I'm gonna put that backslash n
and here is the second line.
So if you notice, this backslash n
is an indication to Python to not treat this as a regular n,
but actually treat this as a new line symbol.
What that does is it prints out everything,
until it hits that new line,
and then it prints everything else afterwards,
so it's able to break up your print statement
into multiple lines.
Another feature that uses that backslash is t,
which stands for tab.
So if I run this, it'll actually insert a tab,
those five spaces in between where that backslash t was.
That's just something to be aware of.
Okay.
If we hop over to the Jupyter notebook,
you'll notice there's a Python 3 alert
when it comes to printing.
Let's go ahead and take a better look
at what that's actually talking about.
Python 3 alerts.
There's something to note, if you're using Python 3
versus Python 2, print is a function,
not a statement anymore.
If you notice earlier, we've been printing things
with print, space, and then that string.
In Python 2, your print statements are actually gonna be
print functions and they're gonna look like this.
They're gonna say print, parentheses,
whatever string you want to print,
and then close parentheses.
That happens to be a point of confusion
because a lot of times you start tutorials
that are either in Python 3 or Python 2
and one of the very first assignments you have to do
is print hello world and people get confused
based on what version they're using.
You can go ahead and fix this, if you're using Python 2,
but want to use the print function.
Just as before, you can import from the future module
and we'll go over modules later on in the course,
but if you want to be printing using Python 3 functions
instead of Python 2, you can put this line in your code,
from underscore underscore future underscore underscore
space import space print underscore function,
and that will import this functionality into your Python 2.
Up next we're gonna be learning about string basics,
such as length and string indexing.
I won't go ahead and import this,
I'll keep using the Python 2 notation,
but if you're using Python 3, just keep in mind
this is what your print functions are gonna look like.
If your using Python 2 you can
import that functionality with that statement.
Let's go ahead and move along to some string basics.
We can use a function called len
to check the length of a string.
I can say, hello world, close it off with single quotes,
and then I can put that inside a length function, len.
The way that's gonna look is, len open parentheses,
whatever that string is, close parentheses.
If I run that, it counts the length of the string.
Keep in mind, as I said before, the strings are a sequence.
That means that Python can use indexes
to call parts of that sequence.
That also means that Python is taking to account
that middle space as part of it's count.
If you count this here, there's 10 letters,
but that space counts as another part of that sequence,
so the total count of that length of that string is 11.
Alright, so let's go ahead and assign a label
and create a variable, here.
I'm gonna say, s is equal to hello world.
Now if I call that s, either by printing it
or just calling s there, s has been assigned hello world.
Great.
Lets go ahead and start indexing.
Indexing uses brackets in Python.
The way this is gonna work is I can say s, open bracket,
the index number, close brackets,
and that will return the first element.
So something to note in Python
is that indexing starts at zero.
Like I said before, each of these letters
and spaces in this string is part of a sequence.
So Python is thinking of this capital h
as being in the zero part of the sequence,
e as being in the one part of the sequence,
two, three, four, so on and so on.
Let's say I wanted to get that second letter,
which if we're counting from index zero,
that's gonna be bracket one, then that can be e there.
Great.
We can also perform slicing
and slicing grabs everything up to a designated point
and the syntax for that is using a colon.
I'll show you a quick example.
Let's go ahead and grab that s, open bracket,
one, colon, close bracket.
Before we actually run this, let's break down
what Python's gonna say.
It's gonna say, for this s object, which is hello world,
grab everything from that first, that one index,
and this colon means onwards.
This will grab everything from one all the way to the end
and since indexing starts at zero,
that's gonna be ello space world.
If you notice, something to keep in mind
is right now there's no change to that original string.
We're just grabbing part of it with this notation.
Okay, so you can also say grab everything up to something.
Let's say I wanted to grab everything up to the third index.
That will give you hel.
To keep in mind, it's everything up to the third index.
If I look at hello world again, let's just go ahead
and show s, that's zero, one, two.
If I say colon to three, that says grab everything,
that's what the colon stands for,
up to that third index.
Remember it's up to, it doesn't actually include it,
which is why we only get three letters back.
The zero, the one, and the two index.
Just to reiterate, here we're telling Python
to grab everything from zero up to three,
not including the third index.
You'll notice this a lot in Python.
A lot of the statements and usually a lot
of the indexing statements are in the context of up to,
but not including.
Hopping back to that colon notation.
If I wanted to grab everything,
then I can just say colon and that says grab everything.
Something that's really nice about indexing
is that we can also go backwards.
If you imagine that this string is almost like a loop,
if h is zero, then negative one or one backwards
would be the last letter or element in that string.
So I can say s, bracket, negative one
and that will return d.
So that's the last letter.
So one index behind zero,
it loops back around and grabs that d.
I can also use that same notation to, let's say,
grab everything but the last letter.
I can say grab everything,
but that last letter there.
So that will be hello worl, without that d at the end.
Another thing we can use indexing and slice notation
is to grab elements of a sequence by a specified step size.
If you notice right now, the default is one,
but we can use two colons in a row and then a number
to specify a frequency to grab elements.
What I mean by that is a quick example.
I could say square brackets, colon, colon,
so that means grab everything up to everything
and that third number is gonna specify the frequency,
so in step size.
So right now this will be everything,
so grab everything, that colon, colon in step sizes of one.
But I could also say go in steps of two.
I could say, colon, colon, step size two.
Now that's pretty much gonna grab every other element
or letter in that string.
Something you can also do is use that same notation
to print that string backwards.
I can say grab from the beginning of everything
to the end of everything, but your step size
is gonna be negative one, so that's actually telling Python
to traverse the string backwards and it's actually gone
and printed out that string in reverse.
This is just a simple notation for reversing a string.
These double colon notation methods
are not super common, but this reversing of a string
is a pretty quick and common way,
at least this particular line is pretty common.
These other ones are not super common,
but it's important to know them
in case you ever find yourself needing them in your code.
Alright.
Let's go ahead and learn about some string properties.
Something that's important to note
is that strings have a property known as immutability
and the way you spell that
is i m m u t a b i l i t y, immutability.
What this means is that once that string is created
the elements within it can't be changed or replaced.
For example, remember s currently stands for hello world.
Let's say you wanted to try to change
the first letter to x instead of h.
You might think you'd be able to say,
hey, that zero one, set it equal to x.
But if you notice, we get an error.
The type error is string object
does not support item assignment.
As you go along in learning Python,
these errors are gonna be super helpful
to find out what you're doing wrong in your code.
Something that's always important to remember for strings
is that they're immutable.
Once it's created, you can't go around changing
the particular elements in the sequence.
What you can do, though, is concatenate strings together.
So you can add on to them, you can't just change
what's already there, though.
What I mean by concatenating is,
let's say you have s, you can use the plus symbol
to concatenate strings together.
So I can say s plus and then let's go ahead
and make another string, so I can say
concatenate me, which is basically
just saying to stick it onto it.
Here I have hello world, space, concatenate me.
While I can't change particular elements in that string,
I can add onto it, so that is allowed.
I can also reassign s completely.
Just as we saw earlier in some previous lectures,
I could say s equals s plus concatenate me
and now if I run that and I check what s is,
now s is equal to hello world, space, concatenate me.
Great.
Some other arithmetic symbols you can use for strings
is the multiplication symbol.
For instance, if I say letter is equal to
the string just z and then if you notice
I call letter as that variable and I get z.
Then, if I say letter times 10,
Python's gonna print that letter 10 more times
or 10 times the original amount, whatever it happens to be.
So then if I say, let's say letter equals zz.
Print out that letter check.
Now I've printed 10, so now it's double as many times.
Okay and now we're gonna wrap up our method
with a quick introduction to built in strings.
Excuse me, built in string methods.
Objects in Python, they usually have built in methods.
These methods are basically
just functions inside the objects.
We'll go into all that in much more depth later on,
but they basically allow us to perform
actions or commands on the objects itself.
Let's go ahead and create or reassign s again,
just to say hello.
Here I have s equal to hello
and the syntax for methods on objects
is going to be whatever that object label name is,
in our case s dot and then you call the method on it.
One of the most simple methods for strings
is to upper case a string.
That method is known as upper, close parentheses there.
Basically, what this is doing is it's saying
okay, take my string s, that period or decimal point
is an indicator that I want to call a method
on that object and then the method I'm using is upper.
I'm gonna say close parentheses because I'm not gonna add
what are called arguments into that method.
What that does is it basically
upper cases that entire string.
The reason we're using Jupyter notebooks
and that's super awesome, is you'll see if I click tab,
right after that decimal or a period, I get a list
of all the different methods I can use on my strings.
If you want you can go ahead and check out
the advanced string lectures and we'll go over
and break down a lot of these different methods
that are super useful for strings.
A couple more methods I want to show you
is lower and I can close parentheses there.
That will lower that string again, so you'll notice here
that capital h is now lower case h.
Another thing is I can split a string.
I can say, s dot the split method, close parentheses
and if you notice here, nothing happens.
It's returning a list, which we'll learn about in
a little bit, but I can say split by a particular element.
I can say split by e and now you'll notice
it's returned a list of that string,
but it split it where that e occurred.
I have h as an element and now llo
as another element in that list.
We'll be going over lists in just a second.
Great.
That's about it as far as strings in general.
We'll be working with them a tonne in Python,
so go ahead and review the Jupyter notebook
that goes along with this lecture.
Make sure you understand everything
and we'll be recovering and regoing over strings
as we move along in the course.
Great and like I said earlier,
if you wanna learn more about some of these methods,
go ahead and check out the advanced strings lecture.
Okay, thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.