Hello everyone, and welcome to your lecture on
Object Oriented Programming.
Now Object Oriented Programming, or otherwise known as OOP,
tends to be one of the major obstacles for beginners
when they're first starting to learn Python.
So there's many many tutorials and lessons covering OOP
so feel free to Google search other lessons
and I will also put some links to other useful tutorials
at the bottom of the Jupyter Notebook
if you scroll down here.
There's four really nice other great resources
on Object Oriented Programming
to serve as extra learning material for you
as you learn about Object Oriented Programming.
So for this lesson, we're gonna construct our knowledge
of OOP by building on the following topics.
We're gonna start by learning about objects themselves
and remembering what it means to be an object.
Then we're learn about using the class keyword.
Then we'll create class attributes.
We'll create methods within a class.
We'll learn about inheritance,
and then we'll learn about Special Methods for classes.
We're gonna take this very slowly and methodically
and most likely this Object Oriented Programming lecture
will be broken up into smaller chunks
so they're easier to digest, if you will.
Okay, so we're gonna start by remembering
about Basic Python Objects.
And before we begin with the live coding,
I actually really encourage you to just go ahead
and read through the entire Jupyter Notebook here
before you actually see this video
just so you at least see everything once
before jumping into the LiveCode.
Now go ahead and after your done reading this notebook
'cause there's actually a a lot of text here for you to read
that'll help your understanding
which I'm going to explain right now
throughout the video lecture,
but it's nice that you've at least seen it once before.
Okay, let's go and hop over to the actual coding now.
So let's start the lesson by remembering about
Basic Python Objects.
So for example, lets make a list.
Remember lists, just use brackets.
There we have our lists.
And remember how we can call methods on a list.
So we have our object, l, which is a list
and I can call various methods on it.
So I could say count...
Count how many times two shows up.
And we're basically going to be doing in this lecture
is exploring how we could create an object type,
like a list.
So we've learned about how to create functions
such as def square
where you return
that num
to the power of two.
So we've learned about how to create functions,
but you can imagine what would happen if you wanted
to create an object like a list.
Like how would you actually code that in Python?
And that's where Object Oriented Programming
is gonna come into place.
So in Python, let's go ahead and start learning about
objects.
So in Python, everything is an object.
And remember this from previous lectures.
We can use the type function
to check the type of object something is.
So for instance,
I have an integer, one.
And if I use the type function on that,
it'll tell me what type of object it is.
It's an int object.
That's its object type.
What if I wanted to check the type for
this list that I just made?
Which is one, two, three.
It's a type list, so that a type of object it is.
And let's just really drive the point home.
Let's go ahead and make it a tuple.
One, two.
It's a tuple.
Let's go ahead and make a dictionary.
Say k1,
one.
Tells you type is dict.
Okay, so now we know that everything in Python
is an object,
and we can actually use type
to check the type of object something is.
So we know all these things are objects.
So how do we create our own object types?
And that's where the class keyword comes in.
So we'll be using the class keyword
in order to create our own object types.
Okay, so I'm actually going to
stop this first part of the lecture here.
Make sure you read through this entire Jupyter Notebook
before continuing on with the other lectures
in the Object Oriented Programming series
or section of the course.
And keep in mind that in Python everything is an object.
And to drive that point home,
I will show one more example of everything being an object.
So remember we could create functions.
Square,
again.
Return
Num to the power of two.
So even that square function in Python,
it is an object itself.
And what type of object it is?
It's a function object.
So keep in mind that everything in Python is an object.
And now we're gonna learn how to use the class keyword
to create our own objects.
An Object Oriented Programming in Python
is gonna be highly dependent on that class keyword.
Okay, so make sure you read this entire Jupyter Notebook
before continuing on
and then you'll come in fully prepped
for the upcoming videos.
Okay, and just a quick reminder,
there's also, at the bottom, of this Jupyter Notebook
four other great resources in Object Oriented Programming.
And the reason I'm stressing so much that you read this
and take your time with it
is that a lot of people get stuck
on Object Oriented Programming
when they're first learning about Python.
And it's a bit of a learning curve,
but once you get it, you'll feel that it suddenly clicks
and you understand why you're using
Object Oriented Programming.
Okay, so in the next video we'll explain about class.