Hello and welcome to part four
of the Object Oriented Programming section of this course.
So now we're gonna learn about inheritance.
And inheritance is a way to form new classes using classes
that have already been defined.
And then these newly formed classes
are called derived classes.
And the classes that we derive from are called base classes.
So you have your base classes and
then you can create the derive classes from them.
So a lot of important benefits of inheritance
is that you're able to use code again and reuse it.
And then you can reduce the complexity
of your overall programme code.
Okay. So let's go ahead and break down this idea
in the form of a live coding example.
So what I'm gonna do is incorporate some of our previous
work from the Dog class.
But first, I'm gonna create a new class.
Call it Animal.
Hopefully you remember the syntax for creating class.
So we use class key word,
capitalise the name of your class, pass in the object.
Key word.
Okay. So now let's go ahead
and create the initialization method,
underscore underscore init underscore underscore,
pass in self.
And now what I'm going to say is just
have it simply say print
Animal created.
So note, I am not actually passing in any attributes.
It's just gonna be a basic
print Animal created statement there.
So that means if I say A is equal to Animal,
Animal created is printed.
But notice A.
So I click dot tab.
It actually has no attributes associated with it.
So this is just a super simple example of a class.
And usually when you have print statements like this
within your initialization method,
but this is just to show you later on
how inheritance is actually working.
So I'm gonna add two more methods.
One called Who am I.
And it's gonna take it to self.
And it's gonna print Animal,
and again these print statements,
they're just to show later on
how the inheritance is working.
And then one more method called Eat.
Again all methods within a class
always take self as an argument.
And then I'm going to print here,
print Eating.
Okay. So here I have my pretty basic animal class.
And now, I'm going to create or recreate
the Dog class.
But if you notice, I'm not gonna pass objects.
I'm going to pass in or inherit the Animal class.
That base class.
And so the syntax for this
when I initialise it,
I'm gonna have my init method
gonna take in self again.
Now what's going to happen is I'm actually going to
initialise an Animal instance
by calling the init method
with self attached.
And then I'm going to say print
Dog created.
And then I'm going to put in two more methods
called who am I
in this case for the Dog class self.
I'm gonna print Dog.
The one more I'm gonna say def bark.
It's gonna take in self.
And it's gonna print say woof.
Okay. So I have my Animal class.
And I'm going to zoom out of it
so we can see both of them at the same time.
My Animal class and my Dog class.
And let's go ahead and create an instance
of the Dog class or Dog object.
So what do we think is actually going
to happen when I click this?
So let's kind of work backwards here.
I have my Dog.
Remember, it's inheriting from Animal.
And when I initialise the Dog class,
I call the initialised method on Animal,
which prints Animal Created.
But I also print Dog Created within the Dog class.
So I should see the printed statements;
Animal created, Dog created.
And so that's what we get up there.
Now what happens if I say d who am I?
Is it gonna say Dog or is it gonna say Animal?
Well something to note here is that
since I'm calling Dog and Dog has it's own who am I method,
that's gonna override any instances of
the inherited who am I method.
So we'll say Dog.
But, if you notice, I don't have an Eat method
within my Dog class.
But I do have it within my Animal class.
And since it inherited the Animal class,
when I construct the Dog, it will still have
the Eat method available to it.
So I hit Eat and then it'll print Eating.
But I can also have additional methods
that I only have existent in the Dog class.
So let's break this down again.
In this example, we have two classes, Animal and Dog.
The Animal is the base class
and the Dog is the derived class.
And the derive class inherit,
inherits functionality of the base class.
And this is shown primarily through this Eat method.
And the derive class can modify existing behaviour
of the base class.
So I modified it by overriding using the who am I method
within the Dog class.
Okay. So that's inheritance.
So remember it's a way to form new classes using classes
that have already been defined.
It's a bit of an advanced topic for a beginner to learn.
But it'll help you be able to understand
how inheritance works when you're reading
someone else's code.
And then as you progress more and more and
start using classes and Object Oriented Programming more,
you'll be able to see instances where
Hey, I actually, I'm going to create a class
that's very very similar to another class I just created,
I might as well inherit it instead
of creating an object again.
All right, so lastly in this series of lectures,
we're gonna learn about special methods.
We've already gone over one special method,
this init method, which initialises attributes
and everything that's going on with your class.
So we're gonna learn about some other special methods.
Okay. Thanks. And I'll see you at the next lecture.