Hello, everyone,
and welcome to Part 5 of the Object Oriented Programming
section of this course,
and finally, we're gonna learn about special methods.
So classes in Python can implement certain operations
with special method names.
And these methods are actually not called directly,
but by Python-specific language syntax.
So, for example, when we make a list
and I say, "1, 2, 3,"
and I say something like print that list,
Python knows what to do with it,
and that's because it has a special method
and same thing with like the length of a list,
Python knows how to incorporate that,
so there's special methods that Python has built in
that have to do with specific language syntax,
when you call either certain things like
delete, print, or checking length,
and I'll show you what I mean by that
through an example.
So what we're gonna do is create a book class.
Remember, I pass an object here,
and I'm going to initiate it
and this itself is a special method
that's pretty much always used for classes
in order to create a class.
So, I'm going to have three attributes for my book.
It's gonna have a title.
It's gonna have an author,
and it's gonna have a number of pages.
And so, let's go ahead and fill those in.
I'm gonna say self.title is equal to
whatever title the user inputs there.
Self.author, that attribute is equal to
whatever you pass in as the author.
And self.pages is equal to
whatever you pass in as the number of pages.
And I'm also gonna put a little print statement here
for visualisation purposes,
just to show that a book has been created.
OK, usually you probably wouldn't have
print statements there,
but it's just for helping our understanding.
OK.
Now, let's go in and explore some special methods.
So I just fixed that quote there.
Now these special methods.
Well, the first we're gonna explore has to do
with printing,
and to show you what I mean,
I'm gonna run that,
and I'm gonna set b equal to
an instance of the Book.
The title of the book will be Python.
The author, I'm just gonna put Jose for the author,
and the number of pages is gonna be 100 pages long.
So I notice since I have that print statement
and I run that cell,
it tells you a book has been created.
So, remember I could print a list
and Python knew exactly what to print out?
So, what happens if I try to print this book?
If you notice, Python's actually just gonna print
out the definition of whatever b actually is,
the fact that it's a main book,
and then it's also gonna print out some information
on exactly where it's being held in memory.
But what if I wanted to actually print out
some information of this book?
Well, that's where the special methods come into play.
And the special method that has to do with printing
is called __str, which stands for string,
and takes in self as an argument,
and you'll notice special methods are set apart
with that set of underscores.
The underscore, underscore,
and what I'm gonna do is with the special method.
I'm gonna return the title,
the author, and the pages.
And here I'm just using some formatting.
You can use whatever formatting,
as far as the print formatting that makes sense to you.
And I'm gonna input the attributes
that correspond to the title, author, and the pages.
And then, whoops, this should be a period.
Self.author, and then self.pages.
OK, let's zoom out a bit, so you can see the whole thing.
OK, so that's all that string is doing, that special method.
So now, if I create a new book.
"A book has been created," and I print b,
you'll notice that it calls this special method
when you call the print function in Python,
and that's really what special methods,
how they come into play.
They have to do with built-in functions in Python
and what they actually produce.
So, let's explore another method.
So I'm gonna go ahead and remove this one.
Another special method is length.
And I can do __len__,
and this is what Python's gonna use
when you call the length of an object.
In this case, I just actually want to return
the number of pages, right?
'Cause that's the most fitting thing
for the length of a book.
So I can say return self.pages.
I create a new book.
Let's just verify, 101.
"A new book's been created."
And if I print the book, you'll notice,
I'm back to that original instance
where it tells you where it's stored in memory,
since I removed that special method,
but if I check the length of the book now, length of b,
it'll actually return the pages,
so that's a special method used
in conjunction with that length function.
And then, finally, another special method I can use
is the del, or delete method.
So you can delete objects from memory,
if it has that method in it
and I'm gonna say print "A book is gone!"
since we deleted it.
So now if I create this book b.
Let's go ahead and say b, find out what the title is.
Title is "Python."
I can call the delete method, or statement on b,
and it's printed out, "A book is gone!"
So now if I try calling the title,
it says, "b is not defined," so that makes sense.
OK, so these special methods,
remember, they're defined by the use of their underscores
and they allow us to use specific functions in Python
on objects created throughout our class.
So, that's it as far as this general section and lectures
on object oriented programming.
I know it was a lot and I know it's sometimes hard
to understand,
but really, just take it slowly,
make sure you copy exactly what I'm doing,
take your time with it,
and again, like I've mentioned before,
check out a lot of these more great resources on this topic.
It'll take a while for this to really start
cementing itself in your mind,
but what we're going to do is,
for the next Milestone Project
is utilise object oriented programming really heavily,
so you get a good feeling for it.
OK, so in the next video,
I'm going to explain your Milestone Project to you.
Thanks, guys.