Hello everyone,
and welcome to the live coding section
of the Errors and Exception Handling part of this course.
And now we're going to learn how to use
try, except and finally,
which we learned about in context in the previous video.
Now we're actually going to use them.
So let's go ahead and see
if we can get an exception to occur, some sort of error.
I'm going to say 2 plus,
and I'm going to try to add a string to it.
Now clearly this is impossible.
So I get a Type error.
There's unsupported operands + for an integer and a string.
Okay, that makes sense.
So I could have said try,
and now here I'm going to put in code
that I think may put an error out.
Or some sort of exception.
So it says try 2 + 's'
and now I'm going to put in the except block.
I'm going to say except if there's a TypeError,
print
"There was a type error!
And let's see what happens now.
So if you notice, I mention that some of these exceptions
are not unconditionally fatal,
TypeError is one of them.
So TypeError, since it's not unconditionally fatal,
the rest of your code can actually still run
using this try-and-except format.
So what happens is the code tries to do 2 + 's'
except there's a TypeError,
so it prints There was a type error!
And then the finally block,
will execute any code after these exceptions.
So I'll say finally
we'll say print
'Finally this was printed'
So now if we run this,
we get both the except statement
and Finally this was printed.
So something to note here,
is that I don't actually have to specify
what error it is,
otherwise that would require you memorising
the entire list of exceptions,
but if you go back to the Jupyter notebook
and scroll down,
I do have a link there to check out the full list
of built-in exceptions in Python.
And you can check them out all here,
so you can just go ahead and, if you want,
generally browse this,
but there's no point in memorising all of these.
This is just to help you debug your code later on.
So if I just say except, I don't actually need to know
or guess what kind of error's going to pop up.
If I run this cell,
you'll notice I get the exact same thing.
Okay, so this is how you're usually going to see
try-except-finally used in your own code.
You're probably not going to type
in the actual exceptions that you expect to occur.
All right, so let's go ahead and break down exceptions
with try-except-else sort of statement.
So I'm going to do by trying to open a file.
So I'm going to say try,
say f = open
and I'm going to try to open 'testfile'
with being able to write to it,
I'm going to say f.write
'Test write this'
and then what's going to happen is
let me go ahead and make sure I don't have this file
by adding in some numbers.
It's going to try to open a file that's not there.
And I'm going to say except
print 'Error in writing to the file!'
And then I'm going to say else,
print
'File write was a success!"
And if I run this,
it says File write was a success.
Now that's because
when I open a file like this,
it'll actually create the file for me.
So I open the file, testfile1232,
the file didn't exist so Python went ahead
and wrote it for me.
And now if I look at my folder,
I'll have a testfile1232
that says test write this,
so file write was a success.
So that's how you can use else.
So when you don't have any exceptions,
else will help you know that.
So it says try this,
except if there's an error,
print out an error,
else if there's no exceptions and everything went well,
execute this code block.
Now I'm going to try to induce an error
by saying read.
So remember from file opening and closing,
if I just put R,
that means I can only read the file.
I don't have write permission.
So now let's see what happens if I run this cell.
No, I have an error in writing to the file.
Great, so we only printed a statement
and the code still ran.
So we're able to continue doing actions
and running code blocks,
even if I do have an error occur,
which is really nice.
So it's super useful when you have to account
for possible input errors in your code.
So you can be prepared for the error and keep running code,
instead of your code just breaking
the minute it sees some sort of exception occur.
So we could have also just said,
except if we weren't sure
if a certain exception were to occur.
So for instance I know that this sort of error
is called an IO error,
and that's fine.
But I can also just put except,
I just want to make that clear,
that you don't actually have to put in
what kind of error will actually occur.
All right, now continuing on.
Right now we have this else statement
that will execute only if errors
don't occur, right?
But what if we wanted to continue doing stuff
even if an error occurred?
So that's where the finally block of code will run.
So that will run regardless if there's an exception.
Right now we have try-except-else,
so it's going to try some code,
if there's an exception it'll do this.
Otherwise, or else, it'll do that code block.
But what if we wanted to do this code block
regardless if there's an exception or not?
So we're going to use finally to do that.
So I'm going to say try.
Let's say try this code right here,
and say finally
print
'Always execute
finally code blocks!'
So if you notice,
even if there was an error that occurred,
finally was still able to print
Always execute finally code blocks!
So what happened here?
So I had to try this,
I got an error,
and then finally still occurred
even if there was an IO error there.
So I can write an except
I'll do it for any error and print,
'There was an error!'
and let's see what happens now.
So if you notice, this except block of code
basically eliminates Python's built-in output
for exception handling, or the errors popping up.
So you can write in your own except
and print There was an error!,
so your code's a little cleaner.
Then have a finally block that will always execute.
All right, so what we're going to do
is use this in conjunction with asking a user for input.
So I'm going to say,
make a function
let me zoom in a bit here,
make a function, def,
and I'm going to call it askint,
and what it's going to do
is it's going to
try
to set a variable val
equal to raw_input,
I'm using raw_input because I'm using Python 2,
if you're using Python 3 you may just use input.
I'm going to say 'Please enter an integer: '
okay, and what I'm going to try to do after that
is convert it
to an integer.
I'm going to put an except statement,
that says print
'Looks like you did not enter an integer!'
then after that I'm going to say finally,
print
'Finally block executed!'
And then I'm going to say
print the val.
Okay, so let me zoom out now so we can see the whole thing.
All right, so I have my function here,
askint, it's going to try
to take whatever raw_input the user puts in,
convert it to an integer and set that equal to val.
If there's an exception that occurs,
it's going to occur because I wasn't able to convert
whatever they put in as an integer.
So I'm going to print
Looks like you did not enter an integer!
Finally, whether or not there's an exception,
I'm going to print Finally block executed!
And then I'm going to print the val.
So let's see if this works.
Let's go ahead and askint,
close parentheses, there's no arguments,
I run it, it says, Please enter an integer:.
I'm going to enter 3
Finally block executed!
Val was equal to 3.
All right, perfect.
So let's try this again.
I'm going to say askint,
it says Please enter an integer:
Now let's say I was confused
and I entered five.
So if you notice here,
it says Looks like you did not enter an integer!
Finally block executed!
And we have an extra error
because we're trying to locate the variable, val,
before it was actually assigned.
And that's because this prints val
is outside the finally code block.
Okay,
so we got an error
when we're trying to print val,
notice because it's never properly assigned.
So we can go ahead and remedy this
by asking the user and checking to make sure
the input type is an integer.
So what I'm going to do now
is in my except block,
I'm going to say val = int ,
I'm going to say
.
Okay, so let's break down what the code's doing
and I'll space it out so it's a little more clear.
So now my function, what it's going to do,
is it's going to try to take the raw_input a user puts in,
convert it to an integer and set that equal to val.
If there's an exception that occurs,
it's going to say Looks like you did not enter an integer
and then it's going to do it again.
It's going to try again, Please enter an integer,
raw_input converted to an integer.
Finally it's going to print
Finally block executed!
Print val.
Okay, so I ran that.
Let's go ahead and see what happens.
Askint, put an integer,
I'm going to put in five
It says, Looks like you did not enter an integer!
Try again - Please enter an integer:
Now if I put in 5,
everything works.
Great.
So that only did one check.
If you notice, if I try this again,
and mess up twice,
So askint, Please enter an integer:
let's say I put in 5,
it says Try again- Please enter an integer:
let's say I put in 5 again,
we're going to get an error now.
A value error.
Right? Because it's not able
to convert five into an integer.
So what can I do to try to keep continually checking?
Well, hopefully your mind is thinking
about a while loop, right?
I want to do this statement over and over again,
raw_input, check for an integer
until the user actually puts in something correct.
So I'm going to start again,
I'm going to say def askint :
and I'm going to say,
while True:
try to set val equal to that integer,
raw_input of
please enter an integer:
if there's an exception that occurs,
I say except print
'Looks like you didn't--
whoops,
let's make this a double quote
so I don't have to worry about
that's in quote inside,
Looks like you didn't
enter an integer!
And then I'm going to continue
else,
so remember else happens
when the try is actually correct,
so I'm going to print
'Correct, that is an integer!'
and then once I know it's correct,
I'm just going to break out of that finally loop.
Or, excuse me, that while loop.
Then finally after that,
I'm going to print again Finally block executed!
And then outside of this I'm going to print
the value.
Okay.
So let's break down real quickly what's happening here.
I'm going to say while true,
so basically forever,
try to get the input here the first question.
So this is like the very first output.
It says Please enter an integer:
and let's say there's an exception that occurs,
I print Looks like you didn't enter an integer!
Continue
And then it comes back up here,
tries it again
except, continue--
so this is going to keep going forever
until we get a correct input where there's no error.
And it's going to say else
print Correct, that is an integer!
And that will break that while loop there,
and then it's going to say
Finally print the code executed, print val.
So let's in and see if this works.
I'm going to say askint
Please enter an integer:
I'm going to put e, which I know it's not.
I'm going to put r.
So if you notice
my finally block is always being executed
even though I'm having these errors.
But the second I put in a correct number,
with that else statement,
it says Correct, that is an integer!
And then the last time the finally block is executed.
All right, so that's actually it for this video lecture.
So we're just going to go quickly over everything we did.
So try-except-finally,
the very first thing we did
was put in a TypeError exception.
So two plus a string, that didn't make any sense.
So we notice we could use try
so I'm trying to execute this block of code
except if there's any sort of exception,
I print Finally there was a type error!
Excuse me, I print There was a type error!
Then finally this block of code will always execute
whether or not there is an exception that occurs.
Again here I said try
I said open this test file.
Remember we switched from writing to reading permissions?
So if there was an error that occurred,
I said There was an error!
Finally always executes this code block.
Then we started exploring how to deal
with user inputs that are incorrect,
so we made this function,
in this case I say try,
take the raw_input,
try to convert it to an integer and set that as val,
is there any exception,
then I print, Looks like you did not enter an integer!
Put raw_input again, try it again,
but this only works twice, right?
Since it's not in the while loop.
And then finally the block's executed
and then we print val.
And again if you mess up twice in a row,
we're still getting a value error there.
So how do we continue doing this forever?
Well, that's where the while loop comes in.
So we say, while true,
try this block,
if there's an exception,
print that and continue.
Which means it's going to try it again.
And it's going to keep going
and then we can put an else block
which says if there's no exception there,
then print Correct that's an integer
and then we break out of that loop.
Then finally this always executes
whether or not there is an exception.
So you notice here even when there was an error here
and I say Looks like you didn't enter an integer,
the finally block was always executed every single time.
And then at the end,
when I did get it right,
it says Correct, that is an integer!
That else block executed
and then I printed Finally block executed!
Okay, great.
So that's it for this lecture.
Go ahead and explore try-except-finally a little more.
It's going to be super useful in your beginning code
when you're trying to handle user input
that you think may be incorrect.
But later on you'll use it more and more.
Just be careful with it, though,
'cause you don't want try statements
everywhere in your code.
Otherwise it gets harder and harder
to actually debug your code
unless you put in very clear print statements
for your exceptions.
So you can imagine if your code's kind of always running
these finally blocks
and you have a tonne of try blocks in there.
It might be hard to pinpoint
where the actual error is taking place,
if all your print statements are:
There was an error or something for the exception blocks.
So this is super powerful,
and it's a really great tool,
but just be careful with it
and make sure you use it well in your code.
Okay, thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.