Hello everyone.
In this video, we'll be going over
the Errors and Exceptions Homework solutions.
So Problem 1, all you had to do was take the code,
indent it into a try block,
and then add an except block,
and here I said except print an error occurred.
Pretty simple.
Problem 2, very similar.
Had to put try block with z = x/y.
I actually put in the specific error, ZeroDivisionError.
As always, you could have just said except,
and for any error, it would have printed
can't divide by zero.
And the I added the finally block to print all done.
Problem 3 should have been pretty familiar,
given the lecture material.
So for my function, I said while True,
try to get an input that says input integer,
and set it to variable N.
Except to some sort of error occurs,
prints an error occurred, please try again.
Then continue,
else, break,
and then I said print, Thank you,
your number squared is N to the power of 2.
And that was it.
Alright,
hopefully that was pretty straightforward
given the lecture material.
Take your time and read through the code
in case anything was confusing,
and as always, feel free to
post a discussion question if you
are having any trouble.
Thank you.