Hello everyone,
and welcome to the modules lecture.
In this lecture we'll be learning
about what modules really are,
how to import them with an import statement,
how to use them in your workspace,
and also how to instal modules from the internet
that are not included in your basic Python installation.
So, here I have a notebook open call modules
and what we're gonna start off with is how to use them.
And you've actually seen me use these modules a few times,
but now let's formalise how we actually use them.
So you are gonna start with an import statement.
So let me go ahead and jump over to an empty notebook.
So to import from a module you need to say "import",
notice the syntax highlighting,
and then the name of the module.
In this case, I'll import a built-in module
in Python called the math module.
For more built-in modules you can
check out that section of this course.
But for right now we'll start
with a very basic one, the math module.
Now, I can type in math and since I'm
using an IPython or Jupyter notebook,
I can use dot-tab to use all the various
functions that are available to me with this module.
Alright, so let's do a very basic one called sqrt,
which stands for "square root."
So, I can take the square root of four
and I'll output two 2.0, or two point zero.
Now modules are really useful,
so it saves yourself from having to write a lot of code,
and more likely than not someone's already
created a module for you either online
or built into Python for code that you were
thinking of writing before.
So, there's lots of various math functions
that you won't have to write anymore
because they're built into the Python module for math.
Now another we could have used
is to specifically import functions from the module.
So to say "import math" is one way,
but another way, if I just wanted to import
the square root function, I could have said,
"from math import sqrt."
And now you'll notice the syntax for using
square root will actually just be sqrt.
A four.
And I don't have to specify that it's
coming from the math module anymore,
because I used this syntax.
From math, import square root.
So I explicitly told Python what sqrt meant
throughout the rest of my code.
Now as far as formal syntax and code formatting,
you should put all your import statements
at the top of your code.
If you're using this in a Jupyter notebook,
you should put them all in the first cell.
But if you're writing just a normal .py file
or dot pie file, you should put all
your import statements in the top of your code.
Alright, as far as best practises,
you want to try to use this syntax.
From math, import whatever functions you want.
It'll save Python from having to load in
the entire built-in module,
and instead it'll just import the functions you need.
So it'll save headspace that way.
Let's just back to the notebook,
and talk about how to download modules
that are not built in to Python.
So there's two ways to do this.
The best way is to check if Anaconda,
the installation we used since the beginning,
has the module already downloaded for you.
So you notice the Anaconda distribution
actually downloaded a bunch of scientific computer modules
and other poplar modules into Python for you.
So the best way to instal a module right now
is to either open up your terminal
or to open up your Anaconda command prompt,
I'll do that right now.
So you notice here I have my Anaconda command prompt.
If you have a mac you can use the terminal.
So what I'm going to do, is,
open up my command prompt, and let's say I wanted
to instal a particular module I found online.
And we'll discuss how to find these modules
online in just a second.
But what I could do is say "conda", C-O-N-D-A.
Instal, and then the name of either
the package or module I want to instal.
So let's say I wanted to instal Flask.
Flask is a web framework for creating websites with Python.
So I would say "conda instal Flask."
I'd hit enter.
You'll notice a statement saying
"fetching package metadata."
And because Anaconda comes with Flask built in,
it'll actually instal it using the Anaconda distribution.
So you'll notice here since I've already done this before,
I don't get the typical message.
But I'm just installing, updating right now Python.
So that's one way to do it.
I'm gonna pause and jump the video to show you another way.
Okay, so I installed that package
or module using conda instal.
But what if Anaconda distribution doesn't
include that particular module
or package that you're looking for?
Well, you can use pip instal.
Pip, P-I-P, is a package management system
that's used to instal and manage software packages
and it's written in Python.
So most packages that are worth downloading
can be found on what's called
the "Python Package Index," or PyPI.
And that's spelled, P-Y-P-I.
And basically that's gonna allow you
to instal packages from the internet.
So, how do you find these packages
and modules that you want to instal?
Well, let's say I wanted to look for
a package that allowed me to create powerpoints in Python.
You might think that you'd have to programme
that entire thing yourself.
But, you should always do a Google search.
So for instance, I'm writing "python powerpoint module."
The first link is this python-pptx.
So if I click this I'm here at the documentation page.
So what you should do is look around until you find
an installing section on the page.
So I click instal here and you notice I can
instal this python-pptx using "pip instal python-pptx."
So let's go ahead and do that to
show you what it looks like.
So, I go to my command interface,
either terminal or command prompt.
Notice I'm not in Python, I'm just at the terminal line.
And I say, "pip instal python-pptx."
I hit enter and you'll notice it'll begin to instal.
Now, I already have it installed
so my requirement's already satisfied.
You can use "--" to upgrade, in case you want
the latest version of this package.
So, how do you find packages online?
You can either just google search them
or another fun thing to do is go to github.
So, if you go to github.
Github hosts a lot of these packages.
So you can click explore,
go by programming languages, check those out,
so those are actually the repositories
for programming languages themselves.
But, if you want to find packages for Python,
you can go ahead and check out "python".
And we'll discuss this in the next video a little further.
Sort by, let's say, most stars.
And then make sure language, Python is selected.
So, you'll see here the second list, awesome-python,
and we discuss this a bit in the next video,
where it's a curated list of a bunch of different packages
for various things in Python.
So let's say you want to deal with forms in Python,
it'll let you know a bunch of libararies
or packages for dealing with forms, et cetera.
So another fun thing you can do is go to github,
search something that interests you, maybe web scraping.
Click enter.
Search, you'll notice a bunch of web scraping frameworks.
Click Python, so you make sure you're
only looking at Python languages.
Go ahead and maybe check out this first one called "Grab."
So Grab's a web scraping framework.
I've actually personally never heard of it,
so this is also new for me.
So it'll tell you "What is Grab?"
It'll explain it to you how to use it, et cetera.
You can check out the documentation there.
And you'll notice installation.
And for more packages pip is
the recommended way to instal it.
So you say follow this line, "pip instal -U grab."
And it'll instal grab and all its dependencies.
Okay, so, let's go ahead and review very quickly.
How do you use a module or a package
that you downloaded off the internet?
You say "import" and then that module or package name.
If you wanna import particular functions,
you use this notation, "from math import,"
whatever that function is.
So, from the modular package,
import that function or method.
Then, if you wanna download modules
or packages that are not built into Python,
I recommend you first try "conda instal",
whatever that module or package name is.
If Anaconda distribution puts up an error
that it doesn't have it, then I suggest
you use "pip instal," whatever that package name is.
Okay, so that's it, in the next video we'll go
over a quick fun assignment for you to
explore packages online.
Thanks everyone, and I'll see you at the next lecture.