Hello everyone,
and in this video lecture,
I'm just gonna be going over the second
milestone project, the blackjack game.
First of all, congratulations
for making it this far into the course.
I know object oriented programming
is hard to learn, so you should
be really proud of yourself to make it this far.
And you've learned a lot,
so it's time to put it to the test.
So, in this milestone project,
we're going to be creating a blackjack game,
and I'm gonna have you do the following requirements.
So, it's just a simple text-based blackjack game.
You can click the link here in the
Jupyter notebook in case you're
not familiar with blackjack.
The rules are right here.
Hopefully a lot of, most people are familiar with it.
It's basically, otherwise known as 21 sometimes.
It's a card game.
So what you're gonna do is
learn blackjack if you don't know it,
in order to construct the blackjack game in Python.
And the game needs just to have
one player versus an automated dealer.
So the computer's going to deal out cards,
and the player can either stand or hit,
and the the player must be able to pick
their betting amounts, and you need
to keep track of the players money,
how much they have and you also
need to alert the player of wins, losses, busts, etc.
So I'll give you a lot of freedom,
in how much you wanna actually build
out the blackjack game.
But, those are the basic requirements.
If you wanna keep building it out more,
you can have multiple players versus the dealer.
You can have double downs, additional blackjack rules, etc.
So the most important thing throughout
this milestone project is that you
must use Object Oriented Programming and classes
in some portion of your game.
You cannot just use pure functions
like you did for tic tac toe.
So I want you to use classes
to help you define the deck and the player's hand.
There's a tonne of right ways to do this,
so explore it however you feel.
But to give you a quick example,
I'm gonna hop over to the live coating.
So in case it's unclear what I mean
by using object oriented programming
or classes to help you define
the deck and the players' hands.
Maybe start thinking of, we can have a class
called, let's say, player,
and it's gonna have object.
And then let's say player, one of the attributes,
we'll initialise him or her.
And maybe one of the attributes of this player is
possibly how much money they have, so their bankroll.
So we can initialise their bankroll
with, let's say the standard is 100,
but you can choose.
And then we can say self.bankroll
is equal to the bank roll you put in.
And then instead of having to write
a lot of functions, you can write another method
that might be called like adjust_bankroll,
and then we can have, let's say,
we'll always have to have a self argument.
Let's say we can say if you're gonna
add or subtract we can put in an
argument for add or subtract.
So, we'll put in add equals true.
So I'm actually gonna say, I'm gonna
call this add a bankroll not adjust_bankroll
since this will only work for adding money.
So add equals true.
Actually we won't need that anymore.
Let's say instead, the amount.
And what this is gonna do is it's
gonna take your bankroll, and add the amounts to it.
Okay, so now let's create a player.
Let's call this player Sam.
And we'll have him with a bankroll
initially of 1,000.
So now Sam, I can check his bankroll
by calling that method 1,000,
but something else I can do is add to his bankroll, right?
Add_bankroll, I'm just using tab complete here.
Lets say I wanna add 10 dollars to his bankroll.
Now if I check Sam's bankroll, he has 1010.
So this is the kind of thinking
I want you to have as you approach this milestone project.
So I want you to make a class for players,
a class for maybe a deck, a hand.
This is where you can really get
creative and see what works for you.
Okay, so that's enough of hints or examples,
and I'll let you go ahead and explore that.
Remember, take your time with this project,
really explore it.
Another reason I chose blackjack in particular,
is that this is kind of a common assignment,
so you might even have this as a simple
take home project, maybe for another
course in school or even a basic interview position,
and you can also find a lot of examples online.
So, feel free to explore online and Google
to answer your own questions,
but don't Google blackjack game in Python,
otherwise you might get an example
of an entire solution.
Okay, thanks everyone, and remember,
have fun with it.
Okay, I'll see you at the next lecture.