Hello, everyone, and welcome to
this quick video going over the second
Milestone Project 2 Solution,
at least my implementation of a solution,
and it's just a simple game of Blackjack.
So what I'm gonna go over here is just
how I used classes in my solution.
Since that's really the main purpose
of this exercise in general.
So I went ahead and made a card class,
and in my card class, each card
has an attribute, a suit, and a rank.
And then I went ahead and made a string,
remember we had those special methods?
If I said print card, it would return
its suit plus its rank, whatever
those strings happen to be.
And then I had a grab suit and grab rank method
that returned those attributes.
And then I had a draw, which basically
returned the suit and the rank printed out.
Okay.
So then I made a hand class.
And if you notice here,
something I had to take care of
were that Aces can either be one or eleven in Blackjack.
So I had Ace be basically a boolean value,
whether or not there was an Ace in the hand.
And then I had cards and values
so the cards I used list as my data structure.
And then this special method, the str, for printing.
Basically would just return the string
of a current hand composition.
So maybe there's a better way of writing this out
with a list comprehension possibly,
but I just wanted to show, for clarity, a for loop here.
So for every card in the cards list,
I went ahead, called it out, its str method,
and then used this to return the entire
hand composition which is basically just
all the strings put together.
Then moving on to the card add which
adds another card to the hand.
I take my self.cards list and append the card to it.
I check for Aces so if the card rank
is equal to A for Ace, I set self.ace equal to True.
That way that boolean value now knows
that there's an Ace in my hand.
Then I have another method for calculating the value,
and that calculates the value of the hand.
So that makes Aces an eleven if they don't bust the hand.
So if Ace is true, I have an Ace in the hand.
If my value is less than twelve,
then I return value plus ten.
Else, I just return it as if it was a one.
Then I also have a draw method
which has these two factors, hidden and true.
So I don't wanna show the first hidden card,
and that has to do with the way the dealer works.
So we can also continue on to the deck class that I made.
And remember your solution might be
totally different, but as long as
you used object oriented programming,
that was the main point of this exercise.
So I wanted to create a deck in order,
so I have a deck here and I say for suit in suits,
for rank in ranking, append a tuple here.
Or a card, excuse me.
So create a card object with a suit and that rank.
And you might be thinking well
where are these suits and rankings coming from.
So I actually defined them up here.
Hearts, diamonds, cloves, spades,
and then all the possible ranks.
As well as a dictionary of point values for them.
So moving on with this deck class.
I had the creation of it, shuffle it,
which I just used from the random library to shuffle.
I used deal, it just pops items off of the list,
that deck list, and then str was just
for printing the deck composition.
Okay, so that's it for the classes.
I'll let you go ahead and check out the functions.
I used global variables just because
it's in the Jupiter notebook and
it's a little easier that way,
but you didn't have to.
There's tonnes of ways to implement
this game of Blackjack so, as long as it works
and as long as you're happy with it, great job.
Okay, so I'll let you go ahead
and read through the rest of that solution.
Thanks, everyone.