Hello everyone,
and welcome to this lecture on the map function.
So map is a built in function in Python
and it's gonna be one of the first built-in functions
we work with.
And it's a really useful function,
especially when you use it in conjunction
with the lambda expression,
and we'll go into that a little further.
So map comes in the form map
and then it takes in two arguments,
a function and a sequence iterable, such as a list.
And what it does, it applies this function
to every element in this sequence
and then returns a new list with the elements changed
by the function.
So let's go ahead and see what this looks like
in a live coding example.
If you remember from the list comprehension lectures,
we used list comprehension to convert temperatures, right?
Fahrenheit to Celsius.
So let's go in and see what that looks like with map.
So I'm gonna use map.
I'm gonna create a function called fahrenheit
and it's gonna take in a temperature
that's in Celsius
and it's gonna return the temperature in Fahrenheit.
So it's gonna return the temperature in Celsius
and that equation looks like this.
You may remember it from
the list comprehension tutorials.
So here we have our fahrenheit function.
It takes in the temperature
and then returns the temperature in Fahrenheit.
So to give you an example,
let's go ahead and look at Fahrenheit
of zero degrees Celsius is 32 degrees, right?
The temperature where water freezes.
Okay, so what if I had a list of temperatures in Celsius
so I could say zero, less like room temperature,
and then let's say boiling water at 100 degrees Celsius.
So what if I wanted to apply this function
to every element in my temperature list?
That's where map comes in.
So I'm gonna say map,
the name of my function, fahrenheit,
and notice I'm not actually passing any parenthesis,
I'm just passing the name of my function.
So I don't do this.
It's just the name of the function.
And then I pass in the sequence iterable,
in this case my list.
And what I get is every element in that list
with the fahrenheit function applied to it.
Great.
So in this example we could have used a lambda expression
so we didn't have to actually define this whole fahrenheit.
So this is great when you wanna do
some sort of anonymous function call.
So you don't want to have to define entire functions,
so you use the lambda expression.
And I mentioned before,
when we were covering lambda expressions,
that they would be really useful with map
and filter and reduce,
so now we're gonna see them in their true action.
So I'm gonna say lambda take in some T,
multiply it by nine divided by five.
And I'm using 9.0 so I don't get any floating point errors,
I don't get any cut-offs.
If you're using Python Three
you didn't have to worry about that.
And that's my lambda expression
and now I'm going to apply it to my list.
And we get the exact same result.
Awesome.
So now I actually, with map,
don't even have to define
an entire function name and call-it.
I can just use a lambda expression instead.
And usually when you see map in someone else's code
it's almost always using a lambda expression.
Okay, so how can we build on top of this?
So if you remember,
lambda expressions can actually take in multiple arguments.
So I could have something like lambda x, y
return x plus y.
So I could have that sorta lambda function.
And we can incorporate that with map.
So we can pass more than one sequence iterable
and I'll show you what I mean by that.
I'm gonna create two lists.
Actually three.
One, two, a, b, and c,
so let's go, a is gonna have one, two, three,
b will have four, five, six
and c will have seven, eight, nine.
Okay, so I have a, b, c and now what I'm gonna do
is map the lambda expression I had
which takes in two arguments, x and y
and then returns x and y added together.
But remember I'm gonna take in two arguments now, a and b.
So what map is gonna do,
is it's gonna be able to work
with two or more sequence iterables.
So it's gonna apply this lambda function in order.
So it's gonna take zero index of a, zero index of b,
apply this lambda expression.
Then the one index of a, one index of b,
apply this lambda expression,
and continually do that.
So if we see the results, we basically get a plus b,
so one plus four, two plus five, three plus six,
five, seven, nine.
And we can actually extend this further
to even more than two.
So I could say,
let me put a space in here so it's really clear,
x, y, z, plus z input a, b, c,
and you'll notice now we get one plus four plus seven,
two plus five plus eight,
three plus six plus nine.
Usually you won't see something
or map in lambda expressions used
for this many sequence iterables,
at least it's not too common from my own coding experience
but it is used sometimes
if it's the right tool in that case.
So maybe you'd want to perhaps change these variables,
if it's more clear for you
to see it this way.
Although it may be unclear
because it may think you're referencing
those list's themselves
but you will get the exact same result.
Okay, so let's go ahead and do one more example
to really drive the point home of what map is doing.
Let's go ahead and make an example that creates the,
let's say, times every number in a list by negative one.
So I want to map some lambda expression
and the lambda's gonna take the number
and return that number times negative one.
And I'm gonna apply that to my a list.
And there you have it,
negative one, negative two, negative three.
So map, this idea is actually pretty simple.
You put in a function,
remember it's a function name,
you don't actually pass in the parenthesis,
and then you pass in some sequence iterable, like a list.
And then it returns a list
of that function applied to every element in that sequence.
And that's really all there is to map.
And it's super-useful when you use it
in conjunction with lambda.
Alright, so go ahead and read over the other examples
in the Jupyter notebook that we have here
and make sure you understand map
before continuing on
to the other built-in function lectures.
Alright, thanks everyone
and I'll see you at the next lecture.