Hello everyone.
In this lecture, what we're going to do
is I'm just going to go quickly over
the solutions for the Advanced Functions test.
So for problem 1, I used the map
and I mapped the length function
to phrase with the split method applied to it
so I could get a list of all the words,
and then mapping that I just cast it as a list
and returned that.
A little tricky, but it's all on 1 line.
Problem 2, what I did was I used
a lambda expression here
to have X and Y,
and notice I could not convert
the integers to strings.
So what I had to do was take X,
multiply it by 10,
and then add Y
so I could keep moving along
through this digits list.
And then I used reduce
to reduce this lambda expression
on the digits list.
Okay.
Problem 3,
I had to use filter to return the words
from a list of words which
start with the target letter.
So, I made a lambda expression,
Said word, where the first word
if it is equal to that letter filter it out.
On the word list, use that lambda expression.
Again, 1 line.
Problem 4,
I used list comprehension and zip
to zip up the 2 lists,
and then said word 1, plus that connector,
plus word 2, for, the word 1 or word 2
result from that zip.
Problem 5,
I did a little dictionary comprehension here
where I said key value for value key
in enumerate L.
And then problem 6,
finally what I did was said
list comprehension here,
num for count num in enumerate L
if the num is equal to the count,
so that basically means if that number
is equal to the index,
and then return the length of that list,
which returns this count here.
Okay,
so these were all pretty tricky,
especially with the requirement
that they are done on 1 line.
But hopefully you see how powerful
the built-in functions now,
and they can save you a lot of code.
Alright, thanks everyone,
and I'll see you at the next lecture.