Hello everyone, welcome to the second lecture
in the decorator section of this course,
and now we're gonna be talking about
functions within functions.
So we saw previously how we can treat functions in objects.
Remember I assigned a hello function to that greet variable.
Now let's see how we can define functions
inside of other functions.
So we're gonna do this by defining a new function
called def hello,
and again it's gonna take in Jose as a default,
and the first thing it's gonna do
when you call the hello function
it's gonna print
the hello function has been executed.
Okay,
next what's gonna happen is I'm gonna write a function
within another function,
and this function's gonna be called greet.
So what greet is going to do,
and let me zoom out, or zoom, reset here we go,
okay, so
the function greet is within the hello function,
and it's going to return
a string,
so let's have the string say
This is inside the greet function.
And something I wanna do here
just to make it extra clear when we're printing
some of these things, or running them.
I'm gonna put in a tab statement.
Okay.
So continuing on I'm gonna have another function
within this function called welcome,
it doesn't take any arguments,
and what it's gonna do is similarly,
it'll return
with a tab
this is inside the welcome function.
And then outside of everything
I'm gonna say
print
the result of greet
print the result of welcome
and print
now we, woops,
now we are back inside the hello function.
Okay.
So let's just break down what is happening in this function.
So what's happening in this function is
I have hello, the outside function
takes in the name Jose and says print,
The hello function has been executed.
Then I have the greet function,
which just returns This is inside the greet function
then I have the welcome function
which returns this is inside the welcome function.
Those two statements are inside those respective functions.
So when you call hello,
it prints the results of greet,
which is this statement,
it prints the result of welcome, which is this statement,
and then finally it prints
now we're back inside this main Hello function.
So let's go and see what happens when we call Hello.
Great, so it says the hello function has been executed,
and then it says this is inside the greet function,
that's the result of this line,
says this is inside the welcome function,
then it says Now we are back inside the Hello function.
And the reason they're tabbed
is because I'm putting this escape tab character there.
So, let's see what happens if we call welcome.
So note when I call welcome it's not defined,
and that's because due to scope,
the welcome function is not defined
outside the hello function.
So the only function that's aware that welcome exists
is the hello function,
since it's not defined outside of hello,
it's not globally defined so Python doesn't know about it
outside of the hello function.
So, now let's learn about returning functions
from within functions.
So what I'm gonna do now is take
this hello function that we made,
I'm going to get rid of this line,
gonna keep the greets and welcome lines.
But what I'm gonna do now is say
This.
If name is equal to Jose,
that string,
return greet.
And note I'm returning greet, not the result of greet.
So I'm actually returning the function.
If I wanted to return the result I would do this.
But we're returning the actual function.
Then I say else,
return welcome,
again, not returning the results,
returning the function
so we don't have those parentheses there.
All right.
So I have my hello function,
now let's see what happens when we say
x is equal to hello.
So now let's see what happens.
I'm gonna set that,
let's go ahead and delete that,
so something to note is that
because this is a closed parentheses,
that means the name has already been defined as Jose,
since that was the default of hello.
So x already has the name Jose within it.
So if I just call x right now,
I get the function main greet.
So now we can see how x is pointing to the greet function
inside the hello function.
So why is that?
That's because hello had by default the name Jose
and I said, if name is equal to Jose,
return the greet function.
And since the greet function is inside the hello function,
that means right now as far as scope is concerned,
we are aware of it and it will return this function
to this variable.
Which means now x is equal to that function greet.
So now on a global scale I can say print greet,
or print 'scuse me, x
and it will print what's inside of the greet function.
So again, let's take a quick look at this code.
In the if else clause, we are returning greet and welcome.
Not the actual results, we're returning the functions.
And this is because when you put
a pair of parentheses after the function gets executed,
where as if we don't put the parentheses after it,
then it can be passed around
and it can be assigned to other variables
without executing it.
So when we write x equals hello parentheses,
hello gets executed.
So we're actually executing this function
when we assign it to x.
And that's why the name Jose by default
gets placed when you execute hello,
which means this Boolean statement becomes true,
which means we return the greet function
that was inside the hello function,
which allows x to be equal to the main greet function
and then printing x like so with parentheses
means you're actually running the greet function.
Okay, so we've learned how to deal with
functions within functions
and we've also learned how to return functions.
So now in the next video what we're gonna see
is how we can pass function's arguments
into other functions.
And we've seen this already a bit
with functions such as map and reduce and filter,
where we could even pass lambda expressions.
So now we're just gonna go and have an overview
of functions as arguments.
Okay, I'll stop this video here,
and I will see you at the next video
where we talk about functions as arguments.
Thanks and I'll see you there.