Hello, everyone.
And welcome to the third lecture
in the decorator section of this course.
And now we're gonna learn about
passing functions as arguments.
So, in the last lecture we learned
about functions within functions
and how we could return functions.
And now we're gonna learn about functions as arguments.
So, we'll see how we can pass
functions into other functions.
So, again, continue on with the hello.
Gonna reassign the hello function.
I'm gonna just say return to string
Hi Jose!
So, that's my hello function.
Then, I'm gonna make an other function
that takes on the argument F-U-N-C.
And it's gonna print
Other code goes here!
And then what it'll do,
it's gonna print the results
of func.
So, it's expecting func to be a function.
And so now, if I call other,
you'll notice we get an error
'cause it's expecting an argument.
So, I'm actually going to pass
the hello function.
And so, what happens here?
Well, other function takes in a function,
it prints Other code goes here,
which is one of the outputs.
And then it prints the results
of whatever that function happened to be.
Which, in this case, was hello.
Which returns, Hi Jose!
Great, so we've seen how we can pass the function
as objects and then use them within other functions.
So, now we can get started
with manually creating our first decorator.
So, in the previous example,
we kind of actually manually created a decorator.
So, we're gonna modify it to make it very clear
what's actually happening here.
So, I'm gonna say def.
And I'm gonna call this function new decorator.
And it takes in a function as an argument.
And now, there's a function here within it,
called wrap F-U-N-C,
takes no arguments and it prints,
let's just say Code here,
before
executing
the func.
And then I'm gonna call the function
that you pass to this new decorator function.
Then I'm gonna print,
say Code here
will
execute
after the func.
And then what I actually do
is I return this wrap underscore func.
And notice, I'm returning the function itself.
Not the result of the function.
So, that's one function.
And I'm gonna create a new function called func
needs
decorator.
And all this does is it says print
This function
needs a
decorator.
Okay, so, what happens if I call func needs a decorator?
It prints, simply, that statement.
Okay, simple enough.
This is where we actually see how a decorator works.
I'm going to say func
need decorator.
I'm setting that function equal
to
the new decorator function
with the func needs decorator passed within it.
Okay, so let's kinda break down what we just did here.
I have this func needs a decorator function.
All it used to do was print
this function needs a decorator.
So, what I ended up doing was I took this new decorator,
right here, that function,
which accepts a function as an argument.
And I passed it, the func needs decorator.
So, noticed how it's gonna get used
within this block of code.
So, if I call
func needs decorator now,
and run it, notice what I get.
I get Code here, before executing the func.
This function needs a decorator,
which was the original func needs a decorator,
and then I said, code here will execute after the func.
And looks like I spelled execute wrong.
My apologies.
So, if I run these cells,
code here will execute after the func.
So, what happened here?
So, the decorator, just simply,
wrapped the function and modified its behaviour.
So, this decorator wrapped this function
to modify its behaviour.
So, this is exactly what a decorator is.
And now I'm gonna show you
how you can rewrite this code using the at symbol.
Which is a symbol that Python recognises
as a decorator symbol.
So, I'm gonna do at new underscore decorator.
And I'm gonna copy and paste
this original function needs a decorator.
So, notice what's gonna happen now if I say func
needs decorator and I call it.
We get the exact same code,
as if had done this.
Okay.
So, we've just built out a decorator manually here.
And then we saw how we can use the at symbol
to do this automatically in Python.
Again, I'm gonna just slowly break down
exactly what happened here.
Notice all this statement is doing,
this decorator, is exactly what we did here.
It takes in this function
that we called needs a decorator.
And by decorating it with this function,
we pass it into that new decorator function
and reassign it to this function here.
Which allows us to basically do exactly
what we did here but with this at symbol.
So, I really want you to take your time
and read what's going on here.
We created a function called new decorator.
It takes in a function.
It has a function inside of it, called wrap func,
which says print some Code here,
before executing that past function.
Does the function that you passed,
prints Code here will execute after the func
and then returns the wrap func.
Then we created a very simple function,
called func needs a decorator.
All it did was print This function needs a decorator.
Originally when we called it with no decoration,
it just printed that statement.
But we passed it into that new decorator function,
and resigned it to its original name.
So, then when we called it,
you got the Code here,
before executing the function happening.
This, because remember,
we're returning the wrap func.
So, you get basically everything
that's going on the wrap func with the function included.
So, we got code here,
This function needs a decorator,
which is this statement.
And then, code executes here after the func is called.
Now you could've done
this line right here that I'm highlighting,
with this at new decorator symbol.
And you'll realise it's the exact same thing.
So, when are you gonna use this kind of behaviour?
This is really common when you're working
with web frameworks, such as Django and Flask.
Which, you'll run into decorators
a lot with web development.
And you can even go through just
the very beginning of the official Flask tutorial,
and you'll notice that a decorator will be placed there.
A lot of times, that's what prevents beginners
from working with web frameworks,
when they're just learning Python.
Because this sort of notation,
doesn't make any sense to them.
But I hope now, that when you see
how we manually built out
that decorator notation and that reassignment,
you'll feel that it's actually a lot easier
just to call the new decorator,
like this, with the at symbol.
Okay, so that's it for decorators.
And go ahead and check out the Jupyter notebook,
if you're having any trouble.
So, let's go ahead and open it here
and zoom out of it.
I want you to know that this entire Jupyter notebook
takes you step by step,
through decorators, functions review,
the scope review,
then it takes you through
the functions within functions,
returning functions, functions as assignments,
and then creating a decorator,
and using this decorator notation.
So, I encourage you, even if you
went through all the videos,
take your time and really read through
this decorator Jupyter notebook.
Okay, so that's it for decorators.
As for as uses, you probably won't see them
within your own code unless you're doing
some more advanced function passing
or you're interested in web frameworks.
But I hope this entire breakdown,
really helps cement the topic for you.
Okay, thanks, everyone.
And I'll see you at the next lecture.