Hello everyone and welcome to the live code
first lecture in the iterators and generators
section of this course.
So we already gotten a brief introduction
of just the general concept of generators.
Now let's actually make some generator functions
to see how they work.
So what I'm gonna do is create a generator function
and it's gonna look very similar to a normal function.
With one key difference being the yield keyword.
So I'm gonna call it gencubes.
And it's gonna take an argument, n.
And then for num in range n.
So n's gonna be a number.
I'm going to yield, not return,
that num to the power of three.
And then I'm gonna say for x
in gencubes.
Let's say 10.
Go ahead and print x.
So if you notice what's going on here.
Since we have a generator function
we don't actually have to keep track
of every single cubed number that we created.
So as I mentioned, generators are best
for calculating large sets of results.
So if I ended up putting some ginormous number here.
Yes, they would all print.
Which would be a little bit messy.
But if I just wanted to do something
with that number and not actually print it out.
That'd be a lot better than if I had a list return here.
So the way this would look if it was a normal function.
I would have some sort of list out.
And then be, say, out.append
that number.
But you can imagine
if I were to, at the end,
return out and then say for x in gencubes of 10.
Let's go ahead and run this.
You'll notice it's the exact same thing.
But Python's actually keeping out here in memory.
So if this is a humongous number
you're gonna run into errors.
Or just general problems with your code slowing down.
To show you a better example of this
I'm going to create an example generator
that calculates Fibonacci numbers.
So in case you're not familiar with Fibonacci numbers
you can go ahead and go to the Jupyter notebook
and click this link here.
If you want go ahead and pause the video
so you can see what Fibonacci's numbers are.
But basically you can think of it as just
an integer sequence where the last two numbers
are getting summed together for the next one.
So if you can zoom in here.
Check out this first integer.
And in modern uses they usually start at zero.
But what you're doing here is saying
one plus one equals two, one plus two equals three,
two plus three equals five, et cetera.
So on and so on.
So there's a lot of interesting patterns
that you can check out on this page
but that's all you need to know
as far as this lecture video's concerned.
So going back to the lecture for the live code.
Let's go ahead and make a generator called genfibon.
It's gonna take a number, n.
And it's gonna generate a Fibonacci sequence up to n.
So I'll make a equal one. And b equal one.
So we'll go with that more classic starting point.
Or where it starts one, one.
So that first line of that Wikipedia page.
And then I'm gonna say for i
in range n
yield a.
And then after you yield it I'm gonna say
a is now equal to b.
And then b is now equal to the sum of those two.
A plus b.
So now I can say for num
in genfibon 10
print num.
And you'll notice here we start printing.
And you'll notice this sequence of numbers
is actually incorrect.
This is not a Fibonacci sequence.
And I hope you spotted the error.
The reason I showed this is because
this is a common interview question mistake.
But what's going on here is
we need to actually assign a temporary variable.
Since we're reassigning a to b here.
This is actually a statement of just saying
b plus b equals b.
So what we can do, there's actually two ways to do this.
I'll show you the more general way first.
So I would say
a temporary variable
t is equal to a.
Then set a equal to b.
And here I can have b equal to t plus b.
And if I run that now we have the Fibonacci sequence.
Another way to do this is using tuple unpacking.
And that will actually reduce this to one line
where you can do the assignments at the same time.
And that will look like this.
A b equals b.
A plus b.
And you'll notice that's the same result.
Just something to keep in mind.
And we go over this tuple unpacking later on
in the advanced tuple section of this course.
Okay.
Just wanted to mention that since
that's a common interview question.
And it's also a common interview mistake.
As you're learning about generators.
Okay.
So moving along.
We've created this Fibonacci sequence.
So what would this look like
if we wanted to create a normal function?
Well it would look something like this.
I would have
def fibon
n.
Let's go ahead and start it at one again.
So a equals one. B equals one.
Again we can actually use tuple unpacking
to do that assignment.
A comma b equals one comma one.
But we won't do that for now.
We have to assign an output list and then say for
i in range n
output.append a.
And then do the assignment here.
A b equals b.
A plus b.
And then at the end we return output.
And then if I call fibon 10.
I get the Fibonacci list sequence out.
Okay.
So notice again if we call some very large value of n.
You know if I were to pass in a lot of zeroes here.
We would have to hold that entire list in memory.
And we'd have to keep track of every single result.
But for the generators we only keep track
of the current number in that sequence.
So we don't keep track of every single result.
Okay.
So the key to fully understanding generators
is the next function and the iter function.
And this will really help you cement
what's actually going on.
So the next function,
and it literally looks like this, just next.
Allows us to access the next element in a sequence.
So I'll show you through some simple examples.
I wanna create a function.
Or, excuse me, a generator function, simple_gen.
It's not gonna take in any arguments and it's gonna say,
for x in range three
yield x.
Okay.
Now what I'm gonna do,
since everything in Python is an object,
I'm actually going to assign simple_gen
to the label g.
Simple_gen. Close it off.
And then say print,
and this is where the next function comes in.
I'm gonna say print next g.
First one's gonna be zero.
If I do this again. Print next g.
We'll get a one. If I do this again.
Notice I'm gonna keep going up and up.
So now I'm gonna copy this.
Control copy.
And I'm gonna keep going
until we get an error.
Here we go, stop iteration.
So after yielding all the values.
So notice all the values was up to three here.
So that was zero, one, two.
So up to three.
We have a stop iteration error.
So what this error informs us of
is that all the values have been yielded.
So you might be wondering:
Why don't we get this error when we're using a for loop?
And that's because the for loop automatically catches
this error and then stops calling next.
So let's go ahead and check out
how to use the iter function.
Which is I-T-E-R.
So you remember that strings are iterables.
So, for example, I could say
s equals the string 'hello'
for L-E-T in s
prints ets.
Print let, excuse me.
So I'm gonna print every letter in that string.
So, we can iterate though a string
since they're iterables.
But that doesn't mean the string itself is an iterator.
What we can do is check this with the next function.
So, for instance, if I wanted to say,
okay, give me the next one of s.
It'll say string object is not an iterator.
So it's an iterable.
Which means we can iterate through it.
But it's not an iterator itself.
It's not returning stuff like a function.
Alright, so, that's where the iter function
actually comes into play.
So the string object supports iteration
but we cannot directly iterate over it
as we could with a generator function.
Unless we use the iter function.
So I can say s underscore iter is equal to
iter s.
Shift-enter.
And then we can call next on it.
And you'll notice we don't get an error.
This will actually keep calling everything
until we've yielded
all the values.
And then we have a stop iteration error.
Alright, so now you know how to convert objects
that are iterables into iterators themselves.
Okay, I know that was a lot and some of it
may have been a little complicated,
but the main takeaway from this lecture
is that using the yield keyword--
A function that'll cause the function
to become an actual generator.
And this change can save you
a lot of memory for large use cases.
So for more information on generators I actually want you,
and this is a bit of a homework assignment for you,
go to the Jupyter notebook.
Scroll all the way down.
And click these two links.
A stack overflow answer and another stack overflow answer.
And they're basically explanations
on understanding generators.
So if we look at these two links
I want you to go ahead and read here.
Now note, this post assumes 3.x syntax
but it's okay you should still be able to understand it.
And it goes through some of the similar explanations
of I did of next and the iter function.
So I want you to go ahead
and read this stack overflow answer.
I know it's a lot but it's definitely worth it.
And he also points out some 2.x changes.
So that's your first assignment
is read that stack overflow answer.
And then I also want you to read this
separate breakdown on the yield keyword.
So there's another great breakdown
of iterables versus generators here.
And the yield statement.
Okay, so your assignment is to,
after you're done reading that Jupyter notebook,
read these two stack overflow questions
and that should complete your understanding
of generators and the yield statement.
Okay.
So, thanks for listening on to this lecture everyone.
And I will see you at the next section.
Thanks everyone.