Hello everyone.
In this lecture, we're gonna go over quickly
the iterators and generators homework assignment.
So the first problem, I want you to create a generator
that generates the squares of numbers up to some number N.
So fill this generator equation here,
or this function, excuse me,
and pass, remember it should use some sort of
yield statement.
So if I use it, for example, I can say for x in gensquares,
print x.
Okay, problem two, I want you to create a generator
that yields n random numbers between a low
and a high number that are inputs.
So I made a note that use the random library.
You can do that by this line right here,
import random,
and then you can use random.randint with two numbers,
a low and a high,
and it'll output a random number between
the low and the high.
So that's what I want you to use in this function.
And I want you to use it to yield, or generate,
those numbers,
and then you can use it to make sure your code runs
similar to this.
Obviously, these numbers won't be exactly the same
because you're randomly generating them.
Problem three, I want you to use the iter function
to convert the string below into an iterator.
Problem four, I want you to explain a use case
for a generator using a yield statement
where you wouldn't want to use a normal function
with a return statement.
Then extra credit, what I want you to do is explain
what gencomp is doing here.
So we haven't actually covered this yet,
but you may have to do some Googling on stack overflowing
to understand what this line is actually doing.
A quick hint, maybe you should Google what a
generator comprehension is.
Okay, that's it for the iterations and generations,
or excuse me, iterators and generators home assignment.
Best of luck,
and I'll see you in the next lecture.