Hello everyone,
and welcome to the Regular Expressions lecture.
Regular expressions are text matching patterns,
and they're described with some sort of formal syntax.
So you'll often hear regular expressions
used for finding repetition,
for matching text, et cetera.
And as you advance in Python,
you'll see that a lot of your parsing problems
can actually be solved with regular expressions,
and they're also a common interview question.
So, if you're actually familiar with Perl,
you'll notice that the syntax for regular expressions
are really similar in Python.
The module we're gonna be using
is the regular expressions operations module,
which is just RE in Python.
Here I have open the documentation page for it.
You can see it's pretty extensive
and there's a tonne of stuff you can do
with regular expressions in Python.
We're just going to be going over
the most useful functions it has.
But again, I encourage you to check out the entire
Jupyter Notebook that's associated with this lecture.
But let's go ahead and get started
with some live code so we can see how it works.
So, let's say I want to search for some patterns in text,
which is one of the most common uses
for a regular expression.
The first thing you're gonna do is
import the regular expression module.
Next, I'm gonna make a list of patterns,
and these are just gonna be two strings: term1
and term2.
Then I'm gonna make a large text string,
and it's gonna say:
This is a string with term1,
but not
the other term.
So notice it has term1 but not term2.
So how do you actually use
the regular expression module?
So one of the features you can use is search.
So you can use the search method,
and we can search for a particular pattern,
so in this case I could search for,
just to show you an example,
hello,
and in the next argument you pass
the text you want to search.
So I can say,
hello
world.
I need to close off the parentheses,
and notice how you get a match object.
That's something I want you to keep in mind
as we go throughout the larger example.
So you're gonna get a match object
and it's actually more than just a bullion.
So what I'm going to do now is hop over
to the Jupyter Notebook and copy
some code right here.
And then I'll break down the code.
You can go ahead and feel free to copy this code as well,
just to save you some typing time.
But what this code is going to do,
it's gonna say, for pattern in patterns,
so for every term in this pattern's list,
it's gonna print, searching for
the pattern in that text.
Then, if search pattern text,
so if that match object exists,
then it's gonna print, Match was found.
Else, which means no match was found,
it's gonna print that.
So if you go ahead and run this,
you'll notice it was able to say
Searching for term1 in this string,
Match was found.
Searching for term2, No match was found.
Okay, so
we've seen that the search method will take a pattern,
scan the text, and then return that match object.
If no pattern is found, a none is returned.
So I can go ahead and check that out.
I can say, re.search
put in an h here, and then give it a w,
so there's no match,
and we can go ahead and print whatever that is.
You'll notice it's None.
So a None is returned if there is no match.
Now, let's go ahead and take a closer look
at this match object.
And what I'm gonna do now is just say,
this match equals
search of, let's say,
let's just say patterns,
the first term and then the text string.
And now let's check the type of that object,
match, and you notice we get this match object.
So it's actually a lot more, like I said,
than just the bullion.
It also contains information about the match,
including the original input string,
the regular expression that was used,
and the location of the match.
So we can actually call methods on this match object.
So for instance,
I can say match.start
and it will actually tell me the index
of the start of the match.
So at index 22, the pattern started to match with the text.
It can also show me the end,
so I can say match.end
and likewise, it shows me index there as well.
Alright, so that's just something to keep in mind
as far as the match object that the
regular expression module returns.
There's a lot of methods,
and I encourage you to go ahead and explore them,
if you find yourself needing to.
So you can see there's a tonne of methods
here that you can use.
Go ahead and explore those here
or within the documentation.
Alright, moving along now we're gonna see
how we can split with regular expressions.
This is gonna be one of the most
useful features of regular expressions.
So it should look really familiar to you,
given the split methods we've already seen on strings.
And let's go ahead and see what it looks like,
just purely in the regular expressions module.
So I'm going to say split_term,
which is going to be, let's say, @.
And now, I'm going to put a phrase in.
So I'm going to say,
What is your email, is it
hello@gmail.com?
Alright, so let's say you wanted to split
at this split term, @.
So you can use the split method,
and say,
split term, give it the phrase,
and it will return a list
with the split,
not with the split term included.
So this should look really familiar,
given what you already know about splits
in a string.
So if I say,
hello world, and I called the split method
that string has built in, it's really similar.
So, the split returns a list
with the term to split on removed,
and the terms in the list
are a split up version of that string.
So make sure you can understand this example fully,
so go ahead and create a couple more examples
in case you're unsure of what's actually going on.
The reason I choose the @ symbol here,
is that's sometimes an interview question,
as far as, how would you split
domain names from an email address.
The answer's pretty much always regular expressions,
as far as one of the most efficient ways to do that.
Now what we're gonna do is move on
and talk about finding all instances of a pattern.
And with that you can use the find all method.
So I can say,
findall,
and what it's going to do is
return a list of all the matches.
So, for instance, the first thing you put is
the pattern you want to match,
so let's say I want to match
the actual word match.
Then I'm gonna put a string that says
Here is
one match,
here is another
match.
So right now there's two matches in that string.
So it'll return both instances of that.
So findall will find all the instances of your match.
So what might be interesting is then you can
count the length of this and it will tell you
how many matches there are in that string.
Okay, so the bulk of this lecture's going to be on
using the RE module syntax of Python.
And what I mean by that is,
the regular expressions, it's gonna support
a huge variety of patterns that just simplify
finding where a single string occurred.
And we're gonna do something called using metacharacters.
So let me go ahead and show you what I mean by that.
Let's go ahead and jump back to the Jupyter Notebook,
'cause it's a little more clear there
with some markdown text.
Let's scroll down,
here we go.
So finding patterns in this syntax,
what does this actually look like?
So, before we begin,
as far as going through a different syntax,
I created this function here,
and it's called multi re find,
and it takes in patterns and then a phrase.
So it takes in a list of these regular expression patterns
and prints a list of all matches.
So it goes, for pattern in patterns
print Searching the phrase using re check
pattern
then it says findall.
Okay, so I'm going to go ahead and copy this function.
You can go ahead and copy it as well,
and paste it here,
and what we're going to be doing now
is going through different syntax.
And this is actually best explained
though this Ipython Notebook.
So, there's repetition syntax.
That's the first syntax that we're gonna be covering.
So what I have here is repetition syntax
and there's gonna be five
main repetition syntaxes we can use.
And they look a little something like this,
you have a star, a plus,
a question mark, curly brackets with one number,
curly brackets with two numbers.
So let me break these down on how they actually work.
And what I encourage you to do
to get the most out of this lecture,
is just take your time and read the Jupyter Notebook,
take the code like this, copy,
and after reading the explanations and markdown,
go to your own live Jupyter Notebook,
run it, and then check the results,
and make sure they make sense to you.
So let's go ahead and start with the repetition syntax.
So if you use a star, or an asterisk,
then what this basically means is
take an s,
followed by
zero or more d's,
which means basically take anywhere that starts with an s.
So if we look at our test phrase,
this particular pattern returned anywhere
that started with an s.
Then what the plus sign does, it says
s followed by one or more d's.
And I know this general syntax looks strange,
but that's the way regular expression in Python work.
So here we can see anywhere where there was an s
followed by one or more d's.
So we don't get all these single s's.
Next output for repetition,
or syntax repetition is a question mark,
and that will be s followed by
zero or one d's.
So if we look at this, here's basically output
of zero or one d's,
no more than that.
So if you have these twos or threes,
those don't show up in the question mark syntax.
After that there's curly brackets,
which will just
allow you to specify how many repetitions you want.
So this says s
followed by three d's,
and this says s followed by
two or three d's, and you can continue on
as you go throughout your code.
Okay, so go ahead and read over the
general explanations for each of those,
which are just basic explanations of what I just said,
and go ahead and test out the code yourself here.
So I know there's a lot to read here
in the regular expressions,
but the most important thing is
that you just feel comfortable
using this syntax: pattern, phrase.
'Cause you can always look up these exact test patterns
as far as syntax later on in this Jupyter Notebook.
So, we went over the repetition syntax,
so there's five ways to express repetition,
and now what we're going to go over is character sets.
So, character sets are used when you wish to match
any one group of characters at a point in the input.
And we use brackets to construct character set inputs.
So for example, this input
for ab, searches for occurrences of either a or b.
Which is a little weird,
'cause you might see brackets and think,
oh, that's a list, where's the comma?
But in this case regular expressions
there's no comma there.
So here, you pass a string as a pattern with brackets,
and it says, either s or d,
look for either of those two patterns.
So basically, everything where
there's an s or a d gets returned.
And now, I can add something like this,
I can say s
followed by one or more of s or d's.
So notice I'm adding now repetition syntax to this here.
And you can see the results here.
So it's s followed by one or more s or d's.
So it kind of makes sense that
the first sd returns every instance,
'cause it's just looking for s or d,
and the second bit will just return anything
starting with an s in this particular case,
since our input test phrase looks like this.
Alright,
so moving along let's look at exclusion.
So we can use this caret to exclude terms
by incorporating it into the bracket syntax notation.
So, for example, bracket, caret,
and then whatever terms you want
will match any single character not in the brackets.
So let's go ahead and look at some examples.
So I have this test phrase that says,
This is a string, but it has punctuation.
How can we remove it?
So, I have a caret here and then a bunch of punctuation:
an exclamation point, a period, a question mark.
I'm gonna zoom in so you can see that.
So here, what I'm doing is,
passing this caret
and then it's gonna have exclamation, period,
question mark, space, and then a plus sign.
So remember, we add that plus
to check that the match appears at least once,
which basically translates into finding
all the words in that string, right?
'Cause I'm saying return everything
where this caret allows us to exclude those terms,
which is just all the punctuation terms.
So this is the kind of regular expression you can use
to remove punctuation from a string.
And note we get a list here that says,
This is a string but it has punctuation,
how can we remove it.
Now there's no punctuation there.
Alright, we'll move along now to character ranges.
So as character sets grow larger,
typing every character that should,
or should not, match can become really tedious.
So what you can do is a dash expression.
And I'll show you what I mean.
So here are some test patterns we're gonna check out.
So, let me zoom out so you can see 'em all.
Here we have sequences of lower case letters,
so we say a through z.
Here we have sequences of upper case letters,
capital A through capital Z.
Here we can have sequences of lower or upper case letters,
so a through z, capital A through Z.
And then we have, again,
one upper case letter followed by one lower case letter.
Alright, so go ahead and then check this code out.
You can go ahead and copy this,
and then paste it into your Jupyter Notebook,
and check the results to see if they make sense to you.
Alright, so for instance, looking at this
this will return anywhere where a capital letter
is followed by a lower case letter,
and these are the two results where that happens,
This and Lets.
Alright, so that was character ranges,
which is basically just that dash notation,
and then escape codes.
So we've probably seen a few of these,
but something to keep in mind is
you can use special escape codes to find specific
patterns in your data.
So just digits, non-digits,
whitespace, and more.
So, for example I've listed all these codes here
and their meaning.
So for instance, if you say findall
and you put in this code, slash d,
it'll think of it as a digit.
Slash capital D is non-digit.
Lower case s is whitespace,
capital S is non-whitespace.
And then lower case w is alphanumeric.
Capital W is non-alphanumeric.
So something to keep in mind in strings,
there already are escape codes built into strings.
So for instance, if I say
print
hello backslash n
new line,
remember this backslash n is already an escape code
telling Python, hey, this isn't an n,
I want you to print this on a new line.
So this is where sometimes
regular expressions get hard to read.
What regular expressions do,
so that Python doesn't get confused that there's
an escape character already in there,
is it adds this r beforehand,
and then some single quotes.
So if we took it this example,
copy it, and take it over to the Jupyter Notebook,
we can look for each of the test patterns.
So this first one,
slash d plus,
sequence of digits.
So this will return any sequence of digits.
The next one is gonna return any sequence of non-digits,
this capital D plus.
After that we can get sequence of whitespace,
non-whitespace.
So here's all the whitespace,
here's all the non whitespace.
And then alphanumeric and non-alphanumeric characters.
So alphanumeric and then the non-alphanumeric.
Alright, hopping back to the Jupyter Notebook.
So you should have at least a solid understanding
after completely reading this Jupyter Notebook.
So I don't expect you to learn everything
just from this quick overview video,
but you should at least have a solid understanding
of the general form.
So you have a pattern,
and then the text you want to search.
So if we look back to the Jupyter Notebook,
it always goes like this.
You have,
either the term, the split term,
and then the phrase,
or the pattern and the phrase or text.
So it always looks like that,
the pattern that your looking for and then the text.
And then where regular expressions really shine
are all these, basically special pattern codes,
that will look for a sequence of digits in this case,
or this will look for a sequence
of lower case letters, et cetera.
We can look at exclusions,
character sets, and repetition.
So I know that's a tonne of stuff,
and most people, unless you're using
this regular expressions quite a lot in your work,
don't memorise this.
They will either look at a table
or look at the documentation.
So, like I mentioned before,
go ahead and take a look at the full documentation
in case you ever need to look something up,
and there's also a nice summary of tables
at this source that I linked to here,
Python Regular Expressions,
so you can check that out yourself.
Go ahead and make sure you read through
this Jupyter Notebook
to fully understand regular expressions.
I hope this video helped you out
as far as understanding the general syntax,
where you have a re module, some dot methods,
and then you check for the pattern and then the text,
and then what makes regular expressions
special in Python is that you have
these various notations for syntax
as far as exclusion,
character sets, repetition, et cetera.
And there's a lot more than that
that you can check out in the
regular expression documentation.
Okay, thanks everyone.
That's probably one of the most difficult
lectures as far as the modules go,
so I really encourage you to take your time
and go through the Jupyter Notebook slowly.
Okay, thank you everyone,
and I'll see you at the next lecture.