Hello everyone and welcome
to the Sets and Booleans lecture.
So in this lecture, we're gonna learn
about two more other object types.
One is the data structure sets
and the Boolean object type which is basically
just the true and false display in Python.
This is the Jupyter notebook that corresponds
with this lecture so let's just go ahead
and start coding and go through it.
Okay, so sets can be thought of as
an unordered collection of unique elements.
And that's the important part, the fact that
those elements inside of that set are unique.
So you can construct the sets using
the Sets function notation.
So it's gonna look something like this.
So I'm gonna make a sets and I'm gonna call,
I'm gonna label it with the variable X here.
So now X is a set.
Great.
Right now, it's an empty set.
So how do I add elements to that set?
I use the add method which is gonna
be X or whatever variable you decided
to call your set dot add for add.
And you can add whatever objects you want to it.
I'm gonna say X dot add one and if I check
now what my X is, it's gonna look
and add that one into that set.
So something interesting here.
You notice that the notation is curly brackets.
This actually does not indicate
that it's a dictionary although
you can draw analogies that it's a set almost
like being a dictionary but with only the keys.
'Cause remember in a dictionary you can't have
multiple keys being the exact same thing.
You can only have unique keys.
You kind of think of a set as just
a dictionary but only keys that are unique.
Let's go ahead and add a different element
to our set which is called X.
Let's go ahead and add the number two to it.
Now I checked that I have one and two in my set.
What happens if I try to add the same elements
that's already in there?
So we know one is already in there.
So what happens?
So you realise there's actually no change.
It won't place another one in there
like it would if it was like a list or something
and that's because the sets only
concerned with the unique elements.
You can actually use that set function
to cast something like a list with multiple
repeat elements to get the unique elements.
I'll show you an example of what I mean by that.
So I'm gonna say L is equal to a list
and in this list I'm gonna have a couple ones,
a couple twos, couple threes and then like a four.
So notice how I have repeated items or elements
in that list that have occurred more than once.
If I take that list and cast it,
remember we kind of use casting
as a term back for using floats
in casting numbers as floats.
So if I use sets of L, notice that the set
is gonna grab all those unique values.
So one, two, three, and four are
the unique values in that list.
And that's basically the gist of sets.
Remember sets are only concerned
with the unique elements and you can
create them by calling this empty
set function and you can to them
with this dot add method.
Sets are gonna be a super useful tool
and we'll come back to them later on
throughout the course as a really unique
tool because of this feature that they are only
concerned with unique elements.
Alright.
Let's go ahead and move along to Booleans.
Python comes with Booleans which are basically
predefined true and false displays.
Almost like integers one and zero.
It also has a placeholder object
called none and let's go ahead
and walk-through a couple examples of this.
So I'm gonna say A is equal to true.
Run that cell and now if I show A it shows out true.
And we can also use comparison operators to create Booleans.
We haven't gone over specific comparison operators.
We'll go over them.
There's an entire section in this course for them.
But I'm just gonna show you a quick example
so I can ask is one greater than two
and the output will be a Boolean which is false
since one is not greater than two.
And we'll go over all these different symbols
and what they mean later on in the course.
Let's go ahead and switch this.
Let's say is 11 greater than two.
Then the output of the Boolean is true.
Okay.
So we can also use none as a placeholder
for an object that we don't want to reassign yet.
And what I mean by none is the actual
word None with a capital N there.
And now B is gonna be a placeholder
and you notice nothing popped out when I set
that cell to run since it's literally none.
And then I can reassign it to maybe a string.
And now B is equal to A or the string of A.
Okay.
So that's it.
It's just a super basic understanding of Sets and Booleans.
We'll touch upon them later on throughout the course.
So just a quick review.
We hop over back to this Jupyter notebook.
Sets are an unordered collection of unique elements.
You construct them using this Set function
and you can add to them with this add method.
Remember they have curly brackets
but that doesn't mean they're a dictionary.
Although you can draw analogies as
a set being a dictionary with only keys.
Remember you can also use Set to cast
another data structure such as a list
to only get the unique values out of it.
We went over Booleans which are basically
just true and false and we went
over none used as a placeholder.
Okay, so we'll learn way more and see Booleans
a lot more when it comes to comparison
operations later on in the course.
We'll also go over them throughout the course.
They're gonna be super useful to have logic within our code.
Okay, so that's about it and I'll
see you at the next lecture.
Thanks.