Hello, everyone,
and welcome to the lecture on tuples.
So, sometimes, some people call 'em tuples,
some people call 'em tuples.
I'll be referring to them as tuples
throughout the rest of the course.
So, in Python, these tuples are very similar
to lists, except, they are immutable,
so that means they can't be changed.
So, right now, I have open the Jupyter Notebook.
And, in this lecture, we're gonna be going over
constructing tuples, some basic tuple methods,
their immutability, and we'll drive that point home,
and then, a quick side talk on when to use tuples.
All right, so this will probably be
a pretty brief lecture, since a lot
of the syntax will feel pretty familiar.
So, how do you construct a tuple?
So, if you remember, you can construct
a list using square brackets.
So here I have a list of one, two, three.
With a tuple, it's almost the same,
except you're gonna use parentheses and commas.
And so, now, t is a tuple there.
So, just like a string or a list,
you can use the L-E-N, the length function,
to check its length, and so that will give you
how many elements are in that tuple.
And then, tuples, just like a list,
can also mix object types.
So I can put in a string along with an integer
into my tuple, and there's no problems there.
And let's go ahead and show that tuple.
All right.
So, again, a tuple is a sequence, just like a list,
and we can index it just as we've seen before.
And so, t of zero, that brings out that string,
and if I wanna access that two, it's in the one index.
And it also supports slicing, so let's say I,
whoops, let's say I wanted to grab the last one.
I could use a negative one.
So, indexing, all that syntax is the same
as it was for strings and lists.
Now, there's a few basic tuple methods
that I wanna introduce to you guys.
So, remember, for a method, you take your variable name,
put a dot or a decimal point, and then,
you write the method name and if it takes any arguments,
you usually have parentheses there.
So, in this case, index will,
you can enter a value that you know is in the tuple,
and it's gonna return the index.
So, if we look at my current tuple, that t,
it has a one string and a two integer there.
So let's say I wanted to figure out
what the index of that item was.
I could put it in.
So, to show you again, let's say
I wanted to know the index of two there.
It responds with one as the index.
So that makes sense.
Another method we can use is the dot count.
So, that will count the number of times the value appears.
So, you put in the element that you know
is in the tuple, and it tells you
how many times it appears in that tuple.
So, for instance, if I make a tuple right now,
that's one, one, two, three.
So I know one appears twice, so if I say t.count,
and I wanna count how many times one shows up,
it responds with two.
Okay, great.
So, something that we're really gonna stress with tuples,
and the thing that really makes tuples unique,
is that they're immutable.
So, that means you cannot change the items inside the tuple.
You can't reassign the items inside a tuple.
So, to show you what I mean, remember
we have our list, l, which is two, two, three.
I'm gonna change it to one, two, three.
Okay, so, we have a list that's equal to one, two, three.
Don't worry about this change to two, two, three.
That occurred because I paused the video
and was playing around with it.
Anyways, so, right now I have a list
that's equal to one, two, three.
And let's go ahead and make our tuple t
equal to a tuple that's one, two, three.
So, if you remember, the list, since it's mutable,
it will support object, or item, assignment.
So I can say l of zero is now equal to,
let's say, a string called s.
And now, there's no problems there.
It's been reassigned.
Now, if you try to do the same thing
with a tuple, it's not going to work.
So, here, I have my tuple, which is one, two, three,
and if I were to try to reassign
the zero index there, which is a one,
let's say I try to make that equal
to something else, like that string s.
It's gonna say, a tuple object
does not support item assignment.
So, this is really important to know.
Tuples cannot be mutated, so they're immutable.
So, you might be wondering, so,
why would I bother using tuples
when they have fewer available methods than a list?
So, if we check out this list,
and then check out all the methods on it,
there's append, count, extend, pop, remove, sort.
And we go over those in the advanced list lectures.
But if I look at my tuple, and press tab,
there's actually only two methods, count and index.
So there's fewer supported methods in the tuple.
So you might be wondering, well,
why would I use that instead of using a list?
And the key to that is their immutability.
So, if you're in your programme,
you're passing around an object,
and need to make sure it doesn't get changed,
so you've gotta make sure the sequence doesn't get changed,
the tuple can be your solution for that.
So, an example of that might be,
if you have a tuple representing
the dates of a calendar, which you know
are not gonna change throughout your code,
you might use a tuple in that sort of context.
So, definitely keep tuples in mind
when you want something to be immutable.
Okay.
So, that's it for this quick lecture.
Let's just jump back to the Jupyter Notebook,
so we can review everything.
And we went over how to construct a tuple,
so you just do that with parentheses and commas,
just like a list, except instead of
square brackets, you're using parentheses.
You can check the length with the L-E-N function.
You can also mix object types in a tuple.
And you can use indexing, just like
we did for strings and lists.
There's only two tuple methods, index and count.
And we went over their immutability.
So, you can't support item assignment in a tuple.
All right, so, that's actually it for tuples.
And we'll see you at the next lecture.
Thanks, guys.