Hey everyone.
So this is a section all about preparing for a job in
product management, in order to maximize your
chances at getting a job.
There's one big problem that's also kind of
a benefit about being a product manager.
The problem is that it's pretty hard to get the job
at first because it requires prior experience.
But on the positive side, once you have that sort of
experience or you've done it at least once, you have
a lot of career security, because everyone else
has trouble getting that experience.
So it's really easy to switch jobs,
and get promoted, and that sort of thing.
There's also just a low number of really qualified product
managers out there, and the demand for them
is really increasing lately.
Unlike programming and computer science, there's no
way to major in product management in college and
say that you have prior experience from that.
So how can you best position yourself to get the first associate product manager job, or junior product manager job?
What you really need to do is demonstrate that you understand
the concept and role of a product manager thoroughly.
But just talking about product management
is not enough to get a job.
You need to have the experiences to point to and
discuss with people that are interviewing you.
All right.
So where can we get these experiences? Well, we can
find them in two major places, either in your current
job, or with a side project.
In this lecture, we're going to talk about finding
relevant experience in your current job,
and then we'll talk about a side project. Since what you do as a product manager is so broad and we just do so many things,
I guarantee you that some sort of stuff you're doing at
your current job is related to product management.
In other words, you're probably already
doing it, you just don't know.
Think about all of the stuff we've learned in this course
so far, and then think about the things that you do
in your current job that involve these concepts.
I'll give you some examples here.
So write down any experience that you have with the following.
Number one - think about any time you've had multiple
things to do either by yourself or with a team and
you have to prioritize what you do first.
You made the priority decision based on information,
and that's what we do all the time as PMs.
Number two - think about all the times you've talked to
any users of a product or a tool internally or externally.
If you work in marketing, for example, then talking to
the people you are marketing to, and focus groups,
or that sort of thing is very similar
to talking to the users of a product.
If you work in customer service, then you're definitely
talking to users of a product on a regular basis.
Number three - think about any times you've given feedback
or reported bugs on the product of your company
or even another one.
Number four - if the company you're with now has a
product team, then recall all of the interactions you've
had with them, and how you may have helped them acquire data to make decisions, or gave them feedback on the product.
All right.
Number five - think about any times you have worked on something at your job with multiple other teams or groups of people.
Have you ever worked with the legal team, the engineering
team, sales, marketing, or customer service? If
you've helped teams communicate something between them,
this is very relevant to being a product manager.
The last thing I want you to consider is any work
you've done to improve the efficiency of a process.
Product managers work a lot with different processes,
so any efficiency you have made better at your
job by finding more efficient ways to do things, or
improving the way things are done, from either stuff
you do every day, or stuff you and your teammates do,
is going to be very relevant to talk about.
So after you've written all of these things down, think
very deeply about each one and then detail each
one of them even more.
These experiences can be put on your resume, and then they
can be talked about during product management interviews.
One other thing you can do is email product managers that you
find online and ask if you can ask them a few questions.
Use what you learn from them to inform
your job applications and interviews.
I recommend browsing for product managers in
industries you're interested in, in places like, let's say,
Product Hunt, LinkedIn, and Twitter.
But if you can't think of anything related in your current
job to product management, then doing a side
project is going to be the most helpful.
We're going to talk about that in the next lecture.
All right, I'll see you there.