What's up, everybody?
Everything in life has to start somewhere.
No, I'm not going to lecture you on philosophy or something like that, but when you're a product manager,
products also start somewhere, and that means that features and new functionality, it all comes from someplace,
Everything that you see or use in your life, any product, at one point it was either an idea in someone's
head or it was a need, like a requirement. Someone said,
"Hey, I need this team to build this for me."
And then they built it.
So there's this theory out there that product managers and executives, they all get in a room and they're
the idea people they just sit there and come up with these fantastic ideas, and then the developers and
designers, you know, make it look pretty,
and build it, and then the executives get rich.
Now, that's actually so far from the truth,
I don't even want to go there.
Your job as a product manager is not to be the idea person.
We're going to talk about that a little bit, but it's really just about getting this huge influx of ideas
and requirements from all over the place.
Requirements are other people coming up to you and saying,
"Hey, I need you to build this."
Maybe a sales team or a marketing team,
"Hey, we need this functionality," that sort of thing.
So you have all of this stuff,
and your job is really just to say, of all of these things,
which ones are good ideas, which ones are bad,
why are they good ideas, and when is the best time to do them, given all of the other stuff that's going
on at the time in the company with technology and in the industry.
Anyways, that's what this section is all about.
So get ready to take a dive into the land of ideas, and user needs, and false user needs, and users thinking
they need this thing when they actually need this thing.
Anyways, I'm getting ahead of myself but this is all coming up,
so I will see you in there.