What's up, everyone?
Welcome back.
So, in this section, we're going to get into the real nuts
and bolts of product management and managing
a project day to day as a PM. This lecture is a little
bit longer, but it's extremely important,
so I really recommend you pay attention here.
So, before we start talking about building, we need to
understand that the things companies build come
from an overall vision that's established
by the CEO or founder.
So the question is, how does this vision
turn into things that get built?
Okay, so we know that the CEO, and founder, or executives,
they have this vision that they want to achieve
about where the company is going,
and really what the purpose is in two, three, or five
years. In order to achieve the vision, the company
has to have goals that they want to reach to achieve it,
to get there to that vision. Like vision,
the goals are decided by the executives, but then they're defined further into metrics usually, like "increase
new users by 5% this year."
So, once these goals are established, the management
teams come up with what are called initiatives.
These are things that the whole company is going
to do and build in order to reach those goals.
An example of initiative would be "translate the product into three other languages this year." Underneath initiatives,
we have what are called releases.
Now, don't worry too much about releases right now,
because it's not really the same at every single company.
But really what it is, it's just a grouping of new features or functionality that's released to the users, to the public, on one
particular date or time period.
We can continue our example and say that if we translated
the product into three additional languages,
we might decide that we have one release in February,
where all three languages are available to the public.
That would be our release, but underneath releases,
there are features and functionality that get released.
The product management world calls these epics.
Underneath epics,
there are things called stories and requirements, but
we're going to talk about that part in another lecture.
Let's finish off this lecture by diving deeper
into this concept of what epics are.
First, we must start with a statement of things that
we're building to solve a problem, and clearly show
what features or functionality we intend to build in order to do that.
This is what we call an epic. We learned in previous
lectures about the concepts behind minimum viable
products, customer interviews, and wireframing.
We use these tools to help us make the right decisions
in solving user problems with features, but once
we know what we want to actually build,
how do we actually get it built?
Well, that's what all of this stuff is going to be about,
and that in particular is where epics come in.
An epic is really just product management lingo for a grouping of one or more features or functionalities that we want to build.
It's the fundamental brick that we build with
as a product manager and a product team.
Just so you know, usually a product team will build out 3-5
epics during a quarter, like a quarter of a year.
This depends on the company size and all that,
but, in general, this really just depends on how much
effort the epic's going to take and that sort of thing.
In real life, an epic example would be something like "translate the app to Spanish" or "implement photo sharing indirect
messages" or "allow users to upgrade to a pro membership."
This stuff might sound a lot to you like a feature,
and that's because it is. One of the reasons that
we use the term "epic" instead of "feature" is because
not all things we do as a product team result in
a new feature for an outside user,
so the term reduces confusion.
There are some other reasons as well but
we're not going to really get into it here.
It's something that will become apparent as you continue.
For instance, we could have an epic that is called
"migrate our data to a new database."
This isn't really a feature for end users, like the people
that are using our product, but it's something
that internally our engineers might need to do,
and we might need to do it to make sure we can scale,
or that we can support more users in the future,
So we've still got to do it and it would still be
called an epic. Epics are also defined as a piece of
work that takes longer than one sprint to build.
If there's something smaller that you want to build
and it's going to take less time than one sprint,
then it wouldn't really need its own epic,
it would just need a user story.
Now, don't worry quite yet about user stories, because
we're going to talk about that in another lecture,
but just know that epics are above user stories, they contain features, and functionalities, and user stories inside of them.
So, epics are the fundamental groupings of features
or functionalities that teams build. In the next lecture,
we're going to talk about what they actually look like
in real life and how you might go about making one.