Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
So let's make a feature table.
Now, you remember what those are.
They are a comparison chart,
and on the X axis, the left side, we put the dimensions that we want to compare ourselves to our competitors
on and on the top, the Y, so to speak,
we put the competitors that we want to compare ourselves to.
Now, you can do it like I'm about to do.
I whip out a piece of paper and I draw it out.
It can get messy very quickly but that's the way I prefer to do it.
You guys can do it whatever way you want.
I suggest, if you're not going to use a written version,
use Google Sheets or Excel.
Why?
Because it'll look clean, it's easier to view, and also the cells can stretch as you type out more.
OK. So let's set it up.
All right, so first off, if you're putting your graph on a piece of paper, draw out your graph. If you're using Google
Sheets or Excel, you don't actually have to do anything.
Just make sure that you leave enough space at the top
for, let's say, at least 4-5 competitors.
You can put as many as you want to,
but I'd say, at a minimum,
for now, let's put 4-5, and then on the other side, leave enough room so that you can put a good variety
of dimensions to compare yourself on.
Now, at the top we fill in our competitors. Now, which competitors do we pick, right? Because we have direct,
indirect, substitute, and potential.
I suggest starting with direct competitors.
Why?
Because those are the ones that are going to be the most similar to you.
But the differences between you and your direct competitors
are the most important.
I personally then like to take the indirects, and the substitutes, and the potentials, throw those in a separate
graph which I'll analyze after my direct graph.
Now, in general, direct competitors are the ones that you really want to stay up to date with, watch their
products, see how they change,
see what they add, what they remove, and try to get a general idea of how they're going to react to you when you do something.
Now, the name of the game for your other types of competitors is to make sure that your solution is obviously
better than your substitutes, your indirect competitors, and your potential competitors for your target
customer group. Use that table as a quick reference to make sure that it's obvious you are better.
Now, if you have a situation where it's not obvious you are better than a substitute, you have a serious
problem and you need to go back and start from scratch.
In the restaurant metaphor, that's like your Italian restaurant serving pizza that actually tastes just
as good or worse than DiGiorno pizza.
That's a fundamental issue you have to address.
Now, on the left we're going to put features and factors.
You can really put whatever you want over here.
I suggest you start with these two: features and factors.
Why?
Because they're not very subjective.
They're pretty easy to nail down and be specific about.
Now, what you choose to put in this part of the table
is entirely up to you.
You need to think really hard about what you think your target customer group cares about with regards
to your product. When they go and they're looking at your product,
let's say it's a physical product,
what do you think is going to be the one, two, three, four,
and number five reason that they choose yours over the others.
Now, keep in mind, every product has
a different vision and a different positioning,
so the features and factors that you think are relevant
to your target customer might be different than
what your competitors think are the most important.
Maybe you think ease of use and price is really the key formula to winning your market, while your competitor
might think instead that it's design, aesthetics, and integrations.
The key here is not to put what your competitors think is important,
it's to put what you think is important to your customer group, because at the end of the day, your product
vision is how you plan to win the market - it's your bet.
It's not realistic to think that you're going to beat every single competitor in every single category
especially if you de-prioritize certain aspects over others.
So brainstorm your best.
And honestly, do some research as well to get a good chunk of what you think is important. Now, for any given product,
let's say I might put price as one that's a very common factor.
I might put reliability, that could easily be a common factor in physical products, or, you know, even
softwares that are dependent on things like up time.
And then as a feature I could say it needs to do
feature X and it needs to have the ability to do Y.
Now, this is just a template,
you need to fill these in yourself, but to help you
kind of get through this,
let's imagine again, in that restaurant metaphor, what would I mean when I say "features" or "ability to
do something"? I know it's goofy to think of a restaurant
in terms of features, but it is actually a way
of thinking about it. So I could say that feature, a feature that I think is important and that my product's
going to have is that we offer a price fixed three course meal, and I think that's really important when
people pick a high end Italian restaurant.
Now, for the ability to do something, maybe I think that being able to make reservations online is important.
It's important to their perception of the restaurant, and that's going to get you more customers and a better experience.
Ok, now that you have it set up, go research your competitors,
and the best way of doing that is to actually
go out and use their products. Give each product an honest appraisal, put in the box what you need to know,
but keep it short and uniform. Answer a yes or no question with yes or no and then it's up to you. You
can put a comma and put one or two more words that might be a little bit more specific, but the key, try to make them uniform,
so when you glance at it, you don't have to read every single cell.
All right, so that is the template.
Next lecture,
let's try to make an actual one.
See you then.