Hey guys, welcome back to the course. In this lecture,
we're moving on to the next part of the process of running an MVP.
Ok, so we know what a hypothesis is and we know
how to make one on our own. Great.
We now have our sights set on what exactly
we're setting out to prove.
You may or may not have noticed this,
but did we ever define what exactly
"proof" or define what exactly "success" in this experiment means?
In one hypothesis we said "buy more." So is that it?
If they buy more, we win? And the other said "X metric improves."
There are three different outcomes to an MVP test
you need to be aware of.
One is you find out that your hypothesis is categorically
false and overwhelmingly not worth doing.
Great, you dump it. It's not really a hard call. Two, you find out
that within a wide margin, your hypothesis is true.
No question about it.
And three, you're somewhere in the middle.
Now, here's the rub.
90% of the MVP experiments you're going to run
as a product manager or as an entrepreneur
are going to end up in situation three: somewhere in the middle.
It's going to look like some people like it and some don't.
And the numbers are going to be all over the board,
it's probably going to be a mess.
So, in our pursuit to see if our users "buy more,"
what exactly do we mean? If 2% of our users buy more or, let's say, our users don't even buy more, but they buy twice as frequently,
is that worth it to, say, build something that takes three months
and four people to do it? Well, it depends on the size of
your company, and it depends on an internal calculation
you have to make.
We need to establish a concept called
"minimum criteria for success."
We need to draw a line in the sand to definitively distinguish
between "Worth it, all systems are a go" and "Not worth it."
Now, why is setting a minimum criteria for success important?
Well, because if you forget to set your MCS,
which is what I'm going to start calling it from now
on, your definition of success, you might end up conflating
a validated hypothesis with a clear signal to proceed.
They could be two different things.
You can validate your hypothesis, for example, in a way that wouldn't make it worth it to go out and start building everything.
Now, what if you just barely validate it?
Well you've got to proceed with caution,
my young product manager friend.
Now, the last thing I'll say about why we use the MCS
is that it gives your experiments clarity and
meaning. We aren't just trying to "improve stuff,"
we're trying to "improve stuff by X amount."
So how do we figure out where our line in the sand should be?
Well, creating a minimum criteria for success is
relatively simple, and, like the hypothesis exercise, there
are roughly about a million different ways to do it.
We're going to take into consideration
and outline two sections in this process.
On the left, we're going to put the cost of building your
product, feature, or the cost of making the change
to your prior existing product, and on the right,
the second section, we're going to put the expected reward.
What do you expect to see in return?
Now, the next step is to fill both of these sections with criteria. Whatever criteria you choose,
it should probably be criteria that clearly signals not only success,
but that your idea is a viable option for your company.
Popular ideas that are monetarily unsustainable
are not generally great ideas.
I know, someone needs to tell that to Silicon Valley.
So, starting in reverse order, let's start on the right
with our expected reward section of this calculation.
We're going to pick a metric that we hope will improve as a result of building our product, feature, or making our change.
If we're, for instance, adding additional sharing features
to a social network, then we're probably targeting
engagement, right? Or some other aspect we've
identified as being crucial to our specific business.
So that could be time spent on page,
it could be actions per session,
it could be number of likes, or something
very literal like number of shares.
Every experiment you run as a product manager
is going to be pointed at something.
When we talk later in-depth about metrics, we have an entire section on it, you'll realize that all metrics
in some way or other are interconnected.
And you, as a product manager, you'll have to have
your eye on a couple or a handful that you associate
with product growth or product success. Whatever metric
we put here needs to either be directly or indirectly
related to one of those crucial metrics.
Otherwise, this is an entirely pointless endeavor and
you're trying to inflate what we call "false metrics."
So put down the potential metrics you hope are going to
be moved by your experiment. If you're building
a new product, they will probably be things like percentage
of people signing up, conversion rate, open rate,
if you use e-mail as a distribution channel, percentage
of positive reactions even, things that indicate
interest from a potential customer, or it could be literally
like "How much money does each customer make us?"
We'll talk in one of the next lectures about pre-product
scenarios specifically and how to tweak this
for that type of situation. For now, we're going to focus more on adding features and or trying to improve user behavior.
Okay.
Once you're done writing out on the right side, let's go
to the left side. On the left side, we need to brainstorm
the costs of doing what we're proposing to do.
Every experiment is going to cost something and you need to have a decent understanding of what's at stake.
So let's say you're a company and you're going to add X feature.
What does X feature end up costing your company?
Well, in this hypothetical, it's probably going to take
developer's time, your time, other people's time,
it's probably going to take up some sweet hot cash.
Keep in mind also that time is money even outside of
what you buy or what you contract to get this done,
so we can reasonably assume, no matter what, that
there's always going to be some form of a dollar amount
to building what it is that we're proposing.
Well, let's try to brainstorm of what could we possibly
have to end up buying in order to do this.
Well, we probably need to promote the feature in some way,
and even if we don't pay money necessarily
for ads, there's also displacement of other ad inventory
you could have used, or lost opportunity because
you just took up an e-mail that
you could have spent on something else.
There are other things you need to take into consideration as well,
like opportunity cost, which is a
little abstract, but, yes, it is a thing. If you pursue X and
fail, then you could have pursued Y and succeeded.
You are one successful feature shorter.
There are other things like pride, brand, morale,
but these things are really up to you to self identify
as important to you and your company, and put
them down, because it's not necessarily true
for every single company.
So think about what the effects of running the experiment are going to be. Take into consideration your organizational size as well.
Large organizations, as we previously learned,
are not going to run scrappy experiments.
The calculus for them is just different.
They're probably going to go with something a little mediar
because they have to put their name on it.
So factor that brand aspect and that aspect that they're going to be around after this MVP experiment into your calculation.
Okay, now that we've talked about how there are basically
two sides to every calculation for a minimum
criteria for success, and we've discussed roughly what
are potential metrics you could put in each section,
in the next lecture, we're going to work on coming up with a minimum criteria of success that works for a theoretical position.
See you then.