All right, so we have both sides of the equation outlined,
and we've identified both the things we are trying to affect.
We've also identified the things that it will cost if we actually decide to go
full steam ahead and build out whatever our wildest dreams have in store.
Now, you at home that are bright probably already know that
whatever experiment we run, we need the
potential upside probably to outweigh the cost,
and since we're setting our line in the sand of success in one specific spot,
we need to identify at what point does the benefit outweigh the cost,
and that's how we figure out that line.
So let's just do that.
I suggest starting on the left hand side first,
so we know exactly what we're spending to make this happen.
The left side also is in general easier to calculate,
because it's based off of cold hard facts,
whereas the right side is a little more speculative.
Now, for demonstration purposes, let's say we work
at our favorite big, bloated, blue bird, the Twitter bird.
Let's say, for some reason, we wanted to add a feature
that allowed us to hover over any link that someone shared or tweeted,
and see a pop-up of whatever that link was referencing.
It's clunky, it's unnecessary, but hey, it's Twitter,
it's not like they ever said no to a feature request.
Ok, let's try to figure out a rough cost associated if we pursued this new feature.
Let's start with development time, because there will have to be
people programming this to make it actually happen.
If you work in tech, this is frequently going to be one of the most
relevant things you have to take into consideration.
Now, you don't need to be a developer to calculate this,
but you will have to do a little bit of outside research.
You might have to talk to your developers, and if you're using a contractor,
well, they're generally required to give you this information upfront anyway.
Let's make up some fake details.
Let's say our feature addition, which is massively scaled back in its first iteration,
will take two developers, two weeks to develop.
Ok, so now we've established what the loss of time is going to be.
These developers, let's say they make $100,000 a year,
they probably make more, to be honest, but we'll say $100,000, make it simple.
So that means roughly, rounded down to $8,000 a month,
two weeks inside of a month, $4,000 for each of them.
You're spending $8,000 to try this just in labor cost.
It's also going to take your time and other people's time.
So let's just, for giggles, assume it takes part time effort from you for two weeks as well.
So let's add in another $2,000.
You generally will get paid roughly the same as developers.
That makes the grand total of labor time at $10,000 just to try out our pop-up.
Now, let's say that you're going to buy some ads to announce the launch of this feature,
and also to drag traffic to test it in its first version, so maybe add in an extra $3,000.
That means our total cost could theoretically be $13,000,
that is a finite number that we can now work with.
Fantastic. Now we have a cost baseline, really helpful.
Now, does this number have to be exact?
Well, no, not necessarily, but you should be in a position
to gather the information you need to make a decent estimate.
If you're using too fuzzy of a math, that probably just means that you were lazy.
At the same time, don't try to spend your entire
life trying to calculate this down to the penny,
because if it's worth it, it's going to obviously be worth it,
it's not going to be something where you only make it worth it
by $10 or $5, or some thin margin.
Now that we know the theoretical cost, let's think what else could be built in that time,
and that brings us to the other thing that it's going to cost us: opportunity cost.
Opportunity cost, specifically in this case, is probably small,
because, hey, it's not a huge feature, but that still is time
those developers could have spent fixing bugs, or building something else,
or even time spent collaborating on a newer, much larger feature.
Regardless, we now have a cost baseline, and we've satisfied
the requirements for the left side of our calculation.
From the looks of it, depending on how large your organization is,
this is probably not a huge risk, so we probably have some flexibility on the right side,
when we start talking about what we need in return.
Let's now try to think critically about what metric has to move
what amount to justify the cost we've just established.
Now, big risks need big rewards, and small risks are ok with small rewards,
that's just generally how this works.
So, if we're pulling two guys off the development team, and taking 50% of our time,
plus some ad money, and the fact that we could be building something else,
what's it going to take to make this worth it?
This is generally just up to you and your team.
You will know what's a big deal and what's not.
Now, outside of that internal decision you guys make,
the best way and the best practice for
going about this is to settle on one specific metric.
Two metrics becomes too confusing, and it makes
it hard to really verify success, so just pick one.
Second, try to think past these metrics and what exactly they mean.
If you have an app that makes money off ads, let's say, well, then,
increasing the time the user stays on your site will increase revenue, that's important.
If you're a startup and you increase user growth by 15%,
could that then affect your ability to raise money?
Think through what your organization needs as a whole,
and if you can't think of anything with regards to business requirements,
well, that's a great sign that you're out of touch
and you probably need a refresher on your company's vision.
Let's try some scenarios for the reward side of our calculation.
Maybe we calculate a money effect, a direct effect on revenue.
Let's say we're thinking that the addition of this feature, although limited,
will, in our test group, raise conversion to a paid program,
let's say it's from free program to paid, by some amount.
That's easy, because then we just have to figure out what is more worth it,
$13,000 or that increase which then gives us more money?
Which number is larger?
Or maybe you can say, well, we have a year-long goal of
raising our average minutes consumed by 40%.
To keep us on that 40% path, we need to see an improvement
in at least 4% since that's roughly the equivalent of a month,
and it's going to take us a month worth of time labor-wise to develop this.
Now, I said a month because opportunity cost,
right, it's two weeks working on this feature,
but if it doesn't work out, you could have spent two weeks on a different one,
so it's kind of a double jeopardy situation.
The point is, try to align this to some bigger goal if you can.
Now, guys, be aware, this is napkin math.
When you're a product manager, you're not always going to have
the actual numbers available most times when you do this.
Sometimes you're going to be adding numbers to potatoes,
and then squaring them by smiles, and then dividing them by green.
It can often times be more abstraction than accounting.
At the end of this calculation, you should know what metric you want to improve,
how big of a cost is it going to take, and then, in your head,
make a basic tit for tat statement that says, "If it's going to cost X,
we need to see Y improvement, or Y metrics to justify
giving the thumbs up and going ahead with this."
All right, so you now know how to think about
and put together a minimum criteria for success.
The next lecture, we're going to talk specifically
about pre-product scenarios and startups,
how do you do it if you don't already have internal established metrics.
See you then!