Hey guys, welcome back to the course. So in this lecture we're going to do more feature tables, but we're
going to do it this time from a different angle in a different way.
Now, watching the last few lectures, you probably think that feature tables are only helpful for comparing
large products on everything they do to other products and everything they do, and that's not actually the case.
The other feature tables, they kind of look like postmortems.
They look like, after you've built your product,
you know, what do we need to work on improve or de-prioritize compared to what our other competitors are doing.
And that's really important. As a product manager, you're constantly doing that and you will have a large
product to hold onto, maintain,
and make sure that you're not losing ground.
But how do we use this technique going forward?
Well, let's say we're proposing a feature, proposing a new product. Can we use this as a way to determine
what we should put into our product
or know whether or not it's feasible?
So let's do just that. We're going to use this now for a proposed feature and we'll go back to our other
example, not GoPro, we're going to use Udemy. Now,
you're using Udemy, online marketplace for education,
anybody can create a course, anybody can take one,
and for the most part they're expensive,
but they also discount very cheaply.
Let's say you're a product manager at Udemy, okay?
And we're going to imagine that we're going to add
the feature that we had previously, which is group
discussions. We think this would be interesting for students to interact with the course in a different way,
post discussions, and that way the instructor can post back
or other students can post to it.
Now, what would you think would be important to that feature?
So, answer those at home while I make my feature table.
It's going to take a little bit, because this time I want to make sure that the lines are actually somewhat straight.
Ok, on the left, let's start with some of the aspects that we think would be important in a group discussion
or a lecture discussion feature.
What we're going to do is we're going to fill these out and then we're going to fill out our competitors and then
we're going to see what they have and offer
before deciding what we're going to do.
So, the first thing I'd like to ask is,
can you actually post a discussion for a lecture?
I'm assuming some competitors might not actually have that.
Another aspect I think would be important is time markers.
If I put a group discussion, ask a question, can I tie that
specifically to one specific piece of the lecture,
so it's not just generic,
you don't know what you're referring to. The next one I think is important are probably engagement features.
If I'm posting, it's a good thing to get other students to post,
and what better way to do that than have things like
likes, and shares, and different ways that people can engage and say whether or not they like the content.
The next one I think might be important is location.
It might be important for a group discussion that
everyone knows where it is and it's prominent,
otherwise people might not use it.
And the last one I'm going to put is post images.
Can you post images?
I think that would be interesting and
could make the discussions more enriched,
something I would guess that's probably par for the course
for a group discussion tool.
Ok, and so I'm just going to fill out some of the competitors based off of the list that I made before looking for Udemy.
And they're the usual suspects. Skillshare is probably
the first one that comes to mind.
Then we probably have Coursera, which is quite a bit different,
but still a competitor. Then we have Udacity,
still a little bit different, but still a direct competitor,
and then the last one is Lynda.
If you guys have ever taken a Lynda tutorial course,
those are competitors. Again, the solution is different,
but they go for the same exact people.
And then of course we're going to put ourselves at the very end. That's us.
Ok, so follow along with me, I want to jump into each product and we're going to find the answers. Now, lucky
for you, I've already logged into all of these different web sites, created accounts, and now I'm going to get
blasted by them every single day with their
promotional emails, but I'll take the hit.
Ok, so this is Skillshare. This is what it looks like.
This is their viewer player.
Notice how it's different than Udemy?
Now, let's see. Do they have - this is the question
we're going to answer - a group discussion tool?
Oh, there they go. Yep.
You post group discussions right there.
So the answer to that one is yes.
The second thing I want to put is integrated,
meaning that it's integrated into the actual lecture viewer.
It's on the same page.
Moving on to Coursera. Now, this is what
the Coursera viewer looks like.
So, the question is, can you post a group discussion?
Looks like you can down here.
You can post right here with a new thread
and these are the discussions.
So I'm going to say yes and, again, I'm going to say integrated.
Moving on to Udacity.
Ok, this is what their player looks like.
This is a quite snazzy looking player, to be honest.
Do they have discussions? Yes, they do.
I just click this. It just kicks me out to a page that looks like this.
I can add discussions and it looks like kind of like a forum, ok?
So I'm going to say yes, but then I'm going to say standalone because it's not actually integrated into the player,
you have to hit a button to then get to it in a separate page.
All right, and the last one we're going to look at is Lynda.com
and this is what the Lynda player looks like.
If you guys have used Lynda before, you probably know the answer to this, which is no, they don't have a discussion tool.
I've looked through this quite a bit and it doesn't appear.
They have note taking tools, but nothing where
I can post a question and have it answered
or talk to other students.
Theirs is a little more two dimensional. They're the instructor,
I am the student, and they are not there.
All right, on to the next one. Can we time mark our posts?
So here on Skillshare, yes, you actually can.
It's right here, and you can add a note,
and it will actually time mark where you are,
and it will reference it specifically. So I'm going to say yes and I'm going to put lecture + time, because I can do either one.
I can either reference the lecture or have this note reference
the actual second that I made the question.
Moving on back over to Coursera.
Let's look at some of the discussions, and I can tell
pretty easily that no, these are not even attached
at all to a lecture or a time, so we're going to say no.
Udacity, let's look at their discussions. Ah, again, it's
a standalone, so we go over here.
Let's see... the Linux command line basics.
Can we tell whether or not they're attached to anything?
If you can't tell very quickly, chances are it's not. Ok.
I don't see anything that says what lecture they're talking about.
I'm not even totally sure what course they're talking about,
I guess it's that one. So that's a no.
Lynda, we don't have to fill out, obviously, because they don't have discussions, so we're just going to toss it out.
All right, so let's take a tour of the engagement features. Ok.
Over here on Skillshare, it looks like I can like and I can reply.
So, relatively simple.
Doesn't look like we have anything more than that
like mentions, or linking, or threading, or anything like that.
Pretty simple, but they do have engagement features,
so I'm going to say they have the like and the reply.
On to Coursera. Let's see what they have.
Well, they actually have a bit more. They have upvoting.
That's actually kind of cool. You can vote on questions and that way the best questions go to the top and that helps everybody.
And I can also reply directly to them.
The other thing I noticed is you can also
follow them right over here, which is interesting.
So, if I follow a question and someone answers it,
it will notify me in some way.
So I'm going to write down voting, following, and replying.
On to Udacity.
Ok, let's see what we can do here. Oh wow, actually quite a lot.
Looks like we can reply, we can favorite it, or like it,
we can link to this or share a link to this post, we can bookmark it.
Let's see.
That's about it.
So those are five features.
It's a decent one, so I'm going to write all those down: bookmarking, linking, replying, and liking. As usual, we're going
to cross off Lynda - get your head in the game, Lynda -
and go back to Skillshare.
Now, the question is, where is the location?
Remember? It could be important
if people can see it, or if it's really close to the player,
or put in a way that everyone's going to
use, that could be an important factor in whether or not the feature launch is successful. Well, Skillshare has it down here.
So, it's on the same screen that we're going to watch the videos on, but it's below the fold, so I'm going
to say below the fold, which means basically it's
below the point where I have to scroll the web page.
In Coursera, it's the same thing. If I'm viewing it like this,
I have to scroll down, which means that, you know, it's important and it's accessible, but it's not immediately obvious.
I have to kind of look for it.
Udacity, we remember it's a button over here.
It's always present but it's a tab, like a separate tab
I would have to click on and then exit out to go to.
And then Lynda.
Lynda, Lynda, Lynda... We know what we're going to say.
All right, so the last one in Skillshare. Can we post a photo?
I believe you can. There we go.
So, you know, I post something, I can put a photo right there and it'll insert it, kind of look like that - my ugly mug.
Coursera. Can you insert photos?
I believe you can as well. There we go.
Now, you can see that we have a rich text editor.
You can throw that in there.
Looks like it's the same story here if I were to reply to something.
It would pop up and, again, I can put a whole lot of stuff in here.
I can even do custom HTML links or I can upload
something there, which is probably like an image.
Lynda obviously doesn't do that. Give it a big X.
Ok, so now we know what the competitive landscape looks like
with regards to making a discussion button.
You at home, ask yourself this question: how would you as Udemy build your discussion tool based off
of what you've seen in your competitors?
Would you try to beat them on all different categories or would you de-prioritize the group discussion because you think you can't win?
Or is it the case that you just want to get something there
so you can say you have it?
It's entirely up to you as a product manager.
You have to make these strategy decisions.
You have the data now to make it, so make your call.
Post that in the group discussion, let's talk about it.
I'd love to see what you guys come up with but for now
I'm going to fill out what Udemy actually does.
Can you post a group discussion in Udemy?
Let's pretend we're flashing forward. We've
implemented the tool, let's answer the question.
So can you? Yes, you can.
It's right there when you're using the viewer and it is integrated.
Can you add time markings?
No, actually you cannot, sadly,
but you can reference the lecture.
So, I would say no, but you can reference lectures.
What engagement features do they have? Sadly, they
only have the basics, like and reply, but they do have
a search feature, which I did not see on any of the
other ones. We can search through discussions and
look for ones that we want. Location, it is prominent.
It takes up like one third of the screen and it's directly on the right. When you log into a course, it's
like the first thing you will see right there, hard to ignore it.
And can you post images? Yes, you can.
Some of you guys don't ever seem to take advantage
of that and it makes me sad, but you can.
Ok, there you go. Now we've made a table for our features.
Ok, now we can do the post-mortem and decide: do we need to make changes to the feature we've already implemented?
Is it important? How far away are we from becoming
the best in this category and should we care?
All right, guys, in the next couple of lectures we're going to talk about analyzing your competitors,
things to keep in mind as a product manager to make sure
you're looking in the right direction.
See you in the next lecture.