Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Let's talk a little bit about startups or pre-product
situations and how this process differs for
calculating your minimum criteria for success.
Now, when you're running the show with an existing product,
an existing user base, and potentially existing
revenue, you're going to be, one, more concerned
with certain metrics, and two, less sensitive to certain
types of risks and certain types of costs.
PMs at a big company generally care about metrics
that are just not of concern to entrepreneurs or people
who are trying to figure out whether or not
their product should exist in the first place.
Average minutes consumed is not very important
if you have zero customers and you're only getting 1%
of your people to even sign up for your service.
Two different worlds. Specifically, in the case of a startup,
you're looking for what we call validation
metrics - is my product a good idea?
Does it meet a user need?
Does my identified problem really exist?
What exactly is a validation metric?
Well, it's something that demonstrates real interest
from your potential customers: percentage of people
that sign up, percentage of people that share your post,
average purchase price,
how many people open your email.
Those are examples.
You're also more concerned with the
economic viability of the project as a whole.
It's hard to justify how much money exactly a feature
will make, but a product is relatively easy, so
we're probably going to look at things like
lifetime value and things like gross margins.
So the biggest difference when you're doing this pre-product
it's really going to be the right side of our equation.
Rewards are just going to be different for you.
You're going to be looking for specific things that
signal interest and not necessarily some behavioral
change you expected to happen. You're also not going
to be as concerned with opportunity cost, because
if it fails and you flop, you're probably looking for a new job.
So make sure that you understand the nuance between the two, because, as a product manager, you might find
yourself in both situations.
All right, so at this point in the process we know
what we want to build Ideally, whether it's a
product, or a feature, or a big change to the product you
already have, we know what we need to test assumption
wise, and we know what outcome we want to get out of these tests.
All right, now let's shift our focus to the ways and the tools that are available to us to get the actual testing job done.
When you run MVP experiments, you're always going to
present in some way, shape, or form something
that implies your new feature or product is already real
and/or coming very soon.
This obviously is not the case, because internally
we actually haven't decided yet whether or not we
want to build it. Now, the extent to which you need to
fake this in order to get the information you need
is what's going to determine what type of MVP you need.
So let's list them out and briefly discuss them.