Hey guys, welcome back to the course. So, in the previous lectures in this section, we covered how to find competitors,
gather information on them, figure out if they're
direct or indirect, and then compare them.
Now, those are all crucial skills for gathering the information you need to make judgments on your competitors.
However, competitors are always going to be there,
if not forever, at least for a while.
And like you, competitors will change.
Competition is an ever changing landscape, and, as a
good product manager - which is what you want to be,
right? - you want to keep tabs on your competition so that as soon as they make a change you can redirect or adjust.
Now, remember the five dimensions that we
judge our competitors on?
We have the product team - how good are they
or how bad are they?
We have design - is it pretty?
We have brand - how important is their brand? Is it a positive asset for them? Is it so strong it prevents you from doing things?
How big is their user base? Is it big or is it just girthy?
And the last one is speed - how much of it are they on?
Now, those are the five criteria that we want to keep in our minds constantly about our competitors and it's always going to change.
They are going to make changes and take initiatives that
will increase certain ones of the five and
sometimes they'll make mistakes and they'll lose some ground on some of those five and you need to be
there to know when it happens.
So, in this lecture, we're going to cover three different events that you should constantly be looking for, and we're going to
cover three different ways that you can keep tabs on
if those events happen. Alright, now there are
obviously a ton of tiny little things that can happen with your competitors and it's worthwhile to know.
Maybe they move a button over here, maybe they make a big change to their web app, whatever it is, it's all worth knowing.
But there are three things, as a product manager, that I think
stick out more than the others, because
they have the ability and the potential to change all of those five criteria we previously mentioned.
So the first one is funding.
Now, this is not really something I've talked a ton about before,
but a lot of companies receive money.
If you're in the startup space, a lot of companies
receive venture capital. The amount of money that's
in their bank account can make an enormous difference
for a number of our five variables.
More money means they can hire more people.
More money means they can spend more money on ads, means that they can hire more contractors, it can pay for more press.
So that means that they can dramatically change their speed.
More money also could mean that they now have more to work with for recruiting, for their product team,
and so you should keep your eye out
in case their product team improves.
It adds small changes to brand, that doesn't necessarily change their design, but it could allow them
to bring on people who can add more design and usability,
and it also could or could not have an effect with user size.
Oftentimes, especially with startups, when they raise money they do spend a lot of it on advertisement and growing their user base.
All right, but how do you know when they get funding?
Where are you supposed to put your ear to the ground for this?
Well, actually it's pretty easy.
Generally, when companies get funded, there's a web site that keeps track of all of that for us and it's incredibly useful.
It's called Crunchbase. So let's check it out.
This is what Crunchbase looks like, just crunchbase.com.
All they do is keep track of how much money people have raised.
Oh my God, WeWork raised $430 million dollars. That's insane.
Sorry, and back to what we were talking about.
All you have to do is search up here for
the organization that you're trying to keep tabs on.
Let's say I worked for Spotify - sorry again, Cole -
and I wanted to keep track of SoundCloud.
SoundCloud, honestly, is the least of their worries,
I'd be more worried about Apple Music.
But let's say that we wanted to keep tabs on them.
Right here we can see information about them,
all of this stuff is really nice.
But the most important thing is it gives us
a timeline of their funding right here.
So not only can we get historical information,
we can also see when this gets updated, and that'll tell
us that they just received a new round of funding.
So how do I get notified when this happens?
Well, it's pretty easy. You just hit follow, and then it'll ask you
to create an account, do that, and then you'll get
emails directly to your inbox every time something major happens with your competitors, specifically their funding.
There you go.
Another thing that Crunchbase is really,
really helpful for happens to be our
number two thing that we want to look out for, and that is acquisitions. Acquisitions, if you're not familiar,
is when a company buys another company.
Imagine a really big fish and a really small fish
and then the big fish eats the small fish,
except in this scenario that small fish actually attaches to the big fish and makes it larger, kind of like the angler fish.
I know that's random, but look it up,
it's the creepiest thing in the world.
When a company buys another company, they're doing it for a number of reasons, and it usually comes down
to the five reasons that we care about.
Oftentimes, companies will buy another company because they have a good product team and they want to
integrate that into their own team.
Sometimes they want to buy a company because they have a lot of users and they would like to integrate
those users into their own user base or at least cross sell them information or gather information on their users.
Either way, bad for you.
They could also buy them because of design.
There are examples of companies that have bought other companies to absorb their design team. Remember
how we talked about Path?
Path got bought for pretty much that reason.
Now, the only two things that doesn't necessarily affect are brand unless acquisitions are prestigious, I mean,
they kind of are, or speed. Speed is tough.
Oftentimes, companies will buy another company because that company seems to get stuff done really quickly.
But you kind of run into a problem where larger organizations as a whole, as they get larger and larger, get slower and slower.
So it's... I don't know, it's kind of a wash.
How we find acquisitions is you just go up here
and they'll list it right at the top. Click it and it will
take us to a page that gives us all their acquisitions,
gives us the date, we can actually click through
and read about the company if we want to.
And since we're already following it, we will get an update.
It will even give us the terms of it. That's pretty cool.
And the last event that we really care about are
feature or new product launches. Why?
Well, because those are major maneuvers that your competitors are making and you absolutely have to know
if they're doing it, especially if they make a product or a new feature that is in some way competing directly with you or copying you.
The best way of keeping tabs on that and a number of other things is a web site called Mention.com.
Now, it's not free, but it is incredibly useful and it has a free trial,
more importantly. What mention.com does is it tracks all of your competitors' social media accounts
it looks at chatter between customers and the company,
it looks for major updates on the company's blogs,
any large seismic shifts, they will email you, and you can even
set your preferences to tell it how often
to email you: only e-mail you when big things happen,
or email me any time anything moves at all.
Let's check out Mention really quickly.
Sign up, it's free, and then you can create your first alert.
So all you want to do is tell it what you're trying to
train their listening system to.
So we're looking for a competitor.
Tell them the name of your competitor, let's say SoundCloud.
There we go.
And move on to the next step.
Here we can set our priorities, what we care about the most.
If you're more concerned about what they say in their social channels, you can make sure to listen to
that more, add more of them.
But we're just looking for feature changes, product launches, so when those happen it's going be a seismic shift.
They're gonna have a blog post about it,
they're going to have a Twitter post,
and probably a Facebook post as well.
You'll get one of them.
So just move on.
You can pick all you want to pull in.
This is incredibly useful, the news setting. Why?
Because a lot of times you might not see the feature launch, but news will pick up on it or news will
pick up on it way before it launches.
That's really helpful.
Also for tracking things like perception, which affect their brand.
Move on to check out your results, we're almost done.
And there we go. Our account is already set up.
Look, we have 76 new mentions for the alert SoundCloud. Alright, so I went out and gathered quite a lot of
information about SoundCloud, it's going back in time.
If I wanted to look at the mentions, I would just go here, and then I can just scroll down this feed and
I can check it out. Here I can search and I can filter through it.
There are a lot of really cool tools for picking out
the signal in the noise, so to speak. You can set
things like keywords you're looking for, or even exclude keywords, so certain things don't ever show up in your feed.
You can also, in your settings, change how often they email you and what type of interactions they consider
important and will notify you about.
All right, cool. Mention is a very powerful tool.
Check out what you can use it for, you can find
a million and one things you can do with it.
This is fantastic for figuring out when they get money, when they get acquisitions, and when they launch
new things. And the last thing we're going to cover is Google Alerts. Google Alerts is not as powerful as Mention,
but it's a broader blanket.
All you have to do is type in the company name that you want to stock and what it's going to do.
It's going to frequently e-mail you and notify you,
if you want to do desktop notifications, any time
new search results show up for your competitor.
That is the broadest sweep you can use.
Incredibly useful though to see how their CEO changes,
to see how anything is popping up, conversations,
things way out there you might not have seen,
all this information - really helpful.
All right, guys, keep track of your competitors,
because if you don't, they might get out of your sights
and they'll come back to bite you later.
All right. See you in the next lecture.