Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Let's dive right back in and start talking
about more MVP techniques.
Now we're going to start talking about ones that
require more resource investment, look a little more
real, less scrappy, but still pretty scrappy.
So the next one we're going to talk about
is called the explainer MVP.
This is a little bit harder to do because it requires
some resources to make. Explainers, if you don't
know what I'm talking about, are those videos that explain what an app does, or what a new feature or feature set will do.
They come in two different types: you have tutorial
style explainers and sales style explainers. In a
tutorial style, you'll see someone manually explaining over a screencast, much in the same way that companies
use tutorial screencasts to explain
how to do certain tasks in their product.
In this version, someone will pretend to use a new feature
or product and explain what it does and why
they made it, but they haven't actually built it yet.
It's all smoke and mirrors.
Actually, the way it looks real is in editing. In editing,
you create this illusion that you have a working
product by animating certain things and having them,
for instance, navigate from one static page to another static page.
They're not connected, they don't work, but
you'll just cut the video so it looks like they do.
Sounds a little nutty?
Yeah, it does.
But this is actually a fairly common way of
pre-validating before you build. True story,
this is actually how Dropbox started. Dropbox, if you're not familiar,
multi-billion dollar company that lets you store anything in their data servers through a desktop and browser client.
When the founder first started Dropbox, he wanted to test
to see if people wanted this idea, this cloud
storage idea where you could sink your files very seamlessly to servers somewhere else and have access
to your files anywhere you go.
So what he did is he just made a fake video of him using his product and put it on YouTube.
The response was huge,
so he knew it was worth building. The other
type of explainer is the sales related explainer,
and this is just more when you make more like a fake promo video that pitches the product or the feature using - who knows? -
it could be one of those, you know, whiteboard videos,
with the super fake looking hand that comes up in
the middle and writes, or you could use an animated one,
or even a talking head video like this as your promo.
A decent example that I actually saw the other day was
a company called Frame.io, that makes a collaborative
web app for video editors and producers -
we actually use it to make our courses.
They made a video pitching a new set of features that added
all sorts of crazy animations and CG,
but actually those features had not been added yet at all.
They just said it was launching very soon and to sign up for a notification. Presumably, if not enough people signed up, then
who knows, maybe they just wouldn't launch
the feature and maybe it'd just disappear.
Either way, no one is the wiser.
The point is that this MVP works because real products
generally will have promotion videos of some
kind, and real features will often have tutorial
videos showing how to use them.
So you just kind of slip in an explainer video, and there you go,
that's your validation. The next MVP we going to
discuss is called the fake landing page pitch experiment
MVP. This is when a business will create one singular page
that pitches all of the benefits of a new
product and then has a call to action
somewhere on the page. Since you might not know
what some of these terms are that I just used,
let's break it down just a little bit.
Landing pages are a term used for web pages that are just
one page. They're a marketing tool so that companies
can run ads and have a very controlled experience
when people move from that ad to that site. It doesn't
generally make sense to have an ad for, let's say,
an e-commerce store that just added the new iPhone SE,
and when people click on the ad that says "We have the iPhone,"
they go to the home page of your e-commerce
store, where nowhere on the page
are you talking about the iPhone.
The person generally will get confused and will probably leave.
So that's one of the primary uses of landing pages,
although they are pretty versatile.
And essentially, if you want your users to specifically
do something, like sign up, or pay, or fill out
a form, you're probably going to use a landing page.
Now, the other term I used was "pitch experiment."
Now, this is just a nifty little term worth knowing,
although you might not ever actually use it in conversation.
It's a term from The Lean Startup framework. A pitch
experiment is basically when you have an online
experiment where you pitch for a new product or a new feature
to an online audience and you see what they do.
Landing pages are a natural fit for this because they're
one completely focused page that you can deliver
a product or feature pitch directly to the user, whether they
like it or not, they can't ignore it. As far as MVPs go,
the landing page pitch experiment is kind of the gold
standard, at least for entrepreneurial MVP tests.
Got an idea for a product? Create a fake product page
and drive traffic to it. See how they react.
Product managers with existing user bases
can also use this technique quite well.
Instead of getting external traffic, you're just going to
drive your internal traffic to a page through
an email, internal ads, push notifications, whatever.
Now, two classic examples of a landing page pitch experiment are, 1, a company called Buffer, and 2, a company called Basecamp.
Let's talk about them. Buffer. Buffer is an online service,
if you haven't actually heard of it, that helps you manage
your company's social media messaging campaigns.
One of the main things it'll do is help you schedule
when your messages go out in advance, so you don't
have to have someone sitting at the computer,
writing all of your Facebook posts.
Now, Buffer started off by creating a fake page pitching what their service would do, and then just drove traffic to the page.
They actually set it up in a way where they put up
pieces of what they thought about adding and then
they saw what things people interacted with, they kind of
just used it as like a puzzle piece, jigsaw puzzle,
put together what their product should actually end up being.
Now, Basecamp, on the other hand, is an online project management tool, something that's often compared
to Asana, or Trello, or any other popular project management tools.
They didn't necessarily start with a landing page.
They actually came out of a web development studio
called 37 Signals, and it was a side project, but they
are very well known for using landing pages
to pre-validate any feature or new side project.
Anytime they have a new side project, they make landing pages that say "This is what it does, this is why it's awesome.
Here's some more information, some photos,
and you should buy it or sign up for it."