Alright, so you've got your resume optimized,
you've got your online brand perfected, and
you're going to interview with a company.
Congrats on getting that first interview! In this lecture,
we're going to talk about some tips to help you
get through the product management interview.
These interviews are tough and that's
because it's not all cut and dry.
You've got to demonstrate some skills, usually
on a whiteboard, or talking through problems.
So what I'm going to do is give you three big tips
on how to nail these interviews.
The first two, we're going to talk about here,
and then the most important one has
its own lecture coming up next.
All right.
Tip number one: use every interview
to make the next one even better.
Each interview you do is going to help you
a lot in making the next interview even better.
Whether it's another interview at the same company
or an interview at a different company, you should
pay very close attention to the questions they
ask you for that product management role,
then think about whether or not you were able
to get a good answer to them or not.
For every question,
take mental notes, or even physical notes, if they let you.
When you go home, start researching those things immediately.
If you didn't understand something, you didn't
have a good answer, go look it up.
So if you make it to the next round of interviews for that company,
then you have more relevant knowledge to discuss.
Even if you don't get that job and you are going to
an interview at another company, this is going to
be super helpful for prepping you for these
types of questions in the future.
You've got to be optimistic here.
These are tough interviews, but each failure is
an increased chance at the next opportunities.
That's how you should look at it.
Tip number two: ask good questions.
The more research you do before the interview about the
company, and the industry, and the product, the better.
You can't do enough, to be honest.
Most interviewers will give you a chance to ask
them questions at the end of the interview.
So you should have some really good questions in mind.
Before you go into your first interview,
do that research on those latest initiatives, and industry
trends, and even what their competitors are doing,
what rounds of funding other people have
raised that are in the same industry,
use this information to ask them thoughtful questions.
I'll give you an example here.
Let's say I'm interviewing for a product management
position at a messaging app, and they compete with
WhatsApp, which is a really popular
messaging app owned by Facebook.
I'd probably ask them questions about how they try
to differentiate themselves in the market and then
what they think the biggest obstacles for them are in the next year.
If WhatsApp releases a feature in, you know, a month
before you do that interview or anytime in the
last six months, you need to say "Hey, what are your
thoughts on that latest feature? Are you guys going
to try to compete with that or what?"
And this really just shows that you're interested in their product,
you understand what's going on in this industry,
and I guarantee that if you ask good questions like
this, you're going to stand out from the rest of the candidates.
All right, let's recap here. Use every interview as
an opportunity to make the next one better.
Don't cheap out on this. You've got to do it.
And then two, ask insightful questions at the end of your
interview that are relevant to the product management
role, the industry, and the product.
If you use these tips, your interview is going to be really
good, and you will be way ahead of the competition.
You're going to be even better off if you watch
the next lecture, because it's a really good tip.