Hey there, good to see you again.
Let's get into the details and how to communicate
with different types of people,
and we'll start first with engineers.
So, engineers are lovers of detail. When talking to them,
emailing them, or anything else,
be very detailed about that thing you're describing.
This is because engineers are always thinking about software
and how what you're saying may or may not
work in a technical sense.
The clearer you are here, the better.
I can't tell you how many times early in my career
I was not detailed enough in my talks with engineers
or while sending them feature specifications.
In order to develop efficiently,
they need to know things that other people don't.
Things like, what happens when the screen
is displayed in other language?
What does the error state read when
something goes wrong on this page?
What happens when there is no data to see on this page?
This is often referred to as an empty state.
As time goes on, you'll get better at predicting what
types of information the engineers need from you.
So, now I'm going to list off some miscellaneous tips
for working with engineers as a product manager.
Number one: if something goes wrong, it's your fault.
This is not just being nice, this is the truth.
You're responsible for the success of the product.
If something goes wrong, or an engineer develops something
incorrectly, because you gave them the wrong
specs, that is your fault, not theirs.
Number two: when you're pitching a feature, be prepared
and have a really good idea of where the feature's
going to go in the future.
When we do Agile development, we think of a feature,
and we think about how it's going to look down the
road in an ideal state, but also what the minimum
viable product will be. Telling developers where you
think something's going to go down the road is going
to help them plan out how we're going to do this
technically in the future, and that matters a lot.
Number three: when possible, you should do the work upfront
on things like checking commit logs, or looking
up data before you ask engineers to do it.
Trying yourself before you ask for someone else's time
is a big sign of respect,
and developers like to know that they aren't
the only ones doing the work.
This will also score you major points.
Number four: watch out for tech debt.
So what is tech debt?
It's a term we use to describe something in the code
or technology which is going to have to be dealt
with later as the result of not doing
something correctly the first time.
Let me give you an example here.
If we're building a new feature that requires a database,
maybe we learned that one way to save time
is to utilize a database that already exists.
However, if the feature becomes very popular and it needs
more space, then eventually it needs its own database.
This impending work is what we call tech debt.
We're going to have to do it at some point.
Engineers hate tech debt, because
they're the ones that have to deal with it.
Be cognizant of this and trust their judgment
on the right way to do things first.
You'll maybe find that a lot of them want to do something
scaled out the first time to make sure we
don't have to come back and deal with it later, which
will stop us from developing features at that point.
Lastly, this is a big one.
Do not treat engineers like an agency.
What I mean by this is don't design and come up with
all of the concepts yourself, or with your designer,
and then just hand the completed requirements
to the engineers to code.
Always give engineers an opportunity to provide you
with feedback and product ideas. Just because they
spend their days coding, doesn't mean that they don't have
any good ideas or opinions of their own on the product.
The way I give them the opportunity to provide feedback
is actively involving them with day to day discussion,
but also, during our planning meetings,
I make it a point to have a part where we tell the engineers
what we think is coming up next and we
give them the opportunity to tell us what they think
about that from the product perspective, not even
the engineering perspective, but
"Is this a good idea? Would users use this?"
It's very important that you bring them in on these discussions.
That is one of the best tips I can give you
for working with engineers,
very important, and engineers will respect you a lot more.
All right, so now you've got a good handle on how to
interact and communicate with engineers.
Let's go into the next lecture and talk a little bit about designers. See you there.