Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
I hope you didn't run out of gas in this section,
because knowing how to design and put together an
effective MVP experiment is going to be crucial to being
a successful product manager. As a product manager,
you're going to hear the term MVP, and you're going to
be expected to follow roughly the same process
that we followed in the section. Coming up with an idea,
designing an experiment, setting up your expectations,
and then running a test is how product managers
decide what to add and what to go forward with.
It's your flashlight in the dark, so to speak.
When you run your experiment and gather your data,
you're going to then take what you have and
compare it to your minimum criteria for success.
If it passes your bar, woo! Congratulations.
If it doesn't, then you need to see
if you can figure out why it didn't work.
Regardless of whether it worked or didn't work,
this is the time to sit down and evaluate what you need to do next.
One thing that has to be understood by any entrepreneur
or product manager is that MVP experiments will
primarily return quantitative data. Quantitative data,
if you're not familiar with the term, is kind of the opposite of
what we were doing when we were interviewing
customers and doing customer development. Quantitative data is going to be data that has numbers, numbers that indicate behavior.
Maybe percentages of users that did this,
how much time someone spent on your page, total sign ups, etc.
When we were interviewing customers, we were getting
what's called qualitative information. Qualitative
information and qualitative data cannot be
expressed in numbers, because it's verbal.
It's not a scale from 1 to 10.
It's a measurement of feeling strongly
about something or "Who is this user?"
And here is a crucial lesson you have to learn.
If you want to make the right call,
you need to make sure you're collecting both types of data.
Numbers will tell you what happened and will give you
unbiased records of what your users did or did not do,
but you can't and will not know why they did what they did
without also speaking to them. The "what" without
the "why" can be incredibly misleading.
Let's say, in a hypothetical, we created a landing page
experiment that targeted hardcore marathon runners
that displayed a brand new shoe that
was designed for running long distances.
When you put it out there into the world and
drove traffic to it, you see that, you know, 14% of users
signed up to be notified of when it gets released.
In fact, some of them, on a separate page,
actually paid for pre-orders.
Both those cases, you decide those are great numbers,
and you give the project a green light.
You build out the shoe and you build out an
advertising campaign to market it for the first time.
Let's say that you advertise in a marathon running forum,
and of all the people that clicked your page,
only 1% ended up buying the shoe. What exactly happened?
Now, you might think this is an exaggerated case,
but it actually happens all the time. Because you've
never collected qualitative data on those
14% of users that signed up,
you never found out that the users that signed up
weren't actually marathon runners at all.
They were casual runners and they bought it because,
hey, they liked the design of the shoe.
So, as a product manager, if you want your MVP experiment
to bear fruitful results you can make sense of,
make sure you incorporate regular conversations
with your users that are involved in your test.
Incentivize them to talk on the phone,
install live chat boxes - you know now how to get this done,
because we have a section on customer development.
This is primarily a discovery process, and throughout your experiments, you're going to find out things that will surprise you.
Maybe your feature ended up being popular, but not at all
by the people you thought would originally like it.
Or maybe your user behavior didn't change the ideal metric,
but it did change an entirely different metric.
All of this is gold to you, because you're finding out the truth about your customer's needs and your customer's preferences.
At the end of this process, though, you need to make a call.
Do you make the feature and give it the green light?
Do you scrap the whole idea and forget
that you ever thought about it?
Or do you think you should re-run the test,
but on a slightly different hypothesis?
These are the decisions you have to make as a product manager.
But now you know how to run MVP tests, which are the
primary way you're going to get the information you
need to guide you in making those decisions.
All right guys, congratulations on finishing the MVP section.
If you guys want to get more on
MVPs, we have my MVP course that's attached to this.
There's a coupon in, like, lecture 4, I think.
Go back, check that out.
The MVP course that I teach is a lot longer and it's a lot
more in depth. It's focused more on entrepreneurs,
but you can still learn a lot about things that
can apply to basic product management.
Like always, guys, questions, concerns, post in the Q&A.
Otherwise, see you in the next section.