Hey, what's up? Welcome back.
The other thing that's going to really help you out
immensely in getting a job as a product manager
is having a good personal brand online.
What you want here is basically an online record that
demonstrates your knowledge of product management
and the skills required. Building credibility before you walk through the door to your interviews is worth its weight in gold.
The best way to demonstrate credibility is to have a
website or blog where you talk about things related
to product management, and have those projects
we talked about available to the public.
Recruiters will often look at your social media profiles and
web site to understand if you're qualified or not for the role.
Since there is not as much information out there on
product management as compared to other topics, it's
actually pretty easy to stand out.
Here's a couple example topics that you
can consider writing about to get started.
Number one, you could write about why a particular product
you use is poor and then how it can be improved.
This is actually a pretty common interview question
that they'll ask you as a PM.
They'll say, you know, "What is a favorite product
of yours and how could it be improved?"
Number two, you could say the top five mistakes you've
made in your current role and what you've learned.
Number three, you could read some product management
books, which we will have in the resources, some
recommendations for those,
and then you could write some blog posts about your reviews
of those books and what you agree or disagree with.
Number four, you could write a post on your thoughts
on recent technology trends, or industry events, and
how you see them developing further or changing the market.
So besides a blog, it's also very helpful to have a
public social media account, like Twitter, where you
participate in product discussions or talk about
relevant things to product management.
I also recommend you go on Quora,
Q-U-O-R-A.com, and ask or answer questions
related to products and product strategy.
Alright, so quick recap.
One of the best things you can do to make sure you have a great online brand is to write or just have a public presence.
If you don't have a website or blog, you should make one.
You should start one.
You should start writing, and you should include some topics related to product management and product strategy in there.
Also, make sure you have a publicly available social
media account, like Twitter, where you talk about
things that are also on topic with product management,
and UX design, and user experience.
All right, I'll see you in the next section, where we'll be
talking about looking for product management jobs
once you feel that you're sufficiently prepared.