Alright everyone, welcome back.
In the last lecture we talked about some real world examples
of metrics from companies you've probably
heard of. It was YouTube, and Twitter, and Facebook,
and you might have noticed that, when I was talking
about some of these metrics, I said that
here are some growth metrics.
You know, the new users, and the monthly actives,
and that sort of thing, and then here's the engagement
metrics, which are things that were
a little bit more specific to each company.
A lot of times, the growth ones were the same, because
they were, you know, the more generic metrics, and
then the engagement ones were very specific to the platform.
In the Facebook example, we had the news
feed position engagement number, and on YouTube we had
the, you know, number of views that were over 30
seconds on average per person. In this section,
we're going to be talking about these different types,
these categories of metrics, and there are a number
of categories of metrics out there, and they are not,
there's no official definition for any of these,
but this is, in my experience, how they're usually sectioned off.
So, in practice, there's a whole bunch of these
different categories of metrics, and these are not,
there's no dictionary definition for this, and you're
never going to have the same ones across companies,
but there's sort of general categories that, in my experience,
I've seen at the companies I've either
worked with or worked for. Some of the most common,
the ones we're going to talk about here are growth
and activation as one category, engagement, retention,
then user happiness, and then revenue.
And those are really the big buckets.
So we'll talk a little bit about each one of these, give some real life examples, and define a little bit further what they mean.
The first category is growth and activation.
This is pretty self-explanatory.
This is a bucket of metrics that basically tracks, and measures,
and informs you how your company or product is growing.
So, some examples of some growth and acquisition metrics
are going to be total new users per month or
per week, then you're going to have new users by source,
we'll talk a little bit about that, and then activated users.
So if you're working as a product manager either on a growth team inside a company or you're a product manager
at a smaller company that's also responsible for growth,
then you want to know obviously how many new
users you have, but you really want to know where
these users are coming from. Are they coming from the SEO
optimizations you did, which is search engine optimizations,
so that people can find you via Google and
search engines, and stuff like that?
Or is it that they're finding you on an app store,
or is it that they're finding you on maybe a blog
somewhere, or perhaps they're finding you because
one of your users shared some content from your
platform or your app out to another platform, like
Twitter, and they click the link and say "Hey, what is this?"
These are all very important to track,
and that would be new users by source.
So we're tracking where they're coming from.
So activation is a big one because there's a really big
difference between a person that has been considered
someone who's found and maybe installed your app
and an activated user.
So what usually happens is a company or product manager
will say that an activated user is someone that
has not only downloaded the app or gone to the web site,
but they've actually signed up and they've performed
a particular type of action, like, maybe, you know, making
their first tweet in Twitter's example, or something like that.
This is hugely important because if you get a million people
to download your app, but only 500 of them
actually get logged in and activated,
well, that's not so useful, now, is it? The second one
is retention, and retention is tied very closely to
the growth and activation metrics.
It's simply a way to find out who's coming back.
It's just how many people were here last month using
your product that are now here this month using it.
again. Some examples of retention metrics are
things like a metric called actually retained users,
and one other one is called resurrected users.
Again, returning users is the number of users
that are returning, that are here again.
They are continually, either week over week,
or day over day, or month over month
using your service, or your app, or your product.
And then, resurrected users is basically something
that we use to describe people that we've gotten back.
So let's say that there was a user that was using
our product last month and they're not here this month.
They haven't been using our product this month, but next
month they do come back because we sent them
either a push notification on their mobile phone or we
sent them an e-mail and said "Hey, did you know we
have these features?" or something like that.
Then, if they do come back, we can say
"Hey, that's a resurrected user."
The implication there is that they were, you know,
"dead" or they were just gone,
so we are now resurrecting them and
bringing them back into our product.
So, in terms of how those might actually be measured in
a number sense, let's say that 100 users downloaded
our app last month and got activated, then we see this month that 60 of them are actually here again this month using the app,
we would say that our user retention rate is 60%.
We know that there's something wrong,
that 40% of people did not come back.
Those people did not find it a good enough product
and that's how we measure it.
Then, for the resurrected users, let's say that those 40
we're now considering gone, like we've sort of
lost them because they're not here this month, but next
month we send them an email or a push notification,
let's say all 40 of those people come back into our app,
we would say that our resurrected user rate was 100%,
because, remember, we have 40 people that
are considered dead or gone,
and now we are resurrecting all 40 of them,
means our resurrection rate is 100%.
Hey, by the way, you might be wondering about these time periods,
the one month, or two months, or that sort of thing.
All of these time periods and actual definitions are really up to each company and/or product team to decide the definitions on.
Basically, the only thing that really matters about
your metrics is that you're keeping them consistent,
so if you're measuring something one way in one
period of time, you have to keep measuring it that way
in the future in order to be able to compare to the past, and you want to keep these things the same for as long as possible.
All right, so the next bucket of metrics is engagement.
Engagement is going to be one of the most common
things for product managers to be tracking that work at
consumer product companies. Engagement metrics,
we've already talked about a little bit,
it's things like Twitter.
How many times did a user tweet on average per day?
How many times did they like something? Etc.
Engagement metrics are usually tailored per company
to encourage a specific type of behavior, depending
on the goals of the company or your industry, basically.
I'll give you a real world example really quick.
I know that YouTube tracks views, they count someone
as viewed if they've watched 30 seconds of video,
30 seconds of a YouTube video. Facebook,
on the other hand, tracks their video views
I think based off of three seconds, so if someone's
watched for at least three seconds.
These are different.
Of course, Facebook is going to report way more views
that way, because it's pretty hard to shut off a
video in three seconds if you're just scrolling past it.
But these metrics, as you can see, are tailored to the
types of metrics that each company wants to report
both externally and internally for reasons of quality
and accuracy, and also being able to be easily
compared to stuff they've tracked in the past.
The next bucket is user happiness.
This is pretty self-explanatory.
It's just a way for us to quantitatively say how happy are our users.
So examples of that would be something called NPS
scores, or number of customers that have written a
complaint to the customer service department.
And then, even something like the AppStore rating for
your particular app in like, the Android or iOS
AppStore. NPS means net promoter score, by the way,
and it's something that was developed a long time ago
that's pretty ubiquitous from company to company.
It's basically a survey that goes out to users that tracks how likely they are to recommend that service or product to other people.
You might have actually seen these before if you've
ever gotten a survey that says "Will you rate us
on a scale of 1 to 10 of how likely you
are to recommend our product?"
The secret behind this though, by the way, is that I think
anything under a 7 is basically counted as a zero.
So if you can't get a user to at least say I'm at least
like a 7, 8, or 9, or 10 in terms of a scale of
likelihood to recommend this to other people, then you're basically, you know, losing out and it's going to throw off the average.
This is because companies want to kind of set a high bar
for customer happiness. Overall, happiness metrics
are some of the most difficult to get because it's not
as easy as just looking in a database for, you
know, number of times someone clicks something, but they are
very important, and they are even more relevant
in industries or companies where there's little competition,
or where people don't have other options, or it's a total necessity.
Some examples for that would be a cable provider or an airline.
I know most people out there hate their cable internet
service or their internet service at home, but
they don't really have a choice because
there's not very many choices available,
so the cable companies, they see a lot of use, obviously,
but it doesn't mean the customer is happy.
And when they say "How happy are you?" to their customers,
they're going to say "Not very. You guys suck."
So the last category of metrics we're going to talk
about is revenue metrics. Revenue metrics, pretty
self-explanatory, how much revenue are we making.
But there's a lot of different ways we can look at this,
and these are very important for product managers
that are working at companies where revenue from
customers is a really big deal, or product managers
that are working inside of consumer companies where
the consumers are not paying anything, but maybe
they're being advertised to, and that's how you generate revenue.
An example of a revenue metric is LTV, which stands
for lifetime value, and that basically means we pick
a period, let's say, a long period of time, like one year,
and we say that's a customer lifetime, then we
say over one year on average how much revenue
does each customer generate us?
So within that space of one year we're getting, let's say,
$300 from each user on average - that would be our LTV.
Another example would be a metric called CAC,
which is cost of acquisition of customer.
Sometimes it's CCA, which is cost of customer acquisition.
It's all the same thing.
It's basically how much money do we have to spend in marketing,
or advertising, or even salaries for salespeople
to on average acquire a customer.
This is very important to track because we want
to keep this number as low as possible.
One other example that a lot of business to business
companies put a lot of value into is a metric called
MRR, which is monthly recurring revenue, and its counterpart, which is ARR, annual recurring revenue.
This is basically how much revenue are we
making per month or per year,
and this is of all of our customers combined,
all of our users combined.
So this is, for a subscription service, let's say, Dropbox,
for example, they have 100 users, and each one
of those users is paying $10 a month.
Well then, their monthly recurring revenue is going to be $1,000.
So you can see how that works.
This is, of course, a huge indicator of value
for subscription businesses like Dropbox.
All right, so let's recap really quick.
There's a ton of metrics out there and some of them
are going to be the same across companies,
a lot of them are going to be different,
but the important thing to know here is that there are
different categories of metrics, and the purpose
of these categories is to ensure that we're covering what's called the customer lifecycle journey or the customer lifecycle.
So I have metrics to know how many people are finding us,
and then signing up, and then using us, and then
I have a metric to measure how happy they are,
and then I have a metric to measure how much
money are they making us,
and finally, sometimes people even add how much
are they referring us to others to account for sort
of a growth, like a viral growth.
But yeah, we want to cover basically the
entire lifecycle for each individual user.
Now, if you're at a larger company, you might work on
a team that is only focused on really one of these
categories or one of the metrics inside of that category,
but if you're at a much smaller company, you might be
a product manager that's responsible for a growth
metric, and a retention metric, and an engagement metric,
and so on and so forth.
All right.
So in the next lecture we're going to get even
further into metrics. We'll see you there.