Welcome back, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to talk more about metrics.
We're going to talk about how to pick good metrics,
what makes a good metric in the first place, and then
we'll go into a couple of other details about how
metrics roll up into other top level metrics.
So firstly, let's talk about how metrics roll up into other metrics.
Let's say that you're working at Facebook, and Facebook's
overall metric is to get people on the site
and leave them there for a long time.
You want people to spend as much time on Facebook as possible.
Well, that doesn't mean that if you're working on, say,
the photos part of Facebook, or the news feed part,
that your metric is going to be the amount of time
spent on Facebook, or maybe even on that page.
It's likely that it would, but sometimes
it's not the most important metric.
Like I've mentioned before, there are sometimes things
that we know that we can track on our individual
team that makes the overall metric for the company increase.
The example that we've used is the comments on Facebook.
If we know that people that leave more comments on Facebook
are more likely to spend more time on Facebook
or one of its related apps, then we might be working
on a team that just tries to increase the number
of comments on average per person.
This is because we know that it will increase the overall metric, which is the metric that the company has a goal for as a whole.
So that's it for that part.
I just want you to understand that, even though a
company might have an overall metric, that you as a
product manager might not always be tracking that exact metric,
you might be tracking something for your team.
The second thing I want to mention is the difference
between exploratory metrics and reporting metrics.
Exploratory metrics are things that you're not always tracking,
or always really telling investors, or
your boss, or other people about how they're doing,
but they're there, it's tracking, and analysis is available
to us just to go poke around and see what user behavior is like.
This contrasts with reporting metrics,
because reporting metrics are the things that we are
tracking over long periods of time to ensure that
our product is doing well and heading in the right direction.
So an example of an exploratory metric would be something
where, let's say I'm working at Twitter, and
the overall goal is to increase the amount of time spent,
again, on the web site or in the app. An exploratory
metric might be the number of times someone clicks a
certain button somewhere, because we're not really
interested in keeping track of this over time,
but if we, as product managers, with our team, our engineers,
and our designers want to kind of try to figure
out a solution in order to keep people on the site longer,
we might go look at the buttons they're clicking,
the pages they're going to, so that we can tell
when they go to this particular page,
all of a sudden they drop off and they don't come back.
So maybe something about that page is bad.
And these sorts of things are just metrics and just data
we look at to help us inform us on other decisions.
These exploratory metrics are basically just data points
that we go in and look at kind of hunting for
a little bit of a clue so that we can know how to potentially build a feature to hit the reporting metric and make that increase.
So, for the purposes of this course, and for the rest
of this lecture, we're going to be talking about
reporting metrics, and these are the metrics that
you're tracking over time to make sure your product
is either getting better or getting worse.
All right.
So what makes a good metric?
Well, let me first say that if you're working at a company
or you join a larger company, I bet they're
probably already going to have a bunch of metrics per
team that they are tracking, and that you can already
begin to try to optimize with features,
and changes, and fixes and that sort of thing.
But let's say, just for the thought exercise, that you
don't have any metrics to track and this feature
that you've been brought in to work on with your team is
completely new, so you have to come up with some metrics.
Well, what makes the metrics good? If I pick some metrics,
how do I know if they're good?
The first thing a metric should be is understandable,
and that means you don't need to go and create
some crazy metric, like the number of times someone
clicked this button twice and then went back and clicked
this other thing and did this thing, and then call that
a particular metric that you're tracking.
It needs to be something that's relatively simple, that you can explain just by telling them the name of that metric.
It's usually like something divided by something else to
get a percentage, or the number of times this person
or this group of people did this thing, it's usually pretty simple.
So keep your metrics understandable.
That brings me to the second point, which is
metrics should usually be a rate or ratio.
And this goes back to what we were talking about in regards to monthly active users versus just total number of users.
You want to pick a metric that is not something that's
going to look like a hockey stick no matter what you do.
Imagine if, say, Twitter, or Facebook, or something
just basically tracked the number of users on their
platform or the number of people that have ever signed up.
That's pretty silly, because maybe some spam accounts sign up,
maybe some people sign up and hate it and
leave. What really matters is total number of users,
and then, from there, you take the total number of users that have actually logged in the last 30 days or something like that.
We call that monthly active.
So it's a portion of a larger number,
and this is the sort of stuff that you want to be doing.
Let's give another example. Let's say we're working at AirBNB.
And for those of you that don't know, AirBNB is a
company that allows you to basically rent out
your house as a sort of independent hotel to people
around the world using their platform. Would you
want, if you're a product manager AirBNB, to be tracking
a metric like total number of nights booked?
Well, actually, you would want to know that number,
but that number is not going to be very effective in
knowing whether or not you and your team
are doing a very good job.
This is because that can be affected by a whole bunch of stuff.
It can be affected by publicity and marketing,
it could be affected by any number of
other things, maybe the economy, etc.
But what we could track is the average number of
nights booked per person in a month or, let's say, six
months, whatever might work for the data that you have.
This is basically measuring a ratio, which is super important,
because the numbers are much smaller and
they are more descriptive of whether or not your product is good.
The third thing I want to point out is correlation.
You don't want to look at two metrics that are correlated
and then assume something from those that isn't true.
I'll give you an example.
So there's an old sort of metrics joke that basically says,
if you look at revenue for ice cream sales,
and then you look at a metric for the number of
people that drown in a pool and die,
those numbers, those metrics, if you looked at them
on a graph, they would track each other pretty closely.
And you know why that is? This is because people
eat ice cream in the summer, obviously, and they swim
also in the summer, because it's hot out.
But you might be led to believe, if you're not paying attention,
that when people eat more ice cream, more people drown,
which makes no sense at all.
So you have to be careful about these things.
So the next point I want to bring out is that you should
pick a metric that is actually able to be changed
and with relative ease, or you should position your metric
so that when you do make changes, the metric
is changing, either going up or down.
Here's an example of that.
Let's say that you have a particular type of user
that, let's just say, only has like one or two hours
available at all during the average day,
and there is no more time than just those two hours in a day.
In that case, you probably wouldn't want to try to maximize
the time spent in your product or in your app
beyond the two hour mark, or maybe not even measure it at all.
This is because there's some external force,
again, in our thought experiment, where the users
only have that amount of time per day.
In that case, you may want to measure something like
the number of times per week that they're using
your product, or maybe the number of times that they log in.
In that case, you might want to measure the number of times per week that the users are using your product.
Are they coming back really frequently?
We're not going to care about how much time they're spending
per day, because we assume once we've got
them near the two-hour mark, they're not going to be
able to spend more time in there anyways, depending
on sort of the nature of the product.
One more quick example for that is, let's say you're running
an e-commerce business, and you sell something
that people only buy, like, they just only buy once per month,
like, 90% of people only buy once per month,
let's say some sort of fancy clothes. In that case,
if the users are coming in once per month, and it's very
unlikely that they're going to come in more
than once per month to use your product or buy something
from your e-commerce platform, then it's going to
be very difficult to get them to come in more than that.
And, of course, we would want to try, but it's going to
be something that involves a lot more than just
our product team, it's probably going to be
marketing and all sorts of other stuff.
So what might we track instead?
Well, in that case, we might just try to get them to spend more money for that one time that they do shop with us once per month.
Let's do a really quick recap.
We know that metrics should be easily understandable,
we know that people should be able to know what they're
about as soon as they read the sort of description
of that metric, you shouldn't pick metrics based on an
erroneous correlation, like the ice cream and drowning
deaths example, you want to pick metrics that actually
do impact each other and are not just tracking
each other due to circumstance.
You also want to have a ratio or rate rather than just
a number that might go up when marketing does
some sales, or when your company gets a lot of publicity,
and we want to make sure our metrics are with
relative ease able to be affected.
So we don't want to really try to change a number or metric that
our users are very unlikely to behave differently within.
All right, so that's it for this one.
And next, we're going to talk about some metrics frameworks
to actually help you think through the process
of choosing metrics and brainstorm a little bit.
See you there.