Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Last lecture, we got introduced to sketching. Sketching is
just a simpler form of wireframing, it's actually
the first form you will use, and the vast majority of
organizations and teams out there first start by
taking pen to paper.
So we covered a pretty good way of going
about making your first sketches,
but in this lecture, let's get some practice.
So, this time, I'm going to sketch out some wireframes,
and if you guys want to follow along, continue the rest
of the lecture, if you think you got it, skip to the next
so I don't hear you complain.
All right, this time let's not do a web site or web app.
Let's do a mobile application, so let's draw out an iPhone.
All right, so what kind of app do you think we should try to make?
I think what I'm going to try to do is, let's make
a mobile application for ordering groceries.
Okay?
Grocery delivery, that's going to be the topic of the app.
The idea is, you know, kind of like a web van where you
can get on your phone and order groceries from nearby
stores to where you live. Alright, now that we have
our iPhone template, what should we start with?
Well, I'd say an easy one to start with is a navigation bar.
I'm assuming that we're going to need a navigation
bar, so I can put some space down at the bottom where
I can click some buttons. Later on, we'll fill that out.
You know, another thing that we could put instead,
we could actually instead make a log in screen. Pretty
much any app that's not a demo or any app that is
complete and something you take seriously has a log
in screen, and log in screens are also called splash pages.
So let's make that splash page or that log in page,
and I like doing this sometimes first
because it gets the juices flowing.
All right, so let's draw out the log in screen.
This is a pretty standard template I'm going to draw out.
If you guys want to use something else, again,
just go out and find your favorite app.
It literally takes four seconds.
You just hit the app icon and see what the first thing
you see is, what's the log in screen.
I'm going to put the name in the middle
and the logo at the top left, like we always do,
and then, how do you think they should be able to log in?
Well, I think it would makes sense to log in
with Facebook login and email.
Cool.
Now we have a finished screen. Now, we should ask the question "Should we link these two screens in any way
or at least draw some form of relationship between the two?"
Yeah, probably, so I'm just going to draw an arrow
from the log in screen to the main screen, and that
just shows that, you know, the log in screen is first,
and it's a linear process going from left to right.
This is actually how most people when they're sketching will do it.
They'll just use arrows.
And then, often, right next to the arrows, what button they're clicking, or a description of the interaction, or maybe an animation.
We don't need to do that.
And also, guys, keep in mind, this is supposed to be rapid.
That's why we do sketching.
No one's going to judge you based off of your ability
to draw or your ability to make something that
looks crisp, and clean, and makes sense immediately.
Remember: function, not form.
All right, great.
Now we have them linked, and for our purposes of showing other people, that's perfect, because that's going to show
them, and it makes a lot more sense to them
pretty much immediately.
Okay, what should we do on the first page?
Again, we're going to have to answer those questions that we asked ourselves as part of the exercise in the last lecture.
Remember the first question? It is
"What is the point of this screen?"
Well, the point of the main screen, I would assume, is to let people actually find a grocery store and start picking items.
I think that speed is probably important, so in the first
screen they should be able to do both those things.
All right, so let's draw it out. Let's make it so that
we can select a store that's near us, because we
obviously don't want order from the same store over
and over again, that's part of the appeal of the app, then
we put a little box where we can display the store names,
just so you know which one you are actually
operating, and then let's just draw in some boxes to show
where the favorite items or most common items
for that store would display.
All right. Awesome.
So we actually have a decent wireframe right there,
but let's put some more detail into it.
Now, let's answer the second question.
"What should users be able to do?"
Well, I think that users should be able to visually see
the grocery items, just so they can really quickly
see what's available, and that's easier for them,
so let's draw in some actual apples, and bananas, and
grapes, and that little circular oranges, you got it, in orange.
I think users should also be able to see
what the price of the items are.
And I don't need to put a range or anything,
so I'm just going to put dollar sign, dollar sign,
because I think that the price, let's just put it right
underneath the image.
I also think that, since grocery stores have so many items,
and I'm on this screen, it wouldn't make sense
to just show me the popular items, regardless of
whether or not the user asked for it, so let's put a
search box, so I'll just draw out a little search box.
Cool. Check, check, and check.
The point is to be able to find a grocery store
and start the process of ordering items.
Other things they should be able to do,
they should be able to search for their groceries,
see them, and know what they cost.
Okay, so now, let's say, if I clicked on one of the grocery items,
what do you think would happen?
Well, I'd probably go to a page where it gives more information.
Why?
Because a user needs more information about an apple,
or a pear, or whatever they're buying in order to buy it.
They're not all commodities.
We need to give more information.
All right.
So let's make a new screen, and we can connect
these just like we connected the other ones.
So, this one, we'll just call this the detail page, and then
the detail page, we'll just draw a big image
of whatever it is, let's just draw an apple
because I'm great at drawing apples.
And now, the user gets a big picture of what it is, and so
that saves us the time of answering the question
of what's the point of this screen.
Well, the point of this screen is to display the items so they can see it, and give them information so that they can purchase it.
What should they also be able to do?
Well, they should probably also be able to read about it,
so I'm going to put some squiggly lines for text.
They should probably also be able to buy it, so I'll put a buy button.
I'm going to guess that they should probably be able
to choose how many of them they're going to buy,
so I'll put a little number box where they can manipulate that.
And there you go, now you have it.
That is a pretty decent wireframe right there.
There's an enormous amount of screens I can make
after that, but I would bore you guys to tears.
Notice how, though, we went about it in a very
systematic way, very logical about it.
Always ask yourselves the questions that
we went over in the last lecture,
that'll get you out of a rut.
I always suggest starting with really easy intermediary screens
or elements that are always on the
page to get the juices flowing, to get you comfortable.
All right guys, in the next lecture, I have a treat for you,
because we're going to use a system called
POP, which is a mobile application that allows us
to take sketches and turn them into prototypes.
Interesting, right?
All right, see you in the next lecture.