Hey there.
So we learned already about how to communicate
with engineers and designers.
But how about the rest of the groups, like, let's say,
executives, sales, legal, and marketing?
Well, let's talk about executives first, and then we'll do a few tips on communicating with the other types of stakeholders.
In my early days of being a product manager,
I always struggled communicating with executives.
It was really tough.
I would send them really big emails with tons of detail,
and they would almost never get back to me.
Later, I found out that the secret to communicating
with executives is being brief.
Executives are the busiest people at the company, so sending them compact but meaningful messages shows
that you value their time.
So, instead of writing two paragraphs, write two bullet points.
"But, Cole," you'll say, "I won't be able to
give them enough information in two bullet points."
That's right.
And they don't need all the information in one e-mail.
If they want more data or information from you,
they know who to ask: you.
Secondly, when talking to executives and other roles,
like sales, always speak in terms of business effect.
By this I mean don't tell them that the user will be able
to do a certain thing in your product more
frequently, but tell them about what it means.
Does it mean more or less revenue?
Does it mean a change in a specific company metric?
If so, tell them that.
Thirdly, communicate in a style that they like best.
Some executives don't like email as it consumes so much time for them and maybe even their assistant reads it for them.
In this case, a better approach might be to give them
a really quick update in the hallway, or at lunch,
or at your next meeting.
Okay, so here's another couple of tips for not only executives,
but all sorts of stakeholders in general.
Number one: it pays off to talk to people on each team
as much as possible. Whenever you get a chance,
hold a meeting, take them to lunch, or just find an
excuse to talk to people from different teams,
like marketing or sales. Number two: ensure that other
teams and people understand that you know the user
base, the technology, and the business very well.
This makes them much more confident about
the decisions you're making in the product.
Number three: update them on the latest developments
as frequently as possible,
but make it clear whether or not they should be
replying or if you just meant to send them an update.
One really good way to do this is, if you have an
internal company blog or wiki, you can just post things
there and they can read it if they want to.
But the important thing here is to be communicating frequently.
Number four: whenever you're updating outside stakeholders
on progress or the completion of a feature,
be sure to tell them about the reason the solution is the way it is.
Tell them a story about the other options you considered
and why maybe those ones did not turn out to be ideal.
So tell them that story about how you got to the product
or solution that ended up being the one that
you built. Alright everyone, with those tips,
you are really well armed to communicate
effectively with a broad range of stakeholders.
This puts you way ahead in the game.
So be sure to keep this section in mind and
frequently come back if you need to.
It's going to take a little bit of time to get this, like,
really ingrained in your head, but you'll learn over time.
I will see you all in the next lecture.