Hey guys, welcome back to the course. So, in this lecture,
we're going to get some practice with Balsamiq.
We're going to create a web site from scratch using
all the tools we covered in the previous lecture.
Now, for those of you guys out there that don't want
to follow along or don't feel like you need practice,
skip the lecture
and I'll see you in the next lecture.
For the rest of you guys, let's get started.
Alright, remember what I said in the last lecture?
Balsamiq is incredibly simple and incredibly fast.
So simple and so fast that in the ten minutes we spent
in the last lecture, or whatever it was, learning how
to use this system, that was all we need to create
an in-depth web site. And to prove my point,
let's go ahead and make a web site.
To prove my point, let's go ahead and make a web site.
I'm going to make a copy of YouTube. YouTube,
when I speak about YouTube, I'm not talking about
the home page, I'm talking about what the screen looks
like when you're actually viewing a subpage.
I would go to All, got to the browser window. In the browser
window, I can type in YouTube, and there you go, see? It
shows it up in YouTube.
Let's expand the size.
Okay.
Now, let's make something like where you'd watch the videos.
Where is the media player? I can go to Media.
Now, Media is where you're going to insert pretty much
anything you want, like, it could be associated with
images, here's a progress bar, here's a street map.
So I'll pull this out so you can see it.
That's like a Google Maps street map. Here's a video player.
So let' say that this is, you know, where you watch videos.
So let's say, oh, we want to put a search bar at the top.
You can use the search bar, it's what's called a search box,
put it at the top, where you would be searching for
your videos.
Let's see.
I love this about Balsamiq.
You can just use icons and they have a lot of the logos
that you would commonly use, like, they have the
Twitter logo, and the Instagram logo, and pretty much
everything you'd want for the most common social
platforms. I'm going to do that, look,
now we have our logo - YouTube.
Let's make that little section over here
where it shows you suggested videos.
What I would do for that, since they're thumbnails, I'd
use an image. Now, images just come out like boxes, which is
perfect for what we want.
I'll just call it "Video" so that
our developer and our graphic designer knows what that is.
With image placeholders, what you can do is you can add
borders and you can actually upload images, insert
them into Balsamiq. So what you do is you just double tap it,
browse for a file.
Everybody loves cats.
So, cats, this is a cool feature I like,
you can just sketch it. If I don't sketch it, it's going to
insert this image with the whole color, it's going to
look kind of weird with the whole black and white thing going on.
So I'll just say sketch it. Alright, let's try to put it back
into the size that you'd expect.
I guess that looks weird.
Now we want to put, let's put a border on it, yeah that looks better. There you go.
Now it looks kind of like one of those
videos you'd have suggested to you.
Now let's add the text that would go next to it.
So, again, this is how I do it. Remember, string, string of text,
I'll put it as the title, so I'll call it "Cat video,"
super original. Since it's the title, I want to make it bold.
Increase the size just a little bit.
Okay.
Now, you can use your keyboard too to move things around.
So if I just go left, it's going to move it one pixel left.
Right, up, down, you get the point. Then right below that,
so now if I want to put text right below it,
all I want to do is hit "Duplicate."
I'll put it right below it, and let's change this, it's called "by," let's just call it the "Cat Person Person," because everybody knows a
cat person, but nobody knows a cat person person.
Let's see. And we'll make it smaller, get rid of the bolding. Here we go.
And let's put a view counter.
That's usually just a number, so let's say
a million people watched this video.
And usually that is a little bit smaller.
I think it's pretty believable.
So what I'm going to do is I want to create this little grouping,
and I want to make it go all the way
down the screen, which is typically what you see in YouTube.
So what we do, click it, and we're going to group these together. Remember how we do group? We hit "Group."
Now they're together.
Now, when I copy my group,
you could even exit out, doesn't really matter.
Copy my group. Voila.
Let's match the grids up, and here you go,
those are suggested videos.
Now, maybe I wanted to put a container around that,
something light, I'll just go to shape again, you know,
a shape,
I am just going to pick a rectangle right here, add it right here.
I want to expand it over. See? Notice how it covered it?
Now, Balsamiq has a layering, kind of like Photoshop.
If you used Photoshop before, it has layers.
The way that you would want this to fade to the back
is you would use this little subgroup.
This will send it back one, oh no, this will send it all the
way to the back, so this will be the bottom of your...
Imagine this is kind of like paper laying on top of each other.
This would be the bottom piece of paper, if you click this,
it's going to bring it all the way to the top,
so it's going to cover anything behind it.
I just want to send it back until it's behind the cat videos.
All right, so the rest of it really is just kind of tiny little details.
It's up to you how much detail you honestly want to put in here.
We can pretend like this is a, here's the placeholder for the image of
whoever made the video, we can add in text again,
say, the name of the video.
"My secret webcam video." Because they want it to
be a secret, but they also want the entire world
to see it, and let's put this realistically much larger.
Drag this down, add some space.
We can add those thumbs up and thumbs down.
Just pick an icon, put it over here, you could even just search for "thumbs." There you go. I'm going to make that small.
Makes sense, right?
And you can even copy it there, right next to it, and then just find another, like, thumbs again, so it's
thumbs down, like the video.
And then we'll just stick someone's face on it,
because it's a webcam, right?
You get the drift now.
You can put an enormous amount of detail into
Balsamiq if you want to, but, as you've noticed, that
really did not take me a lot of time,
and I have a wireframe of a video.
You're obviously going to put more time and effort
into whatever you actually build yourself,
but once you actually get acquainted with it, hopefully
by now you are acquainted, you can really move
at lightning speed and you can really
produce these very, very quickly.
Now, if I wanted to make the next screen at YouTube,
I could just go up to File, hit "Clone current mockup,"
and look, I have the same exact thing, and I can just
move from here and start deleting things wherever
I want, and changing things around.
Now, when you're done and you're happy with what
you've got, all you've got to do is just go up to File
and you can save it as whatever you want it to be.
Make sure to back it up. If you guys are on an older
computer, make sure that you don't have tons and
tons and tons of tabs open, it can really kind of slow down
your computer, but otherwise just export it
to whatever you want.
I like PDF, that's one of the easiest to view,
or you can just do it as an image,
that's what you end up sending to your graphic designer
or your developer, and they will thank you a thousand times over.