Hey and welcome back. In this lecture, we're going to be talking about one more metrics framework that will
help you out with deciding on which metrics you should
look at tracking for a new product or business.
This framework is a little bit lighter than the last one,
a little bit lighter than the heart framework
we just talked about.
It's pretty short and sweet and it's pretty popular in Silicon Valley.
This framework is also really commonly used
with software as a service businesses.
So the framework is called AARRR, as in like
"Aarrr, I'm a pirate!" Kind of weird, right?
But the guy that came up with it,
Dave McClure, he's a venture capital guy out in Silicon Valley, actually he's a partner in 500
Startups, which is a venture capital firm,
so he knows a little bit about what he's talking about,
and he came up with this framework himself because
he was investing in companies, and he said like,
"These are the metrics that I like to see,
these are the ones that you should focus on."
The reason it has that weird name is because it's AARRR,
a five-step process: acquisition, activation,
retention, referral, and then revenue.
This framework is pretty popular with entrepreneurs
or people doing much smaller businesses.
So the general idea here is that, for each of these five stages,
you pick a metric that you want to measure.
And again, just like the heart framework, this is a way
of getting us to think about the lifecycle of
our user. We'll go over each one of these really quickly
because we've talked a lot about all of this so far,
just want to make sure that you're aware of this one.
The first one - acquisition - is just like it sounds.
We need a metric for us acquiring a user.
That means the user went to our web site or
downloaded our app, one of these. They have arrived,
they have, they know about you, and now they are indicating
their interest to begin using you by taking that step.
The second one - activation - I've talked a little bit
about it already, it just means that the customer
that we've acquired is now activated.
So they've signed up, or they've entered their info
on our mailing list, or they have integrated the app
with another app that you're considering to be an important step.
It just means that they are now active,
and you can define that however you want.
Some people just say "Okay, if they've
made an account, they're activated."
Other people will say "Okay, they have to make an account
and then they have to do one small thing, so that
we know that they are now officially active, let's say,
adding a profile picture, or connecting their phone
book contact list to find their friends on your app,
or something like that.
Pretty easy.
The third one is retention.
It means, just like we've talked about before,
they come back, they're repeat
users. Notice how there's not so much
emphasis on engagement here?
This is because the framework just assumes that
you're maximizing engagement in the first place and
that if you're having someone being retained, well,
they're going to be engaged, otherwise they wouldn't
have come back to be retained.
So an example of trying to optimize your retention
rate would be to send the user a notification to
their phone if they haven't logged in in like a week or two weeks,
or send them an email drip campaign.
You know, when you sign up for those e-mails and then
they e-mail you like once a week, and then they,
email you like once every two weeks, and then once a month,
that is trying to get you to come back.
And the fourth one is referral, which means our users are happy enough with their app that they're going to refer it to others.
And this doesn't just mean user happiness.
In fact, it's focused, the way this thing is built,
or the way that it's framed from Dave McClure's mind
is that you can optimize it beyond just making the users happy enough to talk to their friends in real life about it.
In fact, you could put a feature in where they can share it with their friends, and maybe get some credit for doing that.
You might have seen this with Dropbox, where,
when you sign up and you invite a friend, you get
some free storage, this sort of thing.
So, referral - that's easy.
They're going to share it with others.
And the last one is revenue, that means you are making
revenue from this user and that is the further step
down the funnel.
So if you're a consumer company, that means eventually
that they may be buying a subscription, or they've
bought like a pro version, or a full fledged version
of your program or your app, or if you're a company
that's free to use, then maybe they are seeing advertisements,
and you can gauge that per user you're
making this much money off of them.
The goal here is just to quantify the revenue
per user that you're getting.
So that's it, just those five stages, and the way this framework is meant to be used is you just use those five stages as a guide.
So, for each one of the five, those five steps down the funnel,
you just think of a metric that you can
measure that will tell you how you're doing on each one
of those steps, because each one leads to the other.
You're not going to get revenue from someone
unless they are first activated,
so you have to get a lot of people acquired, a lot of
people activated, and then go all the way down the
funnel, and you want to get that bottom bucket revenue
as big as possible, so you optimize the metrics all the way down.
It's just an easy way of thinking about that journey for the user.
So if you want to learn more about the AARRR metrics framework or pirate metrics framework from Dave McClure, just Google it.
There's a slide deck and a presentation he gave
that sort of put him on the map for this.
He became very popular because of this.
It was meant originally as his suggestion to companies
that he's investing in or people that want him
to invest in them, because he feels these are the most important
to venture capitalists and those types of people.
So if you're in Silicon Valley or making a startup, and you
want to get some investment money or something,
this is a great place to start, because these things
do matter a lot to venture capital investors and
other investors in general. That's it for this lecture.
It wasn't very difficult.
AARRR, pirate metrics, Dave McClure, good stuff to
know. I promise you, if you know these two metrics frameworks,
and you tell people about them, or you're in
a job interview and you mention them,
or anything like that, they're going to be impressed.
I'll see you in the next lecture.