Hey everyone, welcome back.
I want to give you a really quick taste of what the day to day activities are for a product manager.
So we're going to go hour by hour through my typical day at the office. So I get to the office at about
9:00 AM and the first thing you do is check e-mails and technology news. Keeping up with the industry
is really important as a product manager.
Some places that I go to keep up with the latest tech news are places like TechMeme.com, Hacker News,
Launch Ticker, Product Hunt, and I'll even type my company name into Twitter and just see what people
are saying about our latest features.
About an hour later, at 10:00 AM I go look at our team's metrics dashboard and I really look for any
weird behavior against our release logs.
So if something's going weird in the metrics in a direction we don't think is optimal, then what we
do is we just look at what happened with the releases lately and try to track down the reason that that
metric is being affected. At this point,
I'll also go and check out customer feedback from emails to support our community operations team.
I'll look at our App Store reviews to see what people are saying about a recent release we've made and
I'll even go hang out in our beta forum for a bit to see what sort of issues people are having or if
they have any feedback for us. About an hour later, at 11:00 AM, we have our team stand up meeting.
So our team gets together and we look at our sprint board and our backlog.
And then each of us says what we're working on at the time, what we recently completed, and if there's
any blockers or if we need help with anything.
I also try to make it a point to tell our team - the engineers and designers that work with me - what metrics
look like lately, you know, that morning, if they're looking good or bad, and if there's any interesting
things people are saying in terms of the product feedback. This is especially if we've had a recent release
from our team and everyone's excited to see, you know, how the users are liking it. So the stand up goes until about
11:15 AM because it's only a 10-15 minute meeting.
After that, I talk with the team designer about our user problems and the latest feedback.
We may even go to the whiteboard to sketch out some solutions that we might be thinking about or just
work on things we've already been brainstorming over the last week or a few days.
So at about noon, 12:00, if we're planning any upcoming features, I'll take some time to write specs,
tickets, and user stories, and insert requirements or wire frames from the designer into those tickets.
At 1:00 PM, depending on the day,
I usually take a little bit of time to test the latest mobile release for our feature.
This is known as the alpha release.
This comes before beta and we'll talk more about this a little bit later in the course. So I test
this on Android and iOS on these two test devices I have.
And then our designer helps with this as well,
and both he and I report our bugs and issues that we found during testing into a new ticket inside of
Jira, our product management tool.
So from 2:00 PM and onwards, the stuff I do changes drastically from day to day.
So here's a few things I may do depending on the day and what's going on in the rest of the company.
If it's a Monday, then I meet with the team to do sprint planning, or sprint grooming, or a retrospective on the last sprint. On most days,
it's likely that I hold 10 meetings with other product managers or stakeholders to work on cross team planning
or get a feature cleared from other stakeholders.
An example of this would be to meet with the sales team and tell them that something is changing.
Some other random frequent happenings that are sprinkled throughout the week are things like meeting
with our data science team to discuss the recent test that we ran and look at exploratory data from user
behavior to help my designer and myself come up with the right solutions for the next iteration.
I also might attend some user tests of our new features or present metrics milestones to executives, investors,
or other product managers.
Sometimes we work with a team to present recent accomplishments of the company. We do this on Fridays
so the company, everyone gets to demo kind of what they've done.
Our team will also hold open houses to ensure that everyone in the company has the ability to talk to
our team and align around any questions or feedback that they have for us.
I also meet a lot with new employees on product vision and direction to orient them.
This is really important to make sure that all the new employees coming in understand what each component
of the product does and which teams are responsible for what.
So as you can see there's really not a typical day as a product manager and it's never dull.
The days are always dynamic but some things like checking industry news and your metrics and meeting
with your own team never change.
I'll see you all in the next video.