Hey guys, welcome back to the course. So, last lecture
we talked about how do you reach out and get these
potential customers or customers you already have
to connect with you and give you feedback.
It's a bit of an ask to get someone either on the phone or in person, so you need to have some skill with it.
So let's get some practice in the actual realm where
you're going to be contacting them - your email client.
So I just kind of whipped open this email right here
and we can use this as a practicing space.
I wrote at the bottom, remember the three things:
short, personable, and valuable.
We need to be short, four to seven sentences, less is more.
Personal,
we need to make sure that whatever we say to the person is specific to them, doesn't feel like a robot is saying it, and valuable,
we need to highlight that they can get some sort of
benefit from talking to us. Alright, building off of
what we said in the last lecture on how in general people are probably going to read only one or two
sentences of what you send them, since this is a cold email,
we need to front load our emails and make sure that
whatever we write that's personal to them, we make
sure that's at the beginning. You can make a crucial mistake
by using your template at the beginning of your e-mail.
That's what they read, they think it's an auto-system
sending it to them, and they bail.
So the first thing you want to do is write
one to two sentences of an introduction.
Now, when I say introduction, I don't mean
introduce yourself necessarily.
One of the things that people generally dislike is that
in the first couple of sentences they hear you
talk about yourself and not them.
That's another crucial mistake people make
when reaching out to people.
They make it all about me, me, me, me, me, when in reality
it needs to be about the person who's receiving
it, because they're the ones that are, you know,
you're asking them to respond.
This is where we get personal, and whatever
you write here, it needs to be specific.
I read your blog post on [...], it was great. I've noticed
that you are struggling with X feature and our product.
I saw that you had a problem with this. A lot of people
have that problem and I'd like to help you.
The next thing you want to do is generally
write two sentences of why you want to talk.
Now, this is your opportunity to insert
the value portion of your email.
Once they get to this section, this is where you kind of
hook them in and give them an incentive to actually respond.
Now, two classic go-to ways of adding value
in these cold emails is to do one of two things.
One - you can say, you know, "I think I can help you
use our product better," in the case of a post product
customer, or in the case of a pre-product potential customer,
you say something along the lines of how
you specifically want to solve their problem.
Those always seem to be the go-to sentences. You see this
pretty much everywhere. If you've ever received
an e-mail, they probably said that. "I would like to
solve this problem for you" or "I can show you how you
can get more out of our product."
Alternatively, if you didn't want to use those two,
you can go a different route.
Now, there are three different avenues or paths
I think you can use that are quite effective.
One is instead of just saying generically
"You have a problem, I want to solve it,"
you appeal to pride.
Pride is a very, very useful thing to use
when you want someone to respond to you.
What I mean is you have the opportunity to say things like,
"You appear to be an expert on [...]."
"You would be able to give us so much valuable information."
Everyone likes to hear that someone has recognized you know more information or you are better in some
way than everybody else.
If you want to appeal to the pride of someone who's
an existing customer, you could say things like, "You have
been a customer so much longer than all of our other customers" or "It seems like you understand our product
much better than other customers."
That relates back to what we talked in the previous lecture.
Make them feel special.
That is one technique that is always open to you
as a product manager and it is very effective.
The second avenue you can go down is appeal to money.
You can use this section, this two-sentence section,
to say why you want to talk, and then incentivize
them by saying that there's some sort of monetary reward
at the end of that rainbow. Who doesn't like money?
The third thing you can do is imply association.
So what I mean by association is you can imply that
you know people or are well situated in a space
that the person you're emailing cares about.
Oftentimes what you can do is you can look at their LinkedIn profile, see what space they're in, and you can
imply that by connecting with you, you know
a lot of other people, that in itself is valuable.
Some people do that, some people are more than willing to talk
just because they think you're a valuable contact.
After that, we have one last thing that you
want to do, and this one is amazingly crucial.
The last thing you want to do is schedule a time.
Now, do you say, "Are you willing to talk?"
No.
Do you say, "Do you have any time next week?"
What you say is "Are you available
Wednesday at 3:30 PM Pacific Standard Time?"
What you're doing here is you're reducing the friction
in between them responding and talking to you.
If you say next week and they're interested, the next time
they'll say "Yes, which day?" and you'll say, "How
about Tuesday?" and they'll say, "Great, propose a time."
It just goes on, and on, and on, you went from one email
to six emails. If you just pick a time and say it,
they're much more likely to say yes
and you don't run the risk of losing them throughout
that process of trying to schedule them.
Don't forget that one - you've probably seen
that technique in your inbox.
Another pro-tip you can use in conjunction with this is
use some of those online scheduling softwares, like Calendly.
There's a ton of them where you don't even have to suggest a time, you just let them click through and pick a time.
All right, so let's look at a well-crafted e-mail that
follows that same template we just went over.
All right, so it says "Hi Sam, I read your article on volunteering your professional skills in Guatemala - it was really inspiring."
"I'm looking to travel more and you've got me thinking about incorporating volunteering when I do." So
right there, that is two sentences.
It's personal. It connects it to his article on
volunteering in Guatemala.
You showed that you read their article and you understood it,
and you're responding because of it.
Now, the next sentence is what we call the value section.
It's just divided for purposes of reading it.
It looks like they still used two sentences, but they said,
"I have a software company trying to improve remote
medical record coding," and then it says, "I'm not looking to sell anything, but since you have so much expertise
with remote coding, I'd love to get your advice on
our products so we don't build the wrong thing."
This is a masterful set of sentences.
Whenever someone sees "I have a software company..."
they usually cringe, but if it's followed
by "trying to improve remote record coding, which is
something you do and probably are frustrated with,"
it instantly sounds like this could be something
that is game-changing.
Then they move on and we use that technique
where they said "I'm not in sales."
"I'm not trying to sell you something."
And then they appeal to their pride by saying "You have expertise."
So what's the value of responding to this e-mail?
Well, it is the fact that, one, you can help them, two, you have
a specific expertise that would benefit them
more than talking to someone else,
and three, and this is the big one,
they're building something that could actually solve your problems.
And then the last one is "If you're available, I'd love to
chat for just 20 minutes Thursday or Friday morning."
You know what I'm going to complain about in that one: they didn't specifically say a time or a set of times, but that's pretty good.
Did you also notice that this came in at six sentences?
So it's very well within our four to seven guideline.
All right, guys, go out there and shoot off some e-mails into the wild, just make sure that you follow this
format or at least you stick to the core principles of being short, personal, and valuable. If you want to use this template,
start with an introduction, then add value, then schedule them.
Make it short, make it valuable.
Alright, guys, see you in the next lecture.