All right. So welcome to a brand-new module and I'm going to show you what you'll be making by
the end of this module.
The app that we're going to be building and improving upon throughout this module is a To-Do list app.
And it's inspired by one of my favorite to-do list apps which is the clear app. And what it allows you
to do is to create new to-do lists,
for example, your travel to-do list, and it shows up as individual color to-do list. And you can select
one of them to go into that particular list and add new items to it.
For example, "Buy Apples," "Buy Pears."
And you'll see that as you add new items, your to-do list start staking on this beautiful gradient going
from lighter to darker as you add new items.
Now, you will be able to check these items off, but you'll also be able to swipe to delete them.
Now, you'll be able to search your to-do list.
For example, let's search for something like "Apple," hit search, and you see all the to-do list items that
contain that word.
And the best part of all is that all of this data is saved and persisted locally on the simulator or
on your physical iPhone device.
So that means that if you go ahead and terminate your app, say, if your app got updated or if your iOS
version got updated, or if you bought a new phone, then all of your user's data is persisted on the device
with no internet connection required.
And if we have a look inside Shopping List, we still have all of our items.
So that is what we're going to learn all about in this module. And in the process, you're going to learn
about all the different ways that you can persist data locally, including user defaults for small bits
of data, or things like quotable where if you want to tap into the documents folder inside your iPhone,
and be able to save items there, and you'll also gonna  learn about using Core Data with a sequel like back in
database, and you're going to be creating a relational database of your own to power your to-do list
app.
And finally, I'm going to show you how you can do everything that you can do with Core Data by using one
of my favorite services which is called Realm.
And by the end of this, you will have created a relational database as a backend and you're going to
learn about how you can code up the front end to make it look as beautiful as we have here.
So I hope you're excited because I'm really excited.
So once you're ready, get started over on the next lesson.