Hello everyone and welcome to Learn App Marketing.
This is Angela from the London App Brewery
and in this course I'm going to be covering all aspects of app marketing and how you can launch your
app into the app stores for success.
So this is a huge topic
and I could literally talk about it for days and days on end.
So you'll find that there's a large number of modules that cover various aspects of app marketing from
idea validation to the how you list your app on the app Store to apps store optimization and much much
more.
Basically everything that you need to know in order to make your app a success.
So without further ado let's get started.
And as always if you have any questions or anything that you want to add to the topics that we're talking
about to start a discussion et cetera feel free to put that at the end of the video and you can view
the comments section as a discussion forum for anything that you've come across,
anything that's worked or not worked for you so that everybody can benefit.
All right.
So let's get started.