All right, guys. We're on to another module of advanced Swift. And in this module, we're going to be building
a calculator app.
So we're going to be using--
So we're going to be using the interface that we designed in our Auto Layout Module a couple of lessons
back and we're going to be giving it some functionality this time. And through the process of building
this calculator app,
we're going to learn about a number of advanced Swift concepts.
So this is what the finished product will look like.
So we could multiply numbers, for example, like this, or we could make it into a percentage, or divided
by 6, whatever it is that we need it to do. So through the process of building this app, we're going
to learn about Swift Structures, otherwise known as structs. And we're also going to look at when you would
use struct versus classes. Then we're going to look at things, such as internal/external parameters and
what that underscore actually means in the code that you see, as well as talking about access levels,
such as private, public, open, internal, et cetera.
And finally, we're also going to introduce Swift Tuples.
So as you can see, it's a jam-packed module full of more advanced parts of Swift. And this section of
Advanced Swift Concepts is more about making your code more manageable and easier to maintain.
So we're not really learning new things in order to be able to do more stuff with our apps, but it's more about making
our codebase more maintainable, so that if we collaborate or if it gets more and more complex, then it's
still manageable because of all of these neat tools and concepts that we're going to learn.
So as I always say, make sure that you don't skip any of the lectures and that you've already done all
of the previous modules before you arrive here.
I know that there's a lot of things that would be neat to just look up and quickly learn, but unfortunately,
a lot of programming builds on top of other concepts
and it's not so easy to just dip in and out of some of these advanced topics, and it's very easy to quickly
get stuck.
But if you've completed all the modules up till now and everything makes sense, then feel free to continue
and we're going to deep dive into all of these advanced Swift topics.