Hey. It’s Angela here again.
And I'm here to give you a virtual pat on the back for getting this far and completing the last module.
Now, today I want to talk about what you should do when you feel really frustrated, like when you feel
overwhelmed with all the things that you need to know and they all seem impossible,
and you’re getting stuck on like, you know, thing after thing, and you just feel like frustrated.
What should you do?
The first thing you should do is take a break.
You've probably been staring at that piece of code for too long.
And, you know, like sometimes when I stare at my own name like for too long it starts looking weird, like
is that really how you spell Angela, like A n g l?
Like you know like if you are not getting a moment to just let your brain think about something else
it will get stuck much much easier.
So take a break.
You know, sometimes sleep on it.
The best solutions come to me when I think about my problem
before I go to sleep, and then the next morning I wake up and I try to tackle that thing that I got stuck
on yesterday. For some miraculous reason it's like I set my brain is like working on it while I'm sleeping.
But the next day solutions come to me just so much easier.
So take a break, let your brain rest, go and exercise, go for like a jog around the block, or, you know, a
fast paced walk if you're not already into jogging like I am. I try to go for like a 30 minute swim at the
local pool if I can and just like the sort of silence underwater when I'm swimming and just being enveloped
by water somehow really helps me clear my thoughts and it makes me feel more calm and when I come back
to my problem I just seem to be better at solving it.
So don't be so hard on yourself. Don’t just sit there and rip your hair out and be like “Why can't I do
this? Why is my code not working?”
We've all been there before but it's not the right thing to do.
Take a break.
Have a moment to yourself.
Think about something else.
Look at something else and then come back to it.
It’s always going to be there for you.
Your problems don’t just run away.