So our app is looking pretty nice, but up till now, there's always been a really serious bug that we haven't
yet discovered in our app.
Now, if you've been playing around with the app quite a bit, you might have discovered this bug already.
But if you haven't, let me show you what it is.
Now, I'm going to add a whole bunch of new items into our itemArray, so that when I run my app, I'm going
to have more than three cells.
In fact, I'm going to have more cells than the table view can possibly display.
So when I scroll, you can see that even though the table view is at "j,"
if I keep going, it goes all the way down to "o," right?
So, now if I click on the first cell and it checks the first cell, and I scroll down to the bottom,
you can see that for some bizarre reason, our cell that's called "n" is also checked.
And if I uncheck it and I scroll back, my first cell is no longer checked.
So what on earth is going on here and what is happening with all this strange behavior?
Well, the answer to this lies in the fact that table view cells
gets reused, and that's what this line means when we're calling dequeueReusableCell,
right?
We're saying that go and find that prototype cell code TodoItemsCell inside Main.storyboard and
generate a whole bunch of it that we can reuse.
So that means when the first cell gets rolled off the table view and it's no longer visible, it actually
goes all the way around and comes back underneath as a new reusable cell.
So how can we prove that this is true?
Do you remember the last time when I asked you as a challenge, why is it that we need this
tableView.dequeueReusableCell method, instead of something like let cell equals a new object of type UITableViewCell.
and we say the style is, let's say, default, reuseIdentifier is the same as we've got here, so that reusable
prototype cell that we had. I'm just going to comment that out and let's run it.
Now, if I check the first object and I scroll my table view until my cell disappears off the screen and
I pull it back, you'll see that that checkmark has disappeared, and that's because the checking or
unchecking, I'm setting a property on the cell. And once the cell disappears off the screen, it gets deallocated
and destroyed.
And when I scroll it back, I'm actually getting a brand-new cell that's getting this message put in.
Now, on the other hand, say, if I use dequeueReusableCell, then in this case, when I check the first cell, I scroll
it up and at the point when that cell disappears off the screen, it comes around the table view and gets
reinitialized at the bottom as a new table view cell. And because it's being reused, that property that
checked accessory is still present here. And that's why we're getting this rather odd behaviors because
we're reusing our cells.
So we found the problem and the problem is that we need to associate a property, not with the cell, but
with our data.
So in order for us to assign a checkmark or no checkmark to each of these items, we need a way to be
able to associate each item with a property checked or unchecked.
Now, how can we do that?
We certainly can't do it using just a plain old array.
But if you pause the video and have a think about how you can associate a property with each of these
items, and see if you can come up with the solution.
All right.
So some of the solutions that you guys might have thought of were maybe instead of using an array, it's
maybe to use a dictionary where you can have key-value pairs, or at a much better solution, would be creating
a model,
and we've spoken about MVC in the past when we did Quizzler. And now this is another scenario where you
start to see the beauty and the reasons why we need to start separating our models, our views, and our controllers.
So let's go ahead and build a data model where each of our items are objects that can have properties
including the title of the item, and also a done or not done Boolean.
So this is a good time point to pause the video and build a new class called item which we can use to
store two properties, one property is a string called title which is where we're going to save the titles
of our to-dos, and the other one is called done which is a Boolean property where we're going to save
whether if the item was checked off or not.
So pause the video and give that a go.
All right.
So let's go over to File, New File, and let's create a brand-new Swift File.
Next, we're gonna call our file Item and we're gonna put our Item into its own folder,
so New Group from Selection. And the folder is going to be called Data Model. And we'll make a New Group
with our TodoListViewController and we'll call it Controllers, and we'll also while we're at it,
might as well put Main.storyboard into a Views folder.
All right.
And finally, I'm just gonna put the Assets and the LaunchScreen together as a group, and I'll call it
Supporting Files. That just gets rid of it and declutters and makes our structure a little bit more clear.
All right, let's head into Item and we're going to create a new class that's called Item.
Now, of course, you don't actually have to name your class the same as the file name,
but in 99.999 recurring cases,
everybody does this, and it will be very, very odd if these two are not the same,
and it's very confusing.
So try to keep these two exactly the same.
Okay.
So we'll have a property called title and this is going to be a string.
And by default, we'll say it's just an empty string. And then we're gonna create another property called
done
and this is going to be a Boolean. And by default, all items will start off as being not done,
so we'll set that as false.
So let's go ahead and hit save and go back to our TodoListViewController, and we can start creating
some of these items.
So I'm just going to common out this line and I'm going to create a new item and I'm going to use our
Item class to do that.
And our new Item is a new object of the type item and newItem.title is going to be equal to this.
And instead of having an array of hardcoded string objects, I'm going to turn this itemArray into an
array of Item objects.
So none of what we've done so far should be new to you because we've done all of this and more inside
Quizzler.
So if you're at all confused about MVC or models-views-controllers, then be sure to have a look back
at the Quizzler module where we go into this in much more detail.
So, now we can say itemArray.append and we're going to pend the newElement which is called
newItem.
So I'm just gonna go and copy and paste this for times' sake and I'm going to amend the code so that
we end up with newItem2 and newItem3. In addition to that, in order for our code to work,
we need to fix it in a couple of places because we're changing from an array of strings to an array
of item objects.
So if we go down here, itemArray.count is still valid because we have an array that has this property
.count.
It doesn't matter if it's an array of strings or array of objects.
But this part, where we set the cell.textLabel.text property, we need to change because itemArray
at indexPath.row is going to return an item object.
And what we need to do is we actually need to tap into its title property using the dot notation and
we also need to change the code where we're adding new items.
So here where we're saying self.itemArray.append(textField.text!) That doesn't really work.
Instead we have to create a newItem that is of the class Item, and we're going to say newItem.title
= textField.text, and then we can say self.itemArray. append, and the thing that we append is
now going to be our newItem.
And now if we hit run, let's see what happens.
So our app is now working using item objects, instead of a hardcoded array, but we still haven't fixed
our checkmark problem because we haven't yet changed the done property
when we toggle the checkmark. Also, we've not updated the code for our add button yet.
In fact, if you click on the add button now, the Apple crash.
But let's do one thing at a time, let's fix the done property first, and we'll tackle the add button in
one of the upcoming lessons.
So inside didSelectRowAt indexPath,
let's set the property of the selected item. So we can tap into itemArray and we can tap into the item
at indexPath.row,
i.e., the current item object that's selected, and we can set the done property to equal the opposite
of what it used to be.
So, if it used to be false, then we want to change it to true, and if it's used be true, then we want to change
it to false.
Now, the long way of doing this is by saying if itemArray [indexPath.row].done = false, then
in that case, we want to set the itemArray [indexPath.row].done to true.
Otherwise, we're going to say itemArray [indexPath.row].done = false, and that's what's
at the toggling, right?
And we can add a bit of code to our selfForRowAt indexPath which if you remember is the delegate method
that figures out how we should display each of the cells. And we can say if itemArray[indexPath.row]
.done = true, then in that case, we're going to set the cell.accessoryType
= checkmark,
and otherwise, we're going to set the cell.accessoryType = .none.
So that means we can get rid of these three lines of code.
Now, our code is incredibly wordy at the moment, but it's good to have it like this when we can test it
and see if it works before we start refactoring and making things look a bit simpler and cutting down
our lines of code.
So, now when we select our cells, you can see that we've actually broken our app because while it's selecting
and deselecting, it's not changing the checkmark one bit.
Now, why might that be?
The reason is because cellForRowAt indexPath is called initially when the table view gets loaded up.
And at that time point, none of our items are done,
so none of them get an accessory mark.
So if we change one of these, let's make the first one, for example, newItem.done = true,
then you can run your app and confirm to yourself that your code is actually working, this part,
or we say, if itemArray[indexPath.row].done, then make the checkmark.
It's working because you can see when we first load up our app, you see that checkmark there.
So the problem that we have to solve then is how do we get this delegate method to trigger again once
we've changed the items done property.
So the magical method here is tableView.reloadData. And we've seen this before and we've used
it before in FlashChat.
But what it basically does is that it forces the table view to call its Datasource Methods again, so
that it reloads the data that's meant to be inside.
So if we go ahead and put a print statement here, "cellForRowAt indexPath Called," you can see that
it got called three times iterating through our array of items when the table view first loaded up.
And now when I select one of these cells and I trigger the didSelectRow delegate method and we've
set our done properties and we get to this line where it says tableView.reloadData, then we're
going to see it called a couple more times.
So watch as I select one of these and you can see that we've got three more printouts of
cellForRowAt indexPath because the table view is refreshed and it's called that delegate method cellForRowAt indexPath
three more times for every single item we have in our array. And now our checkmarks also work,
right?
Brilliant.
So, now let's check and make sure that we've solved that bug that we had earlier on.
So if we go underneath the three items that we carefully initialized and appended, I'm going to paste
in just a whole bunch of appends of our newItem3 to the end of our itemArray, and that just adds
way more items so that we can actually fill up our table view.
So, now, say, if I check these first two cells and I scroll down to the bottom, you can see that we no longer
have that cell reuse problem, and it's because in every single one of these cells, were checking to see
what is the done property for each item, and we're displaying the checkmark depending on what that property
is whether if it's true or false.
So, now that we've confirmed we've solved that bug, let's go back and refactor our code. And I'm gonna
get rid of all of this.
Let's go back and refactor our code so that everything is more succinct.
So the first thing that I want to change is all of this and this is very, very inelegant, and I'll show
you why. Because instead of doing all of this, what I could have said is itemArray[indexPath.row]
.done property equals the opposite of !itemArray[indexPath.row]
.done. So that single line replaces all of these,
what, five lines of code,
and it does exactly the same thing.
It sets the done property on the current item in the itemArray to the opposite of what it is right
now.
If it's true, it becomes false. If it's false, it becomes true. And it's all using this NOT operator,
basically reversing what it used to be. Because Booleans can only have one or two states,
true or false,
so if we put the NOT true, then it becomes false.
If we put NOT false, then it becomes true. So we can go ahead and delete all of that.
Now, the next thing that I want to address is I'm going to delete these two lines because we don't need
it anymore.
And here, instead of using itemArray[indexPath.row many times, I'm just going to create a new
constant code item and I'm going to set it to equal itemArray[indexPath.row].
So this item is now the item that we're currently trying to set up for the cell.
So then instead of writing this, I can simply write item.title. Instead of writing this,
I can simply write item.done. But we can go even further than that to make this bit of code a lot
shorter and a lot more elegant.
And in order to do that, we're going to use the ternary operator.
And this is, again, something that's not unique to Swift.
It's seen in a lot of programming languages, but it's a really neat way of cutting down some code when
we don't want to be so wordy.
So to learn all about the Swift ternary operator, I will see you on the next lesson.