So one of the most obvious ways that everybody thinks of immediately is paying for apps up front. Now
paid apps are really easy to implement.
And essentially it's when you list your app onto either the Google Play store or the Apple App Store,
you essentially just set a price tier.
And those tiers are determined by the app stores themselves.
So as a new developer it's very easy to assume that this is you know the way that you should go.
And the reason for that is mostly guided by results on the apps that you see. For example this is an
app called Fit Men cook that was developed by some friends of ours and essentially features a whole
bunch of healthy recipes by a blogger called Kevin curry.
So they basically launched on the App Store and within the first day they hit the number 2 spot in
the top paid iPhone apps with a pricing model of $2.99.
They were wedged between Monument Valley and Minecraft.
So you can see that these people did really really well off this app essentially.
And you can mistakenly think like, "Oh so you know that's how I should monetize.
I should just price it at $2.99 and put my app onto the App Store and it will perform equally well."
But the thing that you don't realize is that there's a number of behind the scenes factors that determined
the success. Not only the fact that it was a great app but also a number of factors that related to how
they went about promoting it.
So the biggest factor in that is the the guy Kevin Curry who I think got 50 percent of the revenue of
the app without really contribution to the development of it other than his recipes.
But he has a huge following. He has a blog with tens of thousands of subscribers, a Twitter page with
you know 20K followers and a Facebook page with again you know hundreds of thousands of people who
like it.
So what that means is that this guy is a serious influencer in this field and on the day of launch or
even prior to launch, he can gear up his subscribers his followers his fans to download this app within
the first 24 hours.
The thing you have to realize is that on both the Google app store as well as the Apple App Store, the
first 24 hours, 7 days and 30 days of your apps performance is crucial to getting it featured or
getting it highlighted in some sort of ranking.
So if you are able to achieve a massive amount of downloads on day 1 within the first 24 hours that
sends a huge spike and a signal to the app stores.
Potentially furthering your exposure by featuring it somewhere or getting it listed in the top paid
apps.
So that sort of stops a snowball effect that gets you more and more downloads and sustains you within
the rankings.
So this is one way in which paid apps can work really well.
If you find that you can partner with a influencer in a particular niche that applies to your app and
even if they don't do anything at all for the development of your app if they can bring the people from
day 1, then it's well worth going down that route.
Now another way in which paid apps can work is if you're developing something that the world has never
seen before.
So this is an app developed by a guy called Peter Bentley who's a friend of mine and he created an app called
iStethoscope Pro.
Now what he realized was that the iPhone had superior acoustic hardware than it needed to for a telephone.
And this was because it inherited a lot of that hardware that audio hardware from the iPod which as
we all know the iPhone is built upon. So upon realizing that, he decided to tap into the microphone
of the iPhone and he built an app that allows you to point the phone at your heart or at your lungs
and put on some headphones to listen to your heartbeat or your lung sounds.
And he didn't actually do very much advertising at all but he got a massive amount of media attention
just because of how innovative this was.
This was a way of turning your phone into potentially a medical device.
And in fact having used it for a while I can say that using iStethoscope Pro app with the iPhone is almost
as good as some of the £300 £400 pound electronic stethoscopes that are out there on the market.
And in addition to that you can also record your heart sounds or your lung sounds and send it to your doctor by email
for example, which is a huge boon.
And I think they are currently building some sort of research project where they are collecting a lot
of people's heart and lung sounds for research purposes which is really cool as well.
But essentially when this app came out, it was priced at I think 99 cents which at the time was the lowest
priced tier.
He got a massive amount of traction and a massive amount of revenue from this.
And I think just from the revenue from this one app alone he bought a five bedroom house somewhere in
London which is incredible.
So if you're building something that's really unique and I mean it really unique it's not just you know
some variation of something that already exists that has a huge amount of value for people something
like this,
then you are well within your rights to make it a paid app and you will see revenue from it.
Now a third example is where you have the rights to some sort of intellectual property.
So for example, if you own a question bank for a Bar prep course or medical exams, then you are certainly
expected to charge for that information.
And a lot of people do and they actually charge quite a lot.
So a lot of these Bar prep courses or question banks or quizzes actually average something like around
£20  to £30.
So if you have domain knowledge in something such as law or medicine and you create a question bank
then this is a really easy way of creating a niche and relatively lucrative app that can be paid upfront.
Now one of the things that we always get asked about were relating to paid apps is how you should price
it. And what we've noticed through the years is that pricing apps on the App Store is a very delicate
matter.
People's psychology is very funny about pricing. What you find is that if you have an app that is you
know maybe a single use app or maybe entertains people for 30 minutes, then you can charge anywhere less
than $1.99 and people will be fine with that.
People are okay with the idea of spending you know the equivalent of a cup of coffee on an app and even
if its not the most amazing app in the world, they're happy with paying that amount just for a bit of
novelty a bit of discovery.
But once you hit the $1.99 threshold and you go above it, people get really angry
in the review section if your app is not something spectacular. And there's actually a website that
collects a bunch of apps that are priced relatively ridiculously say for example the Professional Chef
app that's $50 or the Water Globe that's $220.
So what we tend to recommend is you know start off low and see how people are responding to your app
if they're liking it.
And then as you add more features and as you have more positive reviews if you feel like the app is
under valued then you can raise it by a dollar at a time and see how people respond to it. And you eventually
reach an equilibrium where people feel like they're getting enough value for what they're paying and
you feel like your app is being bought at the right price.
So play around with pricing is what we're trying to sing.