In this lesson, we're going to add the finishing touches to our BMI Calculator.
We're going to apply the MVC design pattern to add some additional functionality to our app. By the end
of this lesson,
our Apple display a piece of advice text underneath the BMI value, and also show a different background
color depending on whether if the BMI that was calculated happens to be underweight or overweight.
In the process, we'll learn how to work with color laterals and also get more practice working with optionals
in Swift.
Speaking of optionals, prior to our Optionals Deep Dive, we were looking at our BMI property in our struct.
We transformed this property into an optional and we were wondering how to best work with it in the
getBMIValue function. So coming back to our projects,
having learned about all the ways that we can handle optional, let's think about how we can apply those
methods that we learned about to our optional value here.
The first thing that we learned about is we could simply do a "if BMI is not equal to nil,"
well then in that case, and only in that case, do we actually trigger this block.
Now, once we reindent our code, and then we go ahead and unwrap this bmiVvalue safely within the check
of our "if" statement. Now, that error goes away, but we get a new error. It's telling us that we're missing
a return in a function expected to return "String." Because, yeah, when we created this function
getBMIValue, we promised that we would give a string as an output by the end of this function.
But you can see that if the BMI was indeed nil, then this entire block of code is going to be skipped
and we're gonna land right here without having any value to give back.
So what can we do?
Well, we could provide a "else" statement. So we could say that, well, in the case where BMI is nil, then let's
simply just return "0.0."
So that's one way of looking at it. The other way is using are optional binding,
so where we say, if let safeBMI = bmi.
Well, in that case, as long as this has a value, then we should be able to use this safeBMI as an actual
floating point number.
So here we don't have to do any unwrapping anywhere, and we can just simply tap into the safeBMI.
But, again, in this case, we still need that "else" statement because if the BMI is nil, then, again, this block will
be skipped and it will jump to the "else" statement.
Now, if we wanted this code where we're using the BMI value if it has a value, otherwise, providing a default
value, well, then this whole blogger code could actually be vastly simplified by simply deleting the "if"
and the "else" statement, and using our nil coalescing operator.
So in this case, we're going to say that, well, if there is a value in BMI, well, then use that value,
but otherwise, let's just use 0.0 as the value that we format. So out of those three options,
I would actually prefer this approach. The syntax with the nil coalescing operator is both more clear
and more expressive.
So now that we've figured out the bmiValue, the next step is getting hold of an interpretation for the
bmiValue and assigning it a piece of advice as well as a color.
Now in that case, we should probably end up grouping our bmiValue with its color and advice together
in the same data type.
So does that remind you of something?
Well, it means that we should probably create a model for our BMI.
That's right.
We're going to build our app to be more in line with the MVC design pattern.
So in our Models folder, let's go ahead and create a new file, and it's gonna be a Swift File, and let's
go ahead and name it BMI, and make sure it goes into the Models folder. In this BMI file,
I'm going to create a new struct called BMI, and it's simply going to have three properties: a value which
is going to be a float, a piece of advice which is going to be a string,
and finally, a color which is going to be a UIColor.
Now, notice how it's not coming up in my autosuggest here.
And that should be a good hint to you that we actually are using something that we don't currently have
access to,
and this says just as much because we need to switch our foundation to UIKit, so that the UIColor which
comes from UIKit can be found, and we can use it.
So it's a pretty simple struct for BMI.
It's going to be a custom data type that grouped together the value which is the number,
and then the advice text as well as the color.
Now, we can head back into our CalculatorBrain. And instead of having our BMI being a float, I'm going
to change its data type to being that new BMI struct that we created.
But again, it's going to be an optional.
So now that we've changed the data type, we have to do a few fixes in our code.
And the first thing is that we should change this which is no longer a value or a floating point number,
it's now a BMI struct,
instead it should become a bmi.value, so that we can tap into that floating point number.
But notice how as soon as I type the word "value," what gets automatically inserted for me is that question
mark there. And from the last lesson when we did our Deep Dive into optionals, you should be able to recognize
that this is effectively changing our BMI optional.
So because the value is a normal floating point number,
but the BMI is, of course, the optional here,
in order to reach into the BMI to get a hold of that value, we first have to check to make sure that the
BMI is not nil like it is here.
And if it is indeed not nil, well, then we can get hold of the value that lives inside.
But if it is nil, then we're simply going to use "0.0" as of value.
So, that's our first part fixed.
Now down here, though, we can't simply just write BMI value and use optional chaining to try to assign
this to our value property in the BMI struct. Because remember that the value was set as a "let" constant.
Once we create this BMI with the value, advice, and color, all we want to do is just pass it around.
We don't want to change it.
It's only ever going to have one value.
And so that means what we actually want is to be able to create a BMI struct from scratch.
So instead of writing bmi.value, let's create a temporary constant. Let's call it let bmiValue = height,
and then we can create our bmi by using that BMI struct, and then using the initializers to fill
in each of these values.
So the BMI value that we calculated, of course, goes into the value placeholder, and then we need a piece
of advice and a piece of color, but these two things are worked out based on what value we got. Because
the reason why the BMI is such a useful indicator for health professionals is because it takes into
account not just somebody's weight, but also their height. A really tall person has the same weight as
somebody who's really short, then the shorter person probably is more overweight.
So in the BMI chart, you can see these different bands which classify the BMI values, where below 18.5,
they are underway between 18.5 and 24.9, they are healthy.
And then above that, they are overweight, obese, and extremely obese.
The National Institute of Health classify some of these categories and we're going to use these categories
to create an "if" statement in our code.
So as a challenge, I want you to look at the BMI value that we calculated from dividing the height squared
by the weight, and then I want you to print underweight, normal, or overweight based on what that value
is equal to. For this challenge,
just print to the console for now.
We'll be adding the functionality to show the interpretation inside the app in a bit.
So take a look at this breakdown.
Pause the video and try to complete this challenge
All right, so let's first comment out
this line of code which we don't have any values for,
and then we're going to use our bmiValue which gets calculated, and we're going to check to see if the
bmiValue is less than 18.5.
Well, in that case, then we should print "underweight."
But the next category for the normal weight is for people who are between 18.5
and 24.9.
So how can we express that range?
Well, we could use an "else if" which only gets triggered, remember, if the "if" statement, this check, fails.
Well, in that case, if it's not less than 18.5, well, then, is the bmiValue less than
24.9.
Well, in this case, we should be printing "normal weight." And finally, if the BMI value is not less than
18.5, and is not less than 24.9, well, then we can catch everything else
above 24.9 with the "else" statement, and we can print "overweight."
So this is one solution to our problem.
Now, you might have done it slightly differently. You might have checked to see if the BMI value was greater
than 18.5, and it was less than 24.9 to catch that particular range,
and that would be the case if you only had an if statement. But if you have an "else" statement, remember that
it's already checked the previous condition, it's already checked and made sure that the bmiValue is
not less than 18.5.
And that's the point at which the "else" statement actually gets triggered,
so we don't actually have to check the lower end, we just have to check the upper bound which is
24.9. And that's the solution to the challenge.
Now, let's make use of this logic.
So now instead of printing "underweight," "normal weight," and "overweight," let's instead create our BMI struct
when we have these different categories.
So if the bmiValue was less than 18.5, well, then maybe the advice is we should tell them
to "Eat more pies," and the color that we will use to show that they're underweight is maybe we could just
use the UIColor.blue.
Now, notice how UIColor, again, comes from UIKit. And without importing UIKit, we won't be able
to use it.
But there's another way that we could do this by using something called a Color Literal and we're not
going to use UIColor anymore.
Instead, we're going to start typing Color Literal. And once that hint comes up, we're going to hit enter.
And now in this little square, we can double click on it and out pops a little color palette that we
can pick from.
Now, if these colors aren't enough for you, then you can click on Other, and you get the full choice of
RGB Sliders or the rainbow, or the crayons, whichever one you prefer.
But in my case, I'm simply just going to choose this light blue color for people who are underweight.
And then for normal weight, I'm going to say, maybe, "Fit as a fiddle!" and let's add an exclamation mark
here as well to express our enthusiasm.
And let me just fix my typo there.
Now, let's change this color to green for normal weight. And finally, for overweight,
we're going to say, maybe, "Eat less pies!" because that's what everybody eats, just pies all day.
And I'm going to change the color to red. All right.
So I've got blue, green, red, and I've got a piece of advice for everybody from each category. And now we've
calculated the BMI based on the values that were passed in.
We've interpreted them and created a separate BMI struct for each value category.
So let's tie everything that you've learned so far together with a challenge.
Head back over to the CalculateViewController. And down here where we have access to this destinationVC,
which is the ResultViewController that's going to be shown up on screen,
I want you to type two more lines of code.
So we're going to tap into the destinationVC and we're going to set a property called advice,
and we're going to set it equal to the calculatorBrain.getadvice. And then we're also going to tap
into the destinationVC, and set another property codecolor which is going to be coming from the
calculatorBrain as always.
And it's going to be called getColor.
So using what you've learned about optionals, about MVC, and struct, I want you to complete this challenge
by getting rid of the errors here.
Now, you're not allowed to touch anything else inside the CalculateViewController and you have to fix
this code and make it work, so that when you run the app and you change the height to some extraordinary
number and click calculate, it should calculate a low BMI which means a blue background, which means eat
more pies.
And if you had a normal-ish sort of height and a normal-ish sort of weight,
then you should end up with a green background with a "Fit as a fiddle" as the advice text.
And finally, if you have a really low height and a normal weight, then you might get a higher BMI result
with a different advice and a red background.
So, essentially, these two lines of code will allow us to pass on the advice that we get out of our
calculatorBrain, the color that we got out of our calculatorBrain, and make it display in the ResultViewController.
So there's a couple of things that you have to fix and you have to write, and it requires all of your
knowledge that you've learned so far.
Pause the video and try to complete this challenge.
All right.
So there's a few ways that you could have solved this challenge.
But first of all, we have to get rid of these errors. And through the code that I've written, it requires
that we have a property code advice and a property code color in our destination VC.
So that is, of course, going to be our ResultViewController.
So here we've already got a bmiValue, which is a optional string, because when we create the result VC,
we don't yet know these values.
We have to pass it over because the segue creates that view controller, at which point, we don't know
any of these values and it's only when we cast it down to a ResultViewController, and then we can set
its properties.
So we need to create advice and color over here.
So I'm going to create a variable code advice and this is also going to be an optional string, and
then I'm going to create a variable code color which is going to be a optional UIColor.
So now that should get rid of these two errors and that's no longer highlighted in red.
So let's go ahead and address the next part, our getAdvice and getColor methods.
So we currently don't yet have those things in our CalculatorBrain.
So let's go ahead and create it.
Let's create a function called getAdvice and this should probably return a String because the advice
text is a string, and then let's create a function called getColor, and this will return a UIColor. So if
you haven't converted your foundation into a UIKit, then you'll have to do that now in order for Xcode
to know about this data type.
So now it's saying that we're missing a return in a function expected to return.
So in this case, we need to get hold of the BMI's advice property.
So let's go ahead and try to return bmi.advice.
Now, it automatically chains our BMI which currently is still a optional,
and then it tries to tap into the advice property as long as it exists. But, of course, if BMI was nil,
then advice would also be nil,
so therefore, this entire bit of code is actually still an optional string.
So how do we turn it into an actual string?
Well, we could use our optional binding.
We could use our nil checking, or more simply, and to keep it short and sweet,
we could also just give it a default value of "No advice" in the case where our BMI is actually nil.
Now, in pretty much all circumstances, this would never get triggered because our prepare for segue is
always going to be triggered after perform Segway which, of course, lives in the calculatePressed IBAction
which already calls calculateBMI.
Now, we know this but our code doesn't know, and there might be a case in the future where we've forgotten
all about this.
So to catch that optional being nil, we provide a default value which should alert us that something
has gone wrong.
So let's go ahead and do the same in our getColor.
So I'm going to return BMI chained with the .ccolor property. In this case, I'm just going to provide
a default color,
say, UIColor.white, or if you want to keep it consistent with the rest of these, then it might
be a case of turning this into a Color Literal. But, of course, when there are errors, the Color Literal
doesn't really pop up very easily in Xcode.
So I find it's easier to just copy it from somewhere else and paste it in,
and then we can double click on it to change it to white.
All right.
So now that we've created our getAdvice and getColor methods, if we go back to our CalculateViewController
and hit command B to hit our code with its stick, then that should get rid of all of those errors.
But now you might realize that if we run our app, it's still not enough to get the advice and color being
displayed on screen because while we have access to them in these properties now, we're not using them
yet.
So in our viewDidLoad, in addition to setting the bmiLabel also gonna set the adviceLabel's text property
to equal the advice string that we passed over.
And notice how I'm not unwrapping these optionals,
and the reason is because the bmiLabel.text property is actually expecting an optional string because
it can be nil.
You could have a label with no text and that's perfectly fine.
The label can handle that.
So in this case, these two data types match and that's why we're not getting any errors.
But how do we set the background color?
Well, remember that in the UIViewController, we have a property called view, and that view, of course,
comes from the UIViewController. And it refers to this view that we see right here which is, of course,
the background of this screen.
Well, that sounds pretty much like what we need to change in order to change the background. And notice
how at the moment we've got this blue background showing up,
but it could also be yellow or it could be red, or it could be any other color, basically.
So we're going to tap into this view which we always have access to whenever we create a new view controller
and it's already linked to our code with a property called a view by default.
So every single time you drag on a new UIViewController from the object library, and you put it onto
the screen, and you link it up with a UIViewController class, then you should have access to that view
property. And that will determine what the background looks like.
So let's go ahead and change the view.background color property, and we could set it to the color
that was passed over.
So now let's go ahead and run our code. And you should see that when we change our weight and height,
our BMI gets calculated. And depending on the result, we get a different interpretation and a different
background.
So have a mess around with that and see what you get. And if you didn't manage to complete the challenge
in its entirety, be sure to review your code and try to fix it, so that it works. And if optionals were confusing,
then take a look at the Optionals Deep Dive. If this view property tripped you up, then be sure to
take a look at the lessons where we talked about classes and inheritance.
Now, that's it for this module. And I hope to see you on the next one.