In the last few lessons, we've managed to create a Weather Manager object which is able to perform the
networking that fetches the live data from OpenWeather Map,
and then we're able to pass the weather into an actual Swift object which we can access in a Swifty
format like this.
In this lesson, I want to focus on getting hold of our weather conditions because we need to be able
to update this image view with a different image from the system's
SF icons, so that it represents the condition of the weather.
Now, if we take a look at the API doss for OpenWeather, you can see that they've got this section on
list of condition code. And this section here links to all of the condition codes that they use, and that
refers to the ID property in the data that we get back.
What do these IDs actually correspond to?
Well, they're a way of encoding different weather conditions.
So, for example, everything from 200 to 232, encode some sort of thunderstorm, and there's
apparently different types of thunderstorms which I didn't really know about,
like a ragged thunderstorm. I don't want to be in one of those.
Now, we know that we can get hold of the ID which is the ID of the weather condition and we can match
it against these values to see what type of image we should show the user.
So let's go ahead and do that. Instead of getting hold of the description which we're not actually gonna
use,
instead, I'm going to change this property to "id" and the "id" is an integer data type. And I can do
this because the "id" is actually nested inside at the same level as the description.
So changing that over from the description to the "id" or you can if you want to just simply added on
as an additional property if you plan on using the description at some later stage. But they both live
within this Weather struct which is an array of weather conditions that we're getting back which comes
from the entire WeatherData.
So following it down, this is the first property which goes into an array, which then has an object with
a property code "id."
So quite convoluted, but eventually, we should be able to get a hold of this number.
Let's go ahead and try to print that in our WeatherManager just to make sure that it's actually working.
So let's see what it's like in Bali at the moment. And the weather condition code I'm getting back is
803.
And if I check against this table 803 is broken clouds, 51 to 84 percent.
Interesting.
So in this case, I would probably just show a cloud in my app right here.
So this is the perfect opportunity to utilize what you've learned about Swift switch statements a few
modules back.
So I'm going to set this to you as a challenge. Given that we have this ID which I'll call
let id = decodedData.weather [0].id,
I want you to create a function down here that we'll call
getConditionName, and it takes the input in the format of the weatherId which is going to be an integer,
and then inside this function, we're going to return a String. And that string will depend on the Weather
ID.
So we're going to call this getConditionName and pass in the id right here that we get back,
and then inside this method was somehow going to use a switch statement to output a string, and that string
should match the name of one of these symbols.
So, for example, if we were getting clouds, then maybe we would simply return the word "cloud" which would
match with this image's name.
And if we got, say, rain then maybe we would put cloud.rain to get this symbol. Because, eventually,
what we're going to do is we're going to be using that condition name to change this image view here.
So if we got cloud.rain as the condition name, that's what we would see. If we got just a cloud,
then we would get this image. If we got sun.max, then we would get this image.
So feel free to pick and choose whichever icon takes your fancy as long as they more or less match the
condition name that we're getting back from Open Weather Maps table.
And then when you get this condition name back, I want you to go ahead and print it, so that when you
run the app and you put in the name of a location, say in Paris, and you go ahead and get the weather
for it, you should be able to get a name for a SF symbol that matches the weather condition of that
location.
Now, if you already know all about the Swift switch statements and you don't want to complete this challenge,
then you can also head over to the README file and you'll find the switch statement already written
for you. But I recommend that more practice is always good.
So using a Switch statement, try and print out the name of an icon that matches the condition ID from
OpenWeather Map.
I'm going to leave it up to you to pause the video and complete the challenge if you want to. All right.
So here's our Switch statement. And it looks at the weatherID that we get passed over and takes a
look at its value, and tries to match it against these cases, and these cases I've put in as ranges.
So the range between 200 and 232 in the weather condition codes matches a thunderstorm.
So out of all of these pictures of thunderstorms, I think the cloud.bolt looks quite nice.
So I've decided to return cloud.bolt, and I've done basically the same thing to match all of these
different conditions.
And in the default condition where none of these cases match, then I'm just gonna return cloud as the
default option.
Now, if you are at all confused about Switch statements or the range operator, then be sure to head back
to some of those Swift Deep Dives where we talked about those things in more detail. And that's the solution
to the challenge. But now you might be noticing that this file is getting a little bit messy and we're
getting to the point where we kind of need to group some data in a custom data type. And that is, of course,
the role of the data model.
So let's do that now.
Let's reorganize our code in accordance with the MVC design pattern.
This means that we'll take some functionality out of the WeatherManager and put it into a separate
file.
That way, we'll have shorter and simpler files that are easier to understand. If I want to create a custom
weather data model which is able to figure out the condition name based on the condition ID, then I
would need to go into my Model folder and create a New File which I'm going to call the WeatherModel,
and I'm gonna use this file to model what a weather object should look like.
Let's create it as a struct and it's gonna be called a WeatherModel and it's gonna have a number of
properties.
So we definitely need to have a conditionId property which is an Int.
We also need to have a city name property which is gonna be a String.
And finally, we also need a temperature property which is gonna be a Double.
So now I can go ahead and move this functionality of figuring out what the condition name should be
based on the condition code or the weatherId.
This is very much within the realm of the weather object.
So let's go ahead and paste that in here.
Now, back inside our Weather Manager. Instead of having all these disparate pieces of information, I can
create my ID as my decodedData weatherId. I can create my temperature or temp as the
decodedData.main.temp.
And finally, I'm gonna create my city name or I'm just gonna call it name for short
from the decodedData.name property.
So, now that I've got all the properties that I want out of my weather data, I can create myself a weather
object from my new WeatherModel.
So when we initialize it, we have provide the conditionId which is the ID, the cityName which is
name, and the temperature which is temp.
Now, if I wanted to get a hold of the ConditionName, then I can simply write weather.getConditionName
and I have to pass in the ID. But wouldn't it be nice if I could just have a property in my weather
object that's called a condition name and it manages to figure out what that should be.
Instead of getting my weather manager to call the method getConditionName, in order to get the ID.
This is a good opportunity to show you a cool thing that we can do in Swift which is called a computed
property.
So we've got all three properties here which are actually called stored properties because all they
do is they just store pieces of data.
But I can also create a computed property.
So I'm going to create it using a var keyword and I'm going to call it the conditionName, and it's going
to have a data type of String, and then I'm going to open up a set of parentheses. And inside the set
of parentheses, I'm expected to return or output what the value for the condition name should be.
That would require me to work out the condition name which, luckily, I've already got down here in the
form of my Switch statement.
So let's paste that in here and we can use the conditionId property value to switch, and then check
what condition it is to return this string which is going to be equal to the conditionName.
So, now I've got a computed property because this property condition name is going to work hard
its value based on the code inside these curly braces.
What this allows me to do is if I want to get hold of the weather condition, all I would have to do is
say weather.conditionName and I can use it just like any other property.
And if you run your app right now, you'll see it works perfectly
just like before.
But our code is now a lot better after the refactoring and it's a lot more succinct and easier to understand.
So what's a general format for computed properties in Swift?
Let's go over the syntax for computed properties again. In order to create a computed property,
it always has to be a var because the value is always going to change. It's going to be based on the
computation.
And then we give it a name,
so let's call it aProperty. And then we have to give it a data type,
so let's say I want it to be an integer.
Now, in between the curly braces, I have to provide an output that is going to be set as the value of
this property.
So let's say that I wanted to calculate, I don't know, 2 + 5,
So this is the computation
and that means aProperty is going to be equal to the result of this computation which is going to be
7.
That's all computed property in Swift.
And as practice and as a challenge, I want you to figure out how we can get hold of the temperature as
a string with only one decimal place.
So you've done this before using the string initializer,
but I want you to turn that into a computed property now, and it should be called temperatureString.
And if you manage to successfully solve the challenge, then you should be able to print
weather.temperatureString. And when you run the app and check the weather, then you should get the temperature
back in a string format with only a single number after the decimal place.
So pause the video and see if you can complete this challenge.
All right.
So we've got a temperatureString computed property here.
And remember, we always have to provide a data type for the computed property, and then we open a set
of curly braces and actually work out what it should be.
So in this case, I'm going to return a String with the format of a single decimal place,
so thats's "%.1f" and then I'm gonna pass in my temperature which is this Double right
here as the property that's going to be formatted to this particular format. And now when you run your
app, you should be able to see that whatever temperature you get back will be printed with only one decimal
place. And this temperature string now has the data type of a String ready for us to put into our temperature
label.
So in the next lesson, we're going to tie it all together and get our weather app working with all of
these different components together. For all of that and more, I'll see you there.