So previously, we got up to the point where we used and NSUserDefaults to save our data, and then we
created a data model that represented each and every to-do list item so that we can associate each item
with not only just a title, but also whether if they have been done or not done.
So this way, every single time we reload the table view, it will always be up to correctly assign a checkmark
or no checkmark to each and every to-do list item.
Now previously, where our app fell down was when we tried to save data that is of a custom data type to our
to our to-do list.
And the reason we mention was because we're using NSUserDefaults which can only take standard data
types, not any custom types or custom objects that we have created.
So in this lesson, we're going to address this by using a different method for saving our data and persisting
it on the device.
So the first thing that we need to do is to delete this print statement inside our AppDelegate
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions so that we don't get confused between our print statements. And then if we're
going to go into our TodoListViewController
and we're going to create a file path to the Documents folder,
so just super.viewDidLoad,
we're going to create a constant called dataFilePath and this is going to be set to equal FileManager,
which is the object that provides an interface to the file system,
and then we're going to use the default FileManager which is a shared FileManager object.
So this, you should now recognize, is a singleton. And this singleton contains a whole bunch of URLs and they're
organized by directory and domain mask.
So the SearchPathDirectory we need to tap into is the documentDirectory.
Now, be careful here, you're not looking for the documentationDirectory,
that's something entirely different.
We're looking for the documentDirectory.
So have a scroll through what other things you can tap into.
And once you're done, go ahead and enter .documentDirectory. And the location where we're going to
look for it is inside the userDomainMask.
So this is the user's home directory, the place where we're going to save their personal items associated
with this current app.
And because this is an array, we're going to grab the first item, and then we're going to print this
dataFilePath.
So let's go ahead and run our app and see what we get back.
Now, if we have a look inside our debug console, we can see that we've got this optional printed which doesn't
really matter because we haven't unwrapped the optional URL, but this is what we want.
This is the file path that we need.
So let's go into Finder and navigate to this location.
So if you want to navigate up the directory, you can always use command up button and you can go up the
hierarchy until you get to the root which is your Macintosh hard drive.
Now, starting from here, we're going to go into Users, then my current user which is angelayu, and then
we're going to go into Library, and we're going to go into Developer. And inside developer, we're going
to go into CoreSimulator, and we're going to look for the device that is 8D49. So you can always click
on Date Modified, so that it sorts by last open or last modified.
So here we go, 8D49, and then inside data, inside Containers, inside another folder called Data,
there's a folder called Application, and we finally get to our application which is this one 53A.
And you can see here we've got a plist that represents our NSUserDefaults.
Now, inside our app, instead of using NSUserDefaults and grabbing that singleton and saving our data
to that address, we're going to create our very own p list file.
So all we need to do is go to the part where we created the file path to our Document's directory, and
then we just need to use the dot notation and tap into the appendingPathComponent method.
And here, we can add a path component, you can call it anything you want, but it's good to name it something
that makes sense.
For example, in this case, maybe we'll call it items.plist.
Now, if I run the app and chase down that file path,
and you'll see that we haven't yet got the items on plist. We've merely created a path to this new
plist that we are going to create right now.
So let's head back into Xcode.
So let's head back into Xcode and let's modify our code. So instead of using use a default, we're going
to create our own plist at the location of our data file path.
So the first thing that we have to change is this line where we set our itemArray for the key
TodoListArray into our UserDefaults.
And because our itemArray is an array of our custom Item object, then this line fails
and this is when our app crashes.
Now, instead of doing this,
so I'm just going to delete that line,
I'm going to now create something called an encoder and the encoder is going to be a new object of the
type propertyListEncoder and I'm going to initialize it.
Now, what I can do is I can say, let data = encoder
so that's that property listing code that I just created which will encode our data namely our
itemArray into a property list.
So we're going to use our encoder and we're going to use the method encode, and the value that we're
going to encode is our itemArray.
So once I hit enter, you'll see a couple of problems, namely that the encode method can throw an error.
So we know what to do.
We, first, have to create a do block, and then we need a catch block.
And finally, we need to mark this method with a try. And because we are inside a closure, i.e., the part
that gets triggered once the user presses the Add Item button, then we have to mark all our properties
with a self.
Now, once we've encoded our data, the next step is to write the data to our dataFilePath,
and this is also a method that can throw errors,
so we have to mark it with a try also.
So try data
.right,
so writing the data to a location and the location is, of course, going to be a dataFilePath.
So in order for us to access it there, we have to put it out here as a global constant.
And so now we can say dataFilePath. And inside the catch block, we're going to print "Error encoding
item array" and we're going to print out the error that triggered it.
And finally, we have to mark this with a self because we are, again, inside a closure.
So the last thing we have to do before this is going to work is we have to go into our Item class and
we have to mark our class as conforming to the protocols
Encodable.
And this means that the Item type is now able to encode itself into a plist or into a JSON. And for
a class to be able to be Encodable, all of its properties must have standard data types.
So things like strings, Booleans, arrays, dictionaries, they all work, but not if you have a custom class
in here.
So let's hit save and let's fix that.
one last issue. And let's just comment out this line so that we can address it later.
Now, if we run app, let's see what happens.
All right, so let's add a brand-new item.
So all three of these items got initialized because we hardcoded them and added them to the itemArray
which is what we're loading up inside our tableView.
Now, in order to test out our code and see if our encoding worked, we have to press the add button and
we're going to create a new item.
And once I hit add item, you can see that I've got no errors, my debug console didn't pop up telling me that
my app has crashed, and my app is continuing to work.
and it now contains that brand-new list item.
So if we go back to Finder and check out that previous location that we found,
but remember last time when we checked in here, there was nothing inside, it was completely empty?
Well, now that we've actually saved something.,
but now that we've actually uncoded itemArray and wrote that data to that dataFilePath, we now have
this plist.
And if we have a look at it by double clicking, you can see that we've got a whole bunch of items that
have been organized and encoded automatically using our Swift encoder.
Now, it's important to note at this point that, previously, when we were talking about UserDefaults and
I explained why it is that we're unable to save an array of custom item objects, it's because the plist
can only accept a limited number of data types, and that pretty much the standard or foundation types.
But if you take a look over here at our encoded Items.plist, you can see that, firstly, it's an Array
with four items, whereas UserDefaults is a dictionary or a bunch of key-value pairs.
And that's what we always said about UseDefaults.
But if we expand this route, we can see that our encoder has very cleverly encoded each of the properties
into a dictionary, and the individual properties still conform to all of the basic data types.
And this is why even though that both plists are Items.plist is able to save our custom item objects,
but the NSUserDefaults is not, and it's all down to the encoder.
And if I have this live next to my app, if I add another new item-- That's really really imaginative of
me. You can see that it shows up here,
but it also shows up here, right?
But this one bug, when we tried to check our items off or uncheck it, this done
property is not updated in our Items.plist.
So let's have a look at why that might be.
So I'm going to stop the app and we're going to look at the part where we try to save that property.
So you can see here, this is where we've got that Delegate Method,
didSelectRowAt indexPath.
And inside this method, we toggle the item at the current index path,
it's done property to the opposite of what it used to be.
So this is only reflected inside our item of range.
So how can we save this information to itemArray.
Well, we have to use the same process, i.e., let encoder = PropertyListEncoder to encode the data,
and try and write the data to that dataFilePath,
and if there's an error, print an error, and then reload the data.
Now, instead of copying all of this and pasting it over there,
this is a good time to think about creating a save data method.
So let's go ahead and create a new function code saveItems underneath our IBAction.
And inside this function, we're going to copy all of this code.
We're going to cut it
and we're going to paste it inside save items.
So, now because we're no longer inside a closure, we can get rid of these selfs in front of our itemArray
and dataFilePath, and we can also simply call saveItems, both when we add a new item using
the AlertController, but also when we toggle the checkmark.
And we can delete this as well because it exists inside saveItems.
So, now let's hit run and see if our app works.
And now if we check on the first cell which is "Find Mike," you can see that this automatically updates
inside our Items.plist and all the changes are reflected live.
But there's still a bit of an issue here, namely, where are the items that we saved earlier on? Where's the "Save
the World" item? Where's the "Add a New Item" item?
Why is it not showing up in our to-do list?
Well, that's because even though we've written the saving part of the code which encodes our itemArray,
we haven't yet written the code to decode our items.plist in order to populate our table view.
So that, we're going to tackle on the next lesson.