Now the other type of blogging I want to talk about is essentially a form of what's called Content Marketing.
And this is where you create content that's worth sharing that's worth spreading and you're essentially
giving people some of your secret sauce or some of your life learnings. And you giving it away for free
in the hope of spreading your message. And that message might be that you're launching an app or it might
be that you're setting up a startup, whatever it may be.
And some good examples of this relating to apps are actually people who talk about how they did well
on the App Store. For example Stuart Hall with the 7 minute workout app.
And for example the guys behind the Fitmen cook app. They all had these posts that pretty much had very
clickBaity titles that looked like it was from BuzzFeed you know something like "The one weird trick
that got me 2 million downloads on the App Store" or something like that.
And the secret about them is that not only do they have a really catchy title and have mass appeal, but
actually they're very open about you know their secrets and their progress.
Whereas a lot of people are you know very hush hush like you know I don't want to give away my tactics.
But actually you find that even if you give away your secret, sauce even if you give away your best tactics,
the number of people who actually take advantage of it or use it are in the minority.
And if they do it still takes a lot of sweat and tears and determination to make it work.
So in which case they probably deserve the success that they'll get.
So think about how you can create some piece of content that's interesting to people that are within
your app's or within your product's target audience.
So for example if you're creating a coffee app, what you need to think about is how can I create a piece
of content that can appeal to coffee heads.
So it could be something to do with a review of the latest and greatest coffee gear or it could be something
about how I finally made that God shot or like-- And essentially just content that would appeal to people
that overlaps with your target audience for your app or your product.
So this requires quite a bit of thinking and a bit of research and very often what you see people
doing is putting out small taster articles like you know not like 500 words but with a very catchy title.
And looking at the stats of how many people read it, what percentage of the article gets read which you
can see with Medium,
you can see how much interest there is and then you can build a part 2 and a part 3 etc.
And people are far more likely to share good interesting content or information with their friends with
their network than just something like download this app.
And in all of these articles, you get a chance to plug your app and at the same time an appeal to the
right audience.
So how have a think about how you can implement content marketing or how you can start a blog that documents
the journey of your app creation and think about doing it as soon as you start having an idea and building
a product.