Hey, guys. In this lesson, I've got three goals that I want to achieve before the lesson ends. And they're
all to do with creating a better user experience and also creating a better user interface.
Let me show you what we can achieve. On the left is the current version of our app where everything goes
in looking exactly the same because we're using the same reusable cell. And it looks like as if I'm just
being ghosted because I'm just sending lots of messages as myself, never getting a reply.
But on the right here in the final version of the app, I should be able to see a difference between the
messages that I've sent which are marked as Me, and the messages that my recipient has sent which is
marked as You.
So, now I'm logged in as a different user. And if I was to write and hit send,
you can see that this comes out completely different from this one.
The second thing I want to show you how to do is to be able to scroll to the very bottom of the table
view. So that way
If we had a whole bunch of messages, let's just go ahead and add a few more--not sure why Sheffield
came up right now, but let's just go ahead and add some more messages, and you can see already the messages
are no longer showing up in the current window of my table view. And if I scroll down, I'll be able to
see them,
but every time I send a new message, I have to scroll down some more.
So this is not a great user experience
if I have to scroll down every time to see my latest message. And it also means that when I log in to
my app, if there's more messages, then there are in the table view, it shouldn't really show the top one,
right?
It should show the one right at the bottom which is what happened most recently.
So that's the second thing that we're going to be tackling here,
this way of automatically scrolling to the very bottom of the table view. And the last thing I want to
show you how to do is to customize the navigation bar, so that we have a different background color,
a different font size for our title, a different color for the logout button
and the title text, as well as removing the navigation bar from the welcome screen, because it looks a
bit unnecessary here,
right?
Those are the three things that we're going to be tackling.
So let's get on with the first one.
How can we differentiate our sender from our recipient?
Effectively, what we're going to do is in our ChatViewController at the place where we load up our
cells for the tableView, we're going to check to see if the sender of the message that's going into
the cell is the same as the user that's currently logged in.
And if so, then that means this current message that's being loaded up, this current cell, belongs to the
current user, in which case it will show this particular style of cell.
But if the user of the message is not the same as the current user, then we're going to show this style
of message.
So how can we achieve this?
Well, one way would be to have two different message cells, but we can also work with a single message
cell and just style it differently depending on the sender.
And that's the way we're going to do it.
Let's go into our MessageCell.xib file, and make some small modifications.
I'm going to go ahead and copy this right imagery, and go ahead and paste it inside here.
Now, as soon as I hit paste or command V, it usually paste it right next to the previous one. But what I
want to do is I want to actually drag it, so that it comes to the very front of our horizontal stack.
So you should see a line right at the beginning which means that it's being put at the very left part
of the stack view.
And in terms of the hierarchy in the document outline, this is what you should see, the MeAvatar, the Message
Bubble, and the Right Image View.
So this left one shouldn't have the Me image.
Instead, if we click on the Image property, we're going to change it to the YouAvatar which is another
image that we included in the
Assets.xcassets right here.
So, now that we've got two different types of bubbles. What we want to be able to do is to hide one of
these,
if the message came from myself or if the message came from my recipient. Let's go ahead and link up
that image view by opening up our assistance. And we've really got our Right Image View,
so let's go ahead and just call this one the leftImageView, and hit connect.
So, now we've got both of these image views linked up to our MessageCell class,
we'll be able to manipulate the MessageCell inside our
ChatViewController.
So now let's head into our ChatViewController and inside our TableView cellForRowAt indexPath
method,
let's go ahead and modify our cell depending on whether if the current message that is being displayed
into the cell is from the current logged in user or from somebody else.
And to do that let's go ahead and create a new constant code message, and we're gonna set that to the
current message at indexPath row from the messages array.
So this first part before the .body.
Just as a quick reminder, this method tableView cellForRoawAt gets called as many times as there are
cells.
So in our case, we're saying create the number of cells that match the number of messages, and for each
of those cells, call this method to figure out what needs to be displayed in it.
In our case, we're going to be using a message object to populate the cell. So we can now change
the cell.label.text to message.body.
And if we want to get a hold of the sender property of the message, then we can just happen to message.sender,
and we can use an "if" statement to check if this is equal to, so two equals, the current logged
in user.
So we'll use the Auth module, Auth.auth() currentUser.email.
So remember, this is the same thing that we used when we created each of the messages.
So when we said, "let message.sender equals the current user?.email, and then put that messageSender into
the senderField of our new document which gets saved in our messages collection. And that messages collection
is what we're retrieving and putting into the messages array. And then for each of the rows in our table,
we're getting hold of the message and we're checking to see if its sender is the same as the current
logged in user.
So that means that all of these messages that match this criteria are the ones that the current logged
in user sent.
So that means that the cell that they should see is the MeAvatar and this particular message,
and then we have to hide this
YouAvatar, so the one on the left, the one that's linked to the leftImageView.
Let's go back to our ChatViewController and inside this "if" statement,
so this means "This is a message from the current user," and in this case, we're still gonna be creating
a MessageCell from the messageCell class and the MessageCell.xib, but we're going to modify it slightly
differently.
So let's go ahead and move these two lines of code to above where we actually make the adjustments.
So right here.
So, now that we've added the message into the cell, we're ready to go ahead and customize it.
So the first thing we gonna do is gonna say cell.lleftImageView.isHidden is set to true, and
we're going to make sure that the rightImageView is not hidden,
so let's change that property to false.
So, now we're displaying the rightImageView, but we're hiding the leftImageView, and we're also going
to set the cell's background color to make it look a little bit different from the messages that we're
getting from other senders.
So, we're gonna say, cell.messageBubble which is that UI View that is this purple one right here.
We're going to set it to have a different background color which is going to be equal to a UIColor that is
named based on one of our constants.
So remember that in order to use our custom colors that we create in our Assets.xcassets like
this BrandLightPurple, we have to use that method UIColor named, and instead of using the
BrandLightPurple string in here, I'm gonna use the same one that I've already got in my constants right here.
So it's gonna be under the structure K. Inside K,
we've got a structure called BrandColors.
And then inside that, we've got a property called lightPurple.
So let's go back here and tap into the K constant and then we're going to go to brand colors, and then
we're gonna go for light purple like that.
That way we won't make any typos here and we'll be able to get the light purple set as the background
color.
Now, in addition to setting the selves' background color, we're going to also change the labels text color.
So let's go ahead and change that property. And you guessed it, we're going to use the same method
UIColor named, and in this case, though, it's going to be the purple color that we're going to use
as the text color.
So K.BrandColors.purple, so that way we have a light purple background with a purple text.
And in the case where this is a message from another sender, well, in that case,
so the "else" statement is going to have these cell's leftImageView.isHidden set as false,
and the cell's rightImageView.is hidden set as true. And then we're going to basically switch up these two
things, so that instead of having a background color of light purple, it's going to have a background
color purple and the text is going to be light purple instead. Let's go ahead and run our app and see what
this actually gives us.
Now, when we log in and we take a look at our table view, you can see that for all the messages that I've
sent from the same username, so as myself, they have the same appearance. But if I go ahead and log out
and log in with the other account that I've signed up for,
so if you haven't got one, then go ahead and register a new account.
So this is a@b.com
We're now getting all the cells formatted as if the message came from somebody else.
So let's say I go ahead and write a new message,
"I am a@b.com," and hit send.
Notice how we now have completely different formats for this type of message versus the message that sent
from this user 1@2.com.
So, now let's hit send and scroll to the bottom.
You can see that we've now formatted ourselves to be able to differentiate between the messages that
the user sent and the ones that they received.
Now, this is a good point to mention that if you had formatted your cells to be rounded for the previous
dimension, so previously in our MessageCell.xib,
we only had this message bubble and the rightImageView.
But now in addition to that, we've also got the leftImageView.
So given that our Stack View has 20 points of space set between all the elements, we've now changed the
dimensions of the cell.
So if you're wondering why it is that your message bubbles no longer look right or the same way that
you had before,
well, it's because of this line of code.
So if you've changed this to divided by 4 or, say, another number, you'll have to change it to divided
by 5
if you want this perfectly rounded corner like I've got here.
If you wanted to have it square or any other different shape, then feel free to keep it the way that
you've got it.
This is just the quick tip in case you're wondering why it is the shape has changed. So let's tackle
the next problem.
Notice how every time I send a new message, it gets put right at the bottom
and we have to scroll manually to be able to see it which is quite painful,
so let's try and change that. In our Chart View Controller,
the point where we can do this is inside our loadMessages method because it's here where we have our
Snapshot Listener added to our collection.
And every time there's a change in our database, we trigger this closure which empties out our messages
array and adds all of the new messages back in to that messages array.
So at this time point is where we call reload data to trigger these two delegate methods and put the
cells into our table view.
Now, if we wanted to scroll to the very bottom of the table view every time there's a new message added,
then all we have to do is to call a method which is self.tableView.scrollToRow.
Now, this particular method expects a IndexPath provided,
so we're going to have to create that as a constant as well.
So let's call it indexPath and I'm going to initialize a IndexPath object, and I'm going to choose
the initializer that asks for a row number.
This is basically saying scrollToRow. And in this line we're creating which row we want to scroll to.
We want to scroll to the very end of our messages array. So we can simply write messages.count.
But this is not enough because let's do the math.
Let's say that we had an array with two items, right, just "A" and "B."
Well, in this case, the array.count is going to be equal to 2.
There's just two items.
But if we tried to get a hold of the last item in the array by tapping into the item at index 2, then that's
going to be 0, 1, 2.
So it's going to be out of bounds.
So in addition to writing messages.count here, we have to subtract 1 to be able to get a hold of
the last item in our messages array.
And we also have to add the "self" keyword because we are inside a closure.
The next thing it asked for is the section number and we're going to set that as 0 because we actually
only have one section.
Now, if we were inside, say, these settings page of our iPhone, then you'll notice that it has lots of different
sections.
Here's section zero, section 1, section 2.
But we've only got one, so we can set that as the first section.
So, now that we've created this IndexPath object, we can now use it inside here to specify which row
we want our table view to scroll to.
And then the position for the table view is to position that row at the top, and then the animated property,
you can either set to true, which is going to give you an animation of that scrolling to this row,
or you can set it to false if you just wanted to go straight there without the animation.
Let me demonstrate so you can see what's the difference. Let's log in and you'll see that it scrolled,
right?
It just did that animation to go to the very bottom of our table view and show the latest message which
is the effect that we wanted.
If I change that to false, however, you'll see that once the screen loads up, it goes straight to the bottom
of the table view
without that animation.
So I'm going to leave this up to you depending on whichever way you prefer your app to be,
then you can set that property however you want,
true or false. But we've now solved this problem because every time I write a new message now,
if I hit send,
you can see that it pops up right at the bottom,
so I don't have to manually scroll to see it. But there is something that we can still improve here, though,
because when I create a new message and I hit send, the old message doesn't disappear from my text field.
So I have to manually delete it in order to write a new message which is a bit painful,
right?
And I want to pose this as a challenge to you. Can you modify the code, so that when the send button is
pressed, the old text is deleted.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video before I show you the solution
Ready?
Here's the solution.
The key is locating the time point in our code when we send a new message.
And that time point is the IBAction sendPressed.
So all we need to do here is add a little bit of code.
If the message was successfully saved, then we can go ahead and happen to our text field,
our messageTextField and set its text property to an empty string.
This way the text field will empty out whenever we're done with sending the message.
And because we're inside a closure and we're trying to update the user interface, remember that we should
tap into the DispatchQueue.main.async method so that this actually happens on the main
thread, rather than on a background thread, which is where the code enclosures tend to take place.
And that's the solution to the challenge.
Now, let's run our app and see this behavior showing up. let's go ahead and write a message and hit send.
And now that message goes in and our text field clears up.
Perfect.
Now all that's left to do is the last thing that we mentioned which is to format our navigation bar.
The first thing I said we wanted to do was to change its color and change some of the properties.
Now, to change this particular nav bar,
you don't actually change it in this view controller, you change it in the navigation controller. So selecting
this navigation bar from the navigation controller, which controls all of these screens, then we can go
into the attributes inspector and change the Bar Tint color.
So let's go ahead and select our BrandBlue to go in there and you can see that that color now goes
in all the screens where it's being displayed.
And we're also going to change the Title Color. So that will change the text that's going into the navigation
bars
as the title. So at the moment, we're setting that title right here in our viewDidLoad where we said
title = K.appName which, of course, corresponds to our constant app name which is this right here.
An alternative way of setting the title is to click on this navigation item and put it right here
where it'll show up.
So depending on whichever one you want to use, you can set it either in the Interface Builder or as
code inside the Chat View Controller.
Now, let's go back to our navigation bar and change the title color to white and change the font size
to System fonts. And Blacks are really, really bold, so much bolder than bold, and change the size to 25
to make it a lot bigger, so that it shows up.
So, now let's go ahead and give it a spin. And once we go to the Log In page, you can see that there is
this clear difference between the navigation bar and this blue background screen.
So if you want this to look identical, then the way to address that is by selecting the Navigation Bar
on the Navigation Controller, and then changing that Translucent property to false.
So, now let me run that app again.
And on our Log In screen, you can see that those two colors now match perfectly.
Now, the final thing I want to change is to make that Back button stand out a little bit more, because
at the moment, it's blue on blue because we've changed the color of the navigation bar. So, again, selecting
the navigation bar from the navigation controller.
Let's go ahead and change the tint color to white.
That way all of the bar buttons will turn into a white colored button item like so.
Now, all that we have left to do is the last thing which is, how can we disable this navigation bar
so that it doesn't show up on some of the screens?
For example, it makes sense for it to be here because we might want to press back, but on the welcome screen, it looks
kind of ugly just to have it hanging around not doing anything.
Let's go into that WelcomeViewController.
And in order to disable that navigation bar, the property that we can set is code "i is Navigation Bar Hidden."
But the time point where we want to hide it is at the point where the viewWillAppear.
So this is just before the view shows up on screen. And it's at this point in time where we're going
to tap into the navigationController.isNavigationBarHidden and we're going to set it to true,
so that we hide it for our WelcomeViewController.
But notice how if I run the app as it is right now while I've hidden the navigation bar for the welcome screen,
if I go into the log in or the register screens, I've now lost my navigation bar. It's still hidden.
So in addition to hiding it, I also have to unhide it.
And the time point where I want to do that is when we're about to go onto the next screen. And we can
override a method called viewWillDisappear.
So just before the view disappears and the next screen shows up, we tap into a navigation controller
and reset the isNavigationBarHidden property to false. This way just before the view shows up,
we set that navigation bar to hidden.
But as soon as I press log in and my welcome view controller disappears, my navigation bar becomes visible
again.
So that way we only get it on the screen where we want it and we disable it for the screen
when we don't. Now, the final thing to note is
something that won't affect how it behaves. But whenever you're overriding one of these lifecycle methods
from the view controller, such as viewWillAppear, viewWillDisappear, and viewDidLoad,
you should always code the super method like how we have here with viewDidLoad.
So this is something that it's best to get into the habit of doing because it's good practice. And in
fact, when you read the documentation for one of these methods, let's take a look at the one
for viewWillAppear,
you can see that down here in the Discussion, it tells you that if you override this method, like what
we have done here, and we're providing our own custom functionality, you must call super
at some point in your implementation. So that just means that the parent, the UIViewController, which
our class is inheriting from, gets an opportunity to run its own code inside its own viewWillAppear,
and then afterwards, we can run our code which has our custom functionality.
So in order to do this, we write super.viewWillAppear, and then we pass in the same value of animated,
as we have here from our inputs. And we do the same thing for our viewWillDisappear.
And this, even though you'll find that when you run the app, doesn't actually change anything at all.
But it's really a good practice to get into the habit of always calling super whenever you override any
function from the superclass. In the next lesson,
we're gonna be looking in more detail at each of these lifecycle methods that come from the UIViewController
and we're going to see when they get called, and how they allow us to tap into certain time
points during the life of our view controller, and to be able to perform things, such as updating the
UI or triggering animations, or starting timers, et cetera.
So for all of that and more, I'll see you there.