So those are some of the most popular ways of piggybacking off a large audience if you don't have your
own.
Now this doesn't replace building an email list and this doesn't replace getting inbound traffic. But
it is just another thing that you can do in order to get more traction and more growth.
So one thing to remember though is that if your launch fails, don't worry, don't be disheartened because
just like SpaceX where your rockets can explode, you can launch and launch again.
So very often when we do our chat with a Pro Series when we talk to especially app founders, your launch
day is not a magical date that you set you know far in advance and then once it's done, it's done. No, your
launch day is determined by your growth.
So if over a short period of time you see an uptake, then that is a launch day and that's what you will
tell journalists.
So for example a friend of ours who launched the double app which is a tinder style double dating app mention
how their first launch date was when they were featured on Product Hunt.
It grew their user base massively and they told the press like they had just launched right?
Their second launch date was when they got featured on I think the Daily Mail newspaper which again
brought a load of traction and that was their second launch day. Their third launch date was when they
got featured on Dragon's Den which is the UK version of Shark Tank.
So each of these days they treat as their launch day and it's a term that doesn't really mean anything.
So don't worry if you launched
and it basically fell with a thud or exploded like a rocket.
Essentially, the point is to launch and launch again until you see traction and then that is your launch
day.
Incidentally, it's very interesting to mention that Gary who's one of the founders of the double app, comparing
the amount of growth and user acquisition he got from launching on Product Hunt versus being on a televised
popular show like Dragon's Den, he actually ended up with more users more downloads more press and more
attention from the Product Hunt launch.
So it really matters where your audience are. If you're going to get a feature in a very serious newspaper
but your app or your product targets 14 year olds then it's not going to help you all that much.
So think about where your audience is before you start trying to acquire those users.