All right.
So the next thing I want to talk about is cross-promotion. And this is basically where you and another
app--
this is basically where you team up with another app developer and you say that I will promote your
app to my users and you can promote my app to your users.
That way we both win because we double our user base.
Now that's the theory and it sounds very good.
But my point is that it works in certain situations, but more often than not from my experience it doesn't
always work that great because you don't want to send your users away from your apps.
They're not a commodity. They're people who you want to build a relationship with.
And if you're pushing other things on them it doesn't always produce the best outcomes.
So instead, what I urge you to do is help your users discover your other apps.
So if you have more than one app that are mildly related say if you have a meditation app and you have
a workout app, then you should be promoting all of your other bundles of apps within each other. So that
way you share your users between your own apps. But those users never leave your own ecosystem. And
in most cases they seem to have worked much better than driving traffic towards somebody else's app.