So one of the first things that we want to introduce to you is designer vs. non-designer thinking. And
it's almost like that advert about the Mac versus the PC guy.
There's fundamental differences in the way that designers think and non-designers think and simply by
learning about some of the concepts relating to design, the beneficial effects go much further than just
simply creating a beautiful app.
So what do I mean by designer vs. non-designer thinking?
Let's look at colors for example.
So way back in primary school we learn about the seven colors of the rainbow.
And a lot of us go around thinking that there are in fact only seven colors in the rainbow. It's either
red or orange or it's yellow.
But actually to a designer, of each of these different shades have a different mood associated with it
and you would use them differently depending on the situation or the project.
So for example right at the top you know that one might be quite candylike and might be useful for
a project that's more fun and playful whereas at the bottom you've got something that's called wine
and it's got more of an elegant sophisticated mood which you might use for something that targets adults
for example.
So one of the first modules that we're going to dive into is color theory, how do you combine different
colors,
how do you use different colors and in which situations.
And the second arm that makes up the fundamentals of digital design is typography,
so how to choose the appropriate type for your project, how to modify it to grab user's attention or
how to make different typefaces work well together to produce a harmonious design.
So most non-designers will look at these typefaces and see regular italic and bold and this knowledge
we acquired through using word processing software such as Word.
But actually it's so much more nuanced
and as a designer you might be looking at this and seeing a regular and a sans serif or italic and a serif
typeface or bold and slab serif. So in the typographic module
we're going to look into this in more detail.
We're going to learn about different type families, how you would combine different funds and how you
would use typography
not just for form but also for function in your designs.
So essentially you should see this course as demystifying digital design. For a lot of people
good design is a bit like a unicorn. You know it's this magical beast that is very easy to identify once
you've seen it but it's not something that comes into intuitively.
So, for example, as humans it's very easy for us to see design A and compare it against design B and decide
that you know I prefer design A over design B. But as a designer, it's your job to come up with design A and
design B according to the specifications.
Now it's easy to see exposed how you know one of these designs might fit the category of contemporary
better,
but the skill of the designer is coming up with those designs A and B in the first place
according to those specifications.
So we're going to teach you about the fundamentals of digital design as well as the most important aspects
of user interface design and user experience design especially relating to mobile design.
So hopefully by the end of the course, you'll know a thing or two about how beautiful apps are designed
and how you can go about creating your next project and making it look as beautiful as you can.
All right.
So without further ado let's begin.