Let's first tackle how to create
and set up a new iOS project from scratch.
So when you first open up Xcode,
it should show you a "Welcome" screen,
and we can get started straight away
by clicking on the link here that says,
"Create a new Xcode project."
Now, if you don't see this welcome screen,
it might be because this checkbox is disabled,
so you can also go over to File, New,
new Project to do exactly the same thing.
So let's go ahead and create this new Xcode project.
Next, we get to choose the kind of template
we want for our new project.
And firstly, up here, we've got different tabs for creating watch apps, tvOS apps macOS apps, et cetera.
But what we want is an iOS app.
And by default, the Single View Application is selected.
And this is the most customizable type of template.
It basically doesn't assume anything about your app
and you're free to modify it as you need to.
Now for some of these other templates, for example,
the Master-Detail App which looks like this
where you've got the master and detail. So it's a bit like
the male app on iPad and usually it is used for large
screen size where you can actually have
this kind of multitasking
or another popular one is the tabbed app.
So this is where you have the tab bar at the very bottom and you can click between these different tabs
to see different pages on the app.
Now it's important to remember that even if you choose a Single View App at any point later on if you
decided that you needed a tab bar or you needed to make it have Augmented Reality or if you needed a
Master-Detail type of format, you can always add it.
So I always tell students to just start off with a Single View App, and then, later on, depending on what
it is you need,
you can always add it at that point.
So now that we know what our template is all about,
let's go ahead and click next.
On this screen, it's really, really important
that you don't skip ahead because you have
to change this user interface
from SwiftUI to Storyboard in order
for the rest of the lessons to actually make sense.
And after you've done that and checked to make sure that your user interface says Storyboard,
then we can continue with the rest of the lesson
and add a product name.
So this is going to be the name of your app.
And we're going to call ours I Am Rich.
and noticed how down here it's already starting
to build out a bundle identifier.
Now a Bundle Identifier is kind of like
a web address.
It's meant to be something that's unique and it will identify your app uniquely on the App Store and
you can see that it's created by what's called a reverse domain name. So whereas normally, would be something
like your company.com when they put the com at the beginning, and then it's the name of your company.
And that comes from your Organization Identifier.
So the organization name, you can leave blank, and the Team, you can leave as none for now. We'll revisit
this a little bit later on when we actually need to launch our app on a physical device.
But we should add an Organization Identifier.
So for example, our company's web address
would be www.appbrewery.co.
So all Organization Identifier because we're taking a reverse domain name would be co.appbrewery.
So it would look something like this.
And the final Bundle Identifier is this, plus this,
and we get a unique URL because most companies
have a web address and because web addresses are unique.
This is a really simple way of ensuring that a company's app is uniquely identified on the App Store.
Now what if you don't have an organization identifier?
What if you don't have a website?
Then I recommend just running com.
and then adding your name,
so it could be Angelayu for example.
This doesn't actually matter as long as there's nobody else who has used this Bundle Identifier using
your name to try and publish an I Am Rich app on the App Store,
then you'll be completely fine.
Now the very last thing to check is to make sure that the Language that you've chosen to program with
is Swift and the User Interface is chosen as Storyboard.
In later modules, we're going to be diving
into SwiftUI.
But we'll need to learn a lot more about Storyboarding and Swift before we can get there. And for the
rest of the checkboxes, you can leave them unchecked, like I have here. And then go ahead and click next.
Now it's going to ask you, "Where do you want to save your app?"
And if you have a specific folder that you want to save it to,  then this is the point to go ahead and
navigate to that.
Alternatively, you can simply save it on your desktop
if it's not too cluttered, or simply just create
a new folder called Development
and you can start saving all your projects in there.
Now we're going to go ahead and click Create
and it will generate all Xcode project for us.
So that's it.
That's our brand new Xcode project created.
And remember that Xcode automatically
saves all of your changes.
And if you ever want to locate where this project is,
then simply go to the very top over here, right-click,
and click on Show in Folder.
At which point, it's going to show you where it is on your computer. And if you go on to this view, you'll
be able to navigate all the way up to see where it's actually located.
In my case, it's simply on my desktop in a folder called Development. Once that's created,
if at any point you want to pause the course and you want to close down Xcode, then you can always go
back to where you saved it, open up the project folder, and then your project is located inside the file
called I Am Rich.Xcodeproject.
And if you double click on it, it will open it right back up where you left off.
So now that we've seen how to create a brand new project, the next step is to take a look around Xcode
and familiarize ourselves with our working environment.