All right. Let's talk about something that a lot of people seem really interested in and that is getting
press for your app or for your business.
And one of the first things that people tend to ask is "Do I need a PR firm" Do I need somebody to professionally
try and get me press? On one hand
there's some great PR firms out there and they can get you a lot of exposure.
On the other hand, you have to ask yourself can you afford the $100 per hour rate?
In most cases and a lot of tech journalists will tell you the same thing, if you're a small company if
you're a startup, they're far more willing to write a story that came from the founders rather than from
some PR firm that they hired.
So unless you have a lot of cash to burn or you're growing startup with more than 20 employees, don't
worry about getting a PR firm just yet.
Just pitch as yourself as the founder and you will have equal if not better success than hiring a PR
firm.