All right.
So once you've created your very own version of the skeleton project or you've checked out the skeleton
project that I created, then we're ready to get our in-app purchases set up with Apple. So we don't need
Xcode for this step,
so I'm just going to switch it to the background and I'm going to go over to my browser, and we're going
to head over to developer.apple.com/account in order to log in to the developer
portal.
Now, once you have logged in, this is the page that you should see. And here we're going to go over to
Certificates, IDs & Profiles, and you're going to go into Identifiers and click on App IDs.
Now, this is a table that lists all of your app IDs and you can just go ahead and click the plus button
to add a new one.
So, now it takes you through the process of registering a brand-new app ID and this will register your
app on Apple's central database.
So the name of our app is going to be called in InspoQuotes, and then we're going to make sure that
Explicit App ID is set here,
and then we're going to set our Bundle ID.
Now, if you have a look back over to Xcode, you can see that this is the same as our Bundle iIdentifier
in the InspoQuotes, General tab in Identity section.
So I'm just simply going to copy this over to here.
Now, remember, Bundle IDs have to be unique on Apple's databases, so you won't be able to use this exact
Bundle ID.
So I recommend using a reverse domain name.
So if your domain is www.londonappbrewery.com, then com.londonappbrewery.
Now, if you don't have a company that has a website, then you can just do com.yourfullname,
so whatever it may be making sure that you try to keep it as long as possible because, remember, it has
to be unique, and then putting in the name of the app at the end.
Now, it's really important that this matches exactly with what you've got here.
So if it's easier, change it here, and then simply just copy and paste it into here because all of the
capitalizations matter
a huge deal.
Okay.
So next thing is to scroll down to the App Services section and you can see that the Game Center and
In-App Purchase's services are ticked by default.
Basically, whenever you create a new app ID,
they will automatically include these two capabilities to your app. So we don't even have to do anything
and we just have to click Continue.
And now all you have to do is click Register and then click Done.
Now, don't worry if these green lights aren't switched on when you're clicking on Register and Done, they
take a little while to come on and you can view it at a later date and you'll see it switch on after
you've clicked Done.
So this information is going to propagate through Apple's servers and databases.
So while it does that,
let's do a couple of checks to make sure that we have a smooth ride as possible.
Now, first of all if you've published any apps onto the App Store, then you'll know all about App Store
Connect.
This is the place where you put in all of the details for your app and push it onto the App Store.
Now, if you never publish an app and this is the first time then I'll take you through it step by step.
So first things first, head over to appstoreconnect.apple.com, and then go ahead and just log in.
Now,
once you're in, this is what you should see.
There's a whole bunch of icons. And most importantly, at this stage, we want to make sure that up at the
top here,
you don't see any red text.
So, usually, if there's something that you need to sign or you need to check, all you need to read
Apple will routinely on a weekly basis that seems update that contract and legals and a whole bunch
of things. And you just need to make sure that you've made all of those go away by signing the things
that you need to sign,
okaying the things you need to
okay,.
and checking the things that they want you to read.
So, another good place to check while you're here is to head over to Agreements, Tax, and Banking.
So this icon over here.
Now, if you haven't set up your Agreements, Tax, and Banking, then it might say something like
request contracts, and you'll have to click the request button, and fill out all of the information and
submit it. And it might take some time for the agreements to be processed by Apple.
So even after you submit it during the time before it gets approved, you won't be able to test your in-app
purchase products.
So if you see any buttons under the Agreement, Types, and Banking that says request, make sure you fit
it all out and submit it.
And at the point when you see paid applications as a contract type under the contract in effect, then
you are good to go.
And that is when you've made sure that all your Agreements, Tax, and Banking is all in tip-top condition
with Apple. And you can go ahead and click Done.
Now, the final thing to make sure is that when you head over to developer.apple.com, make sure
that they haven't got any pop-ups for you that says, "Accept the latest Apple development program license
agreements."
But if you do have any agreements that you need to sign or read on developer.apple.com, it will
usually also show up at the top of App Store Connect.
So making sure that you don't have any red boxes over here is a pretty sure fire way of knowing that
you are good in the eyes of Apple which, obviously, is very, very important
if we want to make in-app purchases work. So, now that we've delivered and dallied around here, hopefully,
all of our information when we registered our app ID has now been propagated through Apple services
and we are ready to create a brand-new app.
So, again, inside App Store connect,
go ahead and click on my apps. And once you're here, just go ahead and click the plus button to create
a new app.
Now, we're going to fill out this form to create our brand-new app. And don't worry nothing's going to be
released or put onto the app store without you being able to okay it.
So just go ahead and select iOS for your platform.
Now, the name of the app for me is going to be InspoQuotes.
Now, you won't be able to have the same name that I've got because they have to be unique across the
App Store.
So if you want to call it something around InspoQuotes, just add your initials or add, you know, your birthday,
or a special number, or something, until this form actually lets you submit.
Next thing is to choose your primary language, which is going to be English, and then we're going to leave
Bundle ID until the last.
The next thing is the SKU, which stands for stock-keeping unit.
So this is a unique ID that you give to your apps so that you can identify it amongst your App Catalog.
Now, in our case, we tend to prefix it with LAB, LONDON APP BREWERY, and then we'll just list the app number that
it is. This last one, Limit User Access,
we're going to keep it blank.
And finally, we're ready to go ahead and click the dropdown list for our Bundle ID.
Now, as I said before, it takes a little bit of time for the data that you entered previously when you
created a new app ID to propagate through Apple service.
So if you don't see that Bundle ID show up here, then just wait a little bit. Get a cup of tea, eat some
biscuits.
I really like ginger biscuits, but you can eat, obviously, any biscuits you want.
I don't know why I felt the need to tell you this.
Once you come back after a little while, then you should be able to see the bundle identifier that you
inputted previously, which in my case, was com.londonappbrewery/InspoQuotes. And in the front, you've
got the name of the app. So select that to the Bundle ID and we're ready to create our brand-new app.
So, now you get on to the app information and your listing details page,
and this is where when you publish your app, you're going to add your title, subtitle, your information
like which categories should it go in, or what should be the price of the app that you're going to set.
And also uploading your Xcode project to it.
But for now, we're just interested in testing in-app purchases.
So you're going to head over to the Features tab over here and you're going to be inside In-App Purchases
and we're going to click on the plus sign to create a new in-app purchase.
Now, you can see here that there's several options that you have.
And Apple gives you really good examples of when you would use each.
So the four types are Consumable,
so an in-app purchase that gets used ones, and after which, it gets depleted and you have to purchase
it again.
So, for example, if you had a fishing app and you had fish food that you need to lure the fish, then this
will be consumed every time they use it.
Commonly, this is used inside games when you need extra in-game currency, coins, energy, or whatever
that may be.
Now, the next one is Non-Consumable.
So this is something that gets purchased once and does not expire or decrease with use.
So for example, this would be, say, if you had a app that had ads and you charged the user .99 cents to
get rid of the ads, this would be a non-consumable in-app purchase because once they've got rid of the
ads, you shouldn't ask them to buy it again
to get rid of the ads, right?
That would be really, really bad.
So the third one is a Auto-Renewable Subscription. And this, for example, could be Spotify, right?
If they were charging it through the in-app purchases, then they could charge you $10 a month to continue
to get access to their music catalog,
and this would auto-renew every month or every week or whatever it is that you set.
And the final one is something that very few people use which is a Non-Renewing Subscription.
So this, for example, gives you a one year subscription where you're charged every single month.
But after that, it doesn't renew automatically.
So in our case, we're going to choose a Non-Consumable in-app purchase because we want to be able to
give users access to the premium quotes that's locked behind the paywall and they only have to pay
once
in order to get access to the rest of the content of the app.
So this is one of the most frequently used in-app purchase types, and we're going to go ahead and click
Create.
So, now we have to enter a little bit of information for our brand-new in-app purchase.
Now, the first thing is a Reference Name and this is just a name for you to be able to identify it on
App Store Connect.
It doesn't appear anywhere in the app. And in our case, we're just going to call it Premium Quotes just
to make it really clear.
Now, the Product ID is really, really essential. The product ID is going to be your Bundle ID, so whatever
you had in here that you also gave to your app. And then at the end, I usually just tack a dot, and then
the name of my in-app purchase.
So in this case, it will be PremiumQuotes without a space in between. Now, you can capitalize it or not capitalize
it any way you wish,
but make sure that you copy and save this string somewhere because we're going to be using it in order
to test and implement our in-app purchase
a little bit later on because we're going to say inside our app that we're going to point towards this
Product ID, and that is the one that we're going to try and get the user to purchase.
And once it's been purchased successfully, then we show them the premium quotes.
All right.
So next is pricing.
So you have to choose a pricing tier and it goes all the way up to a thousand dollars or a thousand pounds.
But in this case, we're just  going to choose tier 1 which is .99 cents or 99p, as currently, I'm registered
in the U.K. App Store.
Now, the next part if you scroll down is the Localizations
and this is the name that the user will see when they view the in-app purchases of your app on the App
Store.
So you want to give it a name that makes sense to them.
So if you want, you can also use Premium Quotes because that kind of makes sense for us. And for the description,
I'm also going to just write premium quotes because it saves a little bit of time.
Now, when you're actually doing this for your actual app, then you might want to put a little bit of thought
to what you want to tell the user about this in app purchase,
you know, maybe give them a little bit of sales pitch.
Now, if you want to add other localization,
so, for example, users on the Chinese app store, what they should see because, say, if they can't understand
English very well, then they'll be confused about the in-app purchases,
then you can add as many localizations as you wish.
So, for our purposes, we're just going to have the one, yours might say English US if your native store is
the US,
mine says UK. It doesn't really matter as long as you provide the name and description of a single localization
as a default.
Now, this is where you can put an image for your in-app purchase, again, a little bit later on. But it's optional,
so we're going to skip it.
And finally, this is the last part which requires a screen shot of your in-app purchase in action.
Now, we haven't implemented it, so we're just going to skip it and click Save. Now, because we've entered
and filled out all of the fields that need to be filled in,
then it'll allows to do this, but it'll give you this little warning saying, "Missing Metadata,"
and that refers to this section here, so that when you're ready to submit your app to publish, you should
add a screenshot of your in-app purchase being triggered in your app. And I'm going to show you what
that will look like just a little bit later on.
But as far as we're concerned, we're completely ready to get going and start writing some code and testing
our app.
So in the next lesson, we're going to get started creating our InspoQuotes app.
And once you're done over here, I'll see you on the next lesson.