Now, in the past few lessons, we've already massively improved some of our user interface, and it's starting
to really come along and look really nice.
So in this lesson, we're going to tie up all the loose ends and we're gonna do a little bit more
front-end stuff to make our app feel really cohesive and look like it's a real app on the App Store.
So the first thing that I want to do is I want to change the nav bar. Instead of having this small nav
bar,
I want to make it a large title. And in order to do that, there's only one checkbox that we need to check
off.
So if you go into your Main.storyboard and select, not the nav bars for your individual view controllers,
but the actual navigation controller's nav bar. And you can also select it inside the document outline
as well,
it's this particular one that you're interested,
the actual bar rather than the controller. If you head over to the attributes Inspector,
then there's this particular Boolean called Prefers Large Titles. And if you tick it, then you can see that
our navigation bars become a lot bigger
and the titles get bigger as well.
And it looks a lot more like an actual todoList.
And if we run our app, you'll see that it looks a lot nicer
in this particular format. It works much better as the heading.
So the next thing I want to change is that I want to change the nav bar to be consistent, also with the
background color of the category, so that everything on this screen is green. And the place where you're
going to set this is inside viewDidLoad.
So inside the TodoListViewController, go into the viewDidLoad and we are going to tap into our
navigationController.navigationBar. And then we're going to set, not it's background color, because this only
changes the background color of the bar,
but we're going to set the barTintColor. And this will apply it both to the navigation bar as well
as the status bar. And we're going to set this equal to the color based on the selected category.
So it'll be selectedCategory.colour. And, of course, remember, this is a hex string that describes a
color.
So we're going to have to use that UIColor method from Chameleon called UIcolor with hexString,
and then we're going to put that hexString inside here.
Now, as soon as you do that, Xcode is going to complain because we're using optional chaining here.
This value is an optional. And this UIColor using hexString method needs a nonoptional string in order
for this to work.
So you have the option of either explicitly unwrapping selectedCategory, which is not all that safe,
or you can use optional binding.
So we can say if let colourHex = selectedCategory?.colour. If this is not nil, then
we will proceed with this method and we can replace this part here with colourHex.
Now, the other assumption that we're making here, by using this question mark is we're saying if the
navigationController is not nil, then in that case, we're going to set the bar color for the navigation bar.
Now, this assumption is a little bit problematic ,and I'm going to show you why by using a "guard" statement.
So I'm going to say guard let navBar = navigationController.navigationBar, and then else, i.e., if it
is nil, then we're going to throw a fatalError
and I'm going to pass the message for that fatalError as "Navigation controller does not exist."
So what this line is going to do is it's going to create this constant called navBar and assign that
the value of the current navigationBar in the current navigationController.
But if this is nil, i.e., then navigationController does not yet exist, then we're going to throw this
fatalError and we're going to inform ourselves of this problem. And our app is going to crash and we're
going to see this message.
So let's run our app and see what happens.
Okay.
So let's go into our
TodoListViewController. And you can see that our app is right now crashing. And if we click on this error, then it says,
"Fatal error: Navigation controller does not exist."
So the thing is when you start off learning how to develop apps for iOS, people tend to be very afraid
of app crashes.
But as you get more and more experience, you should start to learn that crashes are not bad. They're not
a bad thing.
What you don't want is for your app to fail silently in the background, and your variables and property
is having values that are unexpected and undesired.
But it's not giving you a warning in any sort of way.
So don't be afraid of throwing fatal errors when you have a situation where you definitely don't expect
it to break so that you can catch these problems during testing, rather than in the live deployment app
on the App Store when your app is not behaving the way it should be
and the user has no clue how to report this.
So, now let's stop our app and figure out what's going on.
Why is our navigationController nil at this point?
Why are we getting this fatal error being thrown?
Well, the problem is that we know that viewDidLoad is the time point at which our view for our current
view controller has been loaded up.
Now, the problem is that just because the view has been loaded up, it does not mean that your view has been
inserted into the navigation controller,
it might not yet be in that navigation stack.
So during the process of pushing this TodoListViewController onto the navigation stack to be managed
by the navigation controller, viewDidLoad will get cold.
But the thing that you cannot be sure of is whether if the TodoListViewController is already inside
the navigation stack, i.e., if that process has completed before viewDidLoad gets called.
So in our case, it's clear that viewDidLoad is actually being called before the navigationController
property has been updated, because at this point, it is still nil.
So what can we do?
Well, maybe consider that viewDidLoad might not be the right place to place this code. And if we think
back to the lesson on view controller life cycles, then you might remember that there's another access
point that we can use which was called viewWillAppear. And viewWillAppear gets called later than
viewDidLoad and it's actually at the point just right before the view is going to show up on the screen.
So after the view has been loaded up after the navigation stack has been established, and just before the
user sees anything on screen, this is the time point that we can access using viewWillAppear.
And so I'm going to transplant my code here into viewWillAppear, and it's probably also a good time
to delete this stray bit of code here if you haven't done already
because we no longer need that.
Okay.
So inside our viewWillAppear, we're still going to use our guard let navigationBar. And Xcode is complaining
and giving as a warning at the moment that you've guarded and you've created this constant called
navBar. We're not really using it anyway.
So let's use it. Let's replace this navigationBar that's uses optional chaining.
So this is why our barTintColor didn't change at all previously because navigationController is nil
and the way that optional chaining works is that if this is nil, then this code is not going to be continued.
So this gets skipped over.
So instead, what we want to do is we want to use navBar and we're guarding against scenarios where navBar
is nil by using this guard statement
So let's go ahead and run our app and see if that worked.
Okay.
So we're going to go into the Home screen and you can see that our status bar, our navigation bar, everything
gets changed just by moving our code to a different life cycle time point. And our app doesn't crash,
our fatal error is not being thrown. Because at this point, the navigation property has a value, it's not
nil. And our current view controller is firmly inside the navigation stack.
So the other things that we might want to do here is maybe change the title of our
TodoItemsViewController.
It would be nice if this title reflected the category that we selected,
right?
And it's pretty easy to tap in to because we have this selectedCategory property here.
So we can simply say something like title, which is a string that represents the view that this controller
manages,
and this is basically what the navigationController will tap into to populate the title in the
navBar.
So we can say title = selectedCategory.
And because we're inside an optional binding block where we've already access the selectedCategory's
color through optional binding, then we can be pretty sure that selectedCategory does in fact exist
and it's not nil.
So title will become selected category.name.
So as you progress, you're going to be more flexible with these optionals and figure out ways of being
safe while being constantly aware of what it is that your code is doing, and the places where it can
fall down.
So let's run our app and see if our title gets populated. And if we go inside Home, you can see that our
title used to be Item, but it now is the title of the Category.
So looking pretty sweet, right? Now, there's just one other thing that's bugging me which is, what about
the background of the search bar,
it looks so out of place with that grey background.
Let's change it.
So for us to be able to do that, we first have to create an outlet from the search bar into our
TodoListViewController. So you can either click and drag from the search bar just making sure that you've
actually selected the search bar and not a table view.
Alternatively and probably a much better way is to go from the document outline and drag it into your
TodoListViewController.
And I'm just going to call it searchBar and hit enter to create that IBOutlet, and then we can go inside
viewWillAppear just underneath the line that we wrote previously.
So, we'll tap into searchBar.tint Color
and this applies the tint color to the search bar background
and we're going to set it to equal the same color that we've specified for our navigationBar.
So let's go ahead and hit run and see if that worked.
So we're going to go into Home and you can see everything is now more or less green.
Now, another thing that you might want to change is the color of these buttons.
So, for example, this button currently is sort of a light blue which doesn't look that great.
We manually set this button to be white.
But what if our navigation bar was set to a really light color, for example, white or something like that,
then in that case we might not be able to see these buttons,
right?
So we should do what we've done here which is set these buttons to contrast the color of the navigation
bar and we can do that just below where we set the barTintColor because there's another property in
the navigation bar called the tintColor.
And this applies to all of the navigation items and bar button items.
So that is the one that we want to change.
We're going to set it to the contrasting color of the color of the navBar and we're going to return
it as flat which basically means a low contrast color.
Now, we have a problem here because the output of this particular method is a optional UIColor and that's
fine over here because barTintColor takes a optional UIColor.
But in this case, the contrasting color method requires a nonoptional UIColor.
So we either have to force unwrap it which is unsafe or we will have to create another if let.
So if let fnavBarColour = UIColor created with the colourHex code.
And if that is not nil, then we will set the navBar background the tintColor as well as the search
bar colors.
So we're going to paste that inside this optional binding statement, and then we can change this to
navBarColour, and change this to navBarColour, and also we can change this to navBarColour because it's gonna
be the same.
Now, the next thing that we want to change is the color of the title.
And if we have a look through the UINavigationBar Documentation, then you can see that there's a section
called Customizing the Appearance of a Navigation Bar,
and it talks about how you would change the title text differently from the rest of the controls, so
the bar button items, for example. And you need to change this titleTextAttributes property by setting
the foregroundColor key.
So let's go ahead and do that here.
Now, we're gonna say navigationBar to tap into the current bar.
Then we're going to look for the titleTextAttributes.
Now, it's important that because we're using the large title, we have to change the properties for the
largeTitleTextAttributes, rather than just the regular titleTextAttributes which is the smaller
one that shows up in the middle.
So let's select largeTitleTextAttribute property, and it's expecting a dictionary where it takes a
key which is an NSAttributedStringKey
and it takes a value which is going to be the value for whichever key you choose.
So we're going to create a new dictionary and we're going to tap into that
NSAttributedStringKey. And we're going to use the dot notation to find the key that we want.
And this is a bit like an enum where we're looking through and trying to find the value that we want
to change.
And in our case, it's actually the foreground color that we're interested in changing, the foregroundColor
for the large text title.
And this is going to be set to our contrast color contrasting the navBarColor returning a flat color.
And now, we're almost ready to run our app.
The last thing that we need to do before we can do that is we need to go into our Main.storyboard and
click on that plus button which we manually set to be white
and we need to change it back to default.
And now if we run our app and we go into Home, you can see that everything gets colored correctly, and
also the background color looks exactly as we want it to.. Now, there's just one problem, the navigation
bar and the category view controller is not behaving as expected. In order to fix this,
let's change the navigation bar's background color to blue in the CategoryViewController.
I'm gonna do this in the viewWilllAppear lifecycle method.
So the part where it says override function viewWillApear or add the same guard let as in the
TodoListViewController.
So guard let navBar equals navigationController.navigationBar
else through a fatalError that "Navigation controller does not exist." Except for this time, I'll change
the background color to the UIColor with the hex code pound sign 1D9BF6. So navBar. backgroundColour
= UIColor with hexString pound sign "1D9BF6." And if we run our app, you'll see that it works
exactly as it did before.
Now, the very, very, very last thing that I want to fix is the text color inside the cell for the
CategoryViewController here, because I can barely read it off that dark background.
So we know how to do that. Inside our TodoListViewController,
when we did cellForRowAt indexPath, we had this line of code where we contrasted the color of the background
color.
So I'm gonna go into the CategoryViewController and go into its selfForRowAt indexPath and I'm going
to set the cell's textLabel.textColor to be the contrasting color of this color which came from
the category and returning as a flat color.
Now, of course, if you wanted to, you can either use if let or guard let categoryColour to be equal to this
UIColor created using that category. colour hexString. And if that doesn't work, then I'm gonna
throw a fatalError because it really should.
Now, I can set the cell's backgroundColor to categoryColour, and I can contrast the color, instead of this
long string to categoryColour as well.
And let's run our up and see if that worked.
All right.
Nice.
That's looking a lot better than before.
As you can see, there's so much that you can do with the front-end and the UI.
You can really go to town if you wanted to.
And off the top of my head, I can probably think of even more UI improvements, but we have achieved most
of our design aims.
We wanted to have different colors for each category and that we wanted that color to be carried over when
we go into the TodoListViewController.
We have the category as the title of this TodoListViewController and we've created this gradient
effect for each of our cells, and we've contrasted the text with that background.
So if you do decide to add even more front-end code and make this even more fancy and even prettier,
then be sure to post a video of it or a GIF of it to the Q-and-A section so that we can all admire your beautiful
work.
So I hope you enjoyed making this app with me and learning all about, oh, my gosh, so many things in this
module.
The main reason why I created this module was to teach you all of the different ways that you can persist
this data locally.
And we covered user default,
we covered the quotable protocol.
We covered file storage locally as well as Core Data and Realm which we've used to create relational
databases.
And finally, we've wrapped it all up using a nice UI, and we now have this beautiful to-do list app which
you will no doubtedly use to add new to-do items like other new iOS codes that you're going to learn
about.
That's all for me for this module and I will see you on the next module.