So on the iOS App Store when you list your app there is a field that you can fill in
for all of your keywords. So it's limited to 100 characters and you can try and stuff in as many keywords
as you want.
So the important thing to note for when you're listing an iOS app is that you don't need to add any
spaces.
If you add spaces they will take up your character count.
So just have keyword, keyword no spaces.
First tip.
Second tip is that the App Store will automatically conjure up all the various plural versions of your
keywords as well as all the different combinations.
So say if we're making a coffee app and you want to have the words Coffee Bean and coffee in there,
you don't have to write coffee, coffee bean. Instead just write coffee, bean, whatever else
it is
because the app store already will form all the possible combinations of all your keywords.
Now the third thing to remember is that you can't update your keywords on the fly. In order to update
your keywords
you have to push out an update to your app. So make sure that you think carefully about what you're going
to put in here because to a large extent it's going to determine how highly your app ranks for the keywords
and that will directly contribution to your download rate and hence your revenue.
Now on the Google Play Store, keywords work slightly differently.
So on the Google Play store you're able to add a description as well as a name to your app. And similar
to how websites work,
Google will look through your description to determine what the keywords should be.
So in this case, if you have a particular keyword like coffee, you want to make sure that it appears as
frequently and as naturally as possible in your description.
So don't write a description that's just coffee, coffee, coffee, coffee, coffee.
It has to be in a natural context.
And the closer to the beginning of each of these fields means that the higher the word is weighted.
So if you have an app name that is called Coffee House, it will rank higher for the word coffee than
House coffee for example.
So keep your keywords as close to the top left as possible.