Now another tol I want to talk to you about is pretty new
actually. It only came about because Apple has recently introduce something called Search Ads.
So if you haven't heard about this, this is where basically they now allow apps to appear as ads. So similar
to when you go into Google and you search for something like Weight-Loss all the top results,
these three which are labeled ads, have been paid for in order to appear right at the top for this keyword.
Now for the Apple and the Google App Store you can now do the same for your apps. So you can create
an ad for your app to show up for certain keywords
even if you don't organically rank.
So this can be helpful if you have a new app that has you know virtually no downloads or no notoriety
or no reviews.
But from a lot of testing on our side, it seems quite expensive to get those conversions.
Now the thing I want to talk to you about is not to go and create ads but instead I want to show you
a good tool inside the search ads platform.
If you head over to searchads.apple.com and you hit start.
Then you log in with your Apple ID, you are able to create a new search ad campaign.
Now if you click on that you get access to a keyword research tool and you don't have to actually pay
and you don't actually have to put on an ad or pay Apple anything in order to use this keyword tool.
So this is very similar to the Google Adwords keyword tool.
It basically allows you to get from the horse's mouth the search popularity of certain keywords.
So for example, if we have a coffee app and I type in the keyword coffee, then Apple will suggest to me
various keywords that have high popularity.
So unlike Sensor Tower where a lot of this data is inferred and estimated, this is data from Apple itself.
So the words that are related to coffee that ranked really highly are coffee or coffee spelt badly or
coffee cafe, Starbucks.
So people might not be looking for coffee app but maybe they're looking for the Starbucks app then in which
case they're probably coffee drinkers might be interested in your app.
So this is another cool tool for you to play around with.