Now one thing to remember about key words is that you want to keep in mind where you are in your app development
cycle.
So when you are early stage i.e. you've just launched your app onto the App Store,
then you don't have any metrics to show off.
You don't have any reviews, you don't have any ratings, you barely have any downloads and that is going
to make it hard for you to rank highly for difficult keywords.
So when you're picking keywords, you want to go for something that might not be searched so frequently
but has low difficulty rating. So there's not a lot of apps which are targeting it.
So when we're thinking about ninja game which is one of the most popular keywords that a lot of games
are targeting, maybe consider ninja games you could target something like Warrior Games or samurai games
which don't have as many apps that
are trying to compete for that word in which case you have a higher chance of coming out on top.
Now as you go from your early to your mid and late game when you're racking up those reviews those downloads
those in-app usage time, then you can start thinking about targeting those words that are slightly more
difficult.
But bear in mind which stage you are and try to maximize the chance that you'll show up by selecting
keywords of the right difficulty.