So one of the first things about Facebook ads that a lot of people want to know is isn't it really expensive?
And on a relative basis compared to something like Google adwords,
yes it is expensive.
You'll usually paying something between 50 cents and a dollar for one click.
So that click is simply a click from the Facebook platform onto the App Store.
It might not even equal a download.
So you have to be aware of these costs and make sure by acquiring that one user, you can in fact make
back the same amount if not more from that acquisition.
But on the other hand if you think about the minimum cost of Facebook advertising it's something as
low as a dollar a day.
It just means that your ad won't be as competitive as other ads and it won't be shown as often.
So there's two main styles of advertising. And one is pay per click
so this is how much are you willing to pay per click on your action button
so that could be download now buy now, whatever it is you decide to name it.
Now the other option is cost per thousand impressions or CPM. And this is where you pay for a thousand
people to have come across your ad.
Now that could be in the right hand side bar, that could be in the middle of the feed, that could be on
Instagram that could be basically a glance.
Now paper click or CPC is way more expensive than CPM and what you should do is to try and improve the
conversion of your actual ad so that you make those 1000 impressions really count and you can get more
clicks by paying less by doing so.