So if you've never seen what the insides of Facebook ad manager looks like then just simply have a
look at it. You don't have to pay anything to set up a new campaign.
You can go to ad manager from your Facebook account. And once you arrive there if you've never done any
sort of social media marketing, you'll be scared by how much information you have access to.
So for example, not only can you determine where you want to show your ad to so only in the UK or the age
range of the people you want to show it to or the gender or the language, but you have really detailed
targeting abilities. For example like, what is their residential profile,
are they a homeowner,
are they likely mortgaged,
are they likely to be a second time buyer, are they a private home renter and this is the data that Facebook
and Twitter get from either the users posting it themselves and putting that data into Facebook or from
census data.
So it's actually pretty scary and you should realize that any sort of data that you're putting into
Facebook or you're telling your friends via Facebook will get used against you in advertising.
So for example, you can quite easily target all the women who have changed their relationship status
from single to engaged within the last two weeks.
And if you're a wedding photographer or if you're a wedding band, then that means that every single one
of your ads is being shown to a potential customer rather than just anybody.
So part of is the audience targeting
is really really useful.
But the thing that you have to be aware of is to not make your target niche so small that that pointer
is in the red area.
So you want to keep that point roughly in the center and that usually equates to half a million to a
million people.
And the reason for that is because not everybody is simultaneously on Facebook.
If you don't have a lot of time, you want your ads to show up to as many relevant people as soon as possible.
So we usually say try to aim for the needle roughly in the middle and don't make it too broad or make
it too specific.
It's roughly in this area that you get the best chance of your ads performing well.
So even though you can see that the potential reach is 20 million people the estimated daily reaches
only about 500 to 1300 people.
Now if you up your daily budget to say 20 pounds, then that number will go up.
But we're really looking for the low hanging fruit.
So if your potential reach was only 10,000 people, then your daily reach at a reasonable budget will only
be like 10 people which means that you're not really advertising at scale.