All right.
So that was our introduction to digital design, app design, user interface and user experience design.
I hope you enjoy the course and you're on your way to creating beautifully designed apps.
And when you do, do let us know about it and we can chat about it to all the people that we know.
Now I want to tell you about something called The L.A.B Report.
This is a bi-monthly digest that we curate every two weeks,
so it's not too frequent.
And essentially what we do is we update you on some of things are happening in the tech world, in the
app world, and we curate list of some of our favorite articles on programming, on app design, on app business
and we send it to your email inbox on a Sunday so you can browse through it leisurely and continue on
your journey of learning more about design or app programming or whatever it is that you're interested
in.
So if you're interested in getting access to this all you have to do is go to the link in the text box
below or go to getrevue.co/profile/londonappbrewery and join the club.
So that's all from me
and goodbye for now.