Hey.
Well done for completing the last module.
Today I want to talk about something that has really helped me in my life. And it's in these moments
when something is needed of me
say somebody is asking me to give a talk to 2,000 people or somebody else who wants to fly me
somewhere to teach their entire engineering team.
And it's in these moments when I say to myself "Oh, I can't possibly do that.
That's for-- that's for somebody who's much much better than me."
And it's these moments when if I just ignore that inner voice and I tell myself, "You know what? I'm going
to study for it, I'm going to prep for it.
I'm going to make sure that I'm more ready than anybody else for this position for this role for this
task."
It's these moments that we learn and we become better.
So, always look out for these moments where you're doubting yourself and you're being asked to step up.
If you really do step up then I promise you are going to go so much further than if you just stayed in
the same place.
So keep going
and remember I'm here to cheer you on.