Do you ever find that you reach the end of the day
and it feels like my god
you know I have no more energy or brainpower to do anything else let alone try to study something difficult
like programming.
Now one of the ways that you can really help yourself is either by shifting your study block to the beginning
of the day, so maybe wake up an hour earlier. Or the alternative is to try to reduce the amount of decision
making you make in a day.
So for example if you have the same breakfast every day,
if you have many sets of the same piece of clothing then you can reduce the amount of decisions that
you have to make like what should I eat or what should I wear.
And all of these decisions they take a toll on us.
The more that we have to make of these decisions the more that we struggle to do important things like
learning and studying and especially when it comes to learning difficult skills like programming.
So try to have more routine in your day, try to establish habits so you don't always have to keep asking
yourself what should I do now,
what should I...
And make these decisions. That way you'll end up with more energy and more drive to pursue the things
that you really want to.
So keep going and you're doing great.