So in the last lesson, we talked about the OpenWeather Map API and how we can use it by simply passing
over the queries that we're interested in.
For example, we formatted our final URL that queries the API for the weather in Paris. And we managed
to get hold of that by putting it simply into the browser and getting the browser to fetch this data
back.
Now, this process in programming, we would call Networking.
It's not like going to a room and exchanging business cards.
Instead, your app is talking to a web server.
And in our case, it's OpenWeather Map's web server.
So the web server is like an application in itself.
And what we're trying to do is to talk to the web server of OpenWeather Map and make a request for
data. And as a part of this request, we pass over some of the queries for what data we're interested in,
for example, the name of the city for whose whether we want to get back. Now, when the web server looks at
your query, as long as it can recognize it because you've been abiding by the rules of the API, say, you're
using that letter q which is lowercase, and you're passing over an app ID and you've actually got a
valid app ID, well, then the web server is going to respond back to your app and it's going to send
back the data that you requested. This entire process is called networking. And in Swift, when we want
to perform that networking action, just like what you saw in the browser using Chrome,
there's a couple of steps that we have to go through.
First, we have to create an actual URL object, and then we create what's called a URL session which
is going to be the object that's going to be doing on networking, effectively, like what the browser is
doing.
Step three: we give this you URL session a task, just like how we put the URL into the browser's
URL bar, and gave our browser a task to do which is fetching the data from that particular source.
The final step is to actually start the task. And that's effectively when we hit enter in the search
bar which triggers the entire networking process and, hopefully, we get our data back.
So let's try doing this in our project. In our WeatherManager,
I'm gonna create another method, and this is going to be called performRequest.
Now, the request is going to be based on the URL string that we got which is, of course, going to be
a string data type.
Then we can, instead of printing the URL string, we can call performRequest and pass over this URL
string which now lands in here as the inputs and we can access it through this URL string. And inside
our performRequest method is where we're going to carry out those four steps of networking.
Step one is to create a URL.
So let's create a URL. And we do that by using URL initializer.
So this is going to be a structure that we're going to create.
And as always, we initialize our structures and classes with a set of parenthesis.
And now if we scroll through this list of different initializers, you'll come across one which takes
a string. And that's what we've got, we've got a string to represent the URL. And in this initializer,
we have to pass in our string which is the URL string that we got as the input.
Now, notice how this way of initializing URLs from strings which commonly can have typos,
say, we misspelled "q" and instead wrote "p" by accident,
well, then it might fail.
So that's why this initializer creates an optional URL. And you can actually see that even at the point
when we were choosing from our Xcode autosuggest list, you can see that it creates a optional URL,
URL with the question mark here. So in order to use our URL that's created this way,
we're going to use "if let." So we optionally bind the
URL that's created to a constant code URL
as long as this doesn't fail and doesn't end up being nil. So now that we've got our URL created,
it's time to move on to the next step.
Step two is to create a URL session. And, again, pretty easy, we create a "let" constant which we'll call
session and we're going to set this to a URL session object. So it's not a session task, it's actually
just a session. And as soon as I open my set of parentheses, you can see that there's two ways of creating
a URL session, one with lots of different options, and another one which where we just have a single
configuration property we have to set. The configuration that we're going to use is going to be just
the default configuration. This ends up creating our URL session object which is effectively like
browser. It's the thing that can perform the networking. Now, we can move on to step three
which is to give the session a task. So we can tap into our session that we've just created and we can give
it a data task with URL and completion handler.
So this is the one that you want to choose.
Creates a task that retrieves the contents of the specified URL and then calls a handler or a method
once it completes. So let's hit enter and let's create that line of code.
Now, the URL is, of course, going to be the URL that we created just now.
So that's this one right here.
And the completionHandler,
we're going to leave for the moment.
We're going to proceed forward and finish the last step which is to start the task.
Now, this method returns a URLSession dataTask. So we can set the output as a constant code task.
So now we create a dataTask with our URL, and then we set it equal to this constant task. And in step
four, we can say task.resume.
Now, the naming of this method is a little bit weird.
Why is it not called start?
Why is it called resume?
Well, in the case of tasks, because they can be suspended, and in fact, the newly initialized tasks, just
like what we've done here, where we've created a new task they begin in a suspended state.
So you need to call this method to start the task, basically.
So all of this goodness is coming from documentation reading, as usual.
So now let's address our completionHandler.
What exactly is a completionHandler?
Well, in programming, there's a lot of cases where you have very time-consuming tasks.
And for example, in this case, when we create our task and we start the task, what this task is doing is
it's effectively having to go to this URL, grab the data, go across the entire world, and come back
with the data. That can take anywhere between a fraction of a second to a couple of minutes depending
on your internet connection speed.
Therefore, we can't just wait for it,
right?
Our app needs to do other things.
So instead, we have a completionHandler, which even though it looks like an input parameter, it actually
takes a function as the value.
And you can see that it's a function because it's got the classic things that a function has, the parenthesis
for the inputs, and then a hyphen, an angle bracket for the output. Even though, in this case, the output
is void, which means there's actually no output,
it's just a method like this method which doesn't actually have any outputs. But to represent and to
show us that this is definitely a function,
that's why it has the hyphen angle bracket void.
Effectively, what it's saying is that it needs to take a function as the input.
So let's give it a function.
Let's create a function somewhere down here.
So just before the last closing bracket, I'm going to create a function called handle. and this handle
method is going to take all of the inputs that are prescribed right here. You can see there's the first
input which needs to be of date type optional data,
then another one which is optional URLResponse, and then another one which is an optional error.
A lot of optionals, basically.
So let's go ahead and add our data property which is of type Data optional, and then our response parameter
which is of data type URLResponse optional,
and finally, our error which is going to be of type Error optional.
So here's our method. And if we wanted to signify that, it's not going to return anything, then we can
actually have the return void here as well.
But this actually does nothing when we're just defining a method, that doesn't return anything.
We can also just actually not mention it.
It does the same thing. Now, that we've got our function defined, we can actually pass it in here.
So as soon as I start writing handle, you can see that Xcode has recognize this as a method,
and if I hit enter, it'll insert it in as the value of this completionHandler input. And if I hit command B
to build and hit my app with a stick, then you can see that Xcode is completely happy with what I've
done here,even though it looks a little bit weird.
So let's break it down here.
Effectively, what I'm doing is I'm passing in a call to the method handle which I created here.
And for each of these inputs, I'm actually not passing in any values.
Instead, the completionHandler is going to be triggered by the task.
So when this session completes its networking and the task is complete, it is the one that will call
the completionHandler. And you can have a read of it by option clicking on the completionHandler.
And this handler when it gets called, it's going to pass in those three things
as long as it has them, an optional piece of data, an optional response, and an optional error. So effectively,
we're leaving it to the task to trigger this method.
But once it does, then we'll have access to the data response an error object that it sends us.
So now inside our handle method, we could, for example, check to see was there an error in this whole networking
process.
So if error does not equal nil, well, in that case, why don't we go ahead and print the error.
And because it's an optional, it needs to be unwrapped if we want to use it.
And in this case, because we've already checked that it's not nil,
this will now be able to let us check for errors.
Now, what we want to do if there was an error is we want to simply return.
Now, notice how there's nothing after the return keyword. When I simply just add the word "return," it means
exit out of this function, and don't continue. Because the next step is we want to check what data we
got back.
So if there was an error, then I don't want to actually do anything else.
It obviously failed.
So proceeding forward is probably going to create more problems for me.
But if there were no errors, well, in that case, I'm going to create a "if let" constant, which I'll call
safeData, which is going to use optional binding to unwrap my data object that I got back.
So if let safeData = data, well, then I can take a look at this data. Now, data objects are not quite
as easily printable as strings.
If I simply just went ahead and printed safeData, you won't actually see the contents of the data.
Let's first convert it into a string. So we can say let dataString = String data type, and we're
going to initialize it using one of its initializers.
And if we go down this list of all of these initializers, there's one of these that takes a data object as the
input.
So that's what we need.
We're going to pass our safe data in here and we're going to pass it into a string. And the encoding
for most of the data that we get back from the web is UTF-8 and this is just a standardized protocol
for encoding text in websites. So now that we've got this as a string, we can go ahead and try to print
our data string.
Let's give this code a go and see if it actually works. Now let's give it a spin.
I'm going to search for the weather in Paris, and then when I click search, you'll notice that we get
an error in our debug. And it tells us that there's an error with a error code and the resource that
you're requesting could not be loaded because App Transport Security policy requires the use of a secure
connection.
What does this mean?
Well, notice how even back in the Chrome browser when we were requesting the data from the Open Weather
Map API, we were getting this warning from Chrome as well, saying, "Hey, this URL that you're trying
to access is not secure."
And the reason is because when we're sending this request, anyone one who's intercepting this request
can see our app ID, our units which we might not care about, and our queries. In order for this to be
secured and encrypted,
what we have to do is we have to have an HTTPS request.
So something that looks like this. Whereas our URL that we're using at the moment is an HTTP
URL.
So in order to get to OpenWeather Map's API is through a secure route, then we can simply just change
this to HTTPS.
So this is a common error that you might come across when you're doing networking and it's really important
to be aware of the fact that Apple actually catches you out if you're trying to access an HTTP or trying
to load a resource in an unsafe manner.
So now that we're connecting to Open Weather Map through a secure route, as soon as I go ahead and enter
Paris again, as the request, you'll see down here that I'm getting my data string printed in here with
the coordinates of Paris, the weather in Paris that there is a clear sky, and that the temperature is
23.58 Celsius.
So we've effectively done the same thing as we have done here by putting our request into the URL,
but instead, this time, we're doing it using URLSession. So this way of using the completionHandler
getting the task object to call this method whenever it's done getting the data off of the internet,
allows us to get on with other things, and only trigger our print statement or whatever else it is that
we might need to do with the string
once the process has completed. So while this method works where we create a method and we pass in the
method here as the input value, there's a much more common way of writing this and it involves something
called closures which are effectively functions that are anonymous, functions without a name like this
name here "handle." If you already know about Swift closures and you want to skip the next Deep Dive, then
feel free to do so. But if you want to know how we can use closures to create the typical anonymous function,
then head over to the next lesson and learn more about it there.