It's time for yet another Swift Deep Dive.
And in this Deep Dive, we're going to look at Variables.
So essentially, we've seen that variables are simply a way of giving a name to a piece of data, so that
we can reference it in our code later on.
We did that for our IBoutlets as well as our dice number variable which we created from scratch.
And the problem that it solves is really simple.
Let's say that if I was to give you a phone number to remember and I give it to you written down on
a piece of paper,
now if all I had on there was just a number, I know what my drawers looked like, and if I have a single
piece of paper floating around in there,
after not even a day I'll forget what that number was all about.
So how can we make this better?
How can we remember what this piece of data is about?
We could associate that data with an actual label and give it a name.
So we're essentially taking our data and labeling it with a name.
Well this is essentially a variable because if we needed that piece of data in the future, we can simply
refer to the label name, which is Angela,
and it will be able to retrieve that piece of data.
So we have to write a little bit more if we're creating this in code.
We have to add a var keyword which tells the computer that we're creating a new variable, and then we
add an equal sign to tell the computer that on the right-hand side of the equals sign is the value that
we're assigning to that particular variable.
So you can essentially view creating variables similar to creating just a box,
right?
And you whack on a label which we'll be able to identify what's inside the box and you put some data
inside the box.
And now you can store it somewhere on a shelf ready for retrieval. And by looking at that label, you'll
know what's contained inside.
So if you need the data that's inside, you simply find the right box with the right label.
Now variables were made to be their heat,
right?
That's the whole point.
So we can simply remove the old value and put in a new one if we wanted to.
And now that label name Angela is associated with a completely different piece of data. In the resources
for this lesson,
you'll find a download link for the Swift Cheat Sheet that we've created for you.
And this is just a handy reference guide.
A lot of students like to print it out to have it beside them when they're learning and it's a way for
you to be able to quickly refer to the grammar of the Swift programming language.
So just as an English we have our commerce and our full stops and they have meaning in the sentence
in Swift and other programming languages.
We have certain keywords like the var keyword which is used for creating variables or the equal sign
which is used for assigning a value to a variable.
And this is a handy guide that you can always flip back to when you're completing challenges and when
you're trying to write your own code.
So the way that we create a variable is we start out with the var keyword, then we give our variable
a name, and then we assign it a value.
That's the theory of it.
But let's head into a playground and actually create some code from scratch.
So let's say that we had a variable code a and we gave it a number, let's say, 5, and then let's create
another variable code b and let's give it a value of 8.
Now, if I decided to print these values,
so print a,
and then print B.
Now, notice, in this case, I don't have those quote marks around the a and b because if I had that, then
it would simply interpret this as a command to simply print the letter or the string a.
And that's what you see here.
But if I actually want the value of my variable a, then I have to make sure that I'm putting it in as
a variable name a and b, rather than anything with quotation marks in it.
I can make this a little bit fancier by adding some string interpolation if you remember. The value of
a is,
and then I can add that backslash and put my variable inside some parentheses.
And now I get printed,
the value of a is 5.
And I can do the same thing for b. The value of B is B. And let's just make sure we're not missing that
final quotation mark.
And now we get the value of a is 5, the value of b is 8.
So now that we've covered the theory of Swift Variables, let's get a little bit more practice with Swift
programming through a coding challenge.
Now, as always, the challenges are clearly optional, but solving them will help cement the concepts that
we've covered and make you a stronger programmer.
Also figuring out and solving these little puzzles is gonna be a lot of fun.
So I've collated all of this with programming challenges on a website called Repl.it
You'll find the link under the student resources as always.
So just click on the Interactive Programming Challenges link. Clicking link takes you to the special
Repl.it classroom I've set up for you.
And the big advantage of using Repl.it for these challenges is that you can get your code checked
and look at my model solution.
Once you've created your account, then head back into our Swift classroom page.
Now, here you can browse the assignments, but you won't be able to take them until you click on this button
which says Take and Learn.
Now, once you've done that, our challenges are added to your account
as a student classroom.
So, if you click on the student link, you'll be able to see all the classrooms that you're signed up
to
and when you click on it, you'll be able to see or the assignments that you can take.
So the assignment that we're going to take today is the variables assignment. For this challenge,
I've got the starting code right here and I've got a detailed description on the right for what you
need to do to complete the challenge.
So what's the challenge? Without changing these lines or changing these lines,
can you swap the values of a and b, so that when these two lines execute, it will say the value of a
is 8 and the value of b is 5.
But here's the catch, you can't type a single number.
So in your solution, you're not allowed to type a 5 or an 8.
You have to figure out how to switch these two without simply assigning it with a different number. Because
the easy way is to say, a, well, now equals 8, and b now equals 5.
And I will get that a is equal to 8 and B is equal to 5
and I've switched those two values around, but I have used a number.
So for this programming challenge, we're going to be using code to achieve this,
and you have all of the tools and knowledge to be able to do this, but you might have to think a little
bit outside of the box.
So this is a really, really common interview question that you will get as a programmer.
And it just tests you a little bit in terms of your lateral thinking and whether if you understand variables
well enough.
Once you've completed your solution, you can click this run button to run it down here and it works just
like as with playground.
Now once you're happy with the output that you're seeing, then you can go ahead and click on the Submit
button to submit the assignments. I'll give you a few seconds to pause a video before I show you how
to submit the assignment and view the model solution.
All right.
Ready?
Did you have a go at the assignment and did you manage to get it right?
Let me show you the solution and how to submit your assignment and check your code.
Now, the trick to solving this puzzle is to simply create another variable.
So let's go ahead and replace this line with our code.
I'm going to create another variable code c and I'm going to set c to equal the current value of a.
So at this point, c is going to be equal to 5.
Now, next, we can set a equal to b.
Now, at this point a is now equal to 8.
And finally, we can set B to equal the value of what's held inside c, and so b now equals 5.
And within our three steps if we run our code, you'll see that a is now 8 and B is now 5.
We've managed to switch these two values around in only three lines of code without needing to write
any numbers, such as a = 8 or b = 5.
So now that I'm happy with my solution, I can go ahead and click on submit and you can see that I've
passed all the tests, I've managed to switch the values correctly. Now if I'd gotten it wrong,
now let's say that my code was not yet working and I wasn't getting the right outputs,
if I try to click submit now, you'll see that I get a error and that the output is not matching what
it should be.
So at this point, you can click on "What's wrong?" and you can see the problem which is that the teacher
expected a = 8, b = 5, but your output at the moment has a difference.
So then we can click Keep trying and make sure we've typed the code that will pass all our tests.
We've already checked it using our run button and we now click submit, our tests all passed, and we can finally
click on submit.
At this point, we can actually click on a link that shows up to see the model solution that we provided
for you. So we can go ahead and click OK.
And it will show us the model solution right here. So you can only see the model solution after you submit
your assignment and you can click on the back to submission button to see your own code.
So this is how Repl.it works.
And it allows us to show you the model solution as well as test the code that you've got
and for you to complete these challenges and improve your programming skills. I'll see you on the next
lesson. We will learn more about Swift Arrays.