All right guys.
So you've signed up to the best iOS development course in the world and you're going to find out very
shortly why.
Over 17,000 people have rated this course ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️ stars.
But in order to get the most out of the course there's a couple of things I want to draw your attention
to.
Firstly, the majority of the course is going to be dedicated to programming and learning iOS development, but
there are also full modules on app design and app marketing which will supplement your knowledge on
the entire process of app development.
So be sure to look through the curriculum to find these extra modules and you can work through it alongside
the coding tutorials.
So very often I find that students do best when they do a little bit of programming and then switch
their mind to a different problem such as learning some design skills or learning some marketing skills.
So feel free to dip between the design marketing and coding parts of the course.
Now while you're learning iOS development I tend to recommend that students code on your main computer.
Now this is just my recommendation but I find that students benefit a huge deal if you can watch these
lectures on a separate device so that can be an iPad or that could be another laptop or could be even
a Windows computer.
It doesn't really matter but having the tutorial videos side by side with the code allows you to more
easily compare the code and also code along and complete the challenges in the tutorials.
Now while you're watching the tutorials I find that it's helpful to have a small notebook to note down
some of the things that you might want to do a bit of background research on or you might want to read
up more on something that's mentioned in the tutorials that you find fascinating or something that you
just want to understand more deeply.
So having that there is also really useful.
Now at the beginning of the course you should have already downloaded the entire syllabus.
If you haven't you can head over to the giant course resources list and right at the top the first link
will be pointed towards this PDF.
And in this syllabus I've documented all of the skills that were going to be acquiring as we're building
apps and as we're progressing through the course.
Now I find that it's really helpful when students refer to the syllabus and just check off as they go
along.
The things that they are comfortable with.
So for example in the second module when we learn about the Xcode Interface Builder, you can see that
some of the learning points include things such as how to size UI elements or how to arrange UI elements
by sending coordinates.
So I'm gonna be showing you how to do this in the tutorials.
And once you're certain that you've acquired these skills and understand each of the syllabus points
then you go ahead and just check it off.
Now some of these things might require a couple of reviews so you can market for a review at a later
date or you come back to it.
And that way you'll be at to keep track of the skills that you're acquiring but also which parts need
further review.
Now the coding tutorials were built so that it's a little bit like taking a hike up a mountain and the
slope is carefully designed so that each new tutorial builds on the previous one.
So it's really essential that you don't skip coding tutorials and instead you complete the curriculum
in the order that it was designed.
And this is really important because I know that when I look at a new course and I see something really
exciting like learning machine learning then I'm really tempted to just head straight there.
But it's really really important that you resist the temptation to do each of the tutorials in sequence
because of the fact that everything builds on top of the previous tutorial then it's very easy to get
stuck and get frustrated when you jump around in the curriculum.
Now in the course, there's also a whole bunch of coding challenges and the challenges are there to make
the process of learning iOS development feel a little bit less like school learning and feel a little
bit more like a video game.
So that means that there's plenty of small coding challenges dotted all over the course that are kind
of like, you know, the skeletons in your video games.
You're pretty confident that that you can slash them down.
You know it doesn't take too many hits before you can beat them.
But then there's also end level boss fights and these are kind of meant to be a little bit larger of
a challenge.
So you'll be building an app by yourself or you'll be completing a longer coding challenge and this
is so that not only can you prove to yourself that you've understood the concepts in the tutorials but
also just providing that little bit of extra challenge that makes everything a lot more fun and really
test your skills and pushes you to level up as a programmer.
Now for those you guys who are learning programming for the very first time then I tend to like in the
process of learning programming to a bit like putting a puzzle together because in the very beginning
I'm going to be presenting you with the corner pieces and then I'm gonna give you the side pieces and
then finally I'm gonna give you more of the centerpieces.
And at the beginning it's very difficult to see the bigger picture.
Right you're only seeing the outer edge.
But, as you add more pieces; as you increase your knowledge and your understanding of different concepts
in programming, at some point during the course, you can have an aha moment where the picture suddenly
becomes more and more clear and you realize the relationship between all of these different programming
concepts and how they fit together.
So the important thing is to be patient.
And if a concept is particularly challenging then continue for a few more modules and then coming back
and reviewing that same concept a little bit later on.
So that by the end you'll gain a complete picture of iOS development and Swift programming.
Oh and one last thing.
If you find that I talk too fast or too slow then if you look at the bottom of the video player there
are settings we can see and I probably have us or you can slow the video down so that I talk a little
bit slow like this.
So depending on which way you learn best.
Feel free to change the speed of the videos so that it suits you.
So I hope that's helpful in guiding you through the course and a little bit of a sneak peek of what's
to come.
But the thing I want to emphasize is that you're not doing this alone.
There are loads of other students on the student community who you can chat with and share your experience
help each other.
And also I'm gonna be here for you every step of the way.
So in the next lesson I want to talk about how you can get help at any point through the course.
So see you over there.