There are many ways in which either developers or a QA
department can test an application.
For example, according to the Knowledge of the System,
we can have black box testing. That is testing without any
knowledge of the internal structure of a component or a system or
white box testing, testing that is based on the internal
structure of a component or a system.
We can have other types of tests depending on what you are testing, the
degree of isolation of the components you are testing, and even when in the
development cycle you are testing. In this course,
we are going to focus on unit testing.
Unit tests are tests written by programmers.
The classical definition of unit tests is that they test a piece of code by
invoking it and checking the correctness of some assumptions.
A unit test can test just a method,
for example calculateCommission, or the whole class
involving more than one method.
A good unit test should focus on productivity.
It should be automated, easy to run, ideally by executing
just a command or by clicking a button.
It should be repeatable.
Everyone running the test should be able to repeat it without much problem.
It should be fast, not taking a long time to run,
because fast feedback is important.
But why are these points important?
Well,
fast, repeatable, automated tests can be run as often as possible without
hurting productivity. By doing so, we'll receive feedback that allows us to
detect and correct the problem as early as possible.
If there's a dependency on a database or another component,
for example a WebService,
the test might not be as fast because almost always those
dependencies are slower than just running a class.
And with many tests, execution time adds up.
Besides, if the test depends on an external component to be up,
it might not be as automated or repeatable as we would want, and that's
the difference between unit and integration tests.
In integration tests,
we have external components because the purpose is
to test how they work together.
If we want to unit test this piece of code,
we have to replace the external component with either a fake
dummy object or a mock to keep the component under test
isolated and everything under our control.
So the concept of unit test is simple. But why is having a good suite of tests important?