The structure arrange, act, assert,
annihilation can help you avoid the temptation of testing as much
functionality as possible in a single test method.
But let's take a closer look at the arrange phase.
Test fixture is everything we need to execute the test,
like creating objects and setting properties.
In his book, xUnit Test Patterns,
Gerard Meszaros identified three different
approaches for managing test fixtures.
The first one, transient fresh fixture,
is about setting up a brand new fixture every time you run a test.
On the other hand,
we have persistent fixtures that survive from one test to the next.
So we have a persistent fresh fixture, a fixture that is used for all tests,
but is initialized BeforeEach test runs and a persistent shared fixture,
which allows some state to accumulate from test to test.
Here's an analogy.
Imagine you need to write some notes on a sheet of paper.
Using a transient fresh approach,
you'd use a new sheet of paper for every note you have to write.
You can also use just one sheet of paper,
erasing a previous note to write a new one.
In this case, you'd be using the persistent fresh approach.
Or you could put all your notes on the same sheet of paper without erasing
them if you prefer to use the persistent shared approach.
To implement these approaches,
the unit comes with some annotations that allows you to execute a
method at some point in the lifecycle of a test.
The annotation BeforeEach executes a method before the execution of each test,
while AfterEach executes a method after the execution of each test.
Also,
you can use the BeforeAll annotation to execute a method before all
tests are executed and the AfterAll annotation to execute a method
after all tests have been executed.
By default,
the unit creates a new instance of each test class before executing
each test method to run them in isolation and to avoid unexpected
side effects due to instance state.
However,
we can change this behavior to execute all the test
methods on the same instance.
You can control this by annotating a test class with TestInstance and set the
instance lifecycle mode to either PER_METHOD or PER_CLASS or by starting the
Java Virtual Machine with the system property
junit.jupiter.testinstance.lifecycle.default or by setting this property in a
file named junit‑platform.properties in the root of the class path.
Now let's see how these lifecycle annotations and the
PER_METHOD and PER_CLASS modes work.
I have added to our test class an annotation to indicate
that we want a PER_METHOD lifecycle,
just to make it explicit because this is the default behavior.
A constructor, methods annotated with BeforeAll,
BeforeEach,
AfterEach, and AfterAll, and some print statements in the test
method. SetUp and tearDown is a popular naming convention for
before and after methods, respectively.
Also, notice that the methods annotated with BeforeAll and AfterAll are
static because in a per‑method lifecycle, these methods are called before
the instance of the test class is created.
If we run the class,
we can see that BeforeAll is the first method called. Then, for the first test,
the Constructor, then the BeforeEach,
then the Test, and then AfterEach, and the cycle starts again for the next
test, Constructor, BeforeEach, Test, and AfterEach. One more time for the
last test, and, finally, the AfterAll method.
Now if we change the lifecycle to our PER_CLASS mode and run the test again,
we'll see that the constructor was executed first,
then BeforeAll, and then for each test, BeforeEach, the Test, and
AfterEach and, finally, the AfterAll method.
Since the same instance is used for all the test methods and the
instance is created before calling the BeforeAll method, when using
the PER_CLASS lifecycle, the BeforeAll and AfterAll methods are not
required to be a static.
Now using Meszaros' terminology, our tests are using a transient fresh fixture.
Each test is creating a new instance of the RewardByDiscountService class. But
maybe it would be better to have RewardByDiscountService as an instance
variable and create the object in the setUp method.
Let me delete these lines from all methods, one, two, and three.
This may look like a persistent fresh fixture because
we are using the same reference,
but for each test, we are getting a new instance, so
it's still a transient fresh fixture.
If we were using a persistent fresh fixture, we'd reset the state
on the instance without creating a new one.
And if we were using a persistent shared fixture,
we've used the BeforeAll method to set it up and the
AfterAll method to clean it up.
However, all things being equal,
it's better to work with transient fresh fixtures.
Now you may be wondering, in the PER_METHOD mode, isn't a
BeforeEach method the same as a constructor? Well,
yes, it is.
So can we use a constructor instead of the setUp method?
Well, yes, we can. But using a method annotated with beforeEach is a convention.
We usually initialize the test fixture in the setUp method and not in the constructor.