All right, now let's learn about test hierarchies.
In our test class,
I have removed all lifecycle methods except for the
one annotated with BeforeEach.
Let's move the setNeededPoints and setPercentage methods to the setUp
method and delete them from the zeroCustomerPoints method.
And what about the order creation code?
All right,
let's convert the order variable to the instance variable
smallOrder and move the code to the setUp method.
Let's run the class.
Great.
All tests passed.
Now let's say I want to test the case that given a bigger order,
when the customer has enough points, a discount should be applied.
By the way, when working with double values,
we can pass to the assertEquals method a delta or a
range so that within this given range,
the expected and actual values are considered equal.
I just have to add another instance variable for the bigOrder
and add the products in the setUp method.
Let's run the class.
Great.
But look at our setUp method, it's bigger now.
The problem is that it has to set up the test fixture
for all the tests of the class, and they all need different things.
For this reason, some people don't like to use setUp methods.
They prefer to write a small initialization methods to call them from each test.
But there's a better way.
We can use non‑static inner classes annotated with the Nested
annotation to create a test hierarchy and express the
relationship among several groups of tests.
I have prepared a version of this class that uses nested
tests so you can see how this works.
There's an inner class for the SmallOrder test and
another inner class for the BigOrder tests.
Let's review the SmallOrder class.
BeforeEach and AfterEach work inside nested tests.
However,
BeforeAll and AfterAll methods do not work by default because static
members in inner classes are not allowed unless you set a PER_CLASS
lifecycle mode in the nested class. Anyway,
inside this inner class,
we can have tests that use members of the outer class
initialized in the outer setUp method,
such as the RewardService, as well as members of the inner
class. Nesting can be arbitrarily deep.
So inside the SmallOrder class,
we can have another inner class and put some tests there.
For example, for the case when the customer has zero points,
just don't forget the Nested annotation.
When we run the test,
we'll see that a hierarchy has been created mirroring the
class hierarchy. But we are not done.
We can do better.
We can declare custom display names with the
DisplayName annotation that includes spaces,
special characters, and even emojis to be displayed by test runners.
This works at the class and method levels, so we can do something like this.
Given that 100 points are needed for $10 or whatever,
then 100 points should be needed for a 10% discount.
Given there's a small order and given the customer has
zero points, when the reward is applied,
then discount should be zero, and then points redeemed should be zero.
And given there's a big order, when a customer has enough points,
then a reward should be applied.
Now let's run it.
This increased readability a lot, don't you think? This given when/then
naming convention is used in behavior‑driven development,
a software development process that emerged from test‑driven
development and where an application is specified and designed
by describing how it should behave.
We already talked about the four phases of a test. But in BDD, another way to
say arrange is given, act is called when, an assert is called then. Given, when,
then. Given a fixture, when I perform the action,
then I expect a result.
Using this naming convention can help to strongly associate our test
methods with the requirements of the application.
However, sometimes other names are better.
So use whatever you feel is best.
JUnit provides two ways for changing the display name of a test.
The DisplayName annotation allows you to declare a custom
display name for test classes or methods. And the
DisplayNameGeneration annotation allows you to declare a custom
DisplayName generator for the test class.
These generators can be created by implementing the
interface DisplayNameGenerator.
Some built‑in implementations are Standard, the default behavior, Simple,
which removes trailing parentheses for methods with no parameters,
ReplaceUnderscores, which replaces underscores in method names with spaces,
and IndicativeSentences, which generates complete sentences by concatenating
the names of the test methods and the enclosing classes.
You can use the junit.jupiter.displayname.generator.default
configuration parameter for this purpose. The only thing to remember
is that DisplayName annotations always take precedence over
DisplayNames generated by a DisplayName generator.
Finally, for nested test classes,
remember to use only non‑static inner classes. BeforeAll and AfterAll don't
work by default, only with the PER_CLASS lifecycle mode. A nested test and the DisplayName annotation are a powerful combination.