There was one problem in particular that slowed down JUnit 4 evolution,
a problem caused by the fact that all JUnit functionality is enclosed in a
single JAR file which is used by everyone but that doesn't have a flexible
API to handle everything at the same time.
JUnit popularity caused that all IDEs and build tools included support for it,
great support that makes easy‑to‑execute tests.
But on the other hand,
this coupled IDEs and build tools to JUnit internals
because the API wasn't designed for them.
So they used internal JUnit classes or even reflection for their purposes.
That locked in the development of JUnit because just changing the name of a
private variable could break support for a new version.
Johannes Link summarizes the situation as follows.
"The success of JUnit as a platform prevents the
development of JUnit as a tool." So for JUnit 5,
they wanted to decouple test execution from other
areas like test definition and, at the same time,
provide support for IDEs and other tools to add features in an extensible way.
So they decided that the new JUnit version could provide an API to write tests,
a mechanism to discover and run tests, and,
for tools, an API to run tests.
This facilitates the following goals.
Decouple of tests because if you decouple test execution from test definition,
users can mix tests from different testing libraries,
and those other libraries could use the test execution and
reporting features that IDEs designed for JUnit.
Preference for extension points instead of using runners,
rules,
or subclassing like in previous versions to add
features or change the behavior of JUnit.
This way,
we could use extensions optionally packaged in additional libraries to keep the
JUnit core as simple as possible and backward‑compatible.
And make use of Java 8, features like lambdas,
streams, and default methods in interfaces.
JUnit 5 is the sum of three subprojects.
JUnit platform which provides an API to launch tests from either the console,
IDEs,
or build tools and also for developing a testing
framework that runs on the platform.
JUnit Jupiter for writing tests and extensions.
This project also provides an engine for running
Jupyter‑based tests on the platform.
By the way, if you are wondering why the team chose the name Jupiter,
you'll know it by answering this question.
What is the name of the fifth planet on our solar system?
And JUnit Vintage,
which provides an engine for running JUnit 3 and
JUnit 4‑based tests on the platform.
If you look deeply under the JUnit platform project,
you'll find JARs like junit‑platform‑commons with
common APIs and support utilities,
junit‑platform‑console for discovering and executing tests from the console,
junit‑platform‑engine, an API for test engines,
junit‑platform‑launcher, an API for configuring and launching tests,
typically used by IDEs and build tools,
junit‑platform‑suite‑api with annotations for
configuring test suites on the JUnit platform,
and junit‑platform‑runner for executing tests in a JUnit 4 environment.
There are others, but as you can see,
their primary function is discovering and executing tests.
Then we have JUnit Jupiter This project only has four JARs.
Junit‑jupiter‑api, the API for writing tests and extensions.
Junit‑jupiter‑engine, the engine implementation.
Junit‑jupiter‑params, which provides support for parameterized tests.
And junit‑jupiter‑migrationsupport that provides migration support for
selected JUnit 4 rules to the new extension model of JUnit 5.
And JUnit Vintage, which only contains junit‑vintage‑engine,
the engine implementation to execute tests written in JUnit 3 or JUnit 4.
For this, of course, you'll also need the JUnit 3 or 4 JAR.
So this is the big picture.
We have tests that are written using the JUnit APIs and
are executed by the JUnit platform, which is also used by IDEs and build tools.
Let's look closer.
Here we have a JUnit test class, which only depends on the Jupiter API.
It doesn't know about engines or platforms.
Junit‑jupiter also includes an engine,
junit‑jupiter‑engine that depends on the Jupiter API to run the tests
and is an implementation of the platform engine.
On the other hand, we have IDEs, build tools,
and the console that use the platform launcher to discover,
filter, and execute tests, and it also provides an API to the platform engine.
Following the same architecture,
we can have a JUnit 4 test that depends on the JUnit 4 API,
but uses another engine implementation, junit‑vintage‑engine.
So the JUnit platform is an abstraction that doesn't care if the
test it's going to run is from Junit 5 or 4.
In fact,
other test frameworks can be plugged into this architecture by integrating
their API and implementing an engine to talk to the platform,
and that's the breakthrough of this release. The JUnit platform is available to everybody.