Sometimes you'll want to disable a test method or a whole test class,
maybe because someone forgot to commit something or maybe
because you are in the middle of adding new functionality that
right now is breaking the test suite.
In those cases,
you can use the Disabled annotation to disable methods and classes.
But JUnit also supports other annotation‑based conditions that
allow us to enable or disable tests declaratively.
For example,
EnabledOnOs and DisabledOnOs to enable or disable tests on a particular
operating system, EnabledOnJre and DisabledOnJre to enable or disable tests on
particular versions of the JRE, or EnabledForJreRange and DisabledForJreRange
on a particular range of versions using Java 8 as the default minimum version,
EnabledIfSystemProperty and DisabledIfSystemProperty to enable or disable
tests based on the value of a JVM system property,
EnabledIfEnvironmentVariable and DisabledIfEnvironmentVariable to enable or
disable tests based on the value of an environment variable, or EnabledIf and
DisabledIf to enable or disable tests based on the boolean return value of a
method specified with its name or its fully qualified name if it's defined
outside the test class. Let's see how the Disabled annotation works.
Imagine we are implementing an optimization so this test can pass with an order
of 50,000 products. While we are working on it, we can disable this method with
the Disabled annotation and even show a message.
Let's run the class.
We can see that the disabled tests was not executed.
Now you may be thinking, I don't need an annotation for that.
I just have to comment out the Test annotation, right?
Yes, you can do that.
But remember, our unit tests should be clear and easy to understand. If
you use the Disabled annotation and give a reason, the rest of your team
can know exactly why the test is disabled. And what if you want to
disable all the methods of your tests?
Are you going to comment out all the methods of the class?
I think you'll agree that using the Disabled annotation is a better option.
We can add the annotation at the class level. And if we execute the test of the package, all the tests will be ignored.