Sometimes, instead of disabling the whole test,
you'll want to stop the execution of a test at some point.
Assumptions are an easy way to conditionally stop the execution of a test,
for example if the test depends on something that
doesn't exist in the current environment.
In contrast to failed assertions,
failed assumptions do not result in a test failure.
A failed assumption just aborts the test.
There are three assumption methods, assumeTrue,
which validates if the given assumption evaluates to true
to allow the execution of the test.
The assumption can be a simple boolean expression or a lambda expression
that represents the functional interface BooleanSupplier, AssumeFalse that
validates if they give an assumption evaluates to false to allow the
execution of the test, and assumingThat,
which executes the supplied lambda expression that
represents the functional interface executable,
only if they give an assumption evaluates to true.
Otherwise, this method does nothing.
Let's try this with a demo.
I have already created a test class for the RewardByConversion service.
Let's say that for this test I want to assert that the points
redeemed are zero only if a flag is set.
I don't have a TEST_POINTS environment variable, so the
last assert will not be executed.
We can see an exception here, TestAbortedException:
Assumption failed: assumption is not true.
Notice that the test was ignored. But just to be sure that the first
assertion was executed, let's change this value.
Great.
The first assertion is still executed.
So as you can see,
you can put the assumption anywhere in the body of a test
method. And if the assumption is valid,
the rest of the code will not be executed.
You can even put the assumption in the beforeEach method.
Let me change the value back. Move the assumeTrue method to the setUp method.
And if we run the test, you can see that all the tests were ignored.
All right, let's delete it from here.
And back to the method emptyOrderEnoughPoints, we can also use
assumingThat, which only executes the lambda expression if the
assumption is valid. If we run the class,
everything is fine because the assertion was not executed.
But if we change the condition and run the test again, we'll get a failed test because this time, the assertion was executed.