In this clip, we are going to configure JUnit 5 in a Gradle project.
I have imported a Gradle project in IntelliJ IDEA.
It only has a HelloWorldTest class,
which is not compiling because I haven't added the
JUnit dependency to the project, so let's do it.
Starting with version 4.6, Gradle provides native support for JUnit 5.
We just need to enable it in the test closure by using useJUnitPlatform.
Now to add the JUnit dependencies,
we can start by adding the JUnit Bill of Materials,
BOM.
This will take care of managing the versions of the JUnit JAR files that I'll
add that are compatible with the version I'm using here.
In other words, we still need to declare all the dependencies that we'll need,
but without specifying a version.
For this,
we can individually add each one of these dependencies, for example
the Jupiter API, the Jupiter Engine, and so on. Or we can add, as a
dependency, the artifact junit‑jupiter, which aggregates all
dependencies that are required to use JUnit 5 along with some
optional dependencies.
Let me apply these changes. And in the External Libraries section, you can
see the dependencies that have been added to the project.
One dependency that probably is not always needed is
junit‑jupiter‑params, which is required to use parameterized tests.
We'll talk about this later in the course, but you can exclude
dependencies like this one if you choose to use the JUnit Jupiter
dependency or include exactly what you need. In any case, our test
class now compiles correctly.
If you run this class inside the IDE, you'll see it runs as
suspected. But you can also run it from the command line with
gradlew test. And in the directory build, reports,
tests, tests, you can find a report in HTML format with the results from the test task.