In this clip, we are going to configure JUnit 5 in a Maven project.
I have imported a Maven project in IntelliJ IDEA.
It only has a HelloWorldTest class,
which is not compiling because I haven't added the
JUnit dependency to the project, so let's do it.
In the pom.xml file,
we can start by adding a dependencyManagement section where we
can configure the JUnit Bill of Materials POM.
This will take care of managing the versions of the JUnit JAR files that I'll
add that are compatible with the version I'm using here.
In other words, we still need to declare all the dependencies that we'll need,
but without specifying a version.
For this, in the dependencies section,
we can individually add each one of these dependencies.
For example, the Jupiter API, the Jupiter Engine, and so on.
Or we can add, as a dependency, the artifact junit‑jupiter,
which aggregates all the dependencies that are required to use
JUnit 5 along with some optional dependencies.
If you are only going to run the test inside the IDE, you're done.
But if you intend to run your test with Maven,
you need to configure the Surefire plugin.
I'll add it to the build, plugin's section and apply these changes.
And in the External Libraries section,
you can see the dependencies that have been added to the project.
One dependency that probably is not always needed is junit‑jupiter‑params,
which is required to use parameterized tests.
We'll talk about this later in this course,
but you can exclude dependencies like this one if you choose to use the
junit‑jupiter dependency or include exactly what you want.
In any case, our test class now compiles correctly.
If you run this class inside the IDE, you'll see it runs as expected.
But you can also run it from the command line with mvnw test. And there you have it, Tests run: 1.