One of the main goals of JUnit 5 is to facilitate the
integration of JUnit and tools like IDEs For this,
Junit 5 introduced the concept of a launcher to discover,
filter, and execute tests.
The Launcher API is in the junit‑platform‑launcher module,
and it allows you to provide a custom test engine so JUnit
platforms launching infrastructure can support,
for example, third‑party test libraries.
But in addition to this,
if the IDE you're using bundles an older version of
JUnit to use the different one,
you can include the junit‑platform‑launcher and the corresponding
versions of the JUnit Engines you want to use,
junit‑jupiter engine, junit‑vintage‑engine,
or even both.
Notice that JUnit Platform JARs use 1, not 5, as their major version number.
So be careful with that.
Now if your IDE or tool doesn't support JUnit 5, you have two options.
Run your tests from the command line.
There's a console launcher that uses the Launcher API and
that we'll review later in the course.
Or if your IDE or tool supports JUnit 4,
with JUnit Platform,
you can try a test runner to run JUnit Jupiter tests
as if they were JUnit 4 tests.
You'll find this runner in its own JAR,
which you have to add to your project with the Group ID:
org.junit.platform, Artifact ID: junit‑platform‑runner and
its corresponding version.
This is how it works.
JUnitPlatform is a class that extends from Runner and an abstract
class that you can find in the JUnit 4 JAR file.
JUnitPlatform uses an implementation of the interface Launcher.
This implementation discovers test engines that will run the JUnit 5 tests
and implement the interface TestEngine. Test engines are discovered at
runtime using Java's service loader mechanism.
For example,
if you open the junit‑jupiter‑engine JAR in META‑INF/services, you'll find
a text file named org.junit.platform.engine.TestEngine.
This file has the fully qualified name of the implementation class
of the TestEngine interface This way, the engine implementation, in
this case the junit‑jupiter‑engine,
is automatically registered with the launcher.
So in a few words,
the runner will call the engine that will execute the JUnit 5 tests.
For this reason,
you also need to add the junit‑jupiter‑engine dependency. And
the only thing that you need to do is annotate the Test class
with the RunWith annotation.
However,
since JUnit 5 has features that JUnit 4 doesn't have, the runner only
supports a subset of the JUnit 5 functionality. But the JUnit Platform Runner is an easy way to get started.