We have covered a lot of topics in this module,
but the good news is that you have learned the features of
JUnit that you'll use most of the time.
You learned the phases of a well‑structured test,
arrange where the test fixture is set up,
act where the operation under test is performed,
assert where you check the result of the operation, and the
often‑forgotten annihilate where you do cleanup operations or
reset the state of the system. Remember that there are different
approaches to manage test fixtures, transient fresh,
persistent fresh and persistent shared, and how they can be mapped to the
lifecycle methods that JUnit provides, BeforeAll, BeforeEach,
AfterEach, and AfterAll.
Also, remember that there are two lifecycle modes,
PER_METHOD, the default one, and PER_CLASS.
You also learned about test hierarchies and nested tests, which can help you
manage your setUp methods and structure your test classes.
You learned that no matter how many physical assertions you have,
as long as they form one logical assertion and your test has a
single act/assert pair, everything will be fine.
You learned about the annotations to enable and disable
tests and how to use assumptions to execute a part of a
test based on some condition.
You learned how JUnit allows tests BeforeEach and AfterEach and
other annotated methods to be declared on interfaces as default
methods and how to repeat a test a fixed number of times by using
the annotation RepeatedTest.
Each invocation of a RepeatedTest behaves like a regular
test method with full lifecycle support.
However,
sometimes Parameterized and DynamicTest provide more
advantages than repeating tests.
This will be the topic of the next module. Take care, and thanks for watching.