To learn JUnit, this course will use the following scenario. Imagine we are
working for the company Wired Brain Coffee. This company owns a chain of
successful coffee shops all over the country.
We want to grow and stay competitive, so we are
implementing a loyalty program for our customers.
In this program,
every order generates points, and you can exchange points for rewards.
In particular, the system can give three types of rewards. A conversion reward.
In this case,
the customers can convert their points into money. A discount reward.
In this case, the system gives a discount for an
amount of points. And a gift reward.
In this case,
the system gives a product of the customer's order as
a gift for an amount of points.
So all the examples and demos of this course will be related to testing the implementation of these types of rewards.