JUnit 5 was redesigned to solve the problems of the previous versions,
like tight coupling to IDEs and build tools.
Its new architecture is based on a couple of core principles,
and one of them is to prefer extension points over features.
This way,
we could use extensions optionally packaged in additional libraries to keep the
JUnit core as simple as possible and backward‑compatible.
The extension API for JUnit Jupiter is based on the interface extension.
JUnit provides many extension points during the lifecycle of a test,
and each extension point corresponds to an interface that
extends from the interface extension.
If a class wants to extend the behavior of a test,
it has to implement one of these interfaces.
When the Jupiter engine processes a test,
it steps through this extension points and calls each registered extension.
We can classify all the extension interfaces into three categories.
First, we have general‑purpose interfaces,
such as TestInstanceFactory to create test instances.
TestInstancePostProcessor to post process test instances so you can inject
dependencies or invoke custom initialization methods,
for example.
TestInstancePreDestroyCallback to process test instances after they
have been used in tests and before they are destroyed.
TestWatcher to process the results of test method executions
after a disabled test method has been skipped,
a test method has completed successfully,
aborted, or failed.
InvocationInterceptor to intercept calls to tests.
TestTemplateInvocationContextProvider for implementing
different types of tests that rely on repetitive invocation
of test methods in different contexts, for example with different parameters.
ParameterResolver to dynamically resolve and inject
parameters to test methods at runtime.
And TestExecutionExceptionHandler to handle
exceptions thrown during test execution.
Then we have the interface ExecutionCondition to evaluate if a
given class or test method should be executed.
This is a more powerful alternative to the Disabled annotation. Next,
in addition to lifecycle methods annotated with BeforeAll and AfterAll,
for example, we can have lifecycle callbacks,
like BeforeAllCallback and AfterAllCallback,
BeforeEachCallback and AfterEachCallback, and
BeforeTestExecutionCallback and AfterTestExecutionCallback.
Once you have an Extension class,
you can register declaratively with the annotation ExtendWith,
annotating the class or the method where you want to use the extension or
programmatically by annotating class fields with RegisterExtension or
automatically with Java's ServiceLoader mechanism.
Using this method in the META‑INF services folder of the extensions
JAR file in a text file name
org.junit.jupiter.api.extension.Extension, you put the fully
qualified name of the Extension class so it can be discovered automatically.
And you can enable or disable the autodetection of extensions by
setting the system property
junit.jupiter.extensions.autodetection.enabled to either true or false.
All right,
let's see how to implement a simple extension using
the lifecycle callback interfaces.
I have already created a test class with methods annotated with BeforeAll,
BeforeEach, AfterEach, AfterAll, and two test methods.
Now I'm going to create a new class, LifecycleExtension.
This class is going to implement the interface's BeforeAllCallback,
AfterAllCallback, BeforeEachCallback, AfterEachCallback,
BeforeTestExecutioCallback, and AfterTestExecutionCallback.
Now I'm going to implement the methods of all these interfaces.
They'll just print the name of the interface they represent,
BeforeAllCallback, AfterAllCallback, BeforeEachCallback,
and so on.
Now back to the Test class, I'm going to use the ExtendWith annotation,
passing the Extension class I want to use,
in this case LifecycleExtension.
Let's run this class to see the order in which the messages are printed.
Here we can see that beforeAllCallback from the
Extension class was executed first.
Next, the method annotated with BeforeAll,
beforeEachCallback from the Extension class,
the method annotated with BeforeEach,
beforeTestExecutionCallback from the Extension class,
the Test method, afterTestExecutionCallback from the Extension class,
AfterEach, and afterEachCallback from the Extension class.
After that,
the cycle starts again for the other test method with
beforeEachCallback and BeforeEach.
And at the end,
we can see the message printed from the method annotated with AfterAll.
And finally, the afterAllCallback from the Extension class.
So the extension points were executed before the annotations in the case
of beforeAllCallback and beforeEachCallback and after the annotations in
the case of afterEachCallback and afterAllCallback and
beforeTestExecutionCallback and afterTestExecutionCallback were executed
right before and right after the tests.
Now, what do you think will happen if instead of
applying the extension to the whole class,
we only apply it to one test method? Let's move this ExtendWith
annotation to the method changeAmount and run the class.
You can see that there's a BeforeAll and AfterAll,
but not BeforeAllCallback and AfterAllCallback because these
extension points work at the class level.
Look at the messages printed when the Test changeAmount they
want annotated with ExtendWith was executed.
Now look at the messages printed when the Test
rewardNotappliedEmptyOrder was executed. For this method,
the extension messages were not printed.
Extensions are aware if they are applied to a class or a method.
That's why all the methods from the extension interfaces receive an
ExtensionContext parameter that provides information about the context in
which the current test or class is being executed.
We'll review this context in the next clips. But for now,
keep in mind that an extension can behave differently depending on the context in which it is applied.