With parameterized tests,
you can run a test multiple times with different arguments.
Instead of using a Test annotation,
you have to use the annotation ParameterizedTest.
But unlike DynamicTest,
ParameterizedTests have the same lifecycle as regular test methods.
The only requirement is that you must declare at least one source that
will provide the arguments for each test invocation.
And this is because parameterized test methods come from arguments
directly from a source following these rules.
First, zero or more indexed arguments must be declared.
Usually,
there's a one‑to‑one relation between the argument source
index and the method parameter index,
meaning that if a method defines two arguments,
the source must provide those two arguments.
However, we can aggregate multiple parameters into one.
So zero or more aggregators must be declared next.
And finally,
arguments that can be resolved by a ParameterResolver must be declared last.
In particular,
indexed arguments are provided by an implementation of
the ArgumentsProvider interface.
Each argument provided corresponds to a single method parameter.
So arguments are passed at the same index in the method's parameter list.
An arguments provider can be registered with the ArgumentsSource annotation.
We'll review argument sources later in this module.
On the other hand, using an argument of type ArgumentsAccessor,
we can aggregate multiple arguments into a single one.
An instance of ArgumentsAccessor is automatically injected
into any parameter of type ArgumentsAccessor.
Another way of aggregating arguments is by using a custom aggregator.
You just have to implement the ArgumentsAggregator interface,
for example,
to create a class that converts multiple arguments into an object
of type product and annotate a method argument of type product
with the annotation AggregateWith,
specifying the argument's aggregator implementation.
Finally, to inject any other type of parameters into a test,
you have to use the ParameterResolver interface,
which defines an API to dynamically resolve parameters at runtime.
Three built‑in resolvers are registered automatically,
TestInfoParameterResolver to inject parameters of type TestInfo
in all types of test and lifecycle methods,
RepetitionInfoParameterResolver to inject parameters of
type RepetitionInfo for methods annotated with
RepeatedTest, BeforeEach, and AfterEach,
and TestReporterParameterResolver to inject parameters of type
TestReporter in all types of test methods and methods annotated
with BeforeEach and AfterEach.
To use parameterized tests, you need to add as a dependency of
your project the junit‑jupiter‑params JAR.
Parameterized tests can have custom display names.
There's a default format, but you can change it using the following placeholders.
DisplayName, the display name of the method.
Index, the current invocation index of the parameter source starting from one.
Arguments, the complete comma‑separated arguments list.
ArgumentsWithNames,
the complete comma‑separated arguments list with parameter names.
Or you can use each argument with an identifier that starts from zero.
All right, let's see how to set up parameterized tests,
how the lifecycle is handled, how to define custom display names,
and how to inject test information parameters.
The first thing we need to do is to make sure the project has
the junit‑jupiter‑params JAR as a dependency.
I'll append the pom.xml file.
Junit‑jupiter already includes junit‑jupiter‑params.
But if you're not using this dependency,
you'll have to include the params JAR as a test dependency.
In any case, for this demo, I have created a test class,
RewardByGiftService parameterized test.
It has a setup method annotated with BeforeEach and a
method to create a sample order.
So I'm going to add the method discountShouldBeApplied.
But instead of annotating this method with Test,
I'm going to use the annotation ParameterizedTest.
In the next clip, we are going to talk about argument sources.
But for now, we'll use ValueSource.
ValueSource allows you to specify an array of strings or
primitive types and provides a single parameter.
In this example, I'm injecting the numbers 1, 2, 3, and 4 as long values.
So I'm going to add the parameter productId as long and the body of the method,
which tests if a reward is applied.
If I run the test, we'll see it was executed four times.
In the same way, the BeforeEach message was printed four times.
Parameterized tests have the same lifecycle as regular test methods.
If we add to the argument source a value to fail the
test at the beginning of the list, we get a failed test,
but the rest were executed.
So parameterized tests are executed independently from each other.
Let me delete the value.
By default,
the format for the display names of parameterized tests is the
invocation index followed by the string representation of all the
arguments for that specific invocation.
If we have a DisplayName annotation,
the annotation will give a display name to the container,
not to the tests.
To give our tests a custom name,
we need to use the name attribute of the ParameterizedTest annotation.
When I run the test, you can see the new display name,
Test #1: productid =1 and so on.
Now I'm going to add after the productId parameter,
not before, one parameter of type TestInfo and another one of type TestReporter.
We can use TestInfo to print the display name of the test, for example.
On the other hand,
TestReporter can be used to publish data about the current test that
will be included in reports and the standard output and can be
consumed through an API by IDEs or build tools.
If we run the test,
we can see how the display name was printed, as well
as the test reporter information,
a timestamp, and the value of the parameter. As I mentioned
before, you cannot inject parameters to lifecycle methods
with annotations like ValueSource.
You can only inject parameters of type TestInfo and TestReporter.
Let's modify the print statement.
Run the class, and there you have it.
The display name of the test currently running is printed in the BeforeEach method.