We have used most of the annotations that come with
JUnit to configure our test classes.
However, JUnit also allows you to create meta‑annotations.
In other words,
you can define your own annotations by using one or more JUnit annotations,
and they will inherit their semantics.
For example, let's say we have a test method,
and we want to use an extension to handle the exceptions this method may throw.
So instead of adding an ExtendWith annotation to this method,
we can create a custom annotation.
Let's say TestWithErrorHandler.
We can meta‑annotate this annotation with Test and ExtendWith,
and this will be the same as if we used them in the test method directly.
The advantage is that if we choose the name correctly,
it can greatly improve the readability of our tests.
All right, for this demo, let's create this TestWithErrorHandler meta‑annotation.
If I set the amount of reward to a negative value,
an IllegalArgumentException will be thrown.
Let's assume that for some reason for this test,
I don't want to assert that this exception is thrown or handled inside
the test method or any other method for that matter.
So what I'm going to do is create an extension to
handle these IllegalArgumentExceptions.
Let's name it IllegalArgumentExceptionHandlerExtension,
you know, a big and descriptive name.
This class is going to implement the interface
TestExecutionExceptionHandler that has the method handleTestExecutionException,
which takes a parameter of type ExtensionContext.
And the exception thrown by the test method as a Throwable.
Also,
the method declares that it throws a Throwable just in
case you want to rethrow the exception.
So let's see if the exception is an instance of IllegalArgumentException,
I'm going to print a message.
Using the ExtensionContext parameter, I'm going to get the class and
method name of the test that threw the exception.
I'm using the method getRequiredTestClass and getRequiredTestMethod because, in
this case, I know there has to be a method and its class.
But if you want to write more robust code,
you can use getTestMethod and getTestClass that returns an
Optional that wraps the method and class objects. Next, I'm
going to return from the method.
This will swallow the exception and execute the next method
of the class as if nothing had happened.
If the exception is not an IllegalArgumentException,
I'll just rethrow it. Now I'm going to create the annotation,
TestWithErrorHandler. I'll add the import statements I'm going to need, and
this annotation is going to apply to classes and methods.
It will have a runtime RetentionPolicy, and I'm going
to add an ExtendWith annotation.
Instead of having to use two ExtendWith annotations,
you can pass an array with all the extensions you want to use, in
this case our exception handler and parameter resolver extensions.
Back to our Test class, I'm going to delete this field and the
RegisterExtension annotation, and I'm going to use the
TestWithErrorHandler annotation.
If I run the class, all the tests passed, and there's a message, Exception of
type IllegalArgumentException thrown by
RewardByConversionWithExtensionTest#changeAmount, which was printed by the extension.
Now I can move the TestWithErrorHandler annotation to the method and add the
Test annotation as a meta‑annotation to TestWithErrorHandler. And if I run the test class again, everything will work as before.