If you have watched the module Introduction to JUnit 5,
you'll remember I showed you the minimal configuration to run JUnit 5
tests with Maven where you have to configure the Surefire plugin in
addition to adding the JUnit dependencies,
but you can also add more options in the configuration
section inside the plugin element.
You can include wildcard patterns to execute only
certain classes or even packages.
By default,
the Surefire plugin will automatically include all test
classes with the following patterns,
all Java files whose names start or end with Tests,
all Java files whose names end with Tests,
and all Java files whose names end with TestCase.
And just as you can include classes that don't follow
any of these naming conventions, you can also exclude them.
In addition, you can use tags to include or exclude classes.
We'll talk about this in the next clip. And in the properties section, you
can set configuration parameters with a key value syntax.
All right, let's review an example of how to filter tests with Maven.
I have opened the Maven project that you can find in the directory
of the demos of this module. In the file pom.xml.
I already have a Maven Surefire plugin section. So I'm going to add a
configuration section to add an includes element to include only the classes
of the package com.wiredbraincoffee.reward.tests.
I'm going to import the changes, but it's not necessary
because instead of using the IDE, I'll use the terminal to
execute the command mvnw test.
Maven didn't execute all the tests that this project contains, only the tests
contained in the package com.wiredbraincoffee.reward.tests. Tests run 19, skipped 1.