So prior to Java 2, there was no policy file.
As we said previously,
our application would run in a sandbox if we needed security.
We had to implement the security manager,
and that made life very difficult, and a few people did that.
Essentially, only the browser manufacturers, so they could run applets securely.
Java 2 added a concrete security implementation that delegates
to something called the access controller,
and the access controller reads policy.
The default policy implementation is a text file.
Now it's a fairly straightforward text syntax, as we'll see in a moment.
The policy contains permissions,
and these permissions are assigned by something called a code source.
So the code source identifies where a piece of code has been loaded from,
or who it's been signed by,
and the permissions associated with that signing or with that location.
Something fundamental about all of this is that the access
controller then walks the call stack.
So the check to see if this piece of code is allowed to perform this
action is done right at the bottom of the call stack,
and it's typically performed as we've seen by some code inside the JDK,
and the JDK has permission to do everything.
So if something else is calling the JDK,
it may not be allowed to perform this action.
That thing that's making the call is further up the call stack so we
have to walk the entire call stack to make sure that everything on the
call stack is allowed to do this access,
and everything on the call stack must have the appropriate permissions.
So before we take a look at how this call stack walking works,
first of all,
let's take a look at the default policy file and see what's in there.
So Java comes with a default policy file,
and this is a base set of permissions that all applications have.
This default policy file, as we see here,
lives in %JAVA_HOME%/jre/lib/security/java.policy,
and you can go and take a look at this file.
It's a simple text file.
So what does a policy look like?
In the policy file, we grant permissions based on up to three things.
We can grant a permission based on where code was loaded from,
and this is something called a code base.
We can grant permission based on who created this library.
So the library creator can sign the JAR file,
and we can grant the permission based on that signing.
We could also grant the permission based on who the authenticated user is,
something called the principle.
So the grant syntax is something like this.
We create what's called a grant block, and then here we can say,
I want this code to have these permissions based on this signer,
this code base, and these principles.
Now all of these things are optional apart from the grant block.
So if we leave out the signer and we leave out the code
base and we leave out the principles,
then we are granting these permissions to all code.
The principle is part of the Java authentication and
authorization service or JAAS, and we're not covering that in this class.
So in this class, we care about what the codebase is, and what signedBy is.
So this is the default policy file.
Now, I guess the first thing to notice is that policy files grant permissions.
And what this means is that by default, all permissions are disallowed.
So we have to explicitly say what is allowed.
We can't say certain things are allowed, certain things aren't allowed.
We have to allow everything that we need; otherwise, it's not allowed.
Notice that in here we have two, what are called grant blocks.
So it's inside the grant blocks that we associate permissions with,
in this case, a code location.
So the first grant block says that any code loaded from the Java
extension directories is given all permissions.
So if you want a library that is allowed to do anything,
you can place that library into the extension directory,
and by default, it gets all permissions.
The second grant block then applies to all code.
So this grant block does not have a code base associated with it.
So any other code picks up permissions from this grant block,
and this is sort of programmed into three areas.
There's a permission to say,
stop thread, and there's a comment on this, which says, you
really shouldn't allow this permission.
It's purely there for backwards compatibility,
and it's strongly recommended to remove this permission from the code.
There's also permission there that allows us to listen on a socket. So we can't
create ports here, but if I want to listen to an incoming connection, then we
can do that. So any application is allowed to listen on some dynamic port. And
then the final set of permissions that we are given by default are the
permissions to read Java properties.
So here we can read things like the Java version.
We can read things like the file separator,
the OS version, the virtual machine name,
so basic information about our runtime environment.
If we want any further permissions,
then we will have to add those ourselves into this file,
as we'll see in a moment, into a separate file that we can use to augment this file.