So how does the policy file get loaded?
When the JVM starts up, a policy singleton is created,
and the location of the class for the singleton is defined
here in jre/lib/security/java.security.
So another text file similar to java.policy.
In here is a policy.provider entry,
and that defaults to send security.provider.PolicyFile.
So this is the policy file‑based policy,
and this is the text‑based file that we've seen.
This class, if it's specified this way,
must be present either on the boot class path or in the extensions
directory such that the Java virtual machine can load it.
You can, however, change this later.
So you can call Policy.setPolicy.
Now, of course, you'll need permission to do this.
And as we've seen, the default implementation is a text file configuration.
So we've already seen the default policy file,
but here we're going to put a little more meat on the
bones of the syntax of the policy file.
So we use this grant syntax and it looks something like this.
We say grant and specify a code base or maybe a signedBy. and that
code base could be a file location or it could be a network location.
And notice here, we have some extra syntax.
We have a dash, we have an asterisk here.
So the specific format is this.
We can say grant and then signedBy with a list of signer_names or
codeBase, and codeBase then is a URL. If we have signed code, the
signer_names is an alias into the Java key store, and we'll see more on
how that works a little later in this module. The URL is obviously a
location, and it could be a file location or a network location. The way
the URL works is this.
If the URL ends in a forward slash, that matches all the
classes in the specified directory.
If it ends in a star, an asterisk, it matches all the files in that directory.
So .class files on .jar files. And if it ends with a hyphen,
it matches all files in that directory recursively. So it'll recurse down
through any sub directories that we have. If the URL is for the file system,
then it must start with file:/. And notice that because this is a URL, then it
must be a a forward slash, even on Windows machines; it's not a backslash, it's
a forward slash inside the URL. The policy file also comes with a property
expansion mechanism. So we can use any system properties the Java recognizes
inside the policy file, and it is of this form. So we can say $ and then
property.name. So we can say user.home or java. home or version information or
anything else we need inside the policy file. The Java security file has an
expandProperties property, and if that must be set to true,
which is the default value, to allow the property file to expand its properties.
There's also a special property, which is $/ that expands to the
file separator on whatever system we're running on.
So for Windows,
it would be the backslash for UNIX‑based systems, it would
be the forward slash. That allows us to write somewhat
platform‑agnostic policy files.
So, as an example, so here,
we have a permission, which a java.io.FilePermission, and
we're saying $$, and this expands on UNIX
to /home/cathy/, let's say,
assuming the user is called Cathy, or on Windows to whatever
the user's location is, so in this case,
d:\\users\\cathy, and again, notice at the end of both of
these, user.home expands to /home/cathy,
and then $/ either expands to / or \,
depending on whether it's a UNIX‑based system or a Windows‑based system.
So let's take a look at how we can edit the policy file and how that affects our code.