So this is the demo we saw in the previous module.
And here we're grabbing the version and then we're trying to
write to some random file in the temp folder.
So what I'd like to do is make use of the property
expansion in the policy file and use those properties to
apply permissions to this project.
So instead of getting the version, let's get the home value first of all.
So we'll change this to home,
we'll change this to user.home. And then when we write the file
we'll write this rather crudely to home +,
and then simply say, out.text.
And again, we're going to write Hello, World into the file.
So let me build this.
If I go to the command window, so again we have a security.manager present,
and try and run this, the first thing to note is that by default
we're not allowed access to the property user.home.
So the first thing we have to do is to set that permission.
So in our policy file, we can now add this permission.
So I go into here, I'll copy the version permission here.
So here we want to say, user.home.
I save the policy file, go back to the command prompt, and from here,
run the code again. Okay, so now we have permission to read the
user.home property notice we print out my home folder,
which is users.kevin in this case, but I don't have
permission to write into that folder.
And this goes back to where we were yesterday,
but now we can use the property expansion in the file.
So we're again grabbing this error and going back into the policy file.
So here I can say permission, and I'll copy in this, the
error we saw, make sure put the comma here,
the semicolon at the end, and remove the quotes that we don't need here. At the
moment here, I'm certainly going to hardcode my location.
I need to remember to change this to forward slashes.
And then again, I'll save the policy file,
go back to the command prompt and here run the code again.
And now it works.
But I've hardcoded me, my user, my user.home folder.
So back in the policy file,
we can use property expansion. So rather than saying
C:/Users/kevin here, I can say $(user.home), and then
rather than the forward slash here,
I can say $(/). And again, if I save this and go back to the
command prompt and run the code, again the code works. We're
now writing into my home folder.
If we think of this as the equivalent of a unit test,
the unit test has gone green before I've seen it go red.
So I'd like to see this unit test fail before I let the code out.
So I'm going to make another edit to the policy file.
I'm going to take out that property expansion,
save the file, go back to the command prompt,
run the code again, and it should fail.
And indeed it does.
So it is reading that property file.
It is expanding things correctly.
So I go and put that back in.
Again, save it, and then run the test again.
Again its working, so we are are writing into that folder.
So the next module, we'll see that rather editing the
default policy file, there are ways to augment or indeed
replace that default policy file,
which makes sense, as we don't want to edit the global policy
file. We'd sort of rather carry the policy file along with us that's required for this application.