So the Java policy file is the default policy file that applies to
all Java applications running in this environment.
So if we go and edit that, that edit applies to every
application that will be run under a security manager in this
environment. We prefer not to do that.
So Java provides us away such that we can either override
completely the default policy file or we can augment it.
And the way we do this is by adding a custom policy file from the command line.
As we said,
we can augment the standard settings, or we can replace the standard settings.
And the way we do that is by saying,
‑Djava.security.policy either equals some policy file name or
double equals some policy file name, so a subtle difference.
Equals means augment the current policy file, the default policy
file, and just add these changes.
Double equals means overriding completely the default policy file, so just use my policy file as a replacement. So let's see how we do that.