Hi, my name is Kevin Jones,
and this is the introductory chapter to the Understanding
the Java Virtual Machine Security class.
In this class, we'll aim to understand how Java ensures code is safe to run.
That is, when I execute a piece of code,
is that code allowed to carry out a specific function?
And just to emphasize this, we are looking at code,
not users, so we're not looking at how we can secure a user,
how we can do authentication, and how we can do authorization.
This is specifically looking at Java code.
To that end, we'll take a look at four things.
We'll take a look at something called the Java security manager.
This is a class built into the runtime that helps us manage code level security.
The security manager itself uses something called the access controller.
Initially, when Java was first released, we only had the security manager.
The access controller came along in Java 1.2, or JDK 2, if
you like, to try and make it much easier to manage code
level security. Between them,
these use something called a secure class loader. So a secure class
loader understands where code is loaded from, and security manager
can use that location information to determine whether code should
be allowed to execute or not.
And finally,
towards the end of the class, we'll take a look at
something called privilege scopes.
Occasionally,
you want a piece of code to execute. Even when it's surrounding code, it
shouldn't be allowed to do something. In the next module of this class,
we'll take a look at a little history, and we'll take a look at some of the players in Java code security.