So this is the same demo that we've used in previous modules.
So if you remember, we have a Main class here.
So we have com.knowledgespike.Main and Main uses a
DataAccess library and a DataService library.
On the service it calls write, the service calls write on the DataAccess code,
and the DataAccess code writes to the file system.
And we have a policy file here which grants write
permission to each of these codeBases.
So if I run this code from the command line using
that policy and security.manager, it all works fine.
But suppose that our Service.jar doesn't have permission.
But we'd still like to be able to write to the file system because by writing
into the file system that's, let's say, our audit message.
So I edit the policy file, and I save it.
If I go back to my command prompt and run the code again,
it fails,
and we know it fails because we're doing a full stack
walk to check all the permissions.
So what we'd like to do here is, inside the data access code,
prevent that stack walk.
We want this code to be privileged.
We want this code to be able to write to the file system,
even if other things on the stack frame are not able to.
So let me remove this code.
So the way we make this thing privileged is by using
AccessController.doPrivileged.
And we know doPrivileged takes a PrivilegedAction type with a run method.
And as we're using Java 8 here,
we can use the new lambda syntax to execute this code.
So for the lambda syntax, we've going to say something goes to some method,
and the thing that's being passed in here is a PrivilegedAction.
So we need to add the code in for this method.
So the code for this is simply the writer code that we saw previously.
So what's going to happen here is that when we call doPrivileged,
this method will execute.
This is the run method.
The run method will execute, and inside this run method,
because we're inside a doPrivileged block,
we prevent this stack walk.
So we don't check what's calling us to see if what's calling us has permission.
As long as we have permission, then we're fine.
We can execute this code.
This is going to throw some exceptions,
so we put the appropriate catch clauses in,
and we also need to return a value from this.
This thing returns an object by default.
We'll just return null here to shut the compiler up.
So if I build this code and then go back to the
command prompt and run this code again, this code should now succeed,
as the DataAccess.jar file is privileged.
And indeed it does.
If I go back to my.policy file and remove permissions from
the DataAccess.jar file and then go back to the command
prompt and run the code again, it will fail.
So even though it's privileged,
it's still needs permission to be able to do this.
So we see here that even though the DataAccess.jar
file can try and claim a privilege, once it's claimed that privilege,
anything it tries to do will still be subject to security checks.
So the fact that it can claim the privilege doesn't mean it can do anything.
It's still then subject to the normal security checks,
and we still have to give it permission to write to this file. Otherwise the code will fail.