Hello there, and welcome back to AWS Developer:
Designing and Developing. In this module,
we're going to look at two different ways to
communicate between services or applications.
Simple Queue Service, or SQS, is a way to send messages via a queue system.
Individual messages can be taken off the queue and processed by consumers.
Kinesis Streams are a real‑time, stream‑based messaging
service that works similar to SQS,
but with subtle differences that change the ideal use case.
We'll be looking at both in this module and configuring
them to work with our application.
Let's go over what will be covering in this module.
We'll start by looking at some of the specifics of
polling in SQS and how messages work.
Then we'll create an SQS queue to send race results and look at
how to consume and process those messages.
Next, I'll introduce you to Kinesis streams,
and we'll set one up for our application to send race results to the
races table. And, finally, will cap it off by looking at some of the restrictions and limits with both services