The first step in using a queue in SQS for communication between
services and AWS is to actually create the queue.
Let's start by opening the file in scripts/module_08 named
create‑sqs‑queue.js. Since there's quite a bit of code
required to work with queues, I've done most of the work,
and we'll just be filling in certain parts of the code.
In this file, start by adding your region on line 4.
On line 7,
declare a const named sqs and assign to it a new AWS.SQS constructor call.
This file is only creating a queue, so there's not much to it.
On line 14,
let's create the params const object, and give the queue some properties.
The first property is QueueName,
which we can give the value of the QueueName function argument.
The next property is attributes, which has the value of an object.
The structure of this params object is a little odd compared to the others,
probably because this is another one of the earliest SDKs created.
Most of the properties we'll add here are ones that
I mentioned in the last clip.
The first property here is going to be DelaySeconds,
which is the default delay seconds for each message.
We can just set it to a string with the value 0.
Remember, an incoming message can override this if they want to.
The next property is MessageRetentionPeriod,
which is how long the messages will stay in the queue if they're not deleted.
We'll set this to a string with the number 345600,
which is the seconds equivalent to 4 days.
Next, add the property VisibilityTimeout,
which is how long messages will be invisible after being read.
We can set it to a string with the value 30 for 30 seconds.
Then the last property is ReceiveMessageWaitTimeSeconds,
which will set the long‑polling time of a consumer.
We can set this to a string with the value of 0 and let consumers
decide whether they want to long poll or not.
Now the create script is ready,
so, we can switch over to our command line and
navigate to the scripts/module_08 folder,
then execute node create‑sqs‑queue.js.
Once it's complete, it'll output the details of the queue.
Now in the next clip, we're going to configure our demo project to send messages to this queue.