Route 53 has two key concepts to know when setting
it up to support a domain name.
The first is the hosted zone.
This is basically the domain name itself without subdomains.
For instance, example.com or hbfl.online.
The other concept is the record set.
This is basically a DNS rule which configures an AWS
resource as the destination of a request.
Each hosted zone will have many record sets in it.
In our case,
we're going to create a hosted zone for our demo project and then
configure a route set to send requests to our load balancer.
One note before we start.
Unless you purchase a domain name from a registrar and add
the name servers from your hosted zone,
you won't be able to actually test the changes we'll do in this video.
So if you do want to follow and test it,
purchase a domain name, and use that instead of the placeholder here.
Now, switch over to your code editor and open the file in scripts/module_06,
create‑route53‑hostedzone.js.
This file is simple with just one SDK method needing to
be called to create this hosted zone.
Let's start by updating your region on line 4.
Next, we need to create our route53 SDK object.
On line 7,
create a route53 const and assign to it a new AWS.Route53 constructor call.
On line 10,
we're actually calling the createHostedZone function that we'll implement.
Now on line 14, create a params const object.
The SDK method will only need a couple properties here.
The first is the Name property,
which you can give the value of the hzName function argument.
Above, we're passing this in as hbfl.online.
If you wanted to use your own domain name, just update the string on line 8.
The next property is CallerReference.
This is a unique value that differentiates calls to create hosted zones.
It's required, must be a string,
and the easiest thing to do is to just set it to a timestamp.
So for the value here,
create a string template with back ticks, then evaluate a call to Date.now
by surrounding it in the dollar sign curly brace syntax.
That's all we'll need for properties.
So now we can come into the Promise and call route53.createHostedZone.
The first argument will be our params object and the second
our callback with err and data arguments.
Inside, if there's an err object, then call reject with it.
Otherwise, call resolve and pass in data.
Passing in data here is important because we'll need one of the
values that are output for our next operation.
Now, save the file, and switch over to your command line,
and navigate to the scripts/module‑06 directory.
Execute the command node create‑route53‑hostedzone.js.
Once it's complete, you should see the JSON output for the request.
The Id field under HostedZone is what you need to save
because we'll use it in our next clip where we'll create a record set for this hosted zone.