There are a few high‑level instance attributes that you have to
decide on before starting an EC2 instance.
One of them is instance type, which I covered in the Getting Started course.
Another attribute is the instance class.
These classes are spot instances, on‑demand instances, or reserved instances.
You may have seen these terms,
but I'll define them here and give them a little more explanation.
In this course and the Getting Started course,
we're only using on‑demand instances,
but based on the descriptions, consider giving the other classes a try.
Instance class doesn't have anything to do with what the instance
can do. It really defines the conditions in which the instance
lives and how much you'll pay for it.
On‑demand instances are the usual pay‑only‑for‑what‑you‑use, no‑commitment
instances that we spin up and spin down like nothing.
These instance types are good for applications that
need to be scaled up and down.
It's also the best kind of instance when you're learning
AWS, like we are, because you can kill the instance when
you're done playing with it.
Reserved instances are just like they sound where you make
a commitment to AWS and reserve a set number of instances
for a certain period of time.
There are different links to the commitment time,
typically between one and three years,
but the discounts can be massive, some up to 75% off.
If you're a stable company that will reliably need certain
instances running for that period of time,
reserved instances might be a great way to save some money.
The final class of instances is called spot instances.
These are instances that you bid on, and they utilize spare EC2 computing power.
Think of it like the unused hotel rooms or airline seats that are
sold at rock bottom prices at the last minute just because it's
better to get some money than no money.
Discounts can be even deeper than with reserved instances, up to 90%
off, but there's no real guarantee on availability.
It's suggested that only extremely flexible compute jobs utilize spot instances.
A web application is not a good use case for spot instances, but a research job or data processing job might be a good fit.