AWS provides a REST API to perform operations on services in your account.
Just like any typical REST API, it lets you perform normal CRUD operations,
such as creating EC2 instances or listing all available AMIs.
The API seems very convenient before you discover the
signing procedure required for each request.
When sending any API request to AWS,
you must first sign the entire request with your AWS credentials
and add the generated value as a query parameter.
This is actually common with secure APIs,
but can make it difficult to work with manually.
AWS understands this can be difficult,
which is why they develop and maintain the SDKs.
Inside the code of the SDKs, AWS is signing each request made for you.
Indeed,
most of the SDK is just a thin layer of code over the REST APIs. Making
a request to this REST API, especially signing that request, is a
convoluted process I wouldn't wish on anyone.
It's a process that requires multiple levels of hashing, creating
HMACs, and then actually making the request.
But let's go ahead and take a look at the process involved so
we can appreciate what the SDK does for us.
First of all, you need to decide which version of signature you want to produce.
Version 2 is the older version supported by many of the original services,
but it's largely being deprecated in most places. Version
4 is the preferred signature version.
Certain newer AWS regions actually only support version 4,
as do many newer services.
Each signature version has a different process when signing requests. Version 4
is the more secure, and therefore more complicated process.
With a version 4 signature, you'll start by creating a canonical request.
This is a combination of the HTTP method, the URI path, query parameters,
any headers, and finally, the hashed contents of the request payload.
The next step is to create a string that will be signed for your request.
This string contains the hashing algorithm used, the date, the region,
the service, and finally, the previously derived canonical request that
has been hashed with SHA‑256. And we're not done yet.
Once we have this string, we need to actually sign it. To do this,
we'll need to first calculate a signature by making several
passes through an HMAC. And then finally, signing our string
with the resulting signing string.
That process gives a signature,
which we will add as a query parameter to the actual request when we make it.
This process is pretty difficult to get right as I myself
experienced trying to manually sign a request. The errors
when you get it wrong are unhelpful, and the documentation is not the clearest.
Luckily for you, me, and every other developer in the world,
you can instead just used the AWS SDK to make these requests. You won't
have to sign anything at all, it does it all for you.
The SDK uses your local credentials to make the request and then return
the response to you. Due to the complexities involved, I'm sure you'll
be grateful that we'll be using the SDK as our soul interface to the AWS REST APIs for this course.