In order to run your application in AWS,
we need to have one or more EC2 instances to execute that code.
So the first step is to create an EC2 instance.
There are many different ways to do this.
In the Getting Started course, we used the AWS console to create instances.
Another method is to use the CLI, which can be useful with DevOps automation.
But we are going to use the SDK to create an instance with code.
And before we can create the instance, we need to create a few other
resources. In this clip, we're going to create a security group for the
instance. Then, in the next clip we'll create a key pair. And then finally,
we'll use both and create the instance itself.
Because a lot of this course will be using code to perform
operations through AWS, I've created a scripts folder in
the course exercise files.
This scripts folder is organized by module,
so navigate to the module_02 folder. I've created a file we'll use
in this video called create‑ec2‑instance.js.
This file provides a blueprint for the changes we need to make to create
that EC2 instance. Each modification has a TODO comment,
so it's clear where you'll make your modifications.
I'll walk you through the file to start with.
At the top are dependency imports.
Then, we've got a TODO where we need to configure the AWS region.
Next are some local variables being declared.
Then we've got the code that calls several functions to create a security group,
create a key pair, and then create the EC2 instance. Below that
are three functions that we'll implement.
The first is to create a security group, the second to create the key
pair, and the last is to create an EC2 instance using the security group
and key pair that were created. As a side note, an EC2 instance can be
created through the SDK without an explicit security group or key pair.
If neither are given, the instance is assigned the default security group
in your account,
and no key pair is assigned. After the fact, you can reassign security groups,
so getting the default one isn't much of an issue.
However,
the key pair is more serious. If you're using an AMI that isn't
preconfigured to allow a different type of access method,
such as password‑based, then you won't be able to SSH into your
instance. With a vanilla AWS Linux instance,
you must attach a key pair to access it.
Now let's get started with the changes in this file. In
this clip that you're watching right now,
we're only going to be creating the security group.
But after we've made all the modifications and we run the file,
we will have a running EC2 instance with a security group allowing us
access and a key pair that has been saved locally,
which we can use to access that instance.
In addition,
the EC2 instance will already have Node installed, the demo project downloaded,
dependencies installed, and demo running on port 3000.
Pretty cool.
So first, scroll to the top of the file to line 2. We need to
import the AWS SDK into a local variable.
Replace the comment with a const declaration with an
identifier of AWS, all in caps. Assign to it a require
function call, passing in the string aws‑sdk.
This dependency comes from the npm repository, which
we'll install before running this code.
Next, take a look at line 5.
The AWS SDK requires you to configure the region each time it's imported.
I'll admit, this gets a little annoying. There are some
abstractions you can do to mitigate this,
but we won't worry about that in this course.
We need to call the update function on the AWS.config property. Into
this function, pass an object with one property called region. You
could add other properties to this object to change other configuration
options on the AWS.config object,
such as the max number of retries for a given request or a
global logger object. Here, just enter a string as the value to
the region key property with the region you're using. I'll
enter us‑east‑1 here for mine.
Now we need an ec2 object created from the AWS object.
This is what we'll call different operations on.
Declare a new const variable called ec2, all lowercase. To the
right side of an assignment operator, use the new keyword and call
the AWS.EC2 function with no arguments,
and that's all that's needed to create that object.
Now we can scroll down and start implementing some functions in the order
they're called. On line 31, we want to create a security group.
Most SDK operations have a similar pattern.
First,
declare the parameters object to be passed to the SDK function. Then, call
the function, passing in a callback to handle the result.
We'll follow that pattern for these functions and for most
of the code we'll write in this course.
So to start with, create a const named params. Assign to it an empty object.
We're going to be using the createSecurityGroup function
here, and two of the params arguments that it wants is a
description and a group name.
We'll be taking an argument to this function called sgName,
and we can use that as the value for both of these properties.
They don't have to be the same,
but I find that the description isn't too useful until you
have a massive number of security groups.
Even then,
it seems that tags are used more for management in those situations than
descriptions. With the params defined, we can continue to the meat of the
function. For this function and most of the code in this course, we'll also
be using promises instead of callbacks.
I find this approach a little easier to understand and read.
So on line 36, return a new Promise.
It will take a function with the resolve and reject arguments.
This might be a good place to also mention that we'll be
making full use of ES6 in this course.
If you haven't learned many of the new features,
you might want to brush up on them so you can get a better understanding of the
code we're writing. Now, inside this Promise argument function body, we'll call
our first SDK function, ec2.createSecurityGroup.
The first argument will be the params object we created. Then, a
callback function with the err and data arguments.
Unfortunately, the SDK doesn't support promises firsthand,
so we'll need to use callbacks here.
Basically,
this function is creating a security group with the
name and description that we pass it.
It will not create any security group rules. Inside the
function body, call reject with the err object, if there is
one. In the else, create a block.
This is where our code will execute if the security group creation was
successful. Because our security group is essentially empty,
we want to add a rule here.
We'll want to enable port 22 so that we can SSH into the instance once it's
been created, and port 3000 so we can view the demo app.
So, start by creating a new const called params, again,
and assigning an empty object to it.
There are a few properties required to create the security group rule,
which should sound familiar to you if you've set one up with the
console before. The first is the GroupId to apply the rule to. We
can get that from the data argument supplied by the creation
callback. For the value here, enter dataGroupId.
The next property is IpPermissions, which is an array.
This array enables us to configure multiple rules in one request. Create an
object in this array and add the property IpProtocol. The possible values
for this are protocols like TCP or UDP for some examples. Enter tcp here,
all lowercase. The next two properties, FromPort and ToPort, define the
port range that you're enabling the rule for. In the first case, we'll
enter the number 22 in both FromPort and ToPort since we're allowing SSH
here. Finally, add the property IpRanges with the value as an empty array.
Here's where we can define who this rule applies to. Add an empty object
with the property CidrIp. We'll enable access to anyone,
so give this property the value of 0.0.0.0/0.
Now we need to also add the rule for port 3000, so copy this rule
object, add a comma after it, and then paste.
The only different property will be the FromPort and ToPort,
and you can set both to 3000. Awesome! Now we're ready to use that big
params object in an SDK call. On the ec2 object, we'll be calling the
authorizeSecurityGroupIngress function.
The ingress part of that function call refers to
these rules being inbound rules.
There is also a function called authorizedSecurityGroupEgress,
which is for outgoing rules. Call the function and pass the
params object as the first argument. The second will again be a
callback function with the argument err.
Even though this function does return a second argument,
we'll just ignore it. Inside the callback, call reject again
if there's an err object, in the else,
just call resolve. And with that code complete,
we've successfully created and assigned rules to a security group. In the next video, we'll create the key pair.