API Gateway is one of the newer AWS services,
and it reflects an evolution of routing with cloud resources.
While there is API directly in the name,
it is by no means only for use with APIs.
It actually really works well for all types of routing.
So what exactly is API Gateway?
It's essentially a routing layer that allows you to configure many rules on
the same domain and connect it to many different resources.
The language of API Gateway is couched in classical REST terms.
Each part of a URI path is called a resource,
and on those resources you configure methods.
Each method can be configured to have a certain behavior
and send the request to some AWS service.
You can transform the request before sending it on,
and also transform the response as well.
Each method on a resource is configured separately,
so you could have different operations on a path
going to different AWS resources.
It's really flexible and powerful.
In this module,
we're going to set our demo project up to respond from an API Gateway resource.
I'm using this example because you could then see how you could route other
paths on that same domain name to other applications. Now let's get started with creating our API in the next clip.