An empty Dynamo table is worse than an empty S3 bucket.
Okay, maybe not, but still,
we want to populate our Dynamo table with some data. In your scripts
folder, open the file populate‑dynamo‑table.js. This file uses a helpers
function to get some starting hamster and race data, and then it will put
that data into the respective tables.
Let's start with this file by replacing your region in line 5.
On line 8, we need to create our SDK object,
but we won't be using the dynamodb constructor we used in the last clip,
Although you can use the regular dynamodb object to put items in a table,
the SDK also provides a document client, which simplifies the
putting, getting, and querying of a Dynamo table.
To use this,
first declare a new const with the identifier client. Then assign to it
a new AWS.DynamoDB.DocumentClient constructor call.
This will seriously simplify the calls we need to make. In our
populateTable function, we will be creating a params object from all
the items to insert and then call the batch write function. So we'll
start by declaring our params const object.
This one is a little weird because it has a single root property,
RequestItems. Give it an empty object for the value. Then inside, our
property key will be the name of the table we're inserting into.
To get this from the tableName argument, use square brackets and
put the tableName argument inside as the key.
This is how you can reference a variable value for a property key.
We'll build the value to this property dynamically.
So call data.map and pass in a callback function with one argument called
item. Inside we'll return an object with the property PutRequest. As a
note, you could also make this a DeleteRequest, and the batch write
function processes both. Now for the value, create another object and give
it the property Item with the value of the item argument. With this, we'll
dynamically build out the params object and add a put request for each
item. Inside the next promise, we'll call the client.batchWrite function.
The first argument will be params,
and the second will be a callback function with err and data
arguments. Inside that function, if there's an err object,
call reject with the err argument.
Otherwise, call resolve with the data argument.
Let's go ahead and try this out in our command line.
The table should be finished creating by now,
so run the command node populate‑dynamo‑table.js. You'll
get some empty array like this as output,
which means you're good. In the AWS console,
go to the DynamoDB dashboard.
If you select either one of those tables and then look at the Items tab,
you should see the data that we just pushed present
in the table. In the next clip,
we're going to connect our demo project up to this table to consume the data we just put there.