Once your instance has been created,
there are a few different operations that you can perform on
the instance as you manage its lifecycle.
The most obvious SDK function to use is modifyInstanceAttribute.
Most of the attributes this method allows you to modify our pretty
granular, like the kernel and RAMdisk,
but a few more commonly used attributes are instance
types and block device mapping.
I honestly didn't think there was much for us to dig into with this call,
so I thought we'd try out two other management functions.
The function describeInstances is useful because it will list all the
instances you currently have running in a given region.
You can apply different filters to further filter the query and
limit what types of instances are returned.
I wanted us to give this function a try and see what we get. In your
code editor, open the file manage‑ec2‑instance.js.
We'll start modifying this file by importing the AWS SDK on line
2 and assigning it to an AWS const variable.
Next on line 4, we need to configure the region in the SDK.
Do this by calling AWS.config.update and passing in an object with a
region property with the region you're using as the value. Now on
line 7, let's create our EC2 object that we'll call our operations
on. Declare a const variable named ec2 and assign to it a new AWS.EC2
constructed object.
With our setup complete,
we're ready to implement the listInstances method on line 9.
The describeInstances function only has a few possible
parameters in the params object.
The main one is the filters to apply. These are things
like instance type, VPC ID or tag.
For our purposes, we're not going to use a filter,
but I just want you to know that that functionality exists.
Since we're using the promise pattern, start by returning
a new promise and creating the argument function with
resolve and reject arguments.
Now we'll call the ec2.describeInstances function.
The first params argument is basically going to be empty,
so just enter an object.
The second argument is the callback function with err and data arguments. Like
usual, reject if there's an err object, otherwise resolve with data. Now, we
will need to do something to this data object,
but I just want you to return it as is to show you what the structure is
like. On line 22, this listInstances function is called and the result
logged, so we can just run the file to see the result. On a command
line, make sure you're in the module_02 folder, and then execute node
manage‑ec2‑instances.js.
Once it's finished, it should print out a small piece of JSON to your console.
This is the structure of that data argument that the
describeInstances function returns.
The top level property is called Reservations, and this is a little weird.
A reservation in this context is essentially a request
from some user to AWS to launch an EC2 instance. This
could have come from the console, the SDK,
the command line, or even something like an auto scaling group.
If you have more than one instance on your account,
there's a very high possibility that this array that is assigned to
Reservations will have more than one object in it.
In my case, there's only one because I'm on a clean account.
You'll see each of the objects,
and this Reservations array has an Instances array.
This is the information we actually want.
It's abstracted here just because the JSON printout doesn't
actually go that deep. Back in your code editor,
let's modify line 13 so we only get the instance information back.
We're going to use a little JavaScripting to basically concatenate all
the Instances arrays in every Reservation object.
So, just stick with me here.
First, add curly braces after else around our resolve call.
Then, from the end of the data object,
reference the Reservations property and then chain called to reduce.
Inside this call,
you'll create a new arrow function with two arguments, i and r. I is the
aggregated instances and r is the current reservation.
Inside that function, return a call to i.concat, passing in r.Instances.
And don't miss the uppercase I on that r.Instances.
Then, after the closing curly braces, add a comma and then an empty array,
which is the seed for our reduce function.
Now if we save that and go back to the command line and
execute node manage‑ec2‑instance.js again, we will see all
the instance image information output.
You've got a ton of information here, like the InstanceType, the KeyName,
the PublicIpAddress, and if you've got more than one instance,
you should see them all listed up here.
We'll use a piece of information here for our next
management function, so let's go and grab it.
Find the instance you just launched in the last clip.
The easiest identifier will likely be the KeyName showing hamster_key.
Copy the InstanceId property,
which will be like a lowercase i‑, and then a bunch of letters and
numbers. Swap over to your code editor and paste this instance ID into
the parentheses on line 28 for terminateInstance.
Ensure there are quotes around the ID in case you didn't copy them.
Now, let's implement terminateInstance so that we can
terminate the instance that we just created.
This function is going to take an instanceId as an argument
and tell AWS to terminate the instance.
For the record, you can also stop an instance if you wanted to.
The key difference between stopping and terminating an instance
is that a stopped instance can be restarted,
but a terminated instance cannot.
We will need a params instance for our SDK call, so on
line 23, declare a params const object.
It will only take one property, InstanceIds, which is an array.
This will let you terminate multiple instances with a single call. Inside this
array, just enter the instanceId argument variable. Now make a new line after
line 27 and we'll return our new Promise pattern.
Inside the function argument, we'll make a call to ec2.terminateInstances,
passing in params as the first argument and a callback as the second with
err and data arguments. Do the usual here,
rejecting if there's an err, otherwise resolve with data. And that's it.
It's pretty simple to terminate instances. Now come down to line 37 and
comment out lines 37 and 38. Then, uncomment lines 39 and 40.
Then, switch over to your command line and we're going to terminate our
hamster instance by running node manage‑ec2‑instance.js again.
When it's complete, it'll output the report from what it terminated,
which should contain that same instance ID that was passed in.
And that's it for terminating instances.
If you don't trust your command line,
you can go back to the console and see that the
instance in question is shutting down. In the next clip, we're going to launch an instance from the AWS Marketplace.