Running your own code on a vanilla Linux or Windows instance is
one of the most common use cases for EC2.
But occasionally there is some vendor‑provided
software that you want to run as well.
You could install this yourself,
but you'll often find that there might be an existing AMI with
the software preinstalled available on the AWS Marketplace.
Let's take a look at the marketplace by navigating to the EC2
dashboard in the AWS Console.
Click on the Launch instance button and then Launch instance,
and you'll be on the AMI selection page.
The software available from the AWS Marketplace are just Amazon machine images
with an operating system and custom software preinstalled.
That's essentially it. On the left‑hand menu click AWS Marketplace,
and here you'll be able to see what's on offer.
There is some featured and popular AMIs and then the
categories. You can see there's quite a few available,
thousands of AMIs in fact. For this course,
I wanted us to launch an instance within an AMI from the marketplace,
specifically one with Node preinstalled. In the search
box, type Node.js and hit Enter.
There will be quite a few results, but look for the result
titled Node.js Certified by Bitnami.
There shouldn't be any cost information here.
If an AMI from the marketplace does cost money,
it will have the per‑hour cost listed next to the image information.
You may see some other entries with a cost associated with it.
Node is free, and the Bitnami AMI is free as well.
Now click More info and then the link ending in
product detail on AWS Marketplace.
See we're not going to use the consul to launch this image,
but instead grab the AMI ID and use our scripts again.
This next page has a lot more information about the image if
you want to read it. For our current case,
click this Continue to Subscribe button on the right‑hand side.
Now we're in the subscription page.
We have to subscribe to this image,
meaning that we accept their terms and conditions.
If this image had a cost associated with it,
we would also be agreeing to pay whatever amount the image costs.
I've already subscribed, so your screen will look a little different than mine.
Click on the Subscribe button that you see and then
wait a bit and refresh the page.
Once the subscription has gone through,
your page should look like mine with a Continue to Configuration button in
the top right. Click that now. Now we can finally get the AMI ID. You can
adjust some parameters here if you need to,
such as the architecture version of Ubuntu and region.
If you remember I mentioned before, each AMI is region specific.
This is why picking the correct region here matters.
It's technically the same code for each region,
the same image, but the IDs are different based on the region.
Everything should be automatically populated for you
based on the region in your console.
Now, copy the AMI ID that is displayed right here.
Then switch back over to your code editor and open
the create‑ec2‑instance.js file.
We're going to launch an instance using this AMI instead of the vanilla Amazon
Linux AMI. So scroll down to line 88 and paste the image ID.
We could run this now, but there are two more changes.
I want to make. The user data we have here installs Node and Git,
then clones the demo and runs it.
We don't need to install Node anymore because the AMI comes with it.
So let's change this user data.
Open up the file titled marketplace‑ec2‑startup.sh.
This is basically the same as before,
minus the Node installation Steps and the Linux Package Manager
updated to apt‑get since the Nitnami image is Ubuntu‑based. Copy the
base64 encoded text minus the starting hash at the bottom and paste
that into the user data section.
The next modification is to the key pair and
security group names on lines 9 and 10.
If we were to run this file again,
it would try to create new resources with those names and
then error out because they already exist.
Let's give them unique names by just tacking on a 2 to the end of each string.
Now save the file,
switch over to your command line, and run the file
with node create‑ec2‑instance.js.
You should see the same type of message as when you ran the file previously.
This time, however,
you're launching the instance with a whole different AMI.
We can skip ahead in time a bit to confirm that the
instance creation worked correctly.
I'm copying the public IP for the newly created instance and
hitting it with my browser on port 3000.
And there's Hamster Ball Fantasy League running on a Node AMI
launched from the AWS marketplace. In the next clip, we're going to create a new AMI from this instance.