As you might expect, DynamoDB,
RDS, and ElastiCache have some more significant limits than the
other services. Persistence is a much more touchy subject and
requires both heightened security and a more strict environment in
order to achieve high performance.
Let's take a look at some of the limits and restrictions.
Dynamo has several restrictions around secondary indexes. You
can only create up to five global secondary indexes and five
local secondary indexes per table.
Those local secondary indexes must be created at the same time
as the table and cannot be deleted after. Global secondary
indexes don't have this restriction.
Finally, when creating a table,
tables with secondary indexes must be created consecutively.
More than one cannot be created at the same time.
RDS has limits around numbers of databases and size of the databases,
which is in the terabytes, but nothing you wouldn't expect.
There are some restrictions about database and user naming,
but they differ with each database engine,
so you need to research those yourself.
ElastiCache, similar to RDS, has a limit around the number of clusters and nodes.
These are soft limits and can be raised with a request to AWS. The one
restriction to remember is that you can't directly access ElastiCache
from outside of the VPC it's created in. Beyond that, there's no other restrictions that need mentioning.