Deployment in API Gateway is kind of unique.
There are two key concepts, stages and deployments.
API Gateway lets you create stages for your APIs.
Think of stages like development, integration, staging, and production.
You can deploy your API to different stages in order to
have a healthy development lifecycle.
Each time you deploy to a stage,
a deployment is created These are saved in the history of each
stage, so you can move between them easily,
especially in cases where you might need to roll back. To make
our REST API accessible, we need to deploy it.
So, open up your code editor and open the file
deploy‑api‑gateway.js. Start by updating your region on line 4.
On line 8, we need to add the ID for your API.
I'll show you where to find this.
Go to the AWS console and in the API Gateway dashboard. You should
see your API, hamster‑api, so click on that.
And if you look in this title bar after the hamster‑api section,
there's some ID in parentheses.
This is your API ID.
So, copy it. And back in your code, paste it inside the string on line 8.
Deploying our API is as easy as just creating a deployment, so
go ahead and create your params const object inside that
function. We'll add the first property,
which is restApiId, which you can give the value of the apiId function argument.
Next is the stageName,
which you can give the value of the stageName function argument.
And if you look on line 10, you can see that we are
passing in prod as the value for this.
This is where you could differentiate prod and staging and dev,
or however you like to differentiate your different environments.
Now, come down into the Promise and we'll call apiG.createDeployment,
passing in params as our first argument and a callback function with
err and data arguments as our second.
If there's an err object, call reject and pass it in, otherwise
call resolve with the data argument. Each time this function is
called, API Gateway will take the current state of your API
resource and deploy it to that stage.
Simple as that. Now let's move over to our command line and deploy our
API by running the command node deploy‑api‑gateway.js.
After it finishes, it'll output the ID of the deployment,
which is actually pretty useless to us.
To get the URL we can try, go back to your web browser and refresh the
API Gateway dashboard. Under hamster‑api on the left‑hand side menu,
click on Stages and you should see a prod stage.
Expand that, and you will see the resources and methods that were deployed.
You can see the any method for our proxy has turned into individual methods.
If you click on the GET under the hbfl resource,
you'll see a prominently displayed link,
which is where the API Gateway was deployed.
We do need to manually modify this just a bit,
so copy the link and paste it in a new browser window.
Our site needs to be accessed with a trailing slash,
so add that at the end of your URL and hit Enter.
Now we're in our demo project running directly through API Gateway.
In the next clip, we'll look at limits and restrictions you may find when working with Route 53 and API Gateway.