Hello, and welcome back to AWS Developer, Designing, and
Developing. This is the last module for this course, and we're
going out with a bang by covering two services that will increase
the real‑time nature of your applications.
Simple notification service, or SNS, is used to send notifications to users
via SMS, email, HTTP, and many other ways. A usual trigger of SNS is
CloudWatch Alarms and those can be configured to make sure that your
application and services stay up and healthy.
Let's take a look at what we'll be covering in this module.
We'll start by creating an SNS topic and subscribing to
it with your mobile phone or email.
Then we'll modify our demo project to publish race
results to the topic and give it a whirl.
Next,
we'll create a CloudWatch alarm to monitor our application health and send
notifications if something happens. We'll end out the module discussing
some limits around SNS and CloudWatch alarms.
And then we'll have a special clip on what resources to delete as you're cleaning up your AWS account after this course.