Hello there.
My name is Ryan Lewis,
and I'm happy to welcome you to this course AWS
Developer: Designing and Developing.
If you've come to learn the ins and outs of AWS, then you're in the right place.
This course has a few objectives,
but the most important is that your understanding and proficiency with
developing in AWS will have leveled up by the end.
This course is intended as a follow up to my previous
course AWS Developer: Getting Started.
I will expect familiarity with many of the most common AWS
services, so if you haven't watched that course yet,
then I definitely suggest taking the time to work through it.
With that being said,
this course does cover many services already covered in the previous course.
The main difference is the approach and details that we'll be
covering. The getting started courses goal was to really get you
familiar with the multitude of AWS's offerings.
This course takes that familiarity and aims to make you
moderately proficient at developing in AWS by adding even
more detail and information.
Additionally,
the focus for this course will be on the development side of AWS and not
cover infrastructure related services like VPC or IAM.
For this course, we're going to focus on taking a web application,
and integrating it into AWS. In the process we'll create and
modify services using multiple different methods,
such as the CLI and SDK.
I'll take special care to include specific details about each service
we're interacting with that should help you understand how to design your AWS architecture for your own applications.