SQS and Kinesis Streams are highly‑performant services targeted at specific use
cases. Understanding how the systems work and the restrictions around them are
essential for designing a robust web application.
In the previous discussions,
we've covered most of the limits around SQS and Kinesis Streams, and of course
they both have the soft resource limits that can be raised.
But there are a few Kinesis Stream limits I wanted to mention here.
The first limit with Kinesis Streams is the limit to the size of the
data blobs you can send through a Kinesis Stream.
They are static at 1 MB. This is basically constrained by the
size of the shards making up your stream.
If you have data larger than that,
you'd either need to break it into pieces or send records of S3
keys where the data is actually stored. In relation to sharding,
there is a limit around the number of put request operations you
can perform each second, and that is 1000 per shard.
If you find yourself hitting that limit,
you'll need to scale your stream up by adding shards to it. And those are all the major limits with SQS and Kinesis Streams.