Route 53 and API Gateway are both constrained by restrictions and limits,
but they come from different concerns.
Route 53 has many restrictions due to the nature of DNS changes,
whereas API Gateway has many restrictions due to it being a new service in AWS.
Let's look at a few of both. In Route 53 you'll notice
quickly that there is a restriction on how fast record set
changes are propagated to the internet, and this is based on DNS rules.
Usually, I've found that if you change your record set,
the change can be observed almost instantly.
If you make an error for some reason, though,
and need to change that same record set again,
the change will be delayed by around 5 minutes.
I've encountered this several times,
so make sure to be careful when changing records sets.
Aside from that, there are the normal resource limits,
but they can all be raised by AWS. API Gateway has limits around
the number of requests you can make to create,
modify, or delete something in your account.
These are hard limits and say, for instance,
that you can only send two create API requests per minute.
All the rest are blocked, and then you just have to wait.
It's kind of inconvenient.
There are also many known issues with API Gateway that
restrict certain types of operations.
AWS maintains a page with these, found here,
and it's a good idea to be aware of some of the issues it currently faces.
I ran into some in the past around the way that API Gateway resolves
requests and spent a few months figuring it out. Beyond that, there are the resource limits as usual, and those can be raised.