All services and resources and AWS have limits. It's
important to be aware of them so that they don't trip you
up when designing AWS architecture.
And that's the worst thing about limits.
You end up hitting them at the most inopportune times.
So let's take a look at some of the limits involved with EC2 and AMIs. EC2 has
a limit on the max number of running instances per region.
This actually gets a little complicated though,
so I'll show you where to view these limits.
Go to the EC2 dashboard in the AWS Console.
On the left‑hand menu, there is a Limits entry and click on it.
You'll see there are a lot of limits here, and they get very specific.
They're also instance‑type specific,
so you can really do a lot of damage if you get creative with
the image types you're using. Scrolling down,
you can see there are a few other types of limits listed
here beyond running instance limits.
One important thing to notice about all of these limits
though is that you can select any of these limits and use
the Request Limit Increase button.
This means that these aren't hard limits.
You can ask AWS to raise them if you ever need to.
If you're using AWS with a corporate account or for your company,
then raising these limits is rarely an issue.
This page largely contains all the EC2 limits.
As for AMI limits, we've already discussed that AMIs are
region‑specific, so definitely keep that in mind.
There doesn't appear to be a limit to the number of
AMIs specifically that you can have.
But since each AMI is stored using an EBS snapshot and
there is a limit of 10,000 EBS snapshots,
I would assume the max number of AMIs you can have is 10,000.
Also,
keep in mind that you do have to pay per EBS snapshot, so having 10,000 AMIs is not going to be cheap.