In the world of the cloud and AWS, terms such as
scalability and elasticity are thrown around like they're
the most common things in the world.
The terms are often used interchangeably, something which I'm guilty of as well.
I've found, however,
that the nuances of these terms often aren't completely understood
and can result in some confusion in how each impacts your cloud
architecture with AWS. In this clip,
we're going to talk about each one in detail.
Scalability in terms of AWS refers to the ability for your
resources to increase or decrease in size or quantity.
There's a lot of infrastructure involved to make something like this happen,
so it's no easy task.
Many of the services in AWS are scalable by default,
which is one of the reasons that AWS is so successful.
Scalability is pretty simple to define,
which is why some of the aspects of elasticity are often attributed to it.
Elasticity is the ability for your resources to scale
in response to stated criteria, often CloudWatch rules.
This is what happens when a load balancer adds instances
whenever a web application gets a lot of traffic.
Scalability is required for elasticity, but not the other way around.
Not all AWS services support elasticity,
and even those that do often need to be configured in a certain way.
It might seem redundant,
but the services in AWS that start with Elastic often support elasticity.
Scalability gives you the ability to increase or decrease your resources,
and elasticity lets those operations happen
automatically according to configured rules.
Together,
they let you sleep soundly at night with the assurance
that your applications are healthy, no matter the situation.
Now in the next clip,
we're going to start our path towards elasticity by creating a launch configuration.