Content coming from CloudFront is typically best when being served
from the CloudFront cache and not from your origin.
Getting this right will dramatically reduce latency to your user.
But when configuring cache,
you'll set a max time to live before the cash retrieves a new version of the
content from the origin. Set the value too high, and when you release new code
then users are still getting the cached version.
Set it too low, and you're not taking advantage of what CloudFront can offer.
There are two real solutions to make the most out of a high time‑to‑live value.
The first is to invalidate content when you've got a new version available.
This can be done by sending an invalidation to CloudFront,
defining which files to replace with new versions.
A single invalidation can have multiple files to invalidate,
even referencing entire directories.
But there are a couple of downsides to using invalidations
exclusively for handling new content.
The first is that there's a hard limit on the number of
simultaneous invalidations you can process.
While the number is high at 3000 objects,
this essentially places an upper bound on the growth
of your application. In addition,
you're only allowed 1000 free invalidations per month.
Anything above that has a price associated with it.
And to top all this off invalidations can take some time.
They aren't instant. While I've often experienced,
it takes only a few minutes to process an invalidation, that was with only a few
files. I can imagine it would take longer with more files.
The second solution,
which would work better for many applications using CloudFront,
is to treat your assets as immutable and never change them.
This way they can be cached the maximum time and
never need a manual invalidation.
The easiest way to achieve this is to generate a unique name for the
object any time it changes. This might be something as simple as adding
a hash to the file name or a date timestamp.
Then,
when you push a new version of the application, it only references
the new files. The first time they're requested,
CloudFront retrieves them from the origin and then
caches them for the maximum time to live.
This has been my chosen solution when working with CloudFront since it has
the side benefit of solving client caching issues as well.
In the next clip, we're going to actually create a CloudFront distribution for our static assets.