We've already changed our code to directly access assets in S3, so
let's create a CloudFront distribution based off that bucket so
that we can get even better performance.
CloudFront SDK functions might hold the award for
most properties in a params object.
I seriously made a separate file for us just because there are
so many. Navigate to the scripts/module_07 folder and open the
CloudFront parameters.js file.
I moved the two biggest sections of params into this file so that
the actual create file is much easier to read.
We've got two sections here, the origins and defaultCashBehavior properties.
Let's get started with adding the origin properties.
This origins object can hold one or many origins,
so there is a quantity property we'll add first. This tells AWS
how many origins will be in the items array.
We're only creating one here, so enter the number 1.
The next property is Items and it has the value of an array.
This is where the origin details will go.
Create one object here.
The first property for the object is DomainName.
This will be the domain for your S3 bucket. We'll build it dynamically,
so create a string template,
then create a variable and add the bucketName function argument.
After that,
continue with .s3.amazonaws.com. And with that we'll build the domain
name dynamically based on whatever your bucket name is.
The next property is Id.
This is going to be a unique value that will be referenced in
the other params chunk, defaultCacheBehavior.
For this value,
create another string template and again reference a
variable with the bucketName function argument.
After add an underscore and the word origin,
this will make an Id based on your bucketName,
so it should be unique enough for our purposes.
The next property is S3OriginConfig, which has the value of an object.
This property is unused by us,
but it's required by CloudFront for an S3 origin to work.
Give it one property, OriginAccessIdentity with the value of an empty string.
Like I said,
it's unused. Now that's everything we need to configure for our origin.
Let's configure the defaultCacheBehavior below to use that origin.
These DefaultCacheBehavior properties do exactly as they say.
They configure the default behavior that our created distribution will follow.
The first property is FowardedValues, which has the value of an object.
This will tell our distribution to forward on cookies
or query parameters to the origin.
In our case, we don't want any of this behavior.
Add the property Cookies with the value of an object. Inside give
it one property called Forward and the value of none as a string.
After the Cookies property, add a property named QueryString and
give it the value of false.
Now,
after the FowardedValues object, add a new property
called MinTTL and set it to 0.
This is the minimum time to keep an object in cache before
forwarding the request back to the origin.
The next property is TargetOriginId, which needs to
match the origin Id we defined above.
The easiest thing is to just copy the value from above and paste
it here, that way you won't get any typos.
Next, add the property TrustedSigners, which has the value of an object.
This will let you create signed URLs for CloudFront content and
only allow users to access content that way. We won't be doing
that, but this is another required field.
Add the property Quantity with the number 0,
then the property Enabled with the value false. After
TrustedSigners, add a property named ViewerProtocolPolicy.
This is where you can define https only, redirect http to https, or both.
I like to redirect http calls to https so add the
string redirect‑to‑https. Next,
add the property AllowedMethods with the value of an object. Here we'll
define what http methods can be used with this distribution. We'll have 2,
so add a property named Quantity with the value 2.
Then add a property called Items with an array as the value. We'll
add two methods here, GET in all caps and HEAD in all caps. After
the Items property, add another property called CachedMethods with
the value as an object.
This defines the http methods that CloudFront will cache. Add
the property Quantity with the value 2.
Then add the property Items with the value of an array.
The items here will copy what's above with GET and HEAD entered here.
And with that, our long properties are complete.
Now we can open create‑cloudfront‑distribution.js. You can
start by updating your region on line 5. On line 8 we need to
create a CloudFront SDK object.
Declare a const called cf and assign to it a new AWS.CloudFront
constructor call. On line 10 we're calling the
createDistribution function and you'll need to enter your bucket
name in the string function argument.
Now let's implement the createDistribution function.
Start by creating our params const object.
Even though I've offloaded most of the properties to that different file,
we've still got quite a few to add here.
Start by adding a DistributionConfig property and
giving it the value of an object.
The first property here will be CallerReference,
which you may remember from the Route 53 hosted zone.
This is a unique identifier for the SDK request we're making. Add a
string template with a variable and the expression Date.now to get a
timestamp. The next property is Comment,
which is sort of like a description or name for your distribution.
It'll be visible on the CloudFront dashboard,
so name it something that will help you distinguish the distribution.
The next property is DefaultCacheBehavior.
This is what we set up in the other file.
So for the value,
call cfParams.defaultCacheBehavior and pass in the
bucket name function argument.
The next property is Origins, which is the other set of properties we worked on.
So set the value to a call to cfParams.origins and pass in the bucket name.
The next property is HttpVersion, which I like to set to
the string http2 to make sure it's future facing. Next,
add the property Price class.
Basically, the pricing is set according to how many edge locations you set.
Add the value PriceClass_100, which is the cheapest,
and only uses edged locations in the U.S.,
Canada, and Europe.
The next property is IsIPV6Enabled, which I also
set too true to be future facing.
And finally, the last property is the most important.
The key is Enabled and you want it to be set to true if you
want to use this distribution at all. Now,
inside our promise, we can call our SDK function as cf.createDistribution,
passing in the prams object as the first argument and a callback
function with err and data arguments as the second.
If there's an err object than call reject with it.
Otherwise, call resolve with the data argument.
Now we can run this file and create our distribution,
so switch over to your command line and navigate to the
script/module_07 folder. Execute the command node
create‑cloudfront‑distribution.js and wait for it to finish.
CloudFront distributions can take some time to actually set up, so
we can modify our demo project in the meantime. First,
we need to get the new domain name for our CloudFront distribution.
So open the AWS console and go to the CloudFront dashboard.
Find the distribution by either the comment or the origin and select it. In
this details screen, copy the domain name found here.
Now, just like with S3,
there are only a few places we need to update static references in our code.
The first is in util/assets.js. So go to that file in your code
editor. Copy the value into the base const on line 1. You will need
to add the https protocol to the domain also. Now one more place, go
to handlers/template/index.html. On line 5 update the URL omitting
any bucket on the path.
Do the same on line 11 with the JavaScript import.
Now, to fully test this out,
you need to follow these steps. Rebuild the project locally,
deploy the code out to your EC2 instance,
upload the files to S3 again, repopulate the Dynamo table, and finally
wait for the CloudFront distribution to get set up.
You can then test out the changes completely with the load
balance URL or the API Gateway URL. A lot of steps,
but our application is becoming really robust. For the rest of the module, we're going to take a look at how static websites work with S3