Amazon provides a few different ways to interact with their cloud.
The web console is one of the first you'll interact with,
and the CLI is probably the second as you configure your local credentials.
But the AWS SDK, software development kit, is likely what you'll
use most of the time in your role as a developer.
This is because the AWS SDK provides a simplest
interface between your code and the cloud.
AWS distributes and maintains these SDKs in multiple
languages so you can develop in the cloud in whatever
language your application is built with.
There are some other open source SDKs for languages that aren't
supported already by AWS. These are typically very usable,
but it's important to know when an SDK is officially supported so that you
can understand the level of support it will receive.
Let's take a look at the official SDKs available from Amazon.
First of all,
AWS provides SDKs for the current most popular
server‑side development languages.
In no particular order, these are Java, .NET, C++,
Python,
Ruby, Go, and Node. On the client side, you can use the
same JavaScript SDK that is used with Node. On mobile, you
have some interesting options.
There are official SDKs for Android, iPhone, the Xamarin platform, and Unity.
With all of these offerings,
it's very likely that your language of choice has a
fully supported SDK from Amazon.
In this course, we're going to be working with an application built on Node,
so we will be using the JavaScript SDK extensively.
If you want to get a head start with it, here's the URL for the documentation site for the JavaScript AWS SDK.