S3 is a monster in AWS,
often rivaling EC2 in its ubiquity across the cloud provider.
The reasons for its popularity are the reliability,
speed, and ease of use that it has, but there are some automated aspects of
the service that make it even more useful for applications.
Two of those features are versioning and lifecycle events.
Versioning allows you to store multiple iterations of the same object
in case you need to access a previous revision.
This can be configured at the bucket level and applies to creating,
deleting, or modifying.
When a file is created, it becomes the current and only version of that file.
If you upload a new file with that same key,
the new upload becomes a current version,
and the original is retained with a unique version ID.
If you then delete the file,
it shows as deleted, but you can always get the older versions
of that file. As a simple bit that can be flipped on a bucket,
versioning is tremendously useful.
The only downside is the cost of keeping multiple versions for each file.
Each version of a file is charged the exact same as the file itself.
So depending on how often a file is replaced or deleted,
this can multiply your S3 costs quite a bit.
One way of managing those S3 costs, not only for versioning, but also for normal
usage, is by configuring lifecycle events for your bucket.
A lifecycle event allows you to set certain rules for what to do
with an object in your bucket once a certain number of days has
passed. One lifecycle event you can trigger is to move an object to
a lower cost type of storage.
For instance, you can say that once a file has been in S3 for 5 days,
move it to either S3 Infrequent Access storage or Glacier storage.
Both offer much cheaper costs for files that don't
need to be accessible quickly.
You can use this option for previous versions of files as well.
This means you can move them to Glacier and offset the cost
of having versioning on your S3 buckets.
The other convenient lifecycle event is expiration,
which allows you to delete files once they've
existed for a given number of days.
As with moving objects, you can apply rules to only affect previous versions,
permanently cleaning out older versions once they've been
retained for a certain amount of time.
Using both of these features can add to the robustness and usefulness of
S3 as the ultimate storage utility. In the next clip, let's get started by creating our first S3 bucket.