This course is designed to not only teach you how
to be an amazing AWS developer,
but also to help you complete the AWS Developer Associate exam.
The exam tests your knowledge of AWS and the many different
services, options, and problems that you encounter in the
process of developing on the platform.
The content of the exam is updated every few years, so while I can't
make any assurances that this course will contain everything you'll
need for the exam whenever you take it,
I am covering each topic as if you'll be tested on it.
The current AWS Developer Associate exam contains all multiple choice questions.
Typically, each question will focus on a single service and ask about topics,
service specifics, or service limits.
There are also questions about debugging certain problems and giving
architecture recommendations based on use cases.
There is no real way to know which services will be on the exam,
but the core services of AWS like EC2, S3, and DynamoDB
are almost guaranteed to be on the exam.
I've also seen service is like SQS, Route 53, and
Elastic Beanstalk to name a few.
Bottom line,
the more you work with and learn about AWS, the easier the test will be for you.
I recommend watching all of the courses in the AWS certified developer path
here on Pluralsight, and then continue building more projects. If there is
a service you aren't very familiar with, it wouldn't be a bad idea to build
something just to give it a shot.
In addition,
I've created a course called Demystifying the AWS
Certified Developer: Associate exam, which serves as a great intro to the exam.
The course covers the exam format,
how to study, which resources to use, and what the
day of the exam will look like.
I recommend watching it after you've completed the AWS certified developer path to put you on the best footing for the exam.