There aren't many limits when it comes to SNS or CloudWatch alarms.
This is mostly due to their simple operations.
CloudWatch does have a few more than SNS,
so let's take a look at the limits that do exist.
One restriction to be aware of with SNS topics is the
allowable characters in a name.
Only alphanumeric characters, hyphens, and underscores are allowed.
Unfortunately, emojis aren't supported.
Amazon really needs to get on it though.
CloudWatch has a limit of five actions that can take place per alarm.
This is a hard limit and can't be changed.
If you need more actions,
you could create a new CloudWatch alarm with the same metrics,
but that might end up being pretty messy.
In addition, a CloudWatch alarm period can only be a maximum of a day.
Remember the period is used to decide whether the alarm should fire or not.
If you're looking for more lengthier time frames than a day,
then CloudWatch is probably not the best solution to make those evaluations.
The last restriction is that even though CloudWatch does have
a mechanism for creating custom metrics,
you are restricted by the metrics that AWS makes available.
For instance,
if we wanted an alarm created whenever Zepto the hamster
came in sixth place three times in a row,
we'd have to look for another place to figure that out.
We all know Zepto is a winner though, and that would never happen,
so maybe this is just a moot point.
And that's it for limits and restrictions.
In the next clip,
I want to give you a guide for cleaning up everything we've created in this course.