In order for us to utilize a bunch of AWS services together,
we need an application to work with.
For this course,
I provided a demo web application project that we'll
modify to make the most of AWS.
Here's the demo app called Hamster Ball Fantasy League.
This site features a make believe league of hamsters
racing each other in hamster balls.
The site is a single‑page application built with React and Redux.
The back‑end application is built with Node and the hapi web application
framework. With HBFL, you can look at individual hamster details to see how
they've been faring, look at race details to see what place each hamster
came in, and also look at the leader boards to see how each user is ranked
based on their favorite hamsters.
If you log into the application,
you can get access to your own data and can pick and choose
which hamsters you want to represent you in the leader boards.
You can only favorite three at a time.
There are some behind the scenes controls in this configuration panel that
let you reset the race results and start them again.
These are all make believe, randomly generated results,
so each time you run the simulation, you'll get a different outcome.
See if you can make it to first place.
This application is going to utilize a multitude of different
services to provide some robust capabilities for users.
Starting in the next module, we'll get this application running in EC2 and see how it feels when it's served from the cloud.