History buckets are great for storing all types of objects, pictures,
videos, text files, you name it.
It's particularly nice for static assets for websites,
and that's what we'll be using it for.
We'll be using the file upload‑s3‑objects.js, so open that in your code editor.
This file has a lot of precompleted code in it mainly because I didn't want you
to bother with loading files from the file system.
As usual, we'll just target some relevant operations to complete.
Start out by entering your region on line 5.
On line 9, replace the bucket name string with whatever name you used to
create a bucket in the last clip, just the string is fine.
The next few lines are where the code actually runs.
A helper function is called that gets all the files in your public folder of
the demo project, then the upload‑ S3‑objects function is called with those
files, so let's go ahead and implement that function.
This function will be a little different than usual because our SDK
function has to be called for each file. For that reason, we'll build
our params function in 2 parts, once on line 16 for the properties that
are common for all files and then make a fresh copy with the unique
file params on line 19.
So on line 16, declare the params const object.
We'll need to know which bucket to upload to so add the bucket property
with the value as the bucket name function argument.
The next property is ACL,
similar to the property we added when we created the bucket.
This ACL is specific to the file that's being uploaded, and since we
want the files we upload to be exposed to all users,
enter the string public‑read here and that's all the common params. On line
21, we're mapping over each element of the files array, and ultimately,
getting an array of promises back. On line 22, were copying the params
object and adding a few more parameters.
The first of these will be added on line 23 with the property key, body.
This will be the actual file contents, which are
available in the file.contents property.
The next property is key,
which is the object key identifier. We can use the file name
for that found on the property file.name.
The next property will be different for each file and its content type.
This should match whatever file is being accessed.
So I've created a helper function called helpers.getContentType. Call that
function and then pass into it the file.name value and the helper function
will return the correct ContentType based on the file extension. And all
that was a very convoluted way of finally getting to a params object, but
now it's complete. On line 29, let's upload the object to S3. Call the
s3.putObject function.
The first argument will be newParams,
which we declared on line 22, and the next argument is our callback
function with err and data arguments. As usual, if there is an err
object, call reject with that err argument, and otherwise, call resolve
with the data argument. On line 36, all of the individual file upload
promises are called and return so we've completed this file now. Move
over to your command line.
We do need to build the project once so that the
JavaScript in CSS files are generated.
Run the command npm run build, this will run
webpack to compile all of the assets.
And once it's complete, we can upload the files,
So execute the command node upload‑s3‑objects.js.
This operation may take a little longer depending on your
upload speed, but once it's complete,
you'll see the E tags for each file output in an array.
Our files are now in S3, but we aren't using them yet.
We need to update our asset references in the demo project source code.
Switch over to the AWS console and go to the S3 dashboard, click into the
bucket we created, and select any one of the files here,
such as application.min.js. In the Overview tab,
there is a link property at the bottom.
We really just want part of that for our purposes, and that's everything
in the link until the file name. This will be the part of the path that
we need to add to our asset references.
We only have two places in our application where we need to modify the path
for the assets, the first is in the handlers/template directory and the
fileindex.html. On line 5, were importing a style sheet,
and right now it's referencing public/stylesheet.css. Remove the public part
of that path and paste in what you got from the S3 object.
Your path should look something like this.
Now on line 11, were bringing in the JavaScript, so again,
remove public and paste over that path.
The other place that we need to modify the path is in the
util folder and the file is assets.js.
At the very top of the file,
there is a base const being created and it should have public right now. You can
remove that completely and paste the S3 URL that you have.
Just make sure that there is no slash at the end so that the final path for
those images is created correctly. In the next clip, we're gonna look at some limits that you may run into with EBS and S3.