In this module,
we looked at a few different ways to deliver content to your users.
CloudFront finds its way into most web projects,
but S3 static hosting is a little more of a special use tool these days.
Let's recap what we covered in this module.
We started by discussing CloudFront invalidations and
why you might not want to use them.
Then we created a CloudFront distribution with all of those parameters.
Next,
we moved on to S3 static websites and set one up
based on our existing S3 bucket.
And finally,
we looked at the few limits concerning CloudFront. In the next module,
we're going to look at interservice communication inside AWS. Both Simple
Queue Service and Kinesis Streams provide ways for services to decouple and communicate in an asynchronous manner.