While SNS is powerful and quite useful, when coupled with CloudWatch alarms,
the true potential of real‑time notification is realized.
There are an endless number of uses for both services, so I hope this
module has inspired you to try out things with each.
Let's take a look at what we covered in this module.
We started by creating an SNS topic.
Then we made an SNS subscription with that topic and your mobile number.
Next we modified our app to send notifications to the topic and
ultimately our mobile phone when race results were finished.
Then we created a CloudWatch alarm and hooked it up to notify
us through the SNS topic.
Finally,
we looked at some of the few limits on SNS and CloudWatch
alarms. And we've reached the end of this course, AWS
Developer: Designing and Developing.
I sincerely appreciate you taking this journey with me to
learn more and more about AWS. At this point,
you're in a good place to start doing some damage in AWS. Find a
personal project or a side project at work that allows you to try out
some of the services discussed in this course, and consider finishing
the other courses in the AWS Developers Certification path to prepare
to master the AWS Developer Associate Certification exam. Again, my name is Ryan Lewis, and thank you for watching this course.