Hello welcome back to the course on deep natural language processing in today's tutorial we're going
to look at how the sequence to sequence and models are trained.
We were talking about the architecture.
And so this is what we've come up with that this is our picture.
What an encoder decoder which reasonable to record neural networks our inputs are fed in.
And then once we have our inputs here then what happens is the decoder starts decoding the values and
the city values back into the decoder as their video.
Now the difference between training and actually apply is that in this case this is the end result.
This is what we want that after our network has been trained once we feed in the sense that is Herrell.
Hello Carol chikin if you're back in Oz once we get in the sentence then we get this as an output.
Yes I'm back end of sentence.
Now we're going to this is the end result.
Now we're going to look at training.
So for training we're going to look at a different set this is going to take one of the sentences from
a different like will take a different email.
And in this case we will already have the full response that was provided in that case.
So this is how it works.
The email was like the recipe I sent you last week and the actual response that for instance this case
I sent like this is hypothetical.
It's never happened but if I had said the response would have been yes it was great and of sense hypothetically.
So if it was good if it was a good rest.
So here we've got.
Did you like that.
And so on and so on.
So that recipe that I said you I said last week end of sentence.
So that's our inputs to the model that's out in.
And then for the decoder we already know that.
So the difference why I highlighted this in red is because we didn't know this.
And the model generated in the training part we actually know the end result and now that will allow
us to train the model.
That's what we're going to look at now.
So here you can see that there is a lot more letters a lot more happening.
So here we've got use We've got double use We've got you twos double twos and these and so in different
literature you might find different notations which is going to stick with this one.
And basically those represent the parameters of our network such as weights such as the weights of the
neural network that's we need two of.
So basically we need to update these parameters through our our training in order for the network to
learn from the training data from the training and how like what does that imply.
That's the main question we're going to answer.
So we're not going to go into the detail of the mathematics or on what weights are where what these
parameters mean and so the main key is we want to get the intuition behind those who want to listen.
What does that exactly mean.
And so there are two main points that we're going to look at.
First one the main one is one that question is like what does it mean that the network is going to be
lower.
Well let's look at it.
So once we get in this sentence or this e-mail says Did you like that recipe that I said last week end
of sentence.
Then the network through training was going to happen in an iterative process going to look at the different
options that you can spit out.
So for instance you will start learning OK what work can I we know the correct board is the correct
pursers word it is yes.
But the network actually has 20000 different options to pick from 20000 different words.
And so through the process of back propagation this network this sequence to sequence model is going
to make sure that the probability of getting the word yes is the highest.
So it's going to update the weights of the parameters of the network in such a way that when the word
yes comes up it will have the highest probability so that indeed it is yes.
Then what what happens next is it moves on to the next where this part of the network is considered
done and then now given that the output here is yes.
And this information is passed on our way here in this information is passed on between this segment
of the Edric and this segment and we're feeding back the value yes into our layer of neurons.
Now we want the output to be it.
This we know that this is the final output that has to be or place number two.
So the network given that this is the input and given that the first word is yes is going to aim to
maximize the chances of or the probability that it or the like is going to maximize the probability
all the word it for some or two.
So it's going to update itself.
It's going to like through the process of stochastic radiation and back propagation.
It's like.
This this error is going to be back later and it is going to update itself in order to maximize the
score that is assigned to the word it in this case out of 20000 words.
Once that is done you move on and will do the same thing for the third place.
Given that we have that input the first word is yes the second one is it it will maximize what you want
about this for now.
Ill maximize the score that is assigned to the word was.
So again backwardation and so on.
And this is we just look at one example as you know in neural networks there there's going to be like
tons of training data tons of data is going through there.
It's like going through every one of them is multiple abox many many many airports it's all happening
like and they're very true to Prose's and the network is adjusting itself to match the match all the
inputs and outputs and so therefore it looks very simple but in reality these are all layers of neurons
and it can actually have more even more levels.
So it could be a deeper network as we saw before.
And so is because it's not that simple.
There is room for it to adjust its weights to accommodate all different options of input e-mails and
outputs.
Answers that were sent.
So the goal for the network is to make sure that it can model the logic and behavior that was observed
in the emails so that like it looks at an email it understands the meaning behind it and then it creates
a response and that should be in line with all the training it has.
So that's how it goes like one by one because that and the other thing.
The second important thing that we need to observe here is that the Wace So a natural question that
you might have is.
OK.
So we've trained up this network for all that say in this case we have a question of 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
9 10 11 words including the question mark plus us 12 and 12 here and then 1 2 3 4 5 on Outwood.
And so this is kind of like the The question this question is related to the fact that we have variable
input and variable outputs.
What ear.
So this looks like a very specific natural 12:5 What if we had 20 and you know what if we like what
if we have 20 here and then were and the response that the net generates is going to be like three words.
So how is it.
It's not ready for that right.
It feels like it's only trained up to work of 12 and 5.
What how can it work with variable.
Like how can a candidate even explore options like a can explore emails that have a different slant
to anything seen before and responses that have might have a different than anything seen before.
The answer is yes.
And the reason for that is as you can see the weights they are actually the same as you go through the
network as you go through.
Like if you add on more parts to the network you add on another like we have more than 12 here if you
add on or remove what will happen is just like it replicates itself every element here has the same
parameters you want everyone here to to an output you have these.
So basically every time like even if you add more more like say you didn't come up end of sentence here
it just kept going.
You'd add more and more and more so that basically means like whatever is trained during the training
process you will have all these parameters and then you'll have one w want you to delve into the.
And then basically that is going to be those that are going to be the foundations of this sequence in
sequence model and regardless of how big it is likes bigger or small is just going to be recreated.
We would have a problem if every time you add a new segment you know like it has its own weights it
has its own parameters.
But in this case because it's replicated we don't care about that.
That means that these these weights are going to be trained through the normal process of backwardation.
That's a great design.
And then regardless of how long.
So however long they are we're training the same thing however long the output is going to be using
those values or those weights that we trained up.
So there we go that's how the sequence the sequence network is trained.
Very similar to any sort of back propagation just the standard back progression and stochastic gray
in the sense that we know about and though the only concepts new concepts are that you know with the
variable and variable inputs and outputs and that is already taken into account so all we had to have
a look at is how does it actually take into consideration the different responses that we have to the
DUPERE emails.
So I hope you enjoy this tural and I'll see you next time.
Until then enjoy the natural language processing.