Hello and welcome to part two building the sector.
Merrill eventually we're getting there and that is in this part that we're going to start using tensor
flow to build the architecture of the.
But it is the architecture of the sectors like Meral which is at the heart at the core of the chapbooks.
So in the previous part we made a lot of for loops.
Now I guess you are an expert in four loops and now in this part you're going to become an expert in
another python technique which is functions we're going to make a lot of functions in this part because
these are going to be the functions that will define the architecture of the sector PSEC model.
So actually we're going to make one function purgatorial and the function we're going to start with
right now is going to be a function that will create placeholders for the inputs and the target.
So what is a placeholder and why do we need to create it.
That's the first question we will answer right now.
So intense a flow all variables are used in tensors.
Tensors are like an advanced array more advanced than an empire array which is of a single type and
that allows fastest computations in the deep neural networks.
So we need to go from the number of arrays the class Signum by race to tensors.
But that's not all because then in terms of flow all the variables used in tensors must be defined as
what we call tensor flow placeholders.
So basically that's an even more advanced data structure that can contain tensors and also other features.
So that's always the first thing we must do when starting to build a deep neural network with tons of
flow we need to create some placeholders for the inputs and the toilet.
And that's exactly what we're going to do right now but we're going to do it through a function that
we'll call model inputs.
And so inside this function we will create a placeholder for the inputs a placeholder for the targets
and then we will add a learning rate and even more hybrid parameters.
So in short we are creating this placeholders to be able to use these variables in the future training.
All right so let's define this function to define a function in Python.
We need to start with them.
Then we need to give a name to that function and we're going to call it model underscore inputs and
this function is not going to take any arguments because it will just directly take the input and output.
And for each of them convert them into placeholders into tensor flow placeholders so that's all good.
And let's go inside the function.
All right so we're going to start by creating some new variable that we're going to call inputs and
that will be this tensor flow placeholder containing the inputs.
And so to create a sense of placeholder Well first we need to call our sense of library which we can
get things to the shortcut we made which is T.F..
So we called sense of flow and from sense of flow we're going to get the place holder function that
is a function that can create placeholders for the input.
All right so now in this placeholder function we need to enter three parameters.
The first one is going to be the type of the data there are the inputs and remember that we converted
our input into unique integers and part 1 data preprocessing.
So the type that will choose here is going to be T.F. we need to call it from tensor of flow that int
32.
All right then next argument is going to be the dimensions of the matrix of the input data.
And since the inputs are the lists of the questions encoded into unique integers we can have a look
at it again sorting questions which you must understand are the inputs.
You can see that these inputs are lists of integers and therefore with the pairing we will get a two
dimensional matrix.
And that's why right now we need to specify this that it's a two dimensional matrix.
And to do this we're going to add here in brackets square brackets none and none.
That's a way to specify that our inputs are two dimensional matrix.
All right.
And then the last argument is just a name that we have to give to the input and we specify this with
the argument name equals and we can put in quotes and put I perfect.
So that creates the placeholder for our inputs.
All right.
And now we are going to do the same for the targets.
So I'm copying this because it's going to be almost the same.
I'm pasting now here I am replacing here inputs by targets and same we have to create a sense of flow
placeholder that will contain these targets data.
Then of course the target data is composed of integers because they correspond to the encoded integers
that encode the words or the answers.
Remember that answers are the targets.
And then we are going to compare the chat but answers to the real answers.
And that's how it will train itself to speak like a human and then Same same dimension for the matrix
of the toilet.
None none to say it's a two dimensional matrix.
And then of course we need to change the name of the input here by Target.
All right so perfect.
We have created placeholders for the inputs in the toilet and now we're going to create two more intensively
placeholders which are going to be simple ones one that will hold the learning rate which is a hyper
parameter and one that will hold the popular keep frob hyper parameter.
That's the way we call it.
And that is just a parameter used to control the dropout rate.
You know the dropout is the rate of the neurons.
You choose to override during one iteration in the training.
Usually the dropout rate is 20 percent so that you activate 20 percent of the neurons during the different
iterations of the training.
And so this key prob parameter for which we're going to create a placeholder will be used to control
this dropout rate because sometimes the drop out is too high.
So we will need to reduce it and sometimes it is too low so we will need to increase that.
And this will be done by the keeper of parameter.
All right so let's create these last two placeholders for the learning rate and keep prob..
So let's do this learning right first.
I'm going to place actually what we copied before.
Replace inputs here by L R then the learning rate is not an integer anymore but a float.
So float 32 then there is no matrix for such a hyper parameter because it's a simple value.
Therefore I'm going to remove this.
And we just need to specify a name for that which is going to be learning rate.
Let's do this learning rate and perfect.
All right then the final one the placeholder I'm going to copy this because this is going to be a float
as well but it's not going to be the learning rate it's going to be that keep prob parameters so you
will see this keep the parameter name everywhere on line you can find it on stack overflow.
There are some nice explanations you can find on the tense of the web site I think in a lot of good
pages.
Keep the parameter is the parameter that controls the drop out rate.
So placeholder flow 32 perfect.
And the name is not learning right but we can call it.
Well let's just call it keep PRUD keep this core problem.
All right.
And that's it.
Now we just need to return what this function is supposed return which is of course all these placeholders
and therefore I'm going to add here.
Return then inputs the placeholders for inputs then targets the placeholder for our target then are
the learning rate and keep prob the parameter that controls the dropout rates.
All right so perfect.
Congratulations you made your first functional use in terms of flow.
That's very important to do this and therefore now we're going to select this and execute our right
function created.
And now we'll move onto the next step until then.
And Jaideep an p.