Hello welcome to the course and deep natural language processing.
And in two days the story we're going to talk about the plan of attack.
We've got quite a diverse and involved intuition session coming up ahead.
Lots of concept to grasp so it will be good for us too.
At the start have a bird's eye view of the things that we're going to discuss.
All right.
Here's what we will learn in this section on intuition.
First of all we'll talk about the types of natural language processing this will lay the foundation
and we will discuss a Venn diagram which demonstrates this deep learning which is deep in our and shows
us where the sequence to sequence what lies in that diagram will keep coming up because it will be very
helpful for us to keep track of how we're progressing into the world of world of natural language processing.
Then we'll talk about classical versus a deep learning models.
Look at some actual examples of applications of a.p.
And there's also be useful just to show us that natural language processing is not limited simply to
chat boards.
It's actually covers a huge range of different applications and we'll see a couple of them here.
There will talk about entry into deep learning models and how they're different to enter in deep learning
models and what they're advantages and then we'll talk about the bag of words and our model.
We'll see two of its variations and this will help us gradually progress to the most advanced model.
The sequence sequence which will start discussing in the next tutorial in the secrecy was architecture.
This is the model that we're actually after.
This is what we're implementing in our chat.
Then we'll talk about the sequence of sequence training.
So it's intentionally placed in this order.
That first bit of architecture and we'll actually see it in action as if it was trained because that
will help us better understand what is is desired from the training and then it will be easier to cover
all the training afterwards.
And that's why they're in that order.
Then we'll talk about search decoding which is the way that the sequence secrecy secret architecture
actually comes up.
Wherefore the model comes up with the outputs that we want to see you know put the different.
Very subtle very very interesting conceptual approach here for research decoding.
And finally we'll talk about at mechanisms.
So this is an additional augmentation of the SEC to sec model which helps with a longer term memory
for the algorithm.
Again a very interesting and quite new concept.
And finally on top of all of that there's two Annexes.
Make sure to check them out.
Next one is artificial neural networks and to recurrent neural networks.
So we included these tutorials easily intuitions tutorials only from our deeper recourse.
And the reason that they're here is because you will need a good understanding of both of them.
Once you dive into them more deeper insight out of things on this course.
So for these Janis's you should make sure that you've covered them somewhere over here before you proceed
to see what sort of architecture you once you proceed you will need to know in an hour and ends and
LSD and which are covered in this part.
So the first couple of stressors What is your final piece.
But then once you go into these areas just make sure that you are familiar with Anand's and recurrent
neural networks because that will be the foundation of our discussion.
And there we go that's the plan of attack for the core intuition for this course.
I really look forward to seeing you on the tutorials.
And until next time enjoy natural language processing.