Hi everyone and welcome back.
This is going to be a quick video of since we're going be focusing on launching the model that we have
in the files.
Intenser board.
All right so quickly what content's or board do.
First of all tensor board is essentially a suite of visualization tools for our algorithm.
It can help us learn a lot about our data by projecting word embeddings into a 3-D space by performing
dimensionality reduction techniques such as principal component analysis.
With this we can see how our model has grouped the words together from our vocabulary.
So for example we can see the nearest neighbor in the embedding space for the words.
And here we have the example of centerboard.
We'll get to in a moment.
And if you want to have some further information about it you can visit the following sites such as
the tensor flow dot org programmers underscore guide slash summaries and tensor board and you can also
take a look at the programmer's guide related to embeddings because really and embedding is a mapping
from discrete objects such as words to vectors or real numbers.
All right.
So this is what we want to get first thing we want to do is open up a terminal.
I have one running right now.
So we're going to actually open a new one just for demonstration.
Let me enhance this so we can see a little better.
All right.
And what we want to do here is if you navigate to the files we are going to be launching the following
model.
Is the train model we want and you can find it if we go to the SEC to Sec.
It will be in models and train model.
We want to we'll keep that.
Just move that over here real quick.
I am working on Mac for reference.
We will use the following command the 10 surfboard log directory equals.
Now we want to use our model directory since we're using this when actually just pull it drop it in
and launch it.
And here we have it the following local localhost we have 6 0 6.
I'm going to pull it up.
Let's go to a local post 6 6 just double check your local host and we will be loading the tensor board
from our data from our train model right now.
It's computing the principle component analysis.
We'll let that load for a minute.
And there we go.
We have it.
And you can explore the options here.
It's just a great way to learn further about your data.
Take a look.
I found 13 tensors you can go into the customisations over here.
You can also let's let's zoom zoom in so far let's take a following word to gravity.
Zoom back out and let's see by word how it's Matt the nearest points in the original space.
And you can search it by the cow.
You can go to the neighbors adjust the parameters.
It just gives you a range of options to explore your data further.
Let's take another one.
Quickly let's go to correct now.
We have our different variations of words how they're maps they give correct corrected correctly incorrect
and you can kind of get an idea of the mapping or in general you know how the and LP these words how
important are the distinctions of differentiations between the two similar meanings or how these words
are mapped in general and how it can have an effect on our chap our model.
If you have the time take a look at this take a look at tensor board play around with the operations
the customisations and the options here.
Just because it's a great tool really working with any kind of algorithm if you can load it into centerboard
you're Green-Wood sensor flow.
It is a great tool to keep to explore your data further and get a better understanding.
All right.
If you have any questions at always please let us know be more than happy to discuss any information
related to the course and with that I will see you in the next video.