Hi everyone welcome back.
In this video we're going to be running the jackpot so let's jump straight into it.
And you have the files attached to this video.
So if you download the files unzip them.
You can also find them here.
If you go through the untrain modeled on zip it you can access the files that way as well but they are
attached to this lecture.
Now the first thing we want to do is we want to open a terminal.
All right we have a new terminal Actually I'm going to close it out since I was already in the directory.
I'm going to open a new terminal.
We also need our files.
This is the folder the entire folder.
In it we have this set to set chat by folder.
Now what we want to do if you're in the terminal prompt We want to go to that location so I'm going
to see a minute drag and drop into it and we're to enter that directory or that path.
And this is what we're looking for we want the set to sec dash chap.
We're looking to use the models Cornello movie dialogue train model the one that we can set the chap
up like that.
So we will be using that come in Python chat up my models slash Cornell movie dialogue slash train model
underscore V-1 slash best weight training checkpoint
and to go over that one more time.
So you see we have our path here will be the models.
Let's go to models.
Since we're in these two sec models Cornell movie dialogue train model V-1 and we want the best training
checkpoint.
And with that I'm going to close this make a little more clear.
Who is this we can run it.
Here we go.
It should initialize and load all khabar load the model
has a lot of weight.
And there we have it you are ready to start chatting with the chatbot.
So let's test out a few.
Hi good.
How are you.
And you can play around with the commands the conversation fantastic and really what we can do here
which makes it even more interesting is if you explore the commands you can actually set the being like
the penalty we can set it with the flag beam lag penalty equals pick a number.
Let's try to we can also set the max answer length and you can see here that the command shows you that
it was set to 2.
We can do the flag for Max answer length.
Let's try five.
These are just as an example.
You can go through the rest if you want to reset them to the default settings.
You will use the flag reset and you have it reset to the default settings and there you have it you
were able to converse with the chat but again play around with the commands.
Experiment with it try and implement new things.
Test the conversations.
It's a great way to learn with any model is just pure experimentation.
Also I almost forgot to mention if you want to train the model further you can actually pick up on resume
training.
Here you can find the instructions in the repository to resume the training model or an existing model.
You can run train pie with the model checkpoint path that's just for a reference if you ever want to
experiment with a further and try other data sets.
I know the core of your movie dataset is one of the go to but you can also think about using the Twitter
corpus the Reddit data set and any other one that you would like to test out on a last note.
Thank you to Abraham again for allowing us to use and explore this model.
If you guys come across any ideas implementations that you would like to discuss any questions about
this model please feel free to share them in the Q&amp;A.
And we would be more than happy to discuss them.
I hope that you have enjoyed this update.
I have taken away some information that you can use to improve your models further.
And with that we can wrap things up enjoy the jackpot.