Hello I'll come back to the course on deep natural language processing.
And today we're talking about classical versus deep learning models.
So let's have a look.
As we discussed about this diagram and on the left what the natural language processing models are overall
and the on the right we have that deep learning models or Also there overlap is that deep natural language
processing those are the very advanced types of natural language processing models which use deep learning
and then find at the bottom here we've got the sequence to sequence models which we'll be interested
in at the end.
And so I thought that this tutorial would be fun if we had a look at a comparison between a couple So
we'll look at a couple of examples from here.
We'll look at an example from here and then finally will image sequence sequence just to kind of lay
out the playing field so we know what we're dealing with and what types exist there because we could
definitely just jump into sequence to sequence and look at the most powerful things.
But then it would still be a mystery what our natural language processing models how the different deep
natural language processing was and how the different sequence sequence with applications and so on.
So let's have a look at a couple examples.
All right some examples we're going to have our diagram on the right and we're going to start going
through these examples one by one.
So number one is that if Alice rules or and this is a way that we used to create chat bots back in the
day.
So if Alce rules are located over here on our diagram in just the A.P. part and what they entail is
a huge list of possible questions and answers to those questions.
And so once somebody in the chat asks a question or we can identify that part of the sentence is the
question that we have proof it then we will give them the correct answer the answer that is associated
with that question.
But as you can imagine such mechanic is such a mechanical approach to answering questions or chatting
with people does not result in anything human like anything realistic and it results in something like
this rather where you have questions and then you have predetermined answers.
But people want something tailored to them something specific they are asking about something else that
doesn't fit into that list of questions and answers.
And just very quickly becomes a mess but that's how we use to create chapel's the next type or the next
natural language processing model.
We will look at.
It's called an audio frequency components analysis and it's used for speech recognition.
And since we're here so we're specifically looking like we're purposefully looking at different examples
and not just chat but we're looking at different applications so you can see that LP can be applied
to speech recognition.
And there used to be or still are algorithms that use non deep learning methods for speech recognition.
And one of them is audio frequency components analysis.
So in essence what happens is we look at the sound waves of somebody talking some proof chorded or real
time audio over human speech and then we try to identify what waveforms exist in there.
So in a very kind of simple way of explaining it let's have a look at.
For example here are the four year transformation and with God there are frequencies where there's this
like one of these He's going over there.
Of course this is this doesn't even look like human speech.
To be frank but the concepts say so like we look at what frequencies it can.
It consists of.
And then we compare them to like the pre recorded frequencies so we know that for instance certain certain
combination of frequencies means this type of word or this type of work and it's not just about the
frequencies of course it's it's much more complex than that but this is a very general overview of what
happens we look at the frequencies a certain mathematical approach.
This is the key point that we're not doing any neural confutation we're not creating neural networks
just doing mathematical calculations around the frequencies that we can observe comparing them to the
mathematical calculations we have in our library all pre analyzed frequencies and then we're matching
it up with finding what word a person is saying what question they're asking or what the sentence is
meaning.
And then that is how we recognize speech.
So there's another version of natural language processing which is in the green area.
Next one is the bag of words model which is used for classification of very very popular approach for
text analysis or natural language processing.
And what it does is basically it also sits in the end all the parts and just the green area.
Although as we will see further on it can see both in the green area and in the purple area over here.
But that's something for a later discussion.
What's the bag of words model does it is there is a bag of words.
And the way it works is you might have like lots of text for instance here we've got tutors or lectures
or examiners who marked grades who gave a pass or a failed grade to different papers or different assignments
that were submitted and then they also left the comment so somebody said great job and left a comment
or one meaning a past somebody said amazing work left to come out of one well done was really really
rich and one poor effort zero could have that better zero.
Try harder next time.
And so on.
And so from this what the bag awards model will do is it will put all these words into a bag and it
will remember so how often does the word grace come up with a one.
And how often does the word great come up with a zero.
This is again a very general explanation a very high level explanation of what happens.
But in essence this is the concept that it will look at the words and Ill look ill try to classify these
words will I.
Ill try to associate these words with either positive result or negative result in our case.
And so in this case like amazing would be most likely associate with both of you don't often see amazing
when you're trying to say when when the sentiment is negative when you try it when the person was trying
to say something like that the work wasn't well done or well would be associated with words like the
word work could be associated with both.
But then these other words they would be mostly associate you pass something like words like poor or
harder or who would have maybe would be associate zero.
And so then will remember that I'll keep these words in a bag and next time something comes up.
For instance somebody says Good.
Good job.
Keep keep it up or something.
Got it.
We'll analyze the words that are in that new sentence by pulling them out of the bag and looking at
them and understanding are they mostly associated ones or zeros.
And then I'll be able to predict they'll be able to classify the new new comments even without knowing
what the mark was pacified will be able to say based on the comment or they will say is it a pass or
fail.
So that's like a very simplistic application of the bag of words.
But there's another one.
OK.
OK so let's look at a deep natural language processing model.
And this one is going to be OK over here.
It's called convolutional neural networks for text recognition.
So they like the model we're going to be looking at further down is indeed a deep natural language processing
model.
But I always wanted to give an example of a different model so not not just the one that we looked at
but also a deep natural language processing model but a different one.
And when I came across is when we use convolutional neural networks for texture cognition and then for
classification.
And so if if you're familiar with conventional networks or even if you're not what they're used for
is a neural network that is used for mostly image recognition for like videos self-driving cars use
them to detect obstacles on roads people and so on.
Mostly it's used for image processing or video processing.
So it is very interesting to see how convolutional neural networks can actually be used for text processing
and the way it works is it's these words are transformed into a matrix and that's done through an operation
called embedding of words.
And then once they're in a matrix the same principles as kind of solution as we were apply for images
and coalitional neural networks are applied.
So there's a convolution operation going through these images then they're they're called Max gold I
mean pulled some pole.
And then they're flattened and then you know then we have the prediction.
So we won't go into detail right now of how convolution convolutional operations work.
There's lots of tutorials out there and so on and it's just not in the scope of the score because in
this course we'll be looking at mostly recurrent neural networks which is RNA in a different type.
But I just wanted to put it out there that you could technically use convolutional neural networks for
text recognition just as you would do with images and very interesting concept.
That was one of the earlier ones that was explored and then we moved on to recurrent neural networks
as we see down the track.
So there we go that's another one.
And then finally the main model that we'll be looking for working with sequence the sequence has many
many many different applications as we see down.
And that's the one that's over there.
So I'll give you a short preview of what's coming up.
Looks something like this and don't worry it might look very complex right now but in a couple of tutorials
from here will be very very comfortable with what's going on here and how this whole construct is working
and why it's called sequence to sequence and what exactly it allows us to do.
So there we go.
I hope you enjoy this quick overview and comparison of the different types of models and different applications
that they have.
And we'll continue next and I look forward to seeing you there.
And until then enjoy deep and O.P..