Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
After making the clean text function we were going to apply it on all the questions and all the answers
to effectively clean their attacks.
So we're going to start as you can see with the questions in the first code section and then we'll take
care of the answers in the next section.
So let's start with the questions.
So it's actually going to be very easy.
We're going to make a new list that will contain all the clean questions and therefore I'm going to
introduce here this new variable that I'm going to call clean on those core questions and that will
be this new list of all the questions that will be cleaned by the can in text function.
So we're going to initialize it as an empty list with the pair of square brackets.
And then of course comes naturally a for loop.
So for now try to guess what I'm going to type try to make Actually the whole story without me.
So well we just want to get our questions and clean them.
So naturally the loop variable is going to be question that arbitrary for you to choose but we're going
to take the questions in the loop and we're going to get them from our questions list that we created
2 tutorials ago.
So we take our questions list that contains the non cleaned version and we're going to take each of
the questions inside these questions and clean them one by one.
And so now we were ready to answer the for loop and inside.
Well simply what we're going to do is apply to clean text function that we made in the previous Statoil.
We're going to clean the question that we're dealing with right now.
The loop and then almost over we're going to append this clean question because this is what is returned
by the clean text function.
We're going to append this clean question to naturally our clean questions list and then we go for all
the question in the non cleaned questions of the questions list.
We're going to clean these questions and we're going to append them one by one to our clean questions
list containing the clean questions.
All right and that's it.
Well that's basically over.
We get our list of clean questions.
And now we're going to do the same for the answers.
And the good news is that it's going to be almost the same we will basically need to replace questions
by answers.
So I'm pasting that here.
I'm going to introduce a new name for the list of answers which will be clean answers naturally.
And so for all the answer in answers I'm going to clean these answers first and I'm going to send them
to my clean answers list.
All right.
Perfect So we're done with our two four loops to create the two new lists of clean questions and clean
answers.
All right so now let's have a look.
We're going to execute these two code sections here.
Make sure to execute the clean text function before if it wasn't done.
And now let's execute this.
There we go.
It takes a little time because it has to make this for loop over all the questions and all the answers.
But here we go.
Now they're ready and so let's have a look.
So we get our questions answered questions and answers.
So as you can see can we make this quick.
First the capital C is now a lower case.
Can we make this quick.
The question mark was removed and same.
Everything in lower cases then as you can see the dashers are gone here.
And let's have a look at the answers we'd start we would start then the dashes are gone dashes are gone.
And if you scroll down you will actually see even more changes like.
OK dash dash.
You're going to.
OK.
No dash.
You are going to.
Well as you can see they were cleaned properly.
We can clean them even more for example.
We can even replace the apostrophe as by I guess but I wouldn't do this because let's go.
I think it's fine to leave it as.
Let's go.
We could also remove the exclamation mark but maybe that helps with the sentiment analysis.
I didn't want to remove it but feel free to experiment you know natural language processing is a lot
of experimenting.
We are going to train our Jedward several times we're going to tweak the parameters we're going to try
to improve it.
And in the end I will actually give you several chat but with some pre-trained morals and some saved
waits for the neurons so that you can get the best one if you need it for your business or your personal
project.
But anyway the data processing phase is also an artist's job.
All right so that's it.
Our questions are clean our answers are clean.
Now we're going to move onto the next step which will be to remove the none important words that is
the non frequent words you know that each word is going to have its own color Culham its own encoding
and therefore if we keep all the words of the corpus there are going to be hundreds of thousands of
them and it will be very difficult for the training to take place in a reasonable amount of time.
So that's why we have to do it and we'll do this from the next tutorial.
Until then Id been I'll be.