In cotland you can use type parameter constraints to limit what types can be used for a generic type.
For example let's say we wanted to write a function that converts every number in the collection to
an int and prints the result.
So let's do our first crack at this function.
We're going to use what's in this main function in a minute.
So we'll say Fanti convert 2 in.
And this is going to take a collection.
So we'll say that it takes a collection and a list of T.
We just saw this in the last video and then we'll say for Nahm in collection line and we'll open up
expression here now.
Got to end.
And of course I need the double quotes.
OK so you're going to see here that we're getting an error.
Now why is it happening.
Well because there is no guarantee that the collection we pass into this function contains numbers.
I mean we're saying that we'll accept a list of any type.
So we could pass this function a list of strings according to this function signature.
We could pass it a list of employee or a list of cars.
Now we don't want to have to write a convert to it for every type of numeric object.
We don't want to have a version for float and double and shorten byte.
So what do we do.
Well in this case we can restrict the generic type to the number class because the number class is the
parent class for all of the numeric types and also the number class declarers the two int function that's
were the two int function lives.
So if we say that we only want to accept a list of numbers then this will work.
And that way the function will accept a list of number or it will accept a list of instances that are
subclasses of number.
Because if are subclasses of number we know that they're going to have the two function.
So when we want to do that we specify the restriction as part of the type parameter declaration so we're
going to come over here.
We're going to say we only want to accept number here for this function and the moment we do that our
error goes away.
So now we're going to call this function with a list of ints and a list of shorts.
So let's go ahead and use the collections will say convert to it and since I know we probably wouldn't
want to do that in reality.
Convert to in shorts and we'll see that we're not getting any errors here at all and if we run
we'll get our ints printed out that have been converted even though they don't need to be and are shorts
printed out.
Let's do a list of float.
Just to show that that will work.
So floats and we'll have to say float here just as we have to say short up here if we hadn't said explicitly
here that we wanted a short.
We would have gotten a list of ints and if we don't say float here we're going to get going to get a
list of doubles so and I'll just say one hundred point three and minus four five eight point forty three.
And we got to put the F at the end here.
OK.
And then I'm going to change this to float because it really doesn't make sense for us to be calling
a convert in function on a list of ints and let's run you will see that these have now been converted
to integers so they no longer have the decimal places.
So that's how you can restrict the time that you'll set for t.
You just specify an upper bound right here as part of the type parameter declaration.
So before when we had this what was the upper bound.
Well in that case the upper bound was any question mark because any question mark is essentially at
the top of the Katlin object hierarchy.
So nullable any every class descends from nullable any.
But of course now that we've changed that we're back at the situation where well you can pass strings
you can pass employees you can pass anything so this no longer works.
So we'll add number back in.
And now if we have a list of strings foules strings equals a list of 1 to 3 if we try to call our convert
to ints on this
you'll see that we can't because it doesn't satisfy the upper bound.
Now what if you want a function with more than one upper bound.
In that case you use the where clause.
So let's write a function that accepts items that are dependable and that implement char sequence so
will say Fanti append animals except in Item one state.
Item 2 this type T and now we want to restrict this to instances that are of type char sequence and
dependable.
So we'll say where t can be char sequence
and it has to be spendable as well.
And then we'll say print line result is.
And I'll open up an expression here must say Item 1 dot append and item 2.
So here we have two upper bounds char sequence in append of all we need char sequence because the dependable
interface works with Char sequences.
So let's call the function with a couple of string builders which Because string builder satisfies the
two upper bounds.
I'm going to comment out the convert to in call here and we'll say append string builder
string one dot string builder string to run that
and we'll see that our two string builder values have been appended together.
Now you can have a bunch of interfaces in there when where clause because it's possible for a class
to implement more than one interface.
But obviously you can only have one class here because otherwise nothing will ever satisfy your where
clause.
So we can't do something like say where T is a short and t is an end to t is because there is nothing
that say short and an end and a double etc..
Ok so how does null lability play into all of this as we know Scotland is quite concerned with no liability.
Now when we use t by itself without any upper bounds does t mean the non-global type only.
Well as we saw it no it actually it's the opposite T except supposed nullable and non nullable types
he can remember that I said just a second ago that when you don't specify an upper bound the upper bound
is actually.
Any question mark.
It's nullable any.
So that means that we should be able to pass nullable types to our functions.
So let's try it out.
Let's change our lists to nullable shorts and nullable floats.
And now of course here we are going to have to change it to nullable question mark and then we'll also
have to say here that that might be no.
But if we go back to the print collection function that we had in the last video so.
So we'll say fine t print collection.
And we were accepting a collection of typed lists T.
And then we had that loop that we were doing for item in collection print line item.
Now we're not specifying an upper bound So this is accepting anything.
Any question mark.
And so now if we have a list of strings let's say or in fact any of our collections we can call this.
So we'll say print collection shorts.
That works.
Print collection strings.
And that works.
Now this short list is now a nullable short list and shorts is non-negotiable strings because we haven't
specified a type so the default is going to be non nullable.
And both of those can call this function no problem.
I'll just comment out to convert to calls and then we'll run
and we'll see that the values of those two lists are printed so if we want to limit print collection
to only non nullable types how would we do that.
Well think about this for a minute if we wanted to restrict the types that we'll take.
How do we do that while we do it the same way we're doing it down here except this time we'll say that
we will take any.
So in this case for saying we just want non-knowledge all types will take any non-bailable type.
And now of course we're going to get an error up here because our shortlist is a nullable list.
So if you want to restrict a function to accepting only no nullable type this is the way you can do
it.
OK so let's just take a moment to talk about what happens with generics under the covers in Katlin now
in Javid generics are a compile time aid.
They help the compiler to know what types are expected and therefore they help to catch errors and they
also help because we don't have to do as much typing.
But when a Java application runs it doesn't have any of the generic information.
And that's called type eraser.
So that information is erased.
So at compile time we might declare an array list of big decimal but at runtime all the JVM will see
is an array list.
It doesn't see the generic type.
So generics are basically syntactical element that help the compiler and US now because the generics
don't make it through to the application that the JVM runs.
You can't use them to do type checking.
So let's switch back to our job of file for a minute so that you can see what I'm talking about here.
And I just realized I did not create the java file in here so let me do that quickly.
I created it in our last project so I'll create another package we'll call it Academie learn programming
dot the Java code.
And then in here we'll create a Java class that will just call.
I guess generics I'll call it job in Erich's
and I'll say public sabbatical boy name string args.
OK so let's do the following I'll say boolean V equals list and I need a list first so list string and
we'll call this strings equals new new array list
and we'll say strings dot add.
Hello.
That's what we had last time.
So now we'll say Boullion B equals Liszt's is in strings rather is an instance of list string and you're
going to see that we're going to get an error and it says illegal generic type for instance of we can't
do it.
And the reason we can't do it is because the JVM doesn't understand generics so there's no way it can
check at runtime whether strings is a list of string.
The best it can do is to check that strings is a list.
So if we knock that off now at all times now it will say Yeah OK I can I can figure that out but I can't
figure this out.
I just don't know.
Generics are a compile time feature.
So in Java the best we can do is to check whether an instance is a list as you just saw.
So this here is the best we can do when it comes to type checking.
Now let's go back to Catlin and you might be expecting me to say and Katlin it works differently but
of course Katlin runs on the JVM.
So in CANTLIN the generics are also a compile time feature generics don't make it into the compiled
application so at runtime all the JVM knows is that if it has a collection then it has a collection.
It can distinguish between the collection classes like it can tell if you have a in an array list versus
a hash map etc. but it doesn't know that at compile time we said that this list should only contain
strings.
It has no way of knowing that.
Now I said that in Codlin we have to use generics with collections.
We can't leave them off.
So how do we use the is operator with collections.
Can we use it in cotland.
Of course C is operator is the equivalent of instance of.
So let's try out the is operator in Katlin.
Let's try to track the type of the strings list and I'll comment this out.
So we're not getting an error.
So we'll say if the list is a list of string Shuli we call that strings if strings is lists of string.
Then we'll print line.
This list contains strings.
And look at that.
We don't get an error.
And if we run
we'll see.
This list contains strings.
So I'm guessing that in this case the compiler is doing the check at compile time and under the covers.
This isn't even generated to the byte code because the compiler can see that it's always going to evaluate
to true.
So there's no need to actually do this check at runtime.
This can be figured out at compile time and that's why we're not getting an error.
I haven't looked at the bite code so I don't know this for sure but that's my guess.
I'm guessing that the compiler is doing that type of optimization.
So we need to try it with a variable that isn't of type list.
Let's create another list and assign it to a variable of type any.
So rather than saying well yeah strings we know it's a list of strings the compiler already inferred
that that's try to trick it now and say Now list any of type any equals list of us TR wan as TR too.
And now let's check the tape for this.
So we'll say if list any is a list of string and right away boom we can no longer do it cannot check
for instance of Eraste type list of straying.
So up here the compiler will know at compile time that we have a list of string here.
It can't guarantee anything so no optimisation can be made it would have to check this at runtime and
it can't and that's why we're getting the error now.
So just as in Java generic types are erased as far as the runtime goes.
OK so let's try doing what we did and then we'll just knock off the generic type.
Remember in Java this works.
So the JVM can at least tell us if we have a list.
Let's do that.
And you'll see we get an error in saying that it wants to type argument because remembering Cartland
you have to specify the generic type.
It's inforced in cotland.
So how are we going to do this.
How can we even check if something is a list.
Well the error message gives us the answer in this case it says use a list and the angle brackets star.
If you don't want to pass type arguments and in this case we can't pass a type argument.
In fact in this context using the Star or asterisks like this is called The Star projection syntax.
It sort of acts like a wild card.
So if we go star like that it works and then we can say print line.
Yes this is a list.
Thank you star projection.
And if we run
we'll see.
Yes this is a list.
Thank you star projection.
So at runtime as I've been saying several times now the JVM is capable of looking at a variable and
comparing it against last.
However it cannot do this it can't do that because the best it can see at run time is list.
So how does this affect the ads and the ads question mark operators because you can use generics with
them to as follows.
We could say well we just start production back in here so that we're not going to get compile time
errors.
We can say if list any is a list
print line.
This list contains strings.
Val essed your list equals the list any as list as string.
And then we'll say print line TR list one dot replace That's her place.
S are wids string.
So here what we're doing is we're saying we're checking whether list any contains a list and if it does
we're using casting here to say then we want to use list any as a list of string.
And then we want to go ahead and treat the first element the second element rather in SDR list as a
string.
So this is all fine and dandy Let's run
and now down here we've replaced this is as TR too in the original list and we've replaced as TR strings
so we're seeing string too because we're doing that for the second element and printing out the result
so that all works great.
But what would happen if we change list any to a list that is not a list of string.
So let's see what will happen if we do that because remember we said that the JVM can't tell at runtime
what type of list it has.
All the best it can do is figure out that it has a list.
And so what we're checking for here isn't that we have a list of string.
We have a list of anything.
And then we just happened to know that we have a list of strings so we're going ahead and saying OK
fine we know we assigned a list string list in here so just go ahead and use it as a string.
This is going to pass etc. But now let's reassign list any.
And I think I declared as a vowel so I'm going to change it to a VAR and right here I'm going to say
list any equals list of.
And let's give it a list of ints.
So let's run now.
And there you go.
We get a class cast's exception Javid not language.
Integer cannot be cast to Javid out Lang string.
Now the compiler tried to warn us about this.
If I switch to messages here which is gives us the result of the compile so the compiler issued a message
on it for line 25 we're doing the casting and it's saying it's an unchecked cast because we didn't actually
verify it here that we have a list of string.
We just verified that we have a list.
And as we can see it can be of any type.
So that's the compiler's way of saying I'm letting this cas through because maybe list any will contain
a list of strings.
So the compiler lets the CAS goes through but it warns us about it and says I'm going to let this go
because it's possible at runtime that list any will contain a list of strings of course it doesn't.
But it's going to let it go through but it warns us it says you're doing something you really shouldn't
be doing and it's possible that you're going to get a class cast exception at runtime but you can cast
this away.
So at least you can check what type of collection you have.
You can use as and the same thing goes with as question mark for nullable types.
So you can cast.
You can cast to a specific generic type but every time you do that depending on what's on the left hand
side it's possible that you might be opening the door to a class cast exception and the compiler will
actually warn you about that.
So that's the best that the compiler can do in this situation.
OK so that's all I wanted to discuss in this video in the next video.
We're going to talk about something called reified parameters.
I'll see you there.