Alright, so now it's time to practice
what you've learned and so we're going
to go through a series of small steps in
the form of challenges and step one is
up on the screen here, this is the only
challenge that will have a slide, because
after this, we'll be in IntelliJ. So this
will be a breeze for those of you who
are familiar with IntelliJ, but for those
of you who aren't, this will be for you.
However, everybody should do this, create
a new Kotlin project called challenge
one and then add a package called
academy learn programming challenge one
to the project, after that add a file to
the package called challenge one and
then add the main function to the file.
So pause the video now and go ahead and
do that and when you have your project
and package and file and main function
created come back to see the solution.
Alright, welcome back so this is just a
matter of creating a project, so we'll go
to file, new, project you want to make
sure that Kotlin is selected on the left
hand side and Kotlin jvm on the right
hand side, we'll click Next and we're
going to call this one challenge1
and click finish.
And I'm going to open it in this window.
So, we have our new project here so I'm
going to expand the project node right
click on the source folder go to new,
package and we're going to call this
package academy.learnprogramming.challenge1
and click ok and then
we'll right-click on the package and go
new, Kotlin class or file and we'll call
this challenge1 and click ok and at
this point, all we have to do is add the
main method, so I'll just type in main
and hit enter and that's it. That's the
first part of the challenge completed,
I hope you did well and you managed to
create an IntelliJ project and file
and package and main function. Alright so
the next thing I'd like you to do and
I'll type this into IntelliJ now is
declare two immutable
strings or rather string variables
called hello one and hello two. Assign
hello to both variables and that's it,
pretty easy. So pause the video and give
it a shot. Okay welcome back! I hope you
completed that challenge okay so let's do it!
We're going to start with val because
we want immutable string variables which
means they can't be changed and those
are val variables we'll call the first
one hello and we'll assign it the string
hello and then do the same thing for the
second one, hello two equals hello
perhaps you did this and that's okay,
that's not the end of the world.
You don't really need to do that but it's
fine if you do it. As I said, when you're
first learning Kotlin your first crack
at something will often be more verbose
than it has to be and then you can
experiment and take certain parts of the
statement away and see if you get any
errors. Okay so the next thing I want you
to do is using one line of code and I do
mean one line of code, test whether hello
one and hello two our referentially
equal. That's the hard one to spell and
print the result. So using one line of
code, test whether hello one and hello two
are referentially equal and print the
result. Pause the video now and give it a try.
Okay, welcome back I'm going to
include some descriptive text in my
solution, but it's okay if you
include any. So here's what I did print
line, hello one is referentially equal to
hello two and then I'm using an expression
as a substitution value and hello one,
and of course we want to use the triple
equals to test for referential equality.
So, we're using triple equals and we're
comparing hello one to hello two. So let's
run and see what we get. And we get hello
one is referentially equal to hello two
and it says that that's true. You might be
surprised at the result. I hope you
didn't pull your hair out thinking you
did something wrong. Now remember that in
Java, there's only ever one instance of a
specific string literal. So here we've
assigned the same string literal to hello
one and hello two. If you use the string
more than once in your code, you're
actually using the same string instance
every time you refer to the string
literal. Now the jvm optimizes strings in
this way and of course we're running on
a jvm, so we get the same optimization
when we run our Kotlin application.
So these two string literals are actually
the exact same instance because when the
jvm comes to execute this line of code,
it looks in what's called a string pool
and it sees that it already has an
instance of a string literal hello and
so it just reuses it, because strings are
immutable and so it's safe for the jvm
to do that. So, you're actually assigning
this the same string instance here,
helloe one and hello two contain the exact same
instance and therefore, they are
referentially equal. So as I said, I hope
you didn't tear your hair out over this,
I wouldn't call it a trick question
because the important thing from this
part of the challenge is that you use
the triple equals, that you know that
when you want to test for referential
equality in Kotlin, you use the triple
equal, so if you did that you did great!
Alright so now I want you to do the
same thing, but I want you to determine
whether they're structurally equal, so do
the same thing as above,
test for structural equality, so pause
the video and give it a shot. Okay well
this one should be easy now in fact you
know you can just copy this line, bring
it down here and then you know we'll
want to change this to structurally
structurally and knock off one of the
equals here, because this is how Kotlin
tests for structure equality and if we run,
we should also see true and we do,
because if two variables are
referentially equal, then obviously
they're also going to be structurally
equal. Okay so let's move on to the next
challenge, the next one is- this time
declare a mutable variable of
type int and assign it the value of 2988,
So this should be a fairly easy one,
go ahead and try it. Okay, so for this one,
we're going to start with var because we
want a mutable variable and then you can
call it whatever you want, I didn't
specify the name, so we'll just call it
num and we can just assign it the value 2988.
Now in this case, we don't have to
specify the type because for whole
numbers the default data type is int, but
if we wanted a byte or a short or a long,
we would have had to have specify the type.
Okay for the next one, I want you to
declare an immutable variable of type
any. Now we're going to talk about this
data type later, for now just know that
the any variable of type any can contain in
any Kotlin type, hence the name any.
So, you can assign data of any type to a
variable of type any, in this case we're
going to assign-
assign it the string the any type is the
root of the Kotlin class hierarchy,
perhaps you already guessed that based
on what I said and then using a smart
cast, print out the upper cased string.
So this is going to be more than one
line of code, so declare an immutable
variable type, sorry an immutable
variable of type any and assign it the
string, the any type is the root of the
Kotlin class hierarchy and then, using a
smart cast, print out the uppercase
string. So good luck with this one
and I'll see you in a bit. Okay, so we'll
start out by declaring our variable and
we'll say val and we'll call it text and
we'll assign it oh and you have to
declare the data type in this case, which
will be a type any and we'll assign it
the string the any type is the root of
the Kotlin class hierarchy. Okay, so now
we want to use a smart cast to uppercase
this, we can't just call to uppercase on
it, because it's of type any not of type
string, so to do a smart cast we'll use
the is operator so we'll say if text is
string and then in Kotlin because it has
smart casting, if this test is true then
in the following block of code, we can
just go ahead and use text as if it's a
string, we no longer have to cast it.
So we'll just print line text dot to
uppercase and we're done. Let's run to
make sure of that. And here's our result,
the any type is the root of the Kotlin
class hierarchy. So this is what smart
casting get to you we didn't have to use-
we didn't have to explicitly cast text
to a string here. Once the test has passed,
the is test, we can then go ahead and use
text as if it had already been cast.
Alright so our final challenge is going to
be the following, using one line of code,
okay just one line of code, print out the
following and make sure your code is
nicely indented- nicely indented so what
I want you to print out is let's see-
and then on the
final line- thar should actually
pull this in. So this is what I want to see
printed in the console and I want you to
do this using just one line of code.
So pause the video and I'll see you in a
bit. Okay now, the verbose way and I
suppose you could do it this way is to
print a string that uses new lines and
blanks, but we're going to do it the
Kotlin way and the Kotlin way is to use
a triple quoted string, so let's start
we'll say val let's call it ones equals
and we'll have our triple quoting and
the first line is going to be 1 2 3
blanks in a 1, our next line and I'm
going to use the default trim character
here, so the pipe will be 2 blanks and 2
ones the third line will be a blank and
3 ones and the fourth line will be 1 2 3
4 ones and then we can close our triple
quoted string and then of course we want
to call the trim margin. So that all of
this white space here is going to be
trimmed off and I've just realized I
said in one line of code, so we're going
to actually delete this and just put
print line here.
And that's it. That's our one line of
code, so let's run and see if we get what
we expect and sure enough we do, in one
line of code we've printed this out and
our code is nicely indented we don't
have one sitting out here. If you're in
the mood for one more challenge, I'm not
going to answer this for you. Hopefully,
you'll figure it out and if you don't,
you can always just ask in the
discussion area. I'd like you to do the
same thing, but use one as the trim
character, so in other words put one here
and print out this, the exact same thing.
Now, if we run this we'll see now that
we're not getting what we want, because
we've got extra characters in here,
because the pipe is no longer the
character and what happened to our first
line? So as an exercise for you,
I'll change this statement here so that you
get what we had before. Okay, that's it
for the challenges and how did you do?
Now, if you missed any don't worry you're
learning a new language and when you do
that, it takes practice and there's a lot
more course to come, so you're going to
be seeing a lot more Kotlin and it's
going to start to feel a lot more
natural to you.
So I'll see you in the next section.