Now let's take a look at companion
objects, the second use case for the
object keyword. Now we know that the
static keyword doesn't exist in Kotlin,
we can't declare anything as static,
instead we can use top-level functions
and properties and as we've just seen,
can also use object declarations when it
makes sense, but we still have a problem.
So let's take a look at some code in
Java, I've already typed some code in,
I've created a Java code package and I
have two classes in here. In some class
I have a private static variable and I
have a public static method that
accesses that variable. And then in some
other class, I just have some other
method and it calls that static method.
So some class access private var and so
here in the main method, I'm creating an
instance of some other class and then
I'm calling the access private var
method here. So if we run this, we'll see
I'm accessing private var six and we'll
notice here that we didn't need an
instance of some class here in order to
call access private var, because access
private var is static. So this class is
able to call the method without needing
an instance of the method. So that's all
fine and dandy, but now let's try to do
the same thing from Kotlin. So we'll go
back to our company communications and
here, I'm just going to create the
classes we need within the same file and
we'll say ok class some class and we'll
say it has a private variable private
var equals 6. Now we can't declare this
static, but we know it's public and final,
so it's kind of equivalent to this.
And now we'll create the method that
accesses it.
So we'll say fun access private var
and let me go back here, I can probably
I'll copy this and then modify it to
save on some typing. No, I don't want to
convert it to Kotlin, so suppose I could
have, so print line I'm accessing private
var and here we'll just use do that
instead and of course we don't need to
semicolon. Okay, so this is all fine
because it can access this variable,
it's in the same class so it can access a
private variable, but can we get to this
function now without having an instance
of some class? And the answer of course
is no. So because the static keyword
doesn't exist in Kotlin, because we can't
declare anything as static, it's not
possible to access functions and public
static members, within classes without
having an instance of the class.
You always need an instance of the class
to access anything that's inside a class,
in this case because private var is
private, it also doesn't have a setter
generated for it or a getter for that matter, so the
only things that can access private var are
inside the class and that's the same
thing in Java as well, though we could
write setters and getters here and of
course, we could make this public
and then other classes could access this
directly, again without needing an
instance. So how do we get the equivalent
situation in Kotlin? How can we have
something inside a class, but not need an
instance to access it? Well this is where
companion objects come in, you can create
companion objects inside classes and you
can access these companion objects
without needing an instance of the class.
So let's add a companion object to our
some class here, instead of doing this,
let's get rid of this stuff, instead
we'll say companion object and now we
can put our variable in our function in
here, we can say private var private var
equals 6 and we can say fun access
private var equals I'm accessing
private var and I need a closing
quotation here. So we've moved the
variable declaration inside the
companion object since the function
needs to access it. Now if you like,
you can think of everything within
the companion object as being static,
which is the equivalent of what we had
in Java. So now we can call the access
private var function without needing an
instance of some class. So in our main
method, let's say let's call it let's go
print line some class dot now we have to
use companion here dot access private
var, I don't need the parentheses here
that's why it's giving me an error.
Alright, so let's run and we'll see I'm
accessing private var six. So now we're
able to access the function without
needing an instance of the class. So we
have the equivalent situation that we
had in Java. Now we had to use the
companion keyword here, because we didn't
give our companion object a name, but you
can give them names, so we could say you
know some companion and then up here we
can instead do that and now we can use
some companion here and if we run, we'll
see the same thing, but let's remove it
again and let's try removing it from
here and we'll see that Kotlin is
actually smart enough to know that you
want to call something in the companion
object, so you don't even have to use
companion, you can if you want to make it
crystal clear to somebody reading the
code that you're actually calling
something within a companion object and
of course you could have a companion
object name here as well, but
you don't have to do it, Kotlin's smart
enough to know that you've got a
companion object and it has a function
called access private var. So that's one
use of companion objects, so if we think
about this in Java terms, what we're kind
of doing is grouping static members
within companion objects and anything
that we have inside a companion object,
we can access them without needing an
instance of the enclosing class.
Now another use of companion objects is you
can use them to call private
constructors, in fact you can use them to
implement the factory pattern. So let's
add two constructors to some class,
I'm also going to add a property, so I'll say
val some strings string, I'm going to
initialize this in a minute in the
constructor, so we'll say constructor
this one will accept a string and all it
will do is assign the property equals
str. And we'll have a second secondary
constructor, it will accept a string but
it will also accept a boolean call it
lower case and basically, if you pass
true then you want to lower case the
string and if you pass false, you want to upper
case the string. So we'll say if lower
case, then we're going to assign srt to
lower case to the property and if lower
case is false, then we're going to assign
the upper case
result to the property. So we've got two
secondary constructors, we don't have a
primary constructor as you can see there
are no parentheses next to the class
name. Now instead of doing it this way,
we can add functions to our companion
object that return instances of some
class, in other words the companion
object can act as a factory.
We'll need a primary constructor for
this, so I'm going to add it now, so I'm
going to say val some string and its
string, now we're going to see tons tons
of errors now, because we have a
duplicate property and also our
secondary constructors aren't deferring
to our primary constructor, but we're
going to use the companion object, so we
won't worry about the errors for now,
we're going to add functions to the
companion object that do the same thing
that each secondary constructor is doing.
So, we'll add fun just assign, accepts the
string and this will just say create an
instance of some class and it's just
going to assign whatever it's passed.
So it will pass this string along to the
constructor and I see there's a typo
here, I'll take that out and then we'll
have a fun which upper or lower case is
the string, so it will take a string and
it will also take a boolean and it
returns an instance of some class and in
here, we'll say if lower case essentially
what we're doing in the constructor then
we're going to return some class and
we're going to pass it string to lower
case, otherwise we'll return it instance
of some class and return it pass it the
string upper case.
Now these two functions are doing
exactly what the constructors were doing,
the first one as we can see has an
expression body and the second one has a
block body. So let's remove the duplicate
property here and the two constructor
definitions, because we don't need them
and I can see that I didn't put a return
state return here, so I'll do that. Okay,
so all our errors have gone away, that's
great, but we want this to implement the
factory pattern which means that we want
this class to be responsible for
creating instances of some class nobody
should be able to do it directly.
So before, they could do it directly because
they could call a secondary constructor,
now they can call the primary
constructor, so we need to make the
primary constructor private, so that
nobody from the outside can construct an
instance of this class, so to do that,
just have to add private constructor
here. So now, none of the constructors
because there's only one is accessible
from outside the class, if you want to
construct, you want to get an instance of
this class, you have to call either just
assign or upper or lower case and those
are in the companion object. So now we
have a class with a private constructor
and factory functions, so let's create
some instances up in the main function
here, so we'll say val some class 1
equals some class dot and we'll just
assign here, we're not going to do
anything to it and we'll say you know
this is the string as is and then we'll
say some class 2 equals some class dot
and we'll say upper or lower case and
we'll say this is the string as is,
I will say true here, actually we'll say
false because we want we want it to be
uppercase so so we'll print line some class
one dot some strings and print line some
class 2 dot some string let's run and
we'll see that we have our two instances,
in the first case we're just assigning
the string and in the second case, we're
saying this isn't the string as is and
we've uppercased it.
So we can create instances of some class
from outside the class but we have to go
through the factory methods, we can't do
something like this
val you know some class 3 equals some
class, you'll see right away we get an
error says cannot access init,
it is private in some class, so we cannot
access the constructor directly, we have
to go through the factory methods and so
that's the second use for companion
objects, you can use them in conjunction
with a private primary constructor and
so you can prevent anything from outside
the class from using a constructor
directly, it has to go through one of the
functions in the companion object.