All right in this video we're going to take a look at what's known as varians.
But under that umbrella you have covariance and contravariant.
And we're going to start by looking at covariance.
We've seen how we can accept a list of tea and set an upper bound so that t can be limited to a type.
We saw that when we had our convert to in function.
So I've created a new project now and we're going to type in our convert to function again.
So we'll say fun convert to in.
And we take a collection that's a list of number.
So this time we're we're trying to do it differently rather than declaring a fun and passing a type
parameter and setting an upper bound of number we're saying no we'll just take a list of number because
we know number implements the two functions so we'll say for now I'm in collection print line number
to it.
So what we're saying here is rather than declaring a type parameter and specifying an upper bound of
number which means that will take t can be any type that's number or that implements number we're saying
well no let's take a list of number because if we have a list of number we know that all the instances
in that list have the two end function.
So that's great.
So let's try this out.
So we'll say Vau shorts short list rather.
And we're going to make this a list of short and we have to explicitly say that because otherwise the
compiler will think that our initial values are in.
Some will say a list of 1 2 3 4 5 and then will say convert 2 inch short list.
So that's wonderful.
And if we take a look at short let's just take a look at the declaration will see that indeed short
extend number.
So that's cool.
And we want a list of numbers so short is actually a list of numbers.
If we go ahead and run this
we'll see that we get our one two three four five.
Everything's working great.
It's working exactly how we expect.
OK so let's now make one little change to this function.
We're going to say you know what we don't want to list a number we want immutable list of number and
now we're going to get a problem of course but we can change that.
We can say mutable list you Turbo list and we can ask for a mutable list of.
But we still have a problem.
It's saying hey I've I've got a mutable list of short you need to pass a mutable list of number to this
function.
And at this point we're scratching our heads saying well wait a minute we do have an amiable list of
number shorts are numbers too.
And this worked with an immutable list so why isn't it working with the immutable list.
Well let's get a little more precise with our terminology here.
When we're discussing generics using type and subtype is more accurate than using class and subclass
depending on the context.
For example a list is a class list isn't a type it's a class but a list of string is a type.
So is list of number list of int and a list of short and we say a list of int or list of short is a
subtype of lists of number because a list of int isn't a subclass of a list of number we're not extending
anything.
It's more that we're saying a list of numbers should be able to accept a list of int Because list of
int is a subtype of list of number.
So it's important to understand the distinction between a subclass and a subtype.
We know that in our case short is a subclass of number but is short a subtype of number.
Now the same goes for supertype.
So in this case a list of number would is a supertype of list of short.
That's how we'd say it.
Now one wrinkle here is nullable versus non nullable types a nullable type is a wider type than the
non-knowledge of type.
Meaning that if you have a knowable type you can store non nullable types into it but you can't of course
you can't do it the other way around.
If you have a non nullable variable you can't store a nullable type into it.
So why have I just said all of this gobbledygook.
This brings us to what's called covariance.
What we want to do here is we want to treat a list of short like a list of number.
And we were able to do that when we were using an immutable list.
So what we're saying is we want list of short to be a subtype of list of number and if we want this
subtyping to be preserved when working with generics we have to declare the type parameter to be covariant.
Now remember when we looked at collections we looked at the collections interface and immutable collections.
And I said that the collections interface was covariant and the mutable collections interface was not
covariant.
And I've just said that if we want list of short to be treated like a list of number then the list of
short has to be a subtype of list of number.
And if we want the subtyping to be preserved we have to declare the parameter is covariant.
So if we're saying that an immutable collection is covariant but a mutable collection is not.
Now maybe we're getting a hint as to why this worked with an immutable list but not with a mutable list
the immutable list is what's called covariant and immutable list is not what's called covariant.
So when we're dealing with something that's covariant subtyping is preserved.
So when something is covariant a list of short is a subtype of A list of number.
But when something is not covariant that's not true.
So we could do this with an immutable list because it's covariant and so the subtyping is preserved.
But when we're dealing with a mutable list subtyping is not preserved.
So in this case we cannot treat a list of short like a list of number.
Now don't worry we're going to look at an example here if that all sounds crazy so let's say we have
a class called Flower.
I'm going to comment this out because I'm going to want to be able to compile whenever we do now.
So let's say Open Class flour because we're going to want to subtype it.
So that's great.
And now let's declare a class called garden and a garden can contain flowers so will say class Garden
and we're going to give it a tight parameter here and we're actually going to say that we want this
to be some type of flower.
So that's great.
So here we're saying you can have a garden of roses you can have a garden of daffodils you can have
a garden of daisies So all of our version of garden you always have some type of flower.
OK so now let's write a function that Waters the garden.
Maybe it calculates the optimal amount of water that you have to use so we're going to make that a top
level function.
So we're going to say I'll do it here right up to class fun water garden.
Garden and it once a garden a flower and it does something.
And now we're going to declare a subclass of flower called Rose.
So we'll say class rose Stenz flower and we need to call the defer to the flower class here.
And finally let's declare a function that will tend to our Rose Garden including watering it so we'll
put this up here so we'll say fun 10 garden and we'll say we want a rose garden and that's going to
be a garden Navarro's screwed up my parentheses here so I'll just take that out and we'll say water
garden rose garden and we get an error.
We get a similar error to what we got with shorts and numbers.
It's good to say that water garden wants a garden of flowers and we're passing it a garden of roses
and we know that Rose is a subclass of flower.
Now this is happening because the garden class is what's called invariant.
We come down to our garden class here.
This class is invariant.
Therefore when we ask for a garden of flower we can only provide a garden a flower.
So for asking for a garden of flower here because this is invariant.
This will only accept a garden of flower.
It will not accept the garden of rose it will not except the garden of daffodil it will not accept a
garden of Daisy.
It wants a garden of flower it is invariant it's stubborn it only wants that period.
So subclasses of flower will not be accepted.
In other words subtyping is not preserved it's invariant.
Now we want garden to be a little more relaxed.
We want it to accept a type of flower and also all of the subtypes.
So we wanted to be able to to use the water garden function with gardens of roses and gardens of daffodils
etc..
We don't want to have to write a version of water garden for every single flower that we can have in
a garden.
So if we want that to happen garden can no longer be invariant.
We have to make it covariant and we do that by adding the out key word.
So I'm going to put out there and boom this is now covariant and we saw this when we looked at collections
we saw that the immutable collection had out but the mutable did not.
However this comes with a bit of a price now that the class is covariant.
We're restricted with what we can do with it and doesn't sound like immutable collections as well you're
restricted with what you can do with an immutable collection.
You can read them but you can't add anything to them.
And we now have the same situation with our garden class.
You can only use a covariate class in what is called the out position and that's why to make something
covariant.
You use the out key word but what does that mean.
What does it mean when we say well now that garden is covariant.
We can only use it in out positions.
Well Katlin has the notion of in and out positions function parameters are considered to be an in position
the function return type is an out position so let's declare a couple of functions in our garden class.
Now that it's covariant will declare a function for picking a flower.
Now I know we haven't really implemented this class but will demonstrate the concepts here so we'll
have a function for picking a flower and we also want a function for planting a flower.
So let's pretend here in our garden class actually we don't need all that room here.
We'll say that we have a list of flowers.
Now I'm not initializing it here this we're not going to fully implement this class.
We just want to demonstrate the concepts so each garden has a list of the flowers.
And of course those flowers will be of type T.
So if you created a rose garden they're going to be roses daffodils daffodils etc. and then we want
a function called pick flower and we're going to give an inch because we're going to say like of course
this doesn't make sense for flowers but pick me the fifth flower and we'll return the fifth flower and
list so we'll return tea and we're going to return flowers.
So if somebody calls us and says pick flower and I was 20 then we're going to return the 20th flower
or rather the flower position 20 in our garden.
OK that's all great.
And I'm actually being deliberately verbose with the code because I want you to see where the Tea is.
I could go like this that would work because the compiler can infer it but I'm being deliberately verbose.
So now let's add the function that plants a flower.
We said we want one function that can pick a flower in one function that can plant flowers will say
plant flower and will take the flower and of course that's got to be of type T.
And we get an error it says type parameter T is declared as out which it is but occurs in the in position.
Now remember that I said Cartland has the notion of in and out positions and the in position our function
parameters and the outer position is the return type of a function.
Now we've made garden covariant which means we've declared it as out.
And this means that we can only use T in the out position so we can use it as the return type of a function.
But we can no longer use it as the parameter type.
And that's why the compiler is complaining we're trying to use something that's out in an in position
so we can pick flowers but we can't plant them.
Now why is this restriction exist.
Well because if we could plant flowers there would be nothing to stop the plant flower function from
being called with a daisy when we have a Rose Garden.
Think about it because a daisy is also a flower a Daffodil's a flower etc..
So if we say yeah you can plant a flower and we're going to take Titely Well since subtyping is preserved
that means that this function would accept a daisy daffodil a rose.
And so you can see how we could get into trouble because all of a sudden we're going to run into the
situation where we're getting a list of mixed types even though we have a Rose Garden.
So once we've said that we want garden rose to be a subtype of garden flower the compiler is not going
to let us add anything to it now because it'll open up this problem of all.
But now any type of flower will match this because subtyping is preserved and that's going to open up
the possibility that we'll be able to add something that isn't a rose to a Rose Garden and obviously
that would be bad.
So when a class is covariant meaning that we've used the out key word subtyping is preserved and the
class can only be used in the out position.
But you'll notice now that if we go up to our 10 to garden we don't have the air anymore.
So our water garden here will now accept a rose garden because subtyping is preserved so it now sees
a garden rose as a garden a flower.
Now you may say hey wait a minute this is being used in the in position but when we're talking about
in and out positions we're talking about member functions.
This is safe because we can't do anything to the garden inside the water garden function that's going
to change the collection because the fact there's not going to be any functions in garden that let us
do that.
So it's OK to call a nonmember function and pass a covariant type as a parameter.
So now that we know what covariance is let's go back to our convert to inte example.
So remember that we were getting an error when we used a mutable list and we tried to pass a mutable
list of short to a mutable list of number.
But we don't get the same error when we do it with a list.
So let's take a look at the list and mutable list classes.
I'm going to go to go to the declaration here and you'll see that there is no out keyword anywhere here
so mutable list is invariant.
It wants the exact type.
So here you've said that you want a readable list of number then that's got to be a mutable list of
number mutable list of short double float.
Int whatever is not acceptable it once immutable list of number.
But if we scroll up to the list class we'll see that list has the out keyword here it is covariant and
so it is saying that you know what I want the subtyping to be preserved.
If you say that you want a list of number.
I'm OK with taking a list of short list of int or whatever.
But of course this class is for immutable lists so there is nothing in here that can change the list
just like there's nothing in the garden class that can change the garden.
Now if you scroll down here you'll actually see that there are some functions in here that are taking
E which is a generic type as a parameter but whenever that happens you'll notice that this unsafe variants
annotation is being used.
And that's telling the compiler that hey I'm taking this variable but this function doesn't change the
list so it's safe to do so in this case.
And what this annotation does is it suppresses the compiler errors associated with this.
So if you're absolutely sure it's kind of like with the not null assertion case you can shoot yourself
in the foot with this.
But if you are absolutely sure that you have a function inside a covariant class and that function does
not change the class in any way an instance of the class.
So for example the contains function just checks to see if something is in the list.
It's not going to change the list.
It's not going to add an element to the list.
It's not going to remove an element from the list it's not going to change an instance in the list by
setting an instance into a specific index all it's going to do is check to see whether the list contains
something.
So in other words all is going to do is read the list is it's not going to write the list.
If you know for a fact that that happens and you can use this annotation and you can pass a covariant
instance to the function.
And so that's why in a few cases you can see that we're using it in the in position.
But you have to use this annotation and you can see that contains all only reads the collection index
saw only reads that last index of only reads that.
But there's nothing in here that changes the list whereas in mutable list you can see right away oh
we're adding.
We have the add function we have the remove function.
These are in the in position and we don't need this annotation because mutable list is not covariant
is invariant and therefore you can both read and write it.
So you can only read covariant instances.
That's essentially what it boils down to and Cartland ensures that that's happening by not letting you
add functions to covariant classes that could potentially change the list.
Because we're the one of the covariant classes because here if we have this pink flower maybe we're
not changing the guard and inside dysfunction or plant flower rather maybe we're not changing the garden
inside plant flower but maybe we are.
And to be super cautious when you declare something is covariant you're just not allowed to use it like
this at all because once you pass this in as a parameter it's possible that you're going to run into
a bad situation.
And let's illustrate that now.
So let's pretend for a moment that mutable list is covariant.
So let's go back to our convert to Ent. function and let's pretend it is covariant and let's instead
of just printing out two in two let's add something to the collection now.
So we'll see a collection dot add 25 because we can do anything right with this collection.
It's been passed in so we can do anything with it.
Now we don't see an error here but you can see the potential problem right away.
If we could call this with a short list immutable list of short you're going ahead and adding an integer
into that list because this is an integer.
It's not a short.
I mean it can fit into a short but that's not the way the compiler is going to type it.
So right away you have a problem what if we had this if we had that youre passing in a short list and
we go well lets add 20 5.3.
Nigga you've got a really big problem youve got a double sitting inside something that's supposed to
be a short.
And so this is the type of problem that you could run into if that restriction did not exist for covariant
classes.
So now we understand as well why the list class cant have an add function because its covariant.
It would open lists up to these types of shenanigans where you could declare a list of I don't know
big decimal and then pass that list into something that accepts a list of any and you could go ahead
and add strings and all sorts of things into that big decimal list because there would be nothing to
stop you from doing that.
Let's go back to list.
So we'll see a list of short here list and we'll make this a list.
And now you can pass in a list of short because this is covariance so it will take a list of T and all
of its subclasses but of course now you can't do this because obviously this would be a big mistake.
And so this is why covariant classes can only declare functions but the type in the out position meaning
with the generic type as the return type of a function.
But as we saw you can use an annotation to accept the type as a parameter as long as you're absolutely
sure that it won't lead to a runtime exception.
So in other words that it's not going to change the covariant instance.
Now in the case of list all the functions that use the annotation don't change the list in any way so
we know it's safe for them to accept a list of a subclass as a parameter.
Now there are a couple of exceptions to note here.
Constructor parameters don't have in n out positions.
So you can always except a covariant class is a constructor parameter.
And that's because constructors are called when an instance is created.
So you know there's no danger of using a constructor to do something that's going to lead to this type
of mismatch where you have a double value in a short list.
But if you declare a VAR variable of type T then t can't be covariant.
Because remember that Cartland is going to generate a setter and the setter will accept t as a parameter.
And if you if t is covariant it can't be in the in position.
So let's just briefly do this all comment this out let's go back to our garden and let's have it except
a parameter var.
I don't know something.
I have no clue what this would accept and I will say that it's a tight t.
This is a contrived example but let's say every garden has a something flower.
I don't know what that would be.
And you can change which flower that something is it some special type of flower.
So we won avara because you can change it.
And so we wanted to setter but now we have an error and it says type parameter T is declared is out
but occurs in invariant position in type T and that's telling us that we can't have avara because t
is in the out position t can now change something about our class.
For example we could pass the rows Rosen here when we have a garden of Daffodil's we could pass a daisy
in when we have a garden of rows because we've said that T Well except flower or any subclass of flour
so once again to prevent a garden of rows ending up with daffodils in it which would be bad for for
this anyway wouldn't be bad in real life but be bad here.
The moment you declare a variable of a covariate classes are you going to get this error.
So this is going to have to be vowel because when with vowel it's only going to generate a getter in
other words it's only going to read t it's not going to write to t.
In other words somebody from the outside can't write to t write to something once it's set and it's
being set in the constructor.
So as we've just said there's no danger of any of these mis mismatch type shenanigans happening when
you're running the constructor.
Also if you have a function or a property that is not visible to the outside world then you don't have
to worry about in and out positions.
So private functions don't have in and out positions you can do whatever you want with them.
And when you think about it that makes sense because if the only functions that can call your function
are inside the class then again you're not going to be in trouble of a daffodil or a daisy sneaking
into a rose garden.
So if we went private var you'll see that we no longer get the error.
Even though this is var and that's because nobody outside the class can touch this property.
And so the only thing this propertys ever going to be is a rose for a Rose Garden a daffodil for a daffodil
garden etc. the in and out rules are there to protect against the outside world doing something that
it shouldn't be doing.
So it's to prevent something from outside trying to add the wrong type of flower into a garden.
OK so that's covariance you use covariance when you want these subtyping to be preserved so you can
pass an instance of the type or the subtype.
So here we can pass an instance of Rose Garden to garden flower and appear when we were using lists
which are covariant we could pass we can pass a list of short for a list of number.
But when you declare something is covariant you do lose the ability to write to an instance to change
an instance and to guarantee that you can't write to it you're not allowed to then in member functions
you're not allowed to accept a parameter of type T.
So that's set for covariance in the next video we're going to take a look at what's called contravariant.
I'll see you there.