okay so we've got three Kotlin classes
now Kotlin bicycle Kotlin mountain bike
in Kotlin road bike so let's start using
these classes so the first thing I want
you to do is to add a main function to
the Kotlin file and then create an
instance of all three types of bikes and
then call the print description function
for all three types of bikes now when
you're creating the instances it doesn't
matter what values you use for the
properties that probably means we'll
create some impossible types of bikes
but that's okay so create an instance of
Calton bicycle an instance of calling
mountain bike and an instance of Kotlin
road bike and then call the print
description function for all three pause
the video and give that a try
okay welcome back so I'm going to add a
main function and by now you should be
familiar with just typing in main and
hitting Enter and IntelliJ will add the
function for us so let's create an
instance of the bicycle so we'll say Val
bicycle equals and then here and make
sure you say Kotlin bicycle because if
you just say bicycle you'll be creating
an instance of the Java class and that
would work nothing would warn you
there'd be nothing wrong with doing that
but we want to create an instance of our
Kotlin class so we're going to use
common bicycle and then I'm just going
to pass 10 for the cadence 3 for the
speed and 10 for the gear I have no idea
if that makes sense and now I'm going to
call the print description so that's one
of our instances created so now I'll say
valve mountain bike equals and I'm going
to say Kotlin mountain bike and for this
I'm going to pass twenty ten ten and
thirty and once again I'm not sure if
that's impossible
or maybe a bike with a really really
high seat and then I'm going to say
mountain bike dot print description so
that's our second instance done and
finally we have Val road bike equals
Kotlin road bike and for this one I'll
pass ten ten ten and three and then I'll
call road bike dot print description so
that's it that's our creating our three
instances and calling print description
for each one so at this point let's run
see what we get
and we'll see that we get the bike is in
gear 10 with a cadence of 10 traveling
at a speed of 3 that's for this bicycle
now the other 2 bikes will be printing
out 2 lines each because remember in
their print description functions were
delegating up to the bicycle they call
in bicycle class to print out the values
for the properties it declares so these
two lines are going to come from the
mountain bike print description function
and it'll say the bike is in gear 30
with a cadence of 10 traveling at a
speed of 10 and then let's go down to
the function and then this line will get
printed so the mountain bike has a seat
height of 20 inches yes that's quite a
high seat and then the same thing will
happen for the road bike so we'll get
the print from the superclasses print
description and then we get the road
bike has a tire width of 10 millimeters
alright so that wasn't too bad that
should have been pretty easy I would
think okay so the next thing I want you
to do is I want you to make the gear
parameter optional in the Kotlin bicycle
constructor and when the gear isn't
specified it should be assigned a
default value of 10 so make the year
parameter optional assign it a default
value of 10 and once you've done that up
in the main function I want you to
create another three instances one for
each type of bike but this time don't
pass the gear value and then once you've
done that do the same thing you're doing
for these three instances and print the
descriptions so make the gear parameter
optional in the cotton bicycle
constructor it should have a default
value of 10 if the gear isn't passed and
then create three new instances one for
each bike don't pass the gear value and
print the descriptions for each one so
pause the video and give that a try
okay I'm going to close down the console
here to give us some more room
so making the gear parameter optional
it's just a matter of adding a default
value for it and we want that to be 10
so we just have to say equals 10 and now
this parameter is optional but as you
probably discovered when you assign a
default value in the superclass and
therefore you make the parameter
optional that does not filter down to
the subclasses so we can see that if we
start creating our three instances so
I'm going to copy these here paste them
here and this will be bicycle - bicycle
- and mountain bike - mountain bike -
road bike - in road bike - and then we
said that you don't want to pass the
gear so I'll knock the gear off this one
and we don't have a problem but if I
come down here and take the gear off
here we get a problem and we get no
value passed for parameter gear so as
you probably discovered making the
parameter optional in a superclass does
not make it optional in the subclasses
and if you think about it that makes
sense first of all you might want a
different default value for these
subclasses and second of all you might
not even want it to be optional for the
subclasses you might have a subclass
where it wouldn't make sense for the
parameter could be optional there might
be a subclass that requires the value
because there isn't a meaningful default
so it's not possible to assign one even
if it is possible to come up with a
default it wouldn't be unusual for a
subclass to want a different default
than what the superclass has so just
making the gear optional and kahlan
bicycle would have passed the first part
of the challenge because I didn't
specify that you had to make it optional
and Calton mountain bike and call and
road bike but the second part of the
challenge where I said to create three
instances and not to pass the gear for
them obviously implies that the gear
parameter should also be optional in the
subclasses what we have to do that
explicitly so I said we wanted any
default value of 10 so when
this case we're going to use the same
default value so we're going to have to
add equals ten to Cottman mountain bike
and equals ten to Kotlin road bike and
now all of our code will compile and if
we run we'll see now these are our new
sets of bikes here I think actually just
these five lines so we'll see that
they're all in a gear of ten so except
for this bike here I guess I didn't pull
it off on the yeah I didn't pull it off
so there we go and let's run again this
time I'm going to actually comment these
out so we're not we're just seeing the
three instances we're interested in and
now we'll see that they're all in gear
ten now it looks like we're repeating
ourselves here because we've got into
equals ten in people's 10 and int equals
10 up here but in a real world
application as I said it's possible and
maybe even likely that the subclasses
would have different default values or
not even want a default value that
they'd want the parameter to be a
requirement all right so your next
challenge is to add a secondary
constructor to the cotman mountain bike
class that accepts a color parameter
color will be a string and all that the
secondary constructor does is prints the
color out now this is sort of a silly
contrived example and I'll tell you why
first of all it's difficult to come up
with a need for a secondary constructor
in a simple application like this
because default parameter values are
usually sufficient but also when you do
have a secondary constructor it's
usually because you want to accept a
value that you're going to use within a
secondary constructor to perhaps
influence what value gets assigned to
one of the other properties so in this
simple example again we really don't
need a secondary constructor but I want
you to do something within the body so
I'm just going to have you print the
color so once again I want you to add a
secondary constructor to call tan
mountain-bike that takes a color
parameter color is a string and all it
does inside the body is print out
the color now it's possible maybe that
the secondary constructor needs to take
more than color I'll let you figure that
out so pause the video and I'll see you
in a minute
okay welcome back let's do it I'm going
to put it above the print description
function so I'm going to say
constructors and we want it to take the
color now we have a decision to make
here because as you probably discovered
we can't just accept color because every
constructor has to delegate back to the
primary constructor we we also need to
take the cadence to speed in the Year
now strictly speaking we don't have to
we could when we're delegating past
constants but that probably wouldn't be
what we want so I'm going to take the
cadence the speed and the gear and the
seat height of course and I also want
color but the question is should I
accept color first before all of the
other arguments or should I accept at
last now normally it wouldn't matter but
we have a default value assigned for
gear and so that influences things
because if we put color last then the
parameter what the default won't be the
final parameter in the argument list now
in Kotlin that doesn't really matter
because as we learn when we're calling
functions we can label the parameters
but it would put the onus on the caller
to have to do that and we probably
wouldn't want to do that we'd want to
design the class so that callers of the
class don't have to label their
parameters so let me add the color
property last to show you what I mean so
I'm going to accept a seat height which
is an int the cadence which is an int
and the IDE is helping me here the speed
which is an INT the year which is an INT
and finally our color which is a string
and then I'm going to put a colon here
because we have to defer back up to the
primary constructor and we do that by
calling this and it wants the seat
height actually if I go back here you
can see that once I type that Colin is
actually suggesting all of these to me
so I'll just let it type for me why do
it myself so there we go
and then inside I'll say print line this
is the color so what are we doing here
we're taking the seat height the cadence
the speed the gear and the color and
we're delegating back up to the primary
constructor here we're taking delegating
up see height cadence speed and gear and
we have been our color now if we wanted
here to be optional here then we need to
assign a default value here so let's
let's do that let's say we're going to
make for this secondary constructor it
doesn't matter what we really pick I'll
pick 10 again but you could put anything
here and so if the caller of the
secondary constructor doesn't pass in
gear then we'll pass 10 up to the
primary constructor but now because gear
isn't the last parameter if we want to
not pass the gear we're going to have to
label our argument so let's go up to the
main function here and I'm going to
comment these two out and I'm going to
say Val and I'll call it mountain-bike 3
equals hot wind mountain bike and I'll
say 20 what order do we have now seat
height cadence speed gear and color so
I'm just going to say 10 10 10 10 and
blue that should be calling mountain
bike mountain bike ok so we have 10 10
10 10 and blue so that's fine we're
passing everything but let's say now we
say you know what we don't want to pass
the gear so we're going to knock the
gear off and now we have a problem
because the compiler is saying I'm
expecting an INT and I found a string
and the reason it's saying that is it's
expecting the next argument to be the
year and we're giving it a string so if
we want to tell the compiler that no no
it's ok we're not passing the gear we
have to label the argument to let the
compiler know so to let it know that
we're passing this for the seat height
this for the cadence this for the speed
getting gear and we're passing the color
blue no it would be better if callers of
this secondary constructor didn't have
to do this we'd like them to not have to
label their arguments what we want is
this blue and if they leave off the gear
that's fine because it's always going to
be the last parameter so the compiler
knows this the seat type this is the
cadence and this is the speed so instead
of writing our secondary constructor
like this it would be better if we moved
the string property up to the front and
now if we go back up to the main
function there's no problem here
so that was one wrinkle to this one
where do you want to put the color no I
didn't say you had to make the gear
optional but and if you didn't that's
fine but I wanted to show you this so if
you were designing this class and this
is what you wanted you would be better
to put the color property up front okay
so let's run this and see what we get
and we'll see that all we get is this is
the blue because I said this is the
color and so this is the blue and I
didn't print out the description let me
do that mountain-bike 3.2 print
description and let's run again and now
we get this is the blue which is coming
from the secondary constructor and then
we get the bike is in gear 10 with a
cadence of 10 traveling at a speed of 10
so it got our default gear value here
and to show that let me change this to
20 temporarily and we'll run again and
now it has a gear of 20 and we're
definitely not passing 20 in here I'll
just leave it at 20 for this secondary
constructor okay for your last challenge
for this section I want you to add a
companion object to the Kotlin mountain
bike class the companion object should
have one property it should be in
immutable list of strings so
list of string that cannot be changed
and call the property available colors
and then I want you to initialize the
list with a list of colors I'm actually
going to type this one out for you
so companion object and it should have a
list of strings called available colors
and initialize the lists to blue red
white black green and brown and then in
the main function once you have your
companion object print the list of
available colors in the main function so
create a companion object in the Kotlin
mountain-bike class the companion object
should have a property called available
colors that's an immutable list of
string and then initialize that list to
the following colors and once you've
done that print the available colors
from the main function now we haven't
really gone over how to print list items
but you should be able to figure that
out you can have the I des autocomplete
give you a hint or you can just you know
go out to your favorite search engine
and you should be able to fairly quickly
find an example of how to print a list
of items in Kotlin we will be going over
this when we look at collections ok so
pause the video and I'll see you in a
bit
all right welcome back so I'll do the
companion object right here I'll say
companion object and I'll accept the
autocomplete and then we want one
property called available color so I'll
say Val available colors and we want it
to be an immutable list so I'm going to
say list of and then these colors here
so I'm going to grab this paste it in
here and of course I need to remove the
end we don't need to be grammatically
correct when we're initializing this
list so now all I have to do is print
out the available colors in the main
function so I'll say Kotlin
mountain-bike dot and you'll see that we
can see available colors and then I'm
going to say for each and then for each
color in the list I'm going to print it
and you will learn all about this in
later sections but essentially what's
happening here is each item in the list
is being substituted for it and so
there's a loop happening under the
covers here so let's go ahead and run
and here are our available colors
printed out blue red white green and
brown now you might have printed them
out in a different way that's fine as
long as you see the same list as long as
you managed to print them okay that's
all for this challenge once you wrap
your head around primary and secondary
constructors and that you have to
explicitly declare when things can be
overridden and declare that you're
overriding them writing classes and
interfaces and Kotlin is pretty
straightforward so that's it for this
challenge and I'll see you in the next
section