(upbeat music)
All right, it's time
to take a deeper look at classes.
Now you know what classes are and what they do
so we're not gonna spend any time on the basics.
I'll just start by reminding you that in Caitlyn
all classes are public and final by default.
So let's start working with the employee class we have here.
I'm gonna remove the private modifier that was just there
for our lecture on Access Modifiers
and we don't need it now.
Now you also saw that we can instantiate the class
as we're doing here, and that we can print the reference,
And that's because the compiler generates a constructor
for us which in this case will be an empty constructor
because we don't have any properties in the employee class.
So let's add a first name field to employee.
Now in Java, we'd create a class called employee.
So let's do that.
I'm going to add a Java file to this project.
So I'll create a new package for that.
So I'll go to new package and I'll call this one
Academy.LearnProgramming,JavaCode as I usually do.
And then in here, we'll just create an employee,
actually we won't call it employee
because that's gonna get confusing.
We'll call it JavaEmployee.
Okay, so here we have a Java class.
And if we wanted to create a first name property,
we do the following.
We'd say, private string first name,
no problems there looks familiar.
And then we'd have a constructor Public JavaEmployee
and we do something like accept a string called first name.
And then within the constructor,
we'd say this dot first name equals first name.
I mean, this is a really common thing in Java.
Now to match what we have in Caitlyn, let's make this final.
And that's fine because the compiler understands
that we're probably going to initialise this
in the constructor which we are.
So now let's go back to Caitlyn.
Now in Caitlyn, there are a few ways we can write
the equivalent code to what we just wrote in Java.
So we're gonna start with the longest way,
because I want you to see what's going on.
But as, as usual, for Caitlyn, there is a shorthand way
that you'll typically use that hides the details.
But let's see those details first.
So to define the constructor,
we're gonna add the constructor keyword here.
And then we're gonna say first name, string.
So what we've just done here is equivalent to what
we basically are doing here in Java, except we're defining
it here on the same line that we're defining the class.
Okay, let's add the property the first name property,
so we'll call it a string.
Now right now, it's giving us an error because it saying
we have to initialise it because we're using val.
So we're going to initialise that
in what's called internet block.
And we'll say this dot first name equals first name.
So this code here is equivalent to what we wrote in Java.
And there's quite a lot going on.
So going back to the constructor and this is very important
Caitlyn has the notion of a primary constructor.
And that constructor is declared outside
the curly braces as it is here.
So here we're actually declaring the primary constructor
and this constructor takes one parameter first name,
which is a string.
Now you can declare other constructors within the classes as
you can in Java, and they're called secondary constructors.
And we'll see those later.
But for now know that when a constructor is declared outside
the curly braces, it's known as the primary constructor
and the primary constructor is very important.
Now after that, we have the property declaration
and you've seen these before.
And then we have what's called the initializer block.
Now this is not a constructor.
So don't mistake this for a constructor.
The initializer block runs when an instance is created
and it's used in conjunction with the primary constructor.
Primary constructors cannot contain code.
I mean, they're declared outside the curly braces
so they cannot contain code.
So if you want to do something, when an instance is created,
and you only have the primary constructor,
then you need to use what's called an Internet block.
So the Internet block is kind of like the body
for the primary constructor, but not quite.
You can have multiple initializer blocks
within the same class, though I'm not sure
why you'd want to do that except for organisation.
Okay, so when we construct an instance of employee
we have to pass the first name
because the primary constructor expects the first name.
That's why we're getting the error up here right now.
So once we've passed the first name in the Internet block
will run and it will assign the first name
that we've passed to the first name property.
So let's go ahead and pass John as the first name.
And then we'll print the first name
instead of just the instance.
And so let's run at this point.
Okay and as we expect, we see John printed.
So this is the long way of doing things, a long way
of writing the equivalent Java class.
We declare a constructor, we declare the property
and then we have an Internet block
that assigns the parameter that we passed
through the constructor to the property.
That's the long way of doing it.
Now let's make our first simplification.
We don't need the initializer block because all we're doing
is assigning a parameter to a property.
And so when that's the case, we can actually combine
the assignment with the constructor declaration as follows.
We can delete all of this here, and we'll just say
ValFirstNameString=FirstNname.
So instead of declaring the property,
and then using an Internet block, because all we're doing
is assigning the value we get from the constructor
to the property we can just do it all in one line like this.
Let's run again and everything still works.
But we can take this even further.
Now remember that one of the goals of Caitlyn
is to minimise the use of boilerplate code.
Now how many times do you write constructors
that just assign parameter values to property values?
I mean, how many times in Java do you see a constructor
or constructors that just have a string of parameters
and all they're doing is you know, this dot x equals x
and y equals y this dot z equals z,
I mean you see that quite often.
So it's boilerplate code.
So Caitlyn, which wants to eliminate boilerplate code
will generate that code for you by default under the covers.
So if all you wanna do is assign parameter values to
the corresponding properties, Caitlyn will do that for you.
It will declare properties with the same names
as the parameters and it will assign the values past
to those parameters to the properties.
So we can actually remove this explicit declaration
and assignment and simply put Val here.
And we're done.
So we're now declaring the property in the signature
for the primary constructor because we've put Val here.
Of course, we could also put var here but by proceeding
the parameter name with val or var,
we're actually doing two things here.
We're saying the constructor takes a string parameter
and we're also declaring the property.
So this constructor signature is now also doubling
as a property declaration.
Now if you're thinking, well, why do we have to include
the constructor keyword since Caitlyn will generate
the primary constructor it shouldn't know we need one
and of course it does.
And so we don't need the constructor keyword,
we can just remove it.
And that still works.
Now we wouldn't be able to remove it if we had annotations
or we were using Access Modifier.
For example, if you wanted to make the primary constructor
protected, you'd do the following.
You'd have to put it back,
you'd have to say protected constructor.
So if you want to change the visibility of the constructor,
you've got to explicitly include the constructor keyword,
but if you want the constructor to be public,
then you don't need to include the constructor keyword.
You can just have this.
So let's run again.
And you'll see we still get John.
So in this one line here, we've declared our constructor,
we've declared a property and we're assigning the value
of the parameter passed to the constructor to the property.
This is the most concise way we can write the code.
And as you can see, we've reduced the number of lines
significantly, I mean, we have to do this in Java,
and that's the equivalent code and Caitlyn.
But I wanted you to see the long way first,
so that you understand what's actually going on
when you see something like this.
There's a lot going on.
It's just you don't have to explicitly type it.
And as I said, if you wanted you could have this as var
and it's still gonna work except of course now the property
will be underlined here to alert us to the fact
that it can be modified.
But we just need a val property
here so we'll change it back.
Now you can provide default values for the parameters.
Let's add a Boolean that indicates
whether an employee is full or part time.
And let's say that this company hires
very few part time employees.
So 99% of the time, the employees will be full time.
In Java we'd write the following
or something like the following anyway.
So we'd say okay, first of all, let me add a field.
So private, let's make it final, again,
Boolean full time.
And then we'd say here, this start full time equals true.
Because 99% of the time that's gonna be the case.
So we don't want developers to have to pass two parameters
when most of the time they don't need the second one,
but of course they will need it sometimes.
So we'll say JavaEmployee FirstName
and BooleanFulltime
and then of course, we'll do something like this.
This .FirstName=FirstName.
And this .FullTime=FullTime.
I mean this is really common in Java
where you've got multiple constructors and each constructor
takes a few more parameters.
We see this a lot.
Sometimes the constructor, some forms of the constructor,
will except a settings object or something.
And if you don't pass it, then you get all the defaults.
Now there are other ways we could write this.
We could just have the one constructor
that accepts both parameters.
We could have the second constructor
called the first constructor to set the first name.
Not anymore though, since we're doing this,
but we still could because we'd be overriding it.
But the point is that often will have multiple constructors
just to handle a different number of parameters.
And this is common with methods in the JDK.
Often there will be a default behaviour that you can change
by passing a flag.
For example, let's go out and look
at the thread class for a minute.
Okay, so here we are at the thread class.
And if we scroll down,
we'll see that it has eight constructors.
And a lot of them defer to other constructors
but provide default values for some of the parameters.
So we'll see here that you can pass a name.
But if you don't pass a name,
if it'll assign a default name for you.
Here you can include a name.
And if you don't pass a name, of course,
you could call this form of the constructor
and then a default name will be created for you.
So a lot of these are just essentially giving the developer
the option of explicitly specifying something or not.
And then the constructors with a fewer number of parameters
will have defaults for the stuff that's not specified.
So let's go back to Intel OJ.
So you can see that stuff like this is quite common in Java.
So now let's go back to Caitlyn
and let's write the equivalent code.
We'll add our full time flag.
Now our first thought will probably be to write
a secondary constructor just like we did in Java.
So instead of having just one constructor we'll have two.
So let's do it that way first.
So to add another constructor use the constructor
keyword just as you do you can explicitly do up here.
Okay, so we want to accept in this constructor
we want to accept
a FirstName, which will be a string and we also wanna accept
a FullTime flag which will be a Boolean.
Now right away can see we're getting errors and the first
error we're getting is primary constructor call expected.
So what does that mean?
Well, if a class has a primary constructor and this class
does because by including parentheses here we're saying
we want to primary constructor, then all of the secondary
constructors have to delegate to the primary constructor.
So in other words, they have
to call the primary constructor.
And this constructor isn't doing that.
So because the primary constructor is handling
the first name property, we have to let it handle
the first name property.
We can't have the secondary constructor also declaring
So we're gonna remove the val from here, because
we're going to let the primary constructor handle it.
And then to call the primary constructor,
we don't call it within the body here.
Instead, we put a colon at the end
of our secondary constructor definition and we call this,
and we want to pass it the first name.
So what this does is this takes the first name
that's passed to the secondary constructor
and use the value to call this.
And the primary constructor will then be called
and it will do what it was doing before.
It will declare the first name property and assign whatever
value is passed to it to the first name property.
So at the moment, this constructor here is doing
the same thing as this constructor here except in Java
where it's actually doing this.
If we do the equivalent thing in Java,
it's doing something like this.
We're getting the error here,
because we declared this final.
So just ignore this because now it's being assigned twice.
It's being assigned up here
and then it's being assigned up here.
But this is the equivalent of what we're doing here.
I'll switch this back.
So now we have this error, though it says Val
on secondary constructor parameter is not allowed.
The compiler doesn't like that.
For first name, we definitely didn't need it because we know
the primary constructor was taken care of declaring
a property but the compiler doesn't like it
on the full time property either.
And that's because unlike the primary constructor using val
and var in a secondary constructor signature
does not lead to the property being declared for us.
So secondary constructors do not declare properties for us.
Only the primary constructor does.
So let's remove the val keyword from here.
And all of our errors go away.
But now let's try to use this full time property.
So we'll go back up to our main function and will declare
another employee ValM2=Employee.
And we'll say Joe, and let's do the same thing.
Well, we'll print the first name
and we're not getting any errors here.
But if we try to print full time
of course IntelIJ isn't gonna suggest it to us.
And I'm sure you expected that
because we haven't actually declared it here.
So as I said before, secondary constructors
don't lead to declarations even if we put the Val back here
which as you can tell isn't gonna work anyway,
but just to illustrate, and then we press dot here,
we're still not seeing full time.
So keep that in mind primary constructors.
You can double the parameter declaration
as a property declaration but you can't do the same thing
in secondary constructors.
We have to actually declare the property
ourselves in that case.
So we'll remove val from here
and we'll actually declare the property in the class.
Now we're getting the air right now
because we haven't signed it yet.
But somebody's full time status might change.
So let's switch that to Var.
But we still have the error because Caitlyn still wants
the property to be initialised for it to be abstract.
Remember, Caitlyn doesn't want nos when you can avoid it.
So let's make this true.
Since we said that 99% of the time employees
will be full time.
So now we'll go back to the print line statement.
And if we put a dot here We can now see full time
and everything's working like we want it to.
Let's add a third employee.
And we'll make her part time just for variety here
and we'll print line her details.
Let's run.
And we'll see that everything prints okay
except I'm printing the same employee over and over again.
You probably spotted that and wanted to yell,
you've made a mistake, you've made a mistake.
That's what I always wanna do when I'm watching a course.
But of course the instructor can hear me.
Okay so this time we've got John, we've got Joe,
true for full time and Jane who is also true for full time.
Why did that happen?
Well, because we happened to sign full time here.
So let's do that.
This start full time equals full time.
No mystery here, let's run again.
And this time Jane has the correct full time status.
Now of course, when you look at this,
and when working with Caitlyn, you always have
to ask yourself is there a more concise way to do this?
And in this case there is because we can assign default
values to the primary constructor parameters.
And this means that most of the time, you won't need
a secondary constructor or you should be able
to at least reduce the number that you need.
So instead of using a secondary constructor,
let's change the primary constructor so that it accepts
both parameters first name and full time
and then we'll assign a default value of true
to the full time parameter.
So let's delete all of this because we're not gonna need it
and instead we'll say Val full time it's a Boolean,
and we'll give it the default value of true.
We'll run.
And we'll see that we get the same thing as we did before.
Because when we don't specify a full time value now
instances will get the default of true.
And when we do well that value is used
and so Jane still has false for full time.
So you can see how default parameter values will cut down
on the number of constructors you need.
A lot of the time, you're only ever going
to need the primary constructor.
You won't have to do this sort of thing
that you have to do in Java.
Now, you don't have to have a primary constructor
if you don't want one.
If you don't want one, you just don't include
parentheses after the class name.
You can still have secondary constructors
even without a primary constructor.
So for illustration purposes,
let's declare a demo class to show this.
So let's say class demo and will say Val dummy,
and we'll make that a string
and then we'll have a secondary constructor.
And all it does doesn't take any parameters.
And all it does is a science evaluated dummy of hello.
And you can see that this all works.
And if we declare an instance of dummy,
let's just print line or demo rather,
let's just print line demo and demo
demo.dummy.
We'll print that
and we'll see that the value of Hello is printed.
So it's perfectly okay to not have a primary constructor.
And you can notice that with this constructor,
we didn't have to defer to anything.
We didn't have to put colon there
because there's nothing to defer to,
there's nothing to delegate to,
there's no primary constructor.
So if you don't want or need the default code that a primary
constructor gives you then you don't have to use it.
Just don't include parentheses after the class name.
Now you might be wondering if you can use default values
and secondary constructors and you can.
So if you wanted to you could also use default values
on them, so that wouldn't be a problem.
Okay, so we're gonna stop the video here
and continue our discussion of classes in the next one.
See you there.