Now let's talk about properties for a minute.
Now you'll notice that in the Cartland code I'm referring to the color field as if it's a property by
just using the dot notation.
Now you can only do it this way if the Java field has getter and setter methods.
So let's go to our Java class and let's comment out the setter for color.
So we'll just comment this out right now and if we go back to our Cartland code we'll see that now we
can't do this obviously because there's no set.
So how am I supposed to set color to green color is private.
And so what the dot notation is actually doing is doing the same thing it's doing in cotland it's calling
get or set under the covers depending on what you're doing.
So will it work if we make our color field public.
Well let's give it a shot and it does.
And let's run to make sure that that is working
and we'll see that it is.
So that's that's a way you can get around this but normally we don't want our fields to be public so
most of the time we're going to want a private field.
And if we want to be able to use the dot notation we need to then make sure that we have setters and
getters assigned and to bring this get her back here.
OK we spent quite a bit of time on covariance and contravariant when we looked at generics.
We looked at you site variants which is happens when you declare something to be variant or covariant
in a function signature.
And I said that doing this is equivalent to using Javins wild cards and so it's not surprising that
wildcard items in Java function signatures will be converted to use site variants or covariance or contravariant
when used from Katlin.
So the question mark extends some class wild card will be converted to out some class.
So that's covariance and the question marks super some class wildcard will be converted to in some class
and of course that's contravariant.
So just be aware of that.
Now a brief word about exceptions if you call a java method that throws an exception and you don't handle
the exception inside the code you don't have to declare that the CANTLIN function throws the exception
because remember that cotland doesn't distinguish between checked and unchecked exceptions.
OK.
Now let's look at var args.
What do you do if you want to call a java method that accepts a variable number of arguments.
Well let's try it out.
We'll add a method to our car class that takes a variable number of arguments so I'll put it before
the two string nested here and we'll say public void variable method.
And this is going to take eight and a string and the strings parameter is variable.
I only put the parameter in there so we have more than just the variable parameter.
And then I'll say for string string and strings system this just feels like I have to type a lot now
especially with the print line system that outsprint line string.
So it's a silly method but it does take a variable argument.
All right so now let's call this method from our Cartland code.
So we'll say Kardon variable Messud 5.
And I guess I need some strings here so I'll say hello my favorite two strings hello and goodbye.
So let's run
and everything's great we see Hello and Goodbye printed from the variable method.
Now let's put these strings into an array and see if we can call the function with an array.
So we'll say string.
Actually I'm in I'm in cotland here so vowel strings equals array of hello and goodbye.
And then we'll say Kardon variable method and this time I'll pass it A10 and we'll pass it our strings
right.
And we can't do it.
So even though the jaba method is really taking an array under the covers as we can see here from the
method code it doesn't work it doesn't work like it does in Java where you can pass an array.
We have to use a spread operator to unpack the array first.
So if I add a Asterix here which is a spread operator everything works fine.
So that's just something for you to be aware of if you want to call a java method that once a variable
has a parameter that can take a variable number of arguments you can't pass an array directly to it
from Cartland you have to unpack the array first.
All right.
Just a short word about void.
Remember that cotland doesn't have void.
So when a job a method returns void it will actually return unit when you call it from Cartland.
So just be aware of that.
So now just a reminder that when a Javid method once a primitive array you can't pass it an array of
cotland integers or floats or whatever other primitive type at once.
You have to pass it an instance of one of the special primitive type arrays.
So if a method wants an array of int you can't pass it in array created using array of you'd have to
create the array using int array of or you'd have to call the two int array function on the cotland
array and pass the result.
So let's try this out.
Let's go to our car class now and let's make up a message that once a primitive array so will say public
void once in array.
And so will say at once and in the array.
And then as usual We'll just print out what's wrong.
So say system and don't print line.
Here's the end.
Now let's call this from Katlin.
So we'll say Kardon Lawrence int array and we'll pass it in array of 2:59 at a rate of.
And you'll see that this doesn't work and we expected this to fail.
It's going to say that at once.
Here's another plot form type.
So once a platform type in terrain we're trying to pass in an array.
And so there's two ways we could fix this.
We can just say Oh all right well given an interesting and right away the error goes away or we could
say well we'll just create an interest in the first place.
So we'll say it into the array of.
And the error goes away.
So I just wanted to remind you and show you an example of passing an array to a method that wants a
primitive type array.
You can't pass a big a array class from Kotla and you have to pass one of the special primitive type
arrays.
All right let's talk about the Object class now.
Now we've said that the any IT'S ACTUALLY THE any question mark class is at the top of the Cartland
class hierarchy.
And as we know the object class is at the top of the Java class hierarchy.
So what happens when the Java code uses object explicitly.
For example what happens to a variable declared as object.
Well if you guess that something declared as object in Java it will be treated like any in cotland.
You're right.
Now remember that any only has a two string hash code and equals functions.
It does not have to wait.
Notify the get class or the clone or the finalize methods that the object class has.
So if you want to call wait or notify you should cast the variable to Java Avodart lancôme object in
your Cartland code.
So let's try this out.
I'm going to add in our car class a field of type Object and I'll just call it an object and I'm going
to add a setter for it to or a getter rather because we want to be able to get this thing called and
I might as well Ibos.
So I'll come here and I'll have intelligent do this for me generate Saturn Geter and yet do it for me
please.
So now we have get an object and send an object.
So now let's try using this field from Cartland
So if we type card Daut and object and then see what intelligence suggests we'll see that we just have
equals hash code into String.
We don't have any of the methods that are normally in the object class.
So if you want to be able to use an object to call let's say notify then you need to cast this to a
Java Language object that's the only way you're going to be able to see the other methods that are normally
in the object class.
So you do the following.
You'd say card not an object as Avodart Lang dot object dot.
And now you'll see that we can see everything that's normally an object.
So now we could go ahead and call notify for example.
So now you can call all the methods he'd normally call an object but remember that you don't have to
do this to call get class because when you use the Java class property that's actually what you're doing.
So instead of explicitly calling the get class method you can just use the dot you know use dot Java
class and that will give you the Java class so for example we can do the following.
Dortch Java class and that's the equivalent to calling get class.
So if you want to call anything other than two string equals hash code or get class you have to cast
it to Avodart line that object first.
OK I'm going to put this back to the class so that you have that in the code rangin a commented out
because you really don't need to be calling notify.
All right let's talk about static fields and methods we know we don't declare stuff is static in cotland
So if there is a static method or a field how is that handled when your you want to use a static method
or field from cotland.
Well those are converted to companion objects.
Now you can't pass the companion object around as a value but you can use its members.
So let's add a static field and a static method to our car class so we'll say public she'll do it above
the non-static member.
So I'll say public static and X equals 5 and then we'll add a static method will say public static string
x string and this will return.
This is X and will increment x y one every time this method is called.
Now first static members making it public is is good enough to be able to get and set the field using
the dot notation.
So now I just go back to Scotland and let's use these static members so will say print line X equals
card X
and we'll say print line car got X string.
And if we run
we'll see that that works fine.
So essentially you access static members in Java classes as you would companion objects.
Now one thing I haven't pointed out is X is mutable and so is color and that's because they have setters
so they're mutable.
This doesn't explicitly have a setter but it's public.
So there's nothing to stop anybody from changing it.
OK the last thing we're going to look at when it comes to calling Java from cotland is Sam conversions.
Now Sam stands for single abstract method and as of Java 8 when a Java interface only has a single abstract
method you can use a lambda expression rather than an anonymous instance when you call a method that
wants an instance of the interface.
So for example the Runnable interface is a Sam interface so we can do the following.
So let me go back to our car class here and we'll just add a method all did at the top of the class
and I'll say public void Demel method.
I'm saying you thread new runnable and we'll accept intelligence autocomplete and I'll say system that
outtrump print line.
Mime in a thread.
So runnable only has one method run and so it's a Sam interface.
We're creating an anonymous instance of runnable and we're passing it to the thread constructor and
I'm actually going to call start here.
And so when we start the thread this runnable will be run.
So because this is a Sam interface it has one method we can actually pass a lambda instead of doing
it this way.
So instead of doing this and I'll comment this out so that you will see this in the code we can instead
do the following.
We can say new thread and we're not accepting any parameters for this function.
We're just going to say system not out of print line in a thread don't start.
And so here instead of explicitly constructing a anonymous instance of a runnable we're instead passing
the thread constructor the lambda.
And we're saying that we're passing it essentially a method that doesn't take any parameters and this
is the method body.
So I showed you all this just to say that Cottman functions can be converted to lambdas in the same
way.
So if you want to call a java method that once an object it implements a Sam interface.
So let's say once a runnable instance then you can do that by passing it a Cartland function.
So let's have our demo method except a runnable as a parameter.
So I'll comment this out so you have it in the code.
And let's say that instead of defining it in here let's say we take a runnable are and then we'll just
say new thread or start.
So let's call this method from Cartland now.
So we'll go back to Catlin and will say Kardon demo method and it wants a runnable So we'll we'll just
pass it along and we'll say print line time in a thread that's Arlanda we don't get any errors.
Of course the the function signature has to match whatever this interface is expecting.
So whatever method this interface contains the function signature has to match.
And here we don't have any arguments at all.
So any parameters so we match.
So let's run this.
And here we are.
I'm in a thread.
So there are a few more things to know about when calling Java from cotland but these are the ones that
you're most likely to run into.
So we're going to leave this topic and in the next video we're going to look at calling Katlin from
Java.
So doing it the other way around.