so in the last video we talked about
text files now let's talk about binary
files well as I mentioned right upfront
Kotlin doesn't have its own io classes
it has added some extension functions to
the jdk s io classes to make them easier
to use or more convenient and while it
has added some functions for binary data
there's really only one that's a
convenience function you can call an
extension function called read bytes on
the file class but it reads the file in
one go and then you'd have to parse the
input and it's also limited to a 2gig
file size but when you're reading a
binary file you often just want to read
in each piece of data as you go you
generally don't want to read the entire
file in and to do that the best way is
to just use the Java classes so I'm
going to do it that way in a Kotlin file
just to show you that it works so in
here in the main function I'll say Val
di equals data input stream and we'll go
file input stream and this time we're
going to read a file called test file
dot bin now here there's multiple
possibilities so I'm going to have to
tell the compiler which one I want and I
don't know why it's not finding data
input stream they both try adding that
one manually ok so now we're all good
now this test file dot bin it's the same
file as test file txt except it's been
written out in binary so that's why
you're getting these weird characters
here when you write a string a utf-8
string as a binary string the length of
the string is written before the string
itself so that when you read it back in
you can actually figure out what the
string is otherwise you'd have no way of
knowing how to parse the data that
you're getting
ok so we'll say Val Fi and that's going
to be a string in fact it's going to be
a var because I'm not going to assign it
yet and then we'll say try and we'll say
all really want to type J don't I wall
true can't type today for some reason T
are you there we go
so while true we're going to say F I
equals di da tree UT f the read UT F
function knows when it's reading a UT f
that it there's going to be a length
which is generally 2 bytes long and then
the string and then print line si and
then of course we're going to have to
catch do F exception this is just a
quick and dirty function to show you
that this works so that's why I've got
an infinite loop and we're just going to
rely on an exception being thrown when
we hit end a file to break us out of the
loop so if we go ahead and run this
we'll see that we get our file contents
exactly as we had them before and we did
it using Java dot IO classes inside a
Kotlin file and we didn't have to do
anything special so I just wanted to
show you that you can do that there's
really as I said no great enhancements
to binary file rating most of the sort
of convenience functions and
enhancements have been added for reading
text files and the same goes for object
streams there is no support for those in
Kotlin at all so just go ahead and use
the Java classes and write code as you
normally would of course you would write
it using the hotland
syntax so as you notice here we're not
using new and we're not using system dot
out dot print line etc but you can just
go ahead and use the Java i/o classes
directly from Kotlin and you don't have
to do anything special so that's really
all there is when it comes to reading
files now what about writing files well
we're not going to spend any time at all
on writing files because there really
isn't anything much new in that area
either Kotlin has added writer and
buffered writer extension functions just
as it added reader and buffered reader
but there aren't any functions
equivalent to read text and read lines
because generally you don't write stuff
out in one shot so I'm going to leave it
to you to go
and explore the hotland style package on
your own and see what you can do in
Kotla and see what convenience functions
have been added and as usual you can
just go ahead and use the Java classes
directly so now we're going to take a
look at try with resources so as you
know the usual way to ensure that a
resource which could be a file or some
other type of resource is released when
you're finished with it is to use a
trying a finally block or at least that
was how you used to have to do it
java introduced try with resources so we
could avoid the situation where you have
a dry and then a finally and in the
finally you have to then check whether a
resource instance is null and then you
close it as possible you'll get an
exception then you know the drill we've
all kind of looked at that ugly code and
thought there must be a better way
so try with resources takes care of
closing the resource for us regardless
of whether an exception is thrown or not
we don't have to explicitly do it now
resources do have to implement the
closable interface to work with try with
resources so let's try to code a try
with resources in Kotlin let's try to do
that so I'm going to come down here I'm
going to say try and you know try with
resources you create the instance of the
resource within the try here so I'll say
let's have a file reader and I'll say
file reader equals and you'll see that
we're getting a compile error because
the compiler doesn't have try with
resources in the same way that Java does
so it really doesn't understand what
we're trying to do here now we've
already seen the equivalent in Kotlin of
try with resources and we saw that when
we saw the use function in when we were
reading our text file remember that if a
function has used in its name then it
closes the resource for us and that's
the equivalent of try with resources in
Kotlin so there's use lines which
handles each line in the file but we've
also seen the general use so the
resource that you use to invoke a use
function will be closed when the lambda
finishes executing or if an exception
occurs while the lambda is executing so
instead of using try with resources
writing it out the way you would in in
Java you use one of the use functions
when you want to ensure that a resource
will be closed regardless of what
happens during execution and that's all
I wanted to say about this I just wanted
to make you aware that there is no try
with resources in the way that you would
write it in Java but it does exist in
Kotlin it's just that you code it using
one of the use functions okay so in the
next video we're going to take a look at
walking the file tree we saw when we
looked at the Kotlin that i/o package
that it has added a couple of classes
for that so let's take a look at how to
walk a file tree in Kotlin