Conlin has added extension functions to the file class that can help us walk a file tree and we'll take
a look at them in this video.
The walk function accepts a direction that specifies whether you want to walk up a tree or down a tree
to walk bottom up function walks up a file tree.
And when you walk up a file tree directories are visited after their files.
The walk down function walks down a file tree and in that case the directories are visited before other
files.
So you can use the walk bottom up function or the walk down function or you can use walk and provide
the direction that you want to go.
If you're familiar with Java in this area Java has a file visitor class that does a similar thing to
what Katlin has so we're going to just code a quick example to show how to walk a tree in cotland and
we're going to use the walk top down function to print the names of all the files in a file train we're
just going to use our project directory as the tree.
So we'll start at the project's working directory.
So let's go ahead and we'll say file and here I'm just going to use dot because I want to start at the
working directory which means the directory we're currently in because that's the default directory
when your application runs it runs with the working directory as the current directory.
And analysts say walk walk down and then for each file that we come across We'll just print printer.
So here it will be each file in the tree.
Now the walk functions all return a sequence of files.
So here we're saying that we're going to get a sequence of files back from walk top down.
So each file is going to be evaluated one at a time and we're going to save that for each item in the
sequence which in this case is a file print it.
So let's go ahead and run
and heres our files so we're starting up at.
And then of course is a whole bunch of files under here that we normally don't see because they have
to do with ideas project files and we don't need to know about them and here are some build files and
then we actually have our source files.
And this is our project file.
And if you look at this you can see that because we're walking top down the directories are visited
before the files.
So here you'll see we come into the source directory then Source Academie etc. and only after we've
visited all of the directories and the Java code directory here then we visit the classes in the Java
code directory and there's just one or the file rather There's just one file in here called dummy class
and then we visit the walk file tree directory before we go into it and see the Cottman file that's
in this directory here.
OK so that was pretty easy.
Let's say we only want to print Cartland files so we don't want to print every single file here we just
want to print Cartland files and we know we have one the one that we're actually working on here now
since the walk functions all return a sequence we can treat the result like a sequence and filter out
entries.
So instead of calling for each right away why don't we go ahead and filter.
So and all I can do this on a nother line just to make this clear so we'll say filter.
So we only want file names or paths if you want to look at it that way.
That and with the DOT t extension.
So we'll say for each file reach path we want t dot name to end with Dot.
And then for anything that passes the filter I don't know if I'll be able to get the oh there we go
the invitation right.
And it turned out to be simple so for each file that passes the filter we want to print it out.
So this should be familiar to to you from looking at changing functions together.
When we were using sequences because essentially this returns a sequence returns a sequence of files.
So let's go ahead and run now.
And now we just get our one file that has the extension Katy.
Now if you to do something before or after each directory is entered you can use the On Enter and on
leave functions the on enter function takes a lambda that returns a boolean and if false is returned
a directory will be skipped.
And that's really all there is to walking the file tree.
You can take a look at the documentation for the file tree walk class to see what functions are available.
And as you can see you can actually do a lot if you chain functions together as because the lock functions
return sequences.
So you can go ahead and do quite a bit on each file in the sequence before you execute a terminal operation.
And that's all we're going to cover for IO because Katlin really doesn't have its own IO classes and
has just added some convenience extension functions there isn't really a lot to talk about when it comes
to Cartland and Io.
However you did see in the last video that we were using the Java classes directly and that's because
as I said at the top of the Course Katlin was designed with Java interoperability in mind and so in
the next section we're going to look at that we're going to look at when you do have to do something
special when you want to use Cartland from Java or Java from Cartland.
So we'll see if they're.