[Music]
Okay I just wanted to do a quick video
on type aliases, because they're related
to variable declarations type aliases
were introduced in Kotlin 1.1 and they
let you use another name for an existing
type, maybe the name will make more sense
for how you're using it in your
application or maybe you just want to
save on typing because as we know by now,
Kotlin really really wants to cut down
on the amount of typing we do and type
aliases are another way to do it. They're
especially useful when dealing with
generic types. Now one thing to stress is
type aliases or an alias for an existing
data type, so when you use them you're
not creating a brand new data type,
you're basically just assigning an alias
to an existing data type. So let's take a
look at string builder, because that's
actually type alias in Kotlin. So if I
type in string builder, and then I'm
going to go to the declaration and
you'll see that the declaration is a
type alias and also it says since Kotlin 1.1
because as I mentioned they were
type aliases were only introduced in Kotlin 1.1.
So, we have string builder and it's
actually an alias for java.lang.stringbuilder.
So what this means is
whenever you use string builder in your
common code you're actually using our
good friend java.lang.stringbuilder.
Kotlin does not have its own
string builder class, so let's say that
we use a set of employee throughout our
application and we don't like to type
set angle bracket employee for some
reason, we just want to be able to type
employee set or maybe even just
employees. So we'd want to declare a type
alias for that, I'm going to get rid of
this and this just because I don't like
to see errors, you always declare type
aliases at the top level so you declare
them outside of any functions or classes
and as you saw, you just type type alias
and then you type the alias that you
want to use so we want to use employee set
and then you just need to put equals and
then the type that you are creating
alias for. So we're saying that in this
file wherever we would use set employee,
we just want to type employee set for
some reason we hate typing these angle
brackets and then we can go ahead and
start using it like we can say you know
val employees of type employee set and
you'll see that the intelli sense that
comes up knows about these type aliases
and so IntelliJ is now smart enough to
suggest this type to you so you can
start using it just like any other data type.
Now, if you wanted to use your type
alias outside this file, you'd have to
import it into any files where you want
it to use it, that's just par for the course.
I'll see you in the next video!