In this video, we're going to go ahead
and download and install the Java
development kit also known as the JDK.
We're going to install it on Linux
specifically we're going to install it
on ubuntu 16.04, so if you're running a
different version of Linux, you should be
able to follow along and do something
similar for your distro and also keep in
mind if you're running on a Windows
machine or a Mac computer
we've actually got separate videos for
your operating systems because the
process is slightly different. We've run
the Linux machine follow along because
you're in the right place. Alright so the
first thing we want to do is open up a
command window, so I'm just going to open
a terminal, let's go in to bring that in
and just enlarge it a little bit and
what we'll do first is we'll do a sudo
space apt - get space update, this will
update the package index type in your
password, another moment to complete,
you can see that was pretty quick so next
thing we're going to do now is type sudo
space add - apt - repository space ppa colon
webupd8team forward slash java
give that a moment to complete as enter
once that's finished, we a sudo space
apt - get space update.
Once it's finished, we're going to do
sudo space apt - get space install space
Oracle space Java 8 - installer and
it'll go to press yes there, select yes
and press enter or select why I should
say type it anyway and then we going to
go through this little configuration
guide, so I'm going to press enter and do
we accept the Oracle binary code license
terms? Yes to that, I'm going to press
enter, you can see that they're going
away downloading the JDK, so give that a
moment to complete I'm just going to
fast forward this video to the end of
the download.
Now the download complete, you can see it's
just finishing the configuration and
that's now complete,
and what we'll do now is we'll type in
sudo space update
- alternatives two minus signs, two dashes in
other words, config space Java and you
can see that there's an option there,
we can select any of those but the correct
option is showing for me you can see
that it shows Java 8 Oracle, so depending
on your installation of Linux, you might
have other versions of the Java
open JDK or a different version of Java
so you could select the relevant option,
but in this case the default option is
correct and we're good to go
so I'm just going to press ENTER then to
not do anything and the last thing to do
is to type in Java space -v, will try
and -- version, Java space - version that's what I was
trying to do the first time and that
deal confirms that I would successfully
installed Java and you can see that it
shows that we're running in this
particular case build
25.1 44 or you can see on the previous
line up here build one point 8.0
underscore 144. So this number here may
be different for you, 144 indicates the
build release of in this case, the
Java development kit version 8, but the
point is that we're good to go, so let's
know downloaded it and installed
correctly and what we can do, we'll check
that Java is on there we can type in Java C
which is a Java compiler just to
confirm that that actually worked and
that's part on the Java development kit
and if you see that, let's come up as
well and if we wanted to we could do the
same thing with the version, so obviously
one point eight point zero underscore
one four four, so in other words we've
got our Java development kit installed
and we can proceed down and move on to
the next video.