Alright, it's time to take a closer
look at functions, we've been writing and
using them, but we haven't really
discussed anything about them. However,
since we've discussed the primary
constructor, you'll already be familiar
with some of this, but it's always good
to review. Now first of all, a bit of
terminology I mentioned this before when
a function is a member of a class, it's
usually referred to as a method or as a
member function, but the syntax for
functions is the same whether they're
declared inside or outside a class.
So sometimes I'll use the term method for
functions because I have one foot in the
Java world other times I say function
but you'll know what I mean, method
function, you'll know what I'm talking about.
So you know what a function is, but let's
take a closer look at how to declare
them. I've got the main method or the
main function rather up here, so as you
know, you start with the keyword fun and
you follow it with the function name.
Next comes the parameter list, now one
thing I haven't mentioned is that the
default return type for a function is
unit, we discussed this earlier and
because it's the default, you don't have
to explicitly specify it, so you don't
have to go like this unit, again Kotlin
is trying to save you typing, so if
you're not returning anything, you're
actually returning unit, but you don't
have to explicitly specify it. So let's
add another function that accepts a
string and two integers and all it's
going to do is multiply the integers
together and then return a string with
the result and it'll use the string
parameter as a label within the returned result.
So we'll say fun and we'll call this
label, label multiply and as I said it
accepts three parameters so it accepts
operand one which is an int
operand two which is also an inr and then
it accepts a label, which is a string and
in this case, it's going to return a
string. So we'll add that to the end of
the function. Now, as I mention the return
type comes at the end of the signature
which makes sense,
I mean given how we declare variables,
so the return type is always at the end
following a colon. Okay, so let's write
our function. So we'll say return label
because we're going to label our result
using the label that we passed in and
then we'll use an expression here,
so we'll say operand 1 times operand 2 and
that's it, that's our function. Now we'll
call it from the main function, so we'll
say print line label multiply and
we'll pass in three four and the result
is for our label. We'll run and we'll see
the result is 12, there's nothing
earth-shattering going on here and in
fact I don't actually need the blank
here, because it's here, so I'll remove it.
Now we can simplify this code further
because hey it Kotlin. Now because our
function consists of one expression
essentially, we're just returning
something here, we can write it on one
line as follows,
instead of putting this inside a block,
we can just say equals we can remove the
return keyword and we can take this away
as well and then we don't really need
the brackets now, because we're no longer
using return. So that's it, that's our
simplified function. So what we're saying
here is the function is returning
whatever comes after the equal sign.
So in this case the function is going to
return this string, we'll run and we'll
see the same result as before, so if all
your function is doing is returning the
result of an expression, you can dispense
with the curly braces in the return and
because of that we can actually remove
the return type here, because now the
compiler can infer it. And so we've
simplified the function even further now.
We don't need the return type,
the compiler can tell that oh you're going
to return a string, you don't need to
explicitly tell me that. Now here's some
terminology functions with curly braces have what's
called a block body. And functions
without curly braces that are doing what
we're doing here, just saying equals and
returning something, they have what's
called an expression body, so you'll hear
those two terms used a function with a
block body will have curly braces and
obviously it's going to be doing a
little bit more probably has more than
one line of code in it and functions
that don't have curly braces that
essentially just say equals and have an
expression, they have an expression body.
Now once again, I'll just say what about
functions that don't return anything?
We discussed the unit type back when we
covered data types and it's equivalent
to void, but let's cut to the chase here
as I mentioned before, you don't have to
explicitly state that a function returns
unit, in that case you can just leave off
the return type, that's actually what the
main function is doing as I showed you
before, there's no return data type
specified, because the function doesn't
return anything, but officially speaking
is return type of unit. Now you might
think that because the main function
doesn't return anything, it can't have an
expression body, it actually can in this
case. If we do this, we'll see that we
don't get any errors and if we run we'll
see that it still works. Now, the reason
this is working is because this print
line doesn't actually return anything,
the type of the function body and the
type of the function, the return type of
the function they actually match, because
print line isn't an expression and so
this actually works, but if we were to do
something like the following fun
whatever equals 3 times 4, you'll see
that works obviously, I mean this
whenever we call this function, we're
going to get 12, but if we were to say
that this returns nothing, now we get an
error, because it's saying that it
requires unit, but it is returning an int.
So we'd have to let the compiler infer
here or we could put an int
here it's working, because this returns
nothing, which is the unit and this also
returns nothing. So it kind of looks
funny but it works. I'll take this out
because that's not in the spirit of
Kotlin. Okay, so let's bring in an
employee class, we love our employee
class and we'll use a first name again
and we'll make it a string and then
inside our class, let's add a function
and we'll call it fun upper case first
name, this is a really stupid function
because obviously we could just probably
do this directly, but let's let's roll
with it. All it does is to upper case is
the name and as you can see here we're
using a function with an expression body,
we don't have any curly braces now, as
you know this function will be public
and final by default just like
everything else in Kotlin. So let's call
it from the main function, I'm going to
revert back to what we had before,
because obviously now, I'm going to be
doing more than just print lining one
thing and we'll create an input employee
val emp equals employee and this time
let's give the employee the name Jane
and then we'll call our function.
So let's say print line emp dot uppercase
first-name. Now, as you can see member
functions are called just like methods
in Java, you just use the instance and
follow it with a period and then the
function name and that's all I wanted to
show you, for this just as with the
primary constructor, we can use default
parameter values as functions. So let's
change the label multiply functions so
it provides a default label, I'm going to
put this on another line so things don't
get too crowded and we'll give it the
label the answer is, so that will be our
default label. And now if we go back up
to where we're calling it and we remove
the label that we passed,
and we run and we'll see that now we get
the answer is 12 and also we now see
Jane and uppercase from our upper case
first name call. Now, you might think that
when we assign a default value to a
parameter, the compiler can infer the
type and so it's okay to leave it off,
but if we try that, so if we say no let's
do that, you'll see that we get an error
and it will say a type annotation is
required on a value parameter, so when it
comes to function parameters, we always
have to include the type, even if the
compiler can infer it, too bad. We have to
include it, so we'll add it back. Now as
we saw in the last video, when we were
looking at data classes in Kotlin, you
can associate parameter values with
names, when you call a function which
lets you specify the parameters in any
order you want. So if we want it to, we
could mix up the parameter orders in our
label multiply call, so back in the
main function, we could do something like
this, we could say label multiply and we
want to specify the label first, so we're
going to say label equals, here's the
result and then we want to put for some
reason, some strange reason we want three
to be operand 2 and we want 4 to be
operand 1 and so we're passing the
parameters essentially in reverse order.
Now, once you've put one parameter out of
order, you have to use names for all of
them, obviously, I mean if you know once
you've done this, the compilers not going
to have a clue what's going on
afterwards in terms of which number is
supposed to go with which parameter.
So let's run and we'll see that we get here
is the result 12, so because we've
labeled our parameters,
the compiler didn't have any problem at all
matching them up with the function
parameters. Now this might not seem all
that useful, but it can be when you have
lots of parameters of the same type,
mean for example, if you had a function
that takes 10 integers, if you see a
function call like this, you know
function call 1 2 5 8,
whatever these aren't matching
what I'm saying, let's say six parameters
somebody coming to look at your code
later or even you coming to look at your
code later, we'll have absolutely no clue
what these parameters actually
correspond to. I mean are they heights
weights, widths, you know what are they?
And so rather than commenting the code,
you could use name parameters even if you're
not calling the function with the
parameters out of order, so in a way it's
another way to document your code.
Now, the official name for this and Kotlin is
named arguments, so if you hear or read
about named arguments, this is what is
being referred to, calling the function
and labeling your arguments in the
function call. Okay, so just as in Java you
can also have functions that accept an
arbitrary number of arguments and you do
this using the var arg keyword, so let's
take a look at how this works, we'll
create a function that accepts some
number of cars and prints out all their
colors, so you'll remember our car class
from the last video, I'm going to add it
back, won't take me long because it's the
data class and we'll say color val color
string, I think we had val model string
and val your int. So there you go, with
just that amount of typing we get our
data class back.
So let's now create a function that
accepts some number of cars and prints
out all their colors, so we can say fun
print colors and it'll take some number
of cars and then, I'll say for car in cars
print the color. So a pretty simple
function, so when you're using var args,
you give the parameter name and then a
type nothing, new there
that's the order in Kotlin. So let's call
the function with three cars, so back in
our main function,
I'll get rid of this and we'll say print
colors and we'll have to create three
cars here, so and actually I'll do this
outside, so that we can reuse them so
I'll say val car 1 equals car blue
Toyota 2015 val car to equals car let's
make this one red and when we can it a ford
and we'll say it's a 2016 and then val
car 3 equals car gray, we'll make this
one a ford too and we'll make it as 2017.
So, let's print the colors for all these
cars and let's run and we'll see blue
red and gray printed. Now you can only
have one var arg parameter in a function
signature, so we can't do something like
this, we can't say oh we want this and
then we want another set of something
else, I don't know another x of type
string, let's say, you can't do that, it'll
say multiple of our arg parameters are
prohibited. So you can only have one use
of the var arg keyword within a function
signature. Now, because we have named
parameters in Kotlin, the var arg
argument does not have to be the last
argument, but if it isn't then you have
to use name parameters when you call
the function. So let's shake up this
function signature a bit, we'll also have
and just of strength called string here.
So we've added another parameter and but
the var arg one is actually the first
parameter and then if we go back to our
print colors, you'll see that we now have
an error because we haven't passed the last
parameter and to do so, we now have to
use a name parameter here. So we have to
say str equals and I'll just say color,
we're not using it, but now you can
understand why you have to do that
because if you don't and let's say this
was actually string, for example then if
you had a bunch of strings here,
the compilers not going to know which ones
belong to the var arg, so you need to
give it a hint here and say these three
are the ones that I want to pass to the
var arg and then here's the string
parameter. So keep that in mind that if
the var arg argument is not the last argument in the
function signature, then you have to use
name parameters. So if we did this the
other way, if instead we put the var arg
at the end, so I'll just temporarily
change this, now we can put color here
and remove it from here and that works
now, we don't have to use name parameters.
Now a lot of functions related to
collections use var arg, you've already
seen a few that you use when working
with arrays, for example the array of
function can take an arbitrary number of
arguments, so if we do something like val
numbers equals array of 1 2 3, this is
actually using a var arg, because you can
have any number of arguments here and if
we take a look at the signature for
array of by going to go to declaration,
you'll see right here that it's using a
var arg, so a lot of functions in the
collections classes use var arg. So now
that we know about var arg, we can
discuss what's called the spread
operator, so let's create an array of car
objects this time, so we'll say val many
cars equals array of
and we'll put our three cars in there.
So, we now have an array of three cars.
Now, let's say we want to call the print
colors function, I'm actually going to
remove the string parameter now, so I'll
remove it from up here as well, so we
have an array of cars and we want to
call this function, if we pass the array
will the function be smart enough
to loop through all the array elements?
Well, it won't be in fact if we try to do
it so we'll say print colors many cars,
will get an error and it'll say there's
a type mismatch, now what's it saying
it's saying that it wants a car and it
found an array of car so here at once a
car and it found an array of car,
now, this differs from Java, because in Java
we could just pass the array, but we
can't do that in Kotlin. So what do we do
in this situation? What do we do when we
have a function that's expecting a var
arg and we have an array and we want to
pass the array to that function?
Well, this is where the spread operator comes
in, the spread operator will unpack the
array and pass the elements as
individual arguments, the spread operator
is the asterisk, so all we have to do is
add an asterisk in front of the array
here and the error goes away, we run
we'll see that we get the colors printed
and they're being printed twice,
of course because we're also calling it up
here. Now you're not limited to using the
spread operator for this purpose, you can
use it any time you need to unpack an
array, for example let's say you have two
arrays of cars and you want to combine
them into a single array and you want to
add another car to the array too. So if
we do this val more cars equals and
we'll say array of and we'll just use
car two and car three, even though
they're duplicates essentially and then
we'll make another
car, we'll call it car four and we'll
just copy car two, so now we want to
combine many cars with more cars and we
want to add car four as well, so we can
do the following, we can say val lots of
cars equals array of many cars, more cars
and car four and to check that we now
have an array with all these cars in it,
we can say for c in lots of cars and we'll
print line c, so let's run and you'll see
that what we've actually done here is we
have an array of three elements,
the first element is an array the second
element is an array and the third
element is car four, so that's what
we've done here, but we didn't want that,
what we wanted was, we wanted an array
with car one, car two car three from many
cars car two and car three from more
cars and then car four. So what we should
have done was use the spread operator,
in front of our two arrays and what will
happen is when we do the array of the
elements in this array will be unpacked
and the elements of this array will be
unpacked, so we'll end up with an array
of seven cars or six cars actually which
is what we wanted, rather than creating
an array where a couple of the elements
are just the arrays we had before. So now,
if we run, we'll see that we get an array
of six cars, so that's another use for
the spread operator, whenever you want to
unpack an array and get at the
individual elements rather than using
the array itself, an easy way to do that
is to use the spread operator. Alright,
I'll see you in the next video where
we'll continue our discussion of functions.