Now let's talk about one of the cool
features of Kotlin called extension
functions. Now extension functions let
you extend any class you want to extend.
However, when I say extend I mean that
you can add functions to it, you're not
extending the class in the sense that
you'll be subclassing it, so don't panic
because you think encapsulation can be
broken. Extension functions are syntactical
illusion, nothing more. So let's
take a look at them, so we're going to
create another class in our file called
utils and we'll add a few functions to it.
In Kotlin, we just use top-level
functions for this, but I want to sort of
do it the Java way. So I'll create
another Kotlin file in our package and
I'll call it utils.
Okay and in here I'll create a class,
nothing earth-shattering so far. Okay, so
let's say that we want to add a function,
utility function that upper case is the
first and last letter in a string,
so let's go. So start with fun and we'll
call it upper first and last, it'll take
a string and it's going to return a
string, so we'll say val upper first
equals and this is going to be we're
going to start at the beginning of the
string and we're going to take the first
letter number whatever in the string.
So substring 01 because remember what
substring it- the second parameter is
exclusive. So this is giving us the first
position in the string and then we're
going to uppercase it. So that's our
first letter uppercase and then we're
going to append
the rest of the string to it, so this
time you want to start at position 1.
So again we're taking the string,
we're upper casing the first letter and
then we're appending the next string to
it, so we've taken care of our first
letter, now we've got to take care of the
last letters, so we'll
return upper first and then we'll take
the substring of zero upper first dot
length minus one, so this is taking the
first, the string all the way to
everything but the last character.
Okay, that's what this first part is doing and
then to that we're going to append and
now we need the last character, we have
to uppercase the last character, so we'll
say upper first dot substring and this
time, we'll say upper first dot length
minus one so we're starting at the last
character upper first dot length and we
need to to uppercase it to uppercase and
that's it. So, this function here upper
takes a string, uppercases the first
letter, uppercases the last letter and
then returns the result. Now it's common
in Java to have static utility classes
that just contain a bunch of static
methods that do things like this,
there might be a utilities class for
file io for manipulating strings and
I'm sort of simulating that here
in Kotlin, so any Kotlin file can import
this class and use this function .
So let's go back to our functions, guy here
and we'll call that, we'll call our
function. So we'll say utils and we have
to create an instance in the class and
then we'll call upper first and last and
let's say this is all in lowercase and
let's print out the result. Now we'll run
and we'll see that the first and the
last letter of the string have been
uppercase, so we know that our utility
function is working okay and of course
as I said, this is kind of simulating the
Java way because you'd have a utility
class with a bunch of static functions
because of course in Java code can't
appear outside of classes and then
the rest of the application would use the utility
function. Now in Kotlin, you could do this,
I mean you could do what we've just done,
but another way you could do it is to
use an extension function. So let's say
you have a class and all it does is adds
a bunch of functions that manipulate
strings, so let's say this utils class
had you know four or five or six or
however many functions that just do
stuff like this with strings, instead of
doing this, it would be great if you
could just add those functions to the
string class, now of course you can't
because you don't own the source code
for the string class, so you can't go in
there and say well I'm just going to add
these functions in here but you can
create the illusion of adding those
functions to the string class and you
use extension functions to do that.
So I'm going to remove this function from
the utils class, in fact I'll eventually
delete this class and let's instead add
an extension function to our functions
file, so I'll copy and paste this to give
us a good start just paste it in here
and now let's create this as an
extension function, so all we have to do
is put string dot in front of the name
here, so we're now saying that we want to
associate this function with the string
class. Now that's not all we have to do
of course, because we're associating this
with a string class, we no longer have to
take the string as a parameter because
we're going to call this function using
a string instance as we would for
example called string to uppercase,
so instead of saying you know upper first
and last str, we're going to say str dot
upper first and last, so what do we do
here? What do we do with these instances?
Well, when you have an extension function
like this, you refer to the instance that
you're using to call it, using this
so all we have to do is change these to
this, the str instances so now what
happens is when we use str to call this,
str will be substituted in here, I mean
it's really being passed as a parameter
under the covers as I said, this is all an illusion
but it makes it look like the upper
first and last function actually belongs
to the string class. So now let's go
ahead and change our code to just call
this as if it's part of the string class
instead of having to do utils blah
blah blah, we can just go like this.
Let's put our string into a variable equals
this is all in lowercase and then we can
delete that from here, we no longer have
to pass it as a parameter and we can
just say s here. So it looks like the
upper first and last function belongs to
the string class but it doesn't, we're
just kind of piggybacking our function
on to the string class using some
syntactical trickery. So what we've done
here is we've preceded the function name
with what's called the receiver type,
so here, string is the receiver type and
this is the class that were pseudo
extending and one thing that you'll
notice here is if I go s dot, IntelliJ
will now suggest our function to us,
so if we say upper here it is, upper first
and last. So this is an advantage of
using an extension function is the IDE
or at least IntelliJ will now start
suggesting this function to you as if it
is part of the class, so it's all this
great illusion that's created to make
things easier for us. So let's go ahead
and run, we should see the same thing we
did before and we do we have our first
letter uppercased our last letter uppercased.
Now, in this example our string s,
it's the receiver object, so string is the
receiver type, it's the type that we're
pseudo extending and the object that we
use to call the extension function is
called the receiver object, so if you see
those two terms being discussed that's
what they mean. Now, we can actually drop
the use of this in the function body.
I want it to explicitly use it first so
you'd understand what's happening in
here, so what's happening in here is
we're calling the upper first and last
extension function using s and so in the
body, s is substituted here as if you
passed it in as a parameter but in this
case, we can actually just remove it and
we'll you'll see that if we run
everything runs as it did before, we have
our first letter uppercase in our last
letter uppercase so this is really
concise and as I said it's a big
illusion, it's making it appear as if the
upper first and last function belongs to
the string class when in fact it doesn't.
It's something that we've tacked on to
the string class. Now your development
team could define extension functions
that everyone uses and when you create
an extension function, you can use this,
as we saw above but you can also access
any public members by name. So if you
were creating an extension function for
a class that had you know five public
properties or members, you could
reference those by name within the body.
So as long as something is public inside
the class that you're tacking the
extension function onto, you can
reference it in the extension functions
body and of course you can reference
this because you'll always be calling
extension function using an object of
the receiver type. So you can use this
and you can also reference public
members within the receiver type.
Now Kotlin uses extension functions quite a
lot, in fact if you look at the Kotlin
standard library, you'll see that a lot
of the functions in there are actually
extension functions to the JDK, so Kotlin
has pseudo extended some of the classes
in the jdk and it's done that using
extension functions and we'll see that
when we cover io in Kotlin. So this is a
pretty cool feature, some developers
worry that it might lead to some lazy
coding, for example instead of people
writing code and using subclasses where
they should, that they might instead just
tack on extension functions but I guess
time will tell how these extension
functions are used
and whether developers go that route
when they shouldn't be. I think it's a
pretty cool feature, the only thing that
might be confusing to a developer that's
not familiar with the code if somebody
might come along and actually actually
think your extension function is part of
the class, but you know it's easy enough
to just do something like this in the
IDE and say go to the declaration and
then you can see right away that oh okay
it's an extension function, so I don't
think that's a big deal. Anyway, that's it
for functions. I'll see you in the next video.