Alright, so this is going to be a
shortish video, we're just going to
quickly have a look at sets. Now they're
similar to lists, except you can't have
duplicate items and you create them the
same way that you create lists and maps,
you can use the set of an immutable set
of functions. Now under the covers, you'll
get a linked hash set instance I'm not
going to go over creating them since you
now know enough and you can experiment
with how to create them on your own, but
let's quickly look at a set of ints to
see some of the Kotlin functions that
are available to you. So I'm going to do
this at the top of the main function,
so that whatever we print will show up
first and we'll say val set int equal
set of and I'll say 10 15 19 5 3 and
minus 22 and now let's add an element to
the set, so we'll say set will print out
the set actually after we do this so
we'll say set ints dot plus 20 and so
this is how you add an element into a
set and let's run now, and we'll see we
get our set printed. So now let's add
another 10 to the set and you can
probably guess what's going to happen
plus 10 and let's run and we get the
same set because sets can contain
duplicate elements. Now you'll notice
that when we added the 20 this did not
change the set because this set is
immutable, so when we printed out the
result of set ints dot plus 20 the set includes
the 20, but we didn't actually assign the
new set to anything, so when we add try
to add the 10, 20 is not going to be in
that set so it still doesn't have it.
Okay, so now let's try removing 19
from the set and see what we get so
we'll say print line set ints dot minus
19 and let's run and see what this gives
us and now we have a set that doesn't
have 19 in it. Now as I pointed out, we're
not really adding and removing the
elements, because this set is immutable
and we're not assigning the result to
anything, we're just printing it.
Okay, let's try to remove an element that
doesn't exist,
so we'll say print line set ints dot minus
and we'll try to get rid of 100,
let's run and as probably guess
nothing happens. Alright, so let's say
we want to get the average value in the
set, well we can say print line set ints dot
average, let's go ahead and run that and
we'll see that the average is 5.0 and you'll
also notice that the result is a double.
Okay, so how about guessing what this
will do? We'll say print line set ints dot
drop 3, what do you think that's going to
do? Take a look at our set and think
about that for a minute before I run,
I guess there are a few possibilities here,
we could be saying to remove the integer 3,
we could be saying to remove the
integer at index 3,
so that would be removing 5 or we could
be saying let's run and now look at our
set, we only have 5 3 and minus 22,
so what we're actually saying here is to
drop the first three elements from the
set and that's what we did. So now let's
briefly take a look at a mutable set,
so I'll say val mutable int equals mutable
set of and I'll say 1 2 3 4 5, so now
let's add another value like we did
before, so we'll say immutable int
actually will print this, so let's say
actually no we'll do this on a separate
line, I'll say mutable int dot plus 10
and now let's print mutable ints,
so we'll run and once again you'll see that
even though the list is mutable, we're
not changing it when we call the dot
plus function because the dot plus
function doesn't change the original
collection, it returns a result, so that's
why I wanted to actually do this in two
separate steps, to show you that even
though this set is mutable the plus
function doesn't work directly on the
set and the same thing is true of the
minus functions, they're defined as part
of the immutable set interface and again
that's something to be aware of
if you're writing code and collections
function doesn't seem to be changing
the collection when you think it should be
then check the declaration of that
function to see whether it actually
operates on a set, another way of looking
at it or on the collection another way
of doing it is to find out what
interface the function belongs to,
the function might belong to the immutable
interface because pretty much all the time
when you're dealing with a mutable and
immutable collection, the mutable
interface is a sub interface of the
immutable interface, so it contains all
of the functions that you can do on
immutable, the immutable collection as well
as additional things you can do on the
mutable collection, so when it comes to
sets, the plus and minus functions are
part of the immutable, immutable set
interface and by the way drop works with
all types of collections. Now there's
another group of collections that don't
implement the collections interface,
they're called sequences and we're going
to cover them later on but what I want
to show you next is some of the cooler
stuff you can do with the collections
classes in Kotlin and we're going to
look at that in the next video.