In this video we're going to go ahead
and download and install IntelliJ IDEA
which is the editor slash IDE that we're
going to be using in this course and
we're going to be doing it for a Linux
platform, specifically a bunch of Linux
16.04. Now if you're running
Windows or a Mac, you'd want to check out
the other videos or the videos that
we've set up for both operating systems
in this section of the course and that's
because the process of installation is
slightly different, but if you run Linux
this is the correct video, so the first
thing to do is open up Firefox or your
browser of choice, we want to go to the
JetBrains website, jetbrains.com and
once we get there we will need to go to
the page where we can download IntelliJ.
Usually you'll see that option
here on the screen because it's one of
their most popular products JetBrains is
the company that have created this
product, so either select it there or
what they don't see that for some reason
come up here into IDEs and IntelliJ
will usually be the first option or very
close to the first option, so go to that
page then click on download and what I'm
going to do is start the download for
the Community Edition and while that's
downloading, we'll come back to this page
and just talk about the ultimate and
community editions and what differences
there are between the two, what I'm going
to do first to save that though and
we'll go into my downloads folder,
you know I'll just go back here to mention
so we can have a bit of a look at the
two options, we've got the Ultimate
Edition as well as the Community Edition.
Now the Community Edition which I'm
downloading is the free and open-source
version and you never have to pay with
that option, so if you want to go ahead
and use that option, it's a good option
and it will certainly work well in this
course, the ultimate edition does come with
a trial, however if after that trial
period if you still want to use it you
will need to pay for it and the
difference between the two is that the
Ultimate Edition has extra features it's
really good for other things other than
standard languages, so it's good for Java
Enterprise Edition and you can see here
are the frameworks and databases and so
on and so forth, so what you can do is
if you decide to try out the Ultimate
Edition, you can try that out for 30 days,
the JetBrains people give you a 30 day
trial to try that out and you could
always come back and download the
community edition later but again either
edition will work and if you want to
try out the Ultimate Edition you can, but
in my case, you saw me download the
community edition. Alright, so let's go
ahead now and install the version that
we've downloaded and over here I can see
now that my version is finished so I'm
going to just open that and go into the
folder where it was actually downloaded.
Well actually what I'll do is I'll just
come down here and close this browser
down and we can see that it's in the
downloads folder and I'm just going to
put this software in a folder on my
computer, so I'm going to first open it
with archive manager and then what I'm
going to do is come back to my home
folder and I'm gonna create a folder for
my apps, so I'm gonna click on new folder
and I'm gonna call that dev and this
is going to be the folder where I'm
gonna put IntelliJ. Now, you are of course
free to put this software or wherever
you like but that's the location where
I'm going to be running it from, once
you've done that, you've selected the
folder where you want it to go, you come
back over here and then you can
literally just click on that and drag it
over and that will move the files into
that location for us then once that's
finished, we can close down both of these
windows and we now want to go into
terminal, so I'm going to click on
terminal, so you go into terminal or
command prompt whatever it's called on
your installation of Linux, they want to
navigate now to that folder, so I'm gonna
go to CD in my case I have a look at the
current folder I'm in my home folder I'm
going to click on CD dev and if we have
a look there by typing ls you can see
that there's the installation of IDEA,
so I'm just going to type in CD space and
then the folder name and then I can go
into the bin folder, so CD space bin,
they have a look at that again and you
can see that there's various files there,
the one we want to start is idea dot sh,
so I'm going to type dot forward slash
IDEA to start up and the first time you
load install you actually start IntelliJ IDEA,
it's a gives you a prompt to sort in
import settings, so if you've got an
existing version of IntelliJ, you can
import the settings and particularly if
you've customized it and you changed
maybe perhaps played around with fonts
and other things can be a good way to
stop your having to re set everything up
again from scratch, in my case though
I haven't got any settings to import so
I'm going to select this option and
that's probably the option you'll choose
in most cases because you probably
haven't had IntelliJ installed on your
computer before, so click on ok and we
need to accept the privacy policy by
clicking on accept, you've got some
options as to how you want the theme or
what the theme is for IntelliJ and you
can see if I select it, we see different
options I'm going to choose IntelliJ
that a standard option with the white
background but you'll choose whichever
one you feel is appropriate and keep in
mind you can always come down here to
to go back to settings within IntelliJ
appearance and behavior appearance and
change that at a later time if you feel
you need to, once you've done that click
on next. Now we want to automatically
create a desktop entry for us, so that we
don't have to go to terminal - command
prompt to start IntelliJ each time so
I'm going to leave that ticked and get
it to do that and again in settings
later on, you can come back to tools
create desktop entry if you want to do
that in the future and you don't want to
do it now for some reason so I'm going
to leave that option selected I'm not
going to create it for all you users if
you wanted to for some reason, you can
click on that checkbox, click on next
now you can't use IntelliJ from the
command line if you want, you can invoke
it and that's an option if you want to
I'm going to click on that even
though we probably won't be doing that
in the course, it's actually there for
you just to do if you want click on next.
Now we've got a number of plugins that
you can configure and some of these are
actually configured already, so you can
enable them or disable them or customize
them, I'd suggest generally you leave
everything else is because you can
always go back in again later and
configure what add plugins at any time.
So I'm going to leave everything as is
there just what other thing to keep in
mind is if you're running the Ultimate
Edition and not the Community Edition,
then I'm installing you probably will
have extra options there because of the
extra functionality that's the
ultimate edition of IntelliJ gives you.
In my case, I'm not going to do anything
I'm just going to click on next and
we've got some other options to download
some featured plugins, we're not going to
be using those plugins in this course
either, so I'm just going to click on
start using IntelliJ IDEA. I need
to enter my password now and that's to
set up the launcher, installer click on
authenticate and IntelliJ should
start, as you can see it's starting.
Okay, so now we've installed
IntelliJ there's a few settings we need
to configure, so to do that we're gonna
come over here and click on configure
come down here to project defaults and
select project structure, what we need to
do is configure a project SDK, if I click
on that at the moment, you can see
clearly there's no SDK defined, so what
we need to do now is associate the java
development kit that we installed in a
previous video with IntelliJ, so to do that
we're going to click on new and come
over here and select JDK. Now what should
happen is that IntelliJ will find the
Java development kit for us
automatically and you can see in this
particular case it did, if for some
reason that doesn't find that for you
automatically, you may need to go ahead
and manually choose the location and
choose the home directory, but in my case
again you can see that that's founded ok
so I don't need to do anything else to
do other than clicking on ok and you can
see once I've done that this has now
changed and we've got the Java version
showing now and if for some reason it
still wasn't selected make sure that you
have got that selected up there the
other thing here that we want to have
selected is the SDK default that is
selected to the latest source,
it isn't using the latest version which
is correct, so we don't need to make any
changes to that and incidentally I
didn't mention earlier but if by chance
you got to the screen and you couldn't
see the option that I could see, project
is the option that you'd select to see
those on the screen. Alright so I'm going
to click on ok now and there's a few
other little minor options we now need
to configure, so let's go ahead and do
those, if you can't configure and click
on settings and what we want to do is
open up here down under editor
expand that list of options and then
under general, do the same thing click on
that firstly we wanna click on auto
import we would have click on or add the
check box click the check box for add
an ambiguous imports on the fly and
then the check box we should click for
optimise imports on the fly.
So click on apply to that and then come
down here to appearance and we want to
make sure that show line numbers is
checked and you can see that by default
it is checked but if for some reason
it's not make sure you do check it there
but you can see in my case it is,
I'm going to click on ok,
at that point we've now finished the
configuration for IntelliJ IDEA, what I am
going to do now is close this down and
I'm going to close down in the command
line the terminal and we should be able
to come over here and if we have a look
for IntelliJ, you can see that IntelliJ
is now appearing there as a desktop
shortcut, so I can click on that and
that's how I can go ahead and
install or run rather IntelliJ IDEA in the future
and you can see that it started fine.
Alright, so that's it that's the
installation and configuration of
IntelliJ IDEA.
Let's now move on to the next video.