OK so now we're going to talk about sequences.
Now we've seen how we can change functions like map and filter together.
And when we do this there's a collection's instance created at each step.
So let's remind ourselves of what we did we did print line and map and what we wanted to do was we wanted
to find the colors for all of the Fords.
And so we started out by filtering to find all of the floor.
So we said filter itd value Daut model equals Ford.
And let me at the filter call here.
So what we're doing here is refining all of the cars that are have the model Ford.
But once we had the Fords we wanted to extract the color so we added a call after that.
We changed map and we said i t dot valued dot color.
And that gives us a list with the colors for all of the Fords.
So let's run
and we see that in our collection we have a red Ford and a green Ford.
So we get red and green.
Now when we did this the filter call returned a collection and then map was called on the resulting
collection.
So this is only a short chain so we only have one intermediate collection instance created here.
But what if we had a whole bunch of function calls chained together or why if the collection we were
working with was huge.
I mean here we have five items in the collection.
So you know it doesn't really matter that there's an intermediate collection being created here.
But what if this contained five hundred thousand items or something crazy like that then we'll start
to get concerned with the intermediate collection instances that are being created at every step of
the chain.
Now one way to avoid the creation of intermediate instances is by using sequences.
So that's one use case for sequences.
Another great use case for sequences is when you don't know how large a collection will be maybe you're
going to fill the collection with the results of a database query and you have no idea how many items
are going to come back.
So what is the sequence.
Well sequences are pretty much the same as streams in Java Katlin provides its own classes for this
because Java streams aren't available on every platform streams were introduced in Java 8 and some platforms
don't support Java 8 yet.
For example Android doesn't.
So Cartland reinvented the wheel here to ensure support on all the platforms that support Katlin.
So if you're familiar with streams in Java then you'll know what sequences are in cotland and trees
and a sequence can be enumerated one by one.
So instead of each step in the chain evaluating the entire collection at once and then returning the
collection and passing that collection onto the next step.
When you work with a sequence each element in a sequence is evaluated individually and is then passed
to the next step in the chain when applicable.
I mean if a value in the collection you are working with obviously fails a filter then it's not going
to be passed along but when applicable values are passed along one by one.
Now since each element in a sequence can be enumerated one by one there is no need to to create any
intermediate collection instances because what's going to happen is you'll evaluate the first item in
the sequence and then pass it on to to the next step in the chain and the second one etc..
There's no need to evaluate the entire collection.
Create a resulting collection instance and then pass that collection on to the next item in the chain.
Now the sequence interface has only one function iterator and the iterator is used to get each element
in the sequence one by one.
You can see sequences as never ending.
They don't have a size so they're a continuous stream of elements but they're not called streams.
They're called sequences in cotland.
Now you can convert a collection to a sequence by calling the sequence function.
But this is really important.
So listen up.
You only want to do this for large collections because Cartland collections are very efficient so there
is no need to use sequences unless you have a large collection and you're going to do something that
creates intermediate results.
Now we don't need to convert our little piddly car or map to a sequence but we're going to anyway.
So instead of treating our collection as a collection in our chain we can easily have it treated as
a sequence by just adding a call to the as sequence function.
So we're going to go as sequence Daut And now instead of our collection being filtered and mapped we've
converted it to a sequence and so now each element in our collection will be evaluated one by one.
There won't be any intermediate collection instances created.
So let's run
and we don't see a resulting list created.
We see a sequence instance reference.
So what's going on.
Well you can perform two types of operations on sequences intermediate and terminal and if you're familiar
with streams in Java you're already going to know all this stuff.
An intermediate operation returns another sequence.
A terminal operation does not return a sequence.
It terminates the chain.
So each intermediate step in the chain has to return a sequence because you want each intermediate step
to be able to evaluate values one by one and then pass each value down to the next step in the chain.
So each intermediate step will return a sequence but when you're done when you want the result at that
point you don't want to sequence.
Remember sequences are like continuous streams of values so when you're done you want something a little
more concrete than a sequence so intermediate operations return sequences.
Terminal operations do not return sequences they terminate the chain because at that point there is
no sequence to pass to another step.
Now intermediate operations are lazy in what this means is they aren't evaluated right away like for
example if you never use a terminal operation then there's no need to actually evaluate a sequence to
do any of the steps because you're never going to get anything concrete.
So let's work with something else for a minute.
Let's go here.
So we'll say a list of and we'll have a list of names.
Joe Mary and Jane.
And then we're going to treat this list as a sequence which would be completely unnecessary in this
case because it's a little piddly three item list and now it's chain filter Emap together so it's a
filter and I'm going to be a little bit tricky in here I'll say I'm going to print and I'm going to
say filtering.
I-T So filtering we're going to fill in here the name that we're filtering and then I'm going to put
a semi-colon and I'm going to add another statement.
Zero equals J.
So you'll notice here that I need a semi-colon.
I'm providing a predicate but I want to print do a print as well.
I can't do this.
That doesn't work.
So this is another case where you need to use semi-colons.
If your writing predicates on the fly like this and you want to do more than one statement.
So what we're going to do is we're going to print what the name that we're filtering and then names
that begin with a capital J are going to pass this filter and then after that we're going to map and
I'm going to use the same trick print line mapping the name that we're mapping and then I'm going to
say just to uppercase.
So that's the transformation that we're going to do here we're going to uppercase all of the names that
pass the filter.
So now let's run
and you'll notice that none of our print lines were executed and that's because filter and map return
a sequence and they're not terminal operations because when you're working with the sequence they return
a sequence their intermediate operations and because sequences are Laysan evaluated they're not evaluated
until a terminal operation is performed because map is returning a sequence in a sequence isn't really
concrete it's just a continuous stream of items so we need something that sort of captures the items
we want any more concrete way we need to perform a terminal operation something that does not return
a sequence and until we do that nothing is going to get executed.
So none of this code was executed because we don't have a terminal operation in this chain.
So let's add a terminal operation.
Let's say that that's great.
So we have a sequence at this point which is names that start with J all uppercase.
And we want to have those names in a list.
So the terminal operation that we're going to use is not to list.
Now this is a terminal operation it does not return a sequence it returns a list.
And so this terminates the chain.
And because we now have a terminal operation when we run our chain should execute.
So let's run
and sure enough our chain executes.
Let's take a look at it so you'll see that we filtered Joe he's first here and he passes the filter
because his name begins with a capital J.
And so we see that we're mapping him right away.
We're not waiting until we've also checked Mary and Jane against the filter and then we pass everything
down to map know each individual item is evaluated one by one.
So we we filter Joe he passes so then we map Joe we filter Mary she does not pass this test so we don't
see Mary being mapped.
We go straight on to filtering Jane and then we map Jane.
So when you use sequences nothing happens until a terminal operation is present.
Now as I mentioned if you're familiar with streams and Javid none of this is going to be new to you
because streams work in the same way.
So because each item in the list is evaluated individually that can mean that some entries are never
evaluated.
For example if the terminal operation is a Find function which returns an entry not a sequence then
that function will return the moment it finds a match.
So it's possible that we won't have to evaluate the entire sequence and that's another potential advantage
of using sequences over collections when you're doing this sort of chaining.
So instead of a two list let's change our code so that it finds the first name that ends with E..
Now we know that Joe is going to match that.
So with that in mind let's change our code to find and we want it.
It ends with.
And in this case we have to use a capital E because the previous step in the chain has upper cased everything
so if we use a lower case e nothing's going to match.
So we'll use it as capital E here I like to have blanks in the curly braces.
So let's run now.
And we'll see that in this case only Joe is ever evaluated because Joe is filtered he passes the filter
Yes so he's passed down to the map.
He's uppercase.
And then he's passed down to the find and he matches so the Find function returns and that's it.
Now our chain is done.
Our chain is terminated.
So we didn't even have to evaluate Marion Jane against the filter.
So now let's remove the sequence and let's take a look at how things change will run
and now we'll see that we filter the entire collection and then we map Joe and Jane because Mary doesn't
pass the filter so she's filtered out at this point and then we we map Joe and Jane and then we come
down here and we don't have a print line in here but we find Joe.
So that's what's actually returned from this entire thing is Joe upper cased.
So even when you're not using a sequence obviously fine when you hit fine the moment it finds a element
that matches it stops it's found its first match.
Now when you're working with collections and not sequences the order in which you call functions can
make a difference.
For example let's change the order of the filter and the map calls so instead of filtering first and
then mapping lets do the following.
We'll do the mapping as the first step.
And now let's run.
And before we do let's just look at this again take to try to remember it.
So we filter all three names and then we map just Joe and Jane.
But now if we run we'll see that we map all three names and we also filter all three names and that's
because since we're not filtering Mary out she gets mapped as well.
So all three names get uppercase and then we check them against the filter.
Now with this small collection that doesn't matter.
But if you're processing thousands of entries then doing the math first would be much less efficient
than filtering the names and then doing the map.
So if you're only ultimately interested in names that begin with Jay then you want to filter out the
names that don't begin with J as early as possible in the chain.
Otherwise you're going to be operating on some elements unnecessarily.
Now when you're using a sequence the order might not be as critical.
And in our example it isn't because the first element matches define.
So if we were to change this back to a sequence and do the same thing.
We're going to see that only Joe goes through because he matches the fine which terminates the chain.
So when you're using a sequence the order might not be as critical.
But let's put Joe last in the list now instead of first
and now let's run
and we'll see that again where we were doing unnecessary things we've passed Mary all the way through
the chain.
Well she didn't make it past this point but she was mapped.
Now maybe we want it that because we're checking everything against an upper case J in the filter call
so it will depend on what you're trying to do.
So all of this is just to say that when you're creating a chain Take a look at it and see if there are
any steps that will process items unnecessarily because of the order in which you've changed the functions
together it's possible that just by switching the order of some of the functions you might be able to
cut out some unnecessary processing.