Welcome back to the recipe book.
We already use ngIf and ngFor in the sections, so we're already using directives
but now I want to enhance this project by adding our own directive which allows us to open the drop
downs which don't work as of now if you click them.
They don't work because we didn't import Bootstrap's Javascript code and I don't want to import
this because Angular should be the only thing interacting with my DOM
but now with the directive knowledge, we can create our own directive which will manipulate these buttons.
I'll add the directive in the shared folder and I will name it dropdown.directive,
so the file is named dropdown.directive.ts.
Of course you could use the CLI to create it and you could even point to the shared folder in the command
to automatically generate it in this shared folder.
I'll do it manually though,
always a good practice and here, the name should be DropdownDirective like this
and of course, we need to add a decorator to turn this into a directive.
So it's the @directive decorator which needs to be imported from @angular/core
and here there is one thing I need to set up on the selector,
I want to define how I can add my directive and I will use an attribute selector,
therefore I'll enclose the name in square brackets. The name now will be appDropdown to have a unique
name which doesn't accidentally interfere with an officially existing attribute name or anything like
that.
Now what should this directive do?
I want to add some functionality to it which allows us to add a certain CSS class to the element it
sits on once it is clicked,
so once this element the directive sits on is clicked and removes the class
once we click again let's say.
So this is your challenge,
try implementing such a method which basically listens to clicks and then toggles some property which
determines whether some class is attached or not and also try implementing some code which dynamically
attaches a CSS class or not. Before you actually start though,
let's find out which class we need to attach.
If you go to the recipe detail component here, if you attach the open CSS class to the div which
holds the button group and you go to your application and select a recipe, you see now it looks like
the dropdown was opened.
So it's this open CSS class, the same for the usage in the header
we need to attach.
So that's your challenge,
build a dropdown directive
which attaches this class
whenever we click on it or removes it
once we click a second time. Let's build this directive together now.
So as explained, I want to toggle it upon clicking this.
So to listen to a click, I should add
@HostListener which is to be imported from @angular/core
and I want to listen to a click event. Then I want to execute toggle open which looks like or sounds like
a fitting name because that is what I want to do,
I want to toggle whether this should be opened or not.
Well then, I will add an isOpen directive which I'll set to false initially and in my @HostListener, I'll
simply set open or isOpen to
what it is currently not. So if isOpen was true,
it will now be set to false
and the other way around.
So with that, I'm toggling that property. Now to dynamically attach or detach a CSS class depending
on this,
all I have to do is, I'll add @HostBinding which needs to be imported from @angular/core and allows us to
bind to properties of the element
the directive is placed on and here,
I want to bind to the class property of that component, of that element, class simply is an array of
all the classes and here, it's all about this open class.
As you learned, that's the CSS class we need to attach dynamically or detach
and now the rest will be handled by Angular since I bind to isOpen,
this will not be attached initially, whenever isOpen switches to true,
it will be attached and whenever it switches to false, it will be removed
and that's our entire directive.
Now to be able to use it, I need to go to app module and add it here, add the dropdown directive and add
the import pointing to the shared folder and with that imported now, I can use it. I can use it in the
detail component, here
I have to use it on the div or on the element where open should be attached to in the end,
so in this case the div with the btn-group class and here, I'll add my own appDropdown directive,
without square brackets, without assigning any value because I don't need to configure anything
on this directive and now in the header, here the place where I need to add it is this list item with
the class of dropdown, here this is what will actually need the open class to show something. With that
in place and and ng serve still running,
let's save this and view this in our application, see if this works the way it should.
Let's test it in the header,
looks pretty good,
we close it by clicking again and here on a recipe,
that looks awesome too.
So that's working exactly the way I want it to work
and with that in place, that already is everything I wanted to build,
so a relatively short recipe book section here.
Now we can move on to services, a very powerful tool and then we will add services in this app here to
greatly enhance it and fix some things which we had to do kind of complicated thus far.
We'll also add some new features.