So now that you learned more about components and data binding and especially how you can communicate
between your components and how lifecycle hooks work and so on,
you gained a lot of new knowledge which is super important for most projects you are going to build, including
our course project.
So in this section, what we're going to do is we're going to fine tune this, we're going to make sure
that we can navigate between recipes and shopping lists, though our solution we'll add right now will
not be the final one, we will improve this even more later in the course and we will make sure that we
can select recipes here and load them in the detail section
and generally, that we have a working communication between our components.
So let's dive into this.