Let's now use our newly gained knowledge about observables in our recipe book in our course project.
Thus far in there, we are already using a pattern which you just learned in the last section that you
shouldn't use or that can be replaced with a better pattern and that better pattern is of course to
replace all our event emitters which we have with subjects.
So for example here, in the shopping list service, we have that event emitter which we already use to
push new information about changed ingredients from component A to B,
well we'll now change this to a subject instead. One tiny thing
I also noticed is that here in the app component, we of course no longer need the onNavigate function
and therefore also not here,
this function handler.
But that's a minor thing,
let's instead focus on the shopping list now and there in the shopping list service,
I want to set up my subject, so for that I will first of all add a new import up there and I will import
subject from RxJS, just as you learned it in the observables section. You can now simply replace event
emitter with subject here because it works almost the same way, that of course means that we can get
rid of that event emitter import up there
and now there's one thing we need to fix though, whenever we call emit,
we now have to call next instead because subjects use next to emit or send a new value.
Now the parts where we consume ingredients changed
however, these parts don't need to change
so here in the shopping list component, where we subscribe to the ingredients changed event emitter previously,
we now subscribe to the subject and that is absolutely fine, it has the same syntax regarding that.
However there is one thing we do need to change, we don't need to change that syntax but as you learned,
it is a good and recommended practice to store that subscription in some property and clean it up when
we leave the component.
So I'll add a private property, igChangeSub or whatever you want to name it, which is of type subscription
and you therefore need to import subscription from RxJS at the top of your file.
Now with that changed, of course it's not enough to create that property, I really want to store my subscription
in that property,
so I'll set this igChangeSub equal to this slService ingredients changed subscribe because subscribe
returns a subscription which we store in there and now to clear it whenever we leave that component,
let's add onDestroy as an interface which you also import from @angular/core, that forces us to add
ngOnDestroy here and in ngOnDestroy,
we can now use our igChangeSub property to unsubscribe and this now is the recommended pattern
which will replace event emitter with a more optimal solution. Now we're using a similar pattern in
the recipes area, if we have a look at the recipes service, there we have the recipe selected property
which is also an event emitter and therefore, since this is also not decorated with @output and not part
of a component which would be a totally different use case,
so since we instead use that for cross component communication through a service, we should replace
this with a subject as well.
So let's replace event emitter with subject here and therefore, we can get rid of event emitter up there
and of course now, however we have to import that subject here,
so let's import subject from RxJS and now make sure that wherever you are emitting a new value,
you now use next
instead. We're still setting up a subscription to it in the recipes component
but that was done to have a solution for loading different recipes before we added routing.
Now with routing added, we actually don't need this anymore because now when we want to select a recipe,
well then we do this by clicking on it and we use the router link directive, here in our recipe item
component, to load different recipes.
So instead here, we can actually get rid of recipe selected in total
but if we would use it as we did before,
so where we would use that to select different recipes, you would use it as a subject. In our case as
I just mentioned,
we can simply get rid of the usage of it and therefore also of the injection of recipes service here
in our recipes component and we can also get rid of the recipe module here.
And with that all cleaned up, we're now using the subject in one place, in the shopping list area, not in a
recipes area because there we have no use case for it right now.
With that, our application looks good and works just like it did before, at least as far as we can go
and now we're using a subject instead of an event emitter.
The other parts you learned about observables - what they do, how they work behind the scenes, that they
can throw errors and that you can use
operators will become a bit more important later in the course but now already, it should be a bit clearer
what this routing params thing is and how we can conveniently pass data from A to B in the best
possible way by using subjects.