Welcome to another course module, welcome to this course module.
We already learned a lot about Angular and thus far, we really built a single page application.
We use directives and so on to change portions of this page
but in the end, we always were on the same page,
if you looked at the URL at the top, it was always localhost:4200.
Now what if you wanted to have a page where you actually display several pages, like you have a
/users or a /accounts page?
Now you might think that for this, you indeed need multiple pages, multiple index.html files or
something like this
but you don't, Angular ships with its own router which allows you to change the
URL in the URL bar and still only use one page but then exchange major parts or a lot of parts of
that page, so that to the user, it really looks like a new page was loaded because maybe only the header
is the same but behind the scenes, it is still Javascript changing a lot of parts in your DOM, in
your page, making it look like a new page was rendered but you're still in the Angular world in your
single page application.
Let's take a closer look
in this module.