Let's now apply our newly gained knowledge about sending HTTP requests in our course project.
So here's the recipe book as we left it after the last course project section and now my goal is to make
sure that we can actually click these manage save data and fetch data buttons to save all our recipes
on a server in the web and with the fetch data button, of course to fetch them.
So the idea is pretty simple, the idea simply is that we can store and fetch all our recipes we created
on demand.
Now obviously, you can alter this in a lot of different ways, you could auto fetch any recipes whenever
the application starts or anything like that,
the core thing we'll handle in this section of course is the sending of the HTTP requests.
So let's take care about this
now.