So now that we get started with this course and with Angular and our project we're going to use in this course,
it's time to dive deeper into Angular to understand what really does, what happens behind the scenes,
how an Angular gets started in the first place and which base building blocks it offers us, how we can
build Angular apps and which features we may use for this.
By the end of this section, you will understand how you can build your basic Angular application, what
it then does and what you need to change to reach a different result.
So with this, let's dive into it and let's start by having a look, what actually happens when we
visit
this page in the browser when we reload this page, how does Angular get started,
what do we actually see here, besides nothing
because there is more to this page than it might look like.