Time to take another look at directives and not only repeat quickly what we've learned thus far but also
learn how to build our own directives and really dive into the difference between attribute and structural
directives
and what this star means on the structural directives.
Well, I already said it right,
we get attribute and structural directives. Attribute directives are called like this because they sit
on elements, just like attributes and structural directives basically do the same
but they also change the structure of the DOM around this element.
If you have ngIf on a paragraph, if that condition is false, this paragraph is removed from the DOM,
so the overall view container is affected,
whereas on the attribute directive, you never destroy an element from the DOM,
you only change properties of that element,
for example the backgroundColor.
So that is why we have attribute directives only affecting the element they sit on and structural directives
which also affect the whole DOM or the view container, the area around the element which they
were placed on.
That is the difference,
now with that let's briefly have a look at the directives we already know and how to use them before we
then dive into building our own ones and learn more about structural directives.