Welcome to this course module. This course module is about forms, so forms on your HTML page and
how Angular can help you with those forms.
Now on first sight, it might be strange why you would need that help, right, because a form is something
you can simply submit to the server but then keep in mind, you're creating a single page application,
so there is no submitting to the server,
instead you will need to handle the form through Angular
and if you then want to submit something to the server, you will need to reach out via Angular's HTTP
service which we'll cover later in the course to that server.
So you will need to handle your forms through Angular and actually, Angular will help you in handling it
because not only will it allow you to get the values the user entered,
it will also allow you to check if a form is valid,
it will allow you to conditionally change the way the form is displayed,
put some red borders around invalid controls, so Angular really ships with some powerful tools when
it comes to working with forms.
Let's take a closer look and let's understand what exactly
Angular does for you, how it handles forms.