Welcome back to the Recipe Book.
Now that we learned about routing in the last course section, it's time to add it to our recipe book
course app.
This is the structure of our app thus far and we already get a lot of components and so on.
Right now we implemented the navigation in our application with ngIf though and that is not really the
best way of navigating around,
instead I want to use the Angular router to load pages and to allow the user to switch between pages.
In this section
however, we will not only add the router, we will also add one new component, the recipe-edit component
because now that we have a way of loading different pages,
we can also add this, this is the component which we will fill with some life after the form section in this course
which will then allow us to create new recipes or edit existing ones.
So I want to set up routing in this section and we definitely need routes to load either the shopping
list or the recipe book
but inside of the Recipe Book section of the app, I want to have some child routes targeting the recipe
detail or recipe-edit component.
These components which will always be loaded on the left side of our list of recipes should be loaded
dynamically and only one of the two should be loaded at a time,
therefore child routing.
So that is the general structure,
let's now put this into practice and build our application, add routing to it
starting in the next lecture.