Time to practice the things we learned thus far in our course project.
Now what is our course project?
My goal in this project which we will build throuhout the course, to which we will come back after the individual
sections of this course, is to build a recipe book and shopping list app,
you saw it in the intro video of the course.
Basically there, we're going to have two sections, shopping list and recipe book and we will be able to
manage our recipes, view them in detail and also to manage our shopping list and even push ingredients
from a recipe directly to the shopping list.
This application will use a lot of the features we learned throughout the course and therefore I think it's
perfect to practice these things and see them come together in a real app.
First of all though, let's try to plan the application because before creating the app, you of course need
to have a plan and therefore in the next lecture, we're going to think about which components we will
need for the different features of this application.