With the basics about routings set, let's enhance our application a bit by going back to the app module and
adding some other routes to it. Let's say that besides our users route here, we also want to be able to
load a single user, so to load the user component which simply well gives us that single user. For
that, we might want to load a user dynamically because if we have a look at our users component, we see
we get three users with different IDs,
so it would be nice if we could pass the ID of the user we want to load in that route path.
One approach would be to set up a route with user/1 and then one with user/2
and it doesn't look very optimal because it's not very dynamic and still, how would we know inside of
this component
which route was loaded?
Okay we could parse the path manually but that's not really a great approach.
Instead, we can add parameters to our routes, dynamic segments in our paths.
We do this by adding a colon and then any name you like, like for example ID, you will later be able
to retrieve the parameter inside of the loaded component by that name you specify here,
so by ID in this case and the colon simply tells Angular that this is a dynamic part of the path.
Without colon, only routes which are users/id and with ID, I literally mean the word ID, would lead
to this component, with a colon user, slash
anything else would load this component and anything else would be interpreted as the ID.
Now with this in place, we are able to load a component, the user component with this dynamic piece sent
to it.
So if we have a look to this user component or at this user/1 component, here we simply say user
with ID and now we have a dummy text here loaded and username with some dummy text here.
Now for now, we won't touch this,
we won't use this parameter,
we will do in the next lecture,
let's now see if we successfully reach this.
So if we save this to let it recompile and we go back and we are in the users,
let's add slash something here
and you see, the single user component was loaded, the same
if we add /1 here.
So this thing, the segment after /users is indeed interpreted as dynamic,
otherwise we would get the error that users/1 is an unknown route.
It isn't because we set it up to be a known one because again, we added this dynamic path segment here.
Now this is how we can dynamically load some route, how we can encode some data into our path,
how can we get access to this data in the loaded component though
because that of course is another key question.
Let's take a closer look in the next lecture.