In the last lecture, we made our child routerLinks here work again,
now let's make clear which one is selected by marking it. We can mark the active link by adding manually
the active class to it.
If we do this, all are marked as active because of course it's added to every instance of this component
because I hardcoded it in there.
So that's the right class
but of course we should add it dynamically with good old routerLinkActive directive and here, I simply
want to pass active as the class name because we just saw this is the CSS class we need to add
and with that it's working as expected. And this is all we needed here,
you also see that recipes is still marked as active at the top because we still are at /recipes
and then at a child route but that doesn't matter for this to be marked as active because it's not
set to exact matching
and actually we want the behaviour we have right now. So that all looks pretty good,
now we can move on to make sure that we can click this new recipe button and this edit recipe button
and actually do something
once we do click them.