So let's continue working on this and let's continue by having a look at how we can add multiple ingredients
because that's also a case we have, so not just one ingredient but multiple ingredients at once.
This is what gets triggered when we're working on a recipe and we then select the add to shopping list
button here, to shopping list.
So that's this case
and we also have update and delete ingredient to handle.
Let's start with add ingredients because this probably is one of the easier cases to add
and for that let's go back to the shopping list reducer and let's handle that second case
and for that of course, we first of all have to go to the shopping list actions and add an appropriate
action.
So below the constant, ADD_INGREDIENT, I'll export another constant, ADD_INGREDIENTS, so plural and
here, the identifier
text is also add ingredients. Now by the way, in theory you could of course deviate here,
you could have a different string value than constant name but it is of course a good practice to keep
those two in sync,
so this makes it easier to match them mentally.
Now this is just the string identifier, an action however is an object as you learned and therefore, we need
a second class which I'll also export.
So I'll export another class, AddIngredients
sounds like a fitting name
and just as add ingredient, this will implement an action. Now this class here
therefore also has a readonly type which here is add ingredients,
so the plural form of that and it will also get a constructor and that constructor should now not take
a single ingredient but multiple. Still I'll store the data we get in the payload property
and again, the name is up to you, this doesn't have to be payload but payload is a typical name and I
would recommend following that convention and the type here will of course not be a single ingredient
but actually an ingredient array because we will add multiple ingredients at once.
So now we export this class here back in the shopping list reducer,
we can now handle that case.
So we handle the case that our type is of type shopping list actions add ingredients here
and I'm getting a TypeScript error, type add ingredients is not comparable to type add ingredient. Do
you have any idea what could be causing this? Keep in mind
that we tell TypeScript that the action type of the action we're getting in the reducer is shopping list
actions add ingredient.
Now that was true when we only had this action but now we have two actions and we can't tell whether
the action that reaches this reducer is actually the add ingredient or the add ingredients action.
Now what we could do is we could fall back to the more generic action interface which we can import
from @ngrx/store,
that's the wrong import,
let's use @ngrx/store.
We could do that but then we get a problem with the payload because that action interface doesn't know
about the payload, so that won't work,
so we need a different approach.
Of course we could simply use any and that would work
but a bit more TypeScript support would be nice and the solution is to export an additional type here,
you can create your own types
so to say with TypeScript, which you can name shopping list actions or anything like that
and that simply is a combination of all the types you want to include into your shopping list actions.
So you create a union of the different action types you want to support in this part of your store and
the union here will consist of add ingredient and separated by a pipe symbol, add ingredients.
This is a TypeScript feature,
this simply says the type of shopping list actions is add ingredient or add ingredients,
so it's one of these two and we export our own type to summarize this.
This is a pure TypeScript thing but during development, this will help us
and therefore now we'll say our action here is actually of type shopping list actions.shopping list
actions.
Now it might look strange,
the first shopping list actions here is simply the alias I'm using here for our bundled import
and you could name this differently,
the .shopping list actions then refers to this union type I have down there which kind of combines
add ingredient and add ingredients and now TypeScript knows that an action is either of these two types
and therefore we get no error here.
Now back to that case then where we handle add ingredients, what do we want to do there? We always have
to return a new state, so a new object here and then, you'll learn that I would recommend that you always
copy the old state first, so all the properties of the old state
and then here, I again set ingredients equal to a new array where I copy all my old state ingredients,
so all the existing ingredient elements in that ingredients array and then I have to add the ingredients
added by my action.payload.
Now action.payload here should not be added like this because what's my action.payload
if we add ingredients? Well it will be an array of ingredients,
so if we add it like this, then we add a array to an array and hence we have a nested array.
I want to add the elements of that payload array to the outer array and therefore here, we should also
use the spread operator to pull these elements in action.payload out of this array and add them to this
ingredients array.
So now this reducer is updated, the actions here are updated,
let's now make sure we also use our new action and we dispatch it whenever we do add ingredients from
a recipe because right now, if I for example add my recipes from that big fat burger here, go back to
the shopping list, we don't see them here and
the reason for that is that I don't get an error but I do add these ingredients from inside the recipe
service and there, I use the shopping list service to add ingredients.
Now that works
but keep in mind that the shopping list service is no longer our source of truth,
we're not using the ingredients from the shopping list service anymore and therefore adding them there
doesn't do anything.
Instead here in the recipe service, instead of using the shopping list service, we should dispatch this
add ingredients action to use our @ngrx/store instead and for that in the constructor, we first of all have
to inject our store which is of type store and that store still has to be imported from @ngrx/store
like in all other places of the app as well and also in the other places, we have to be clear about
what's inside this store,
so you should actually grab the type definition as you have it in the shopping list component for example.
So this object with shopping list and then the nested object with ingredients and use this in the recipe
service here as well
when you inject that store so that TypeScript knows which store that isn't what's inside of that store,
even if you don't select anything from it, there still you should provide it like this.
Now the store is injected into the recipes service and now here in add ingredients to shopping list,
we're not using the shopping list service anymore but instead the store where we dispatch a new action
and that new action should come from our shopping list actions file and for that again, let's import everything
as shopping list actions, that name is up to you, from and now reach out to the shopping list area, to
the store folder and there to the shopping list actions file.
We bundle all exports from that shopping list actions file into the shopping list actions
object here
and with that bundled, when we dispatch an action, we use that but not the bundled exports
but instead the add ingredients class that is set up inside of that shopping list actions file
and this takes an array of ingredients, right,
that is the kind of data this action expects.
This is the add ingredients action,
it expects a payload which is an ingredient array and therefore in the recipe service,
we have to forward such an array. Conveniently we have one here in the ingredients argument,
so let's send this with store dispatch.
And now with that if you go back to your application, this is our current shopping list with apple and
tomatoes, if I
now fetch my data again and I go to the big fat burger and I then execute two shopping list,
if we go back to the shopping list, we have the two ingredients from that recipe here as well and that
works because we're now again using our global store.