This is our example app.
And as you can see we got a user component and they use a service and both are connected because we
inject the user service and the user component.
Now let's say we have a rewords pipe which reverses any string that pipe can be tested isolated.
We do have to use English to package all these two utilities Usul test bed azing Tig and so on.
There are a couple of utilities in this package and actually you already saw most of them.
The address can be seen in the reference link and the next lecture.
But anyways a pipe can be tested totally independent of English too.
Why.
Because how does a pipe work.
It has this transformed function where you pass a string in and get a string out.
No need to involve Englad to for such a basic pipe.
You might have other tasks in your application where the same is true.
If you get a service and then the service you get a method which only transforms some data or at say
doubles the number Well then you can tested isolate isolated.
You don't need to testing package for dead.
You can write a normal unit test and does well I'll show you an example of a reverse pipe.
Now I look at the pipe in the shared folder and I'll treat it manually.
I'll name it rewords the pipe dot TS and in there we of course export a class which is named rewords
pipe.
And on this class we attach the pipe decorate decorator.
As he learned to be imported from an angular co-worker and there I pass an object where I give it a
name of rewords.
Well on the inside of this class I therefore need to have the transform function and Tristram's form
function expects to get a string or de-value lets say which is a string and possibly some parens though
I won't pass some here.
Well and then I can simply return the value splitters
by.
Well nothing so that each character is separated so split it by each character basically call reverse
on that.
That's a normal function vailable on an array and the string is just an array of characters.
And then join them again with nothing in between joining them so that each character is attached to
the code before it without a whitespace in between or something like that.
That is what my rewords pipe does.
Well and now for testing this I can really ride my own rewords pipe spec Dadds TS file.
Now if we have a look at the user components back file How does a spec a look like.
Well if I copy it which is a bit overkill we start here here.
I of course want to get rid of all the IT statements except for one maybe get rid of all these imports
and I can also get rid of the angular to testing utilities because I don't need them.
I also don't need it for each.
There is no set up to be run before each pipe.
All I want to do here for example is I want to create my rebirths pipe which is a new rewords pipe and
that's why it's called isolator that doesn't depend on any other piece of my application.
It doesn't even depend on English to.
And all I want to do is I want to expect rewords pipe trends for them if I pass let's say Hello in there
to equal well and then this should be O L L E H that is all.
And if I save this we should now have 11 successful tests because this clearly should succeed and we
Duzee 11 successful tests indeed after rerunning enty test.
Or if you still had it running after saving this as an isolated test.
Of course you could have some pipe which depends on what you or something like that.
And it really comes down to this question.
Does the thing you want to test depend on Angola two or three pieces of your English two application
.
If yes well then you get these testing utilities like test bed which allows you to create components
exista injector set up the module for testing and so on.
You got to azing fake azing and take two well-handled asynchronous tasks and so on in the lecture at
the end of this module you will learn more about Abu resource about Obert tests you could write are
things you can test if you don't have that if you don't have a dependency on angular 2 or upper pieces
in the app while then an isolated task like this might be all you need.
And with that we had a good introduction to how testing works how we can use the Angua to testing package
the features that offers us to write.
It has to use services.
And as I already said at the beginning I could continue for a couple of hours here but this is not what
this course is about and not what I want to make discourse about.
It is a good introduction.
With Dad you should be able to dive really deeper into it with the article in the next lecture.
You should be able to use your general unit testing knowledge you already have to take advantage of
these tools and you Office you to create components to access to Ranzo on.
And with that that is all I can do.
I can encourage you to dive deeper into it and I hope this introduction was at least helpful to understand
how you might decide when to test the connection to when your component or whatever and when to test
it isolated.
Why unit tests are helpful in the first place.
How to get started with the test and you tell his English to gives you and how to create these example
tests.
We create a two year zone the modules by