Now for animating an item out let's say we wanted to have two different animations which take a different
amount of time.
So two different animations would be rather easy.
Here is where we animate out and we're having it this style being set up during the any made function
.
And if we don't want to have a second style we could add a new animate function here and let's say here
we simply want to change the text color to red.
Now if it's safe this let's see what happens if I do animate out the item on the bottom list if I click
on milk.
Well it's invisible before I see the color turn to red.
That is not really optimal.
So if I switched the order a year so that I at least see this let's see if it at least works how it
should work.
If I click an item it gets red and that is animated out.
But what if I wanted to have both at the same time but maybe with different timings so that they don't
wait for one animation to finish before starting the next.
I can do this by passing or by using the group method.
That's also a method to be imported by Anglo to or from Anglo core.
I mean yes.
So from English coworker.
And in this group method here as an argument we pass an array of animations we want to perform synchronously
.
So at the same time.
So here I can now pass might you any made methods and I'll give it different durations so that we can
clearly see that both happens at the same time.
And now if I save this and we let it reload let's remove an item you see it turns red.
Whilst moving but it moves slower than it takes to turn it red and this is how we can use animation
group to group multiple animations with possibly different timings to gabber to have them at the same
time.
And any made different things over as is your possibly different durations