In the last lecture we found out that Angular tracks the state of each control of the form, whether it's
valid and so on and conditionally also adds these CSS classes.
Now with that information, we can go back to our form and you take advantage of it. Before diving into
the CSS classes,
the easiest way of taking advantage is down here on the submit button,
let's disable the button if the form is not valid.
So I'll just split this over multiple lines and add some property binding, I want to bind to the disabled property
which will add the or which will set the disable state of this button to true or false depending on
some condition
and I will specify the condition here.
Now I could set it true here to always disable it,
that of course is not super useful, instead here I want to check whether the form,
remember we do have access to it on this f local reference here,
so if this form is valid, which would be precise
if it is not valid. So if this form is not valid, the button should be disabled and we can actually see
this once this reloads and
now the button is disabled and only if I enter some valid values here, I can hit the submit button again.
So this is the first improvement in place,
the second improvement is to take advantage of these CSS classes.
We do get these classes added automatically, so we can now go to the stylesheet of this app component
and we could say that on ng-invalid, we want to give it a red border,
so one pixel solid red.
Sounds like a solid idea, doesn't it?
Well if we do this, you see everything is red
now, the two controls but also the overall form.
The reason for this is that our overall form is also invalid
and that Angular also adds the ng-invalid class, CSS class to the form element.
So a better approach would be to make sure that is not added to the form.
Now there are a couple ways of doing this and it's all just pure CSS logic, one idea would be that
we want to be inside of the form element but then it would still place these red borders around grouping
divs,
we will have a look at what I mean with this later.
So the best way is to simply be explicit that we want to add it on inputs for example
and of course you could also add select here, so input with ng-invalid or select with ng-invalid and which
other elements you have.
Just be creative here,
there are different ways of achieving this goal, in the end you just want to make sure that the border is applied
to the right controls.
Now with this in place, we see that now we only have a red border around the invalid controls but we
do have the border right from the start which is also not great because I at least want to give the
user the chance of changing it before showing a warning, showing that it's wrong.
So a better approach might be to make sure that we only add a red border to an input which has the CSS
class, ng-invalid
and also the CSS class ng-touched, so that the user has to at least click into it. Now by default,
we don't see anything red
even though the form is invalid
but if we click in there and decide yeah I'm done this is my value,
well now you see we have a red border because now we had a chance of changing it,
we didn't change it,
it is invalid
and we want to show this
and with that, we're taking advantage of this form state handled by Angular.
We disable the button and we show a visual feedback to the user.
Now you could of course go much further,
you could also add a warning message below this input here for example and output please enter a valid
value or be more precise than that of course
and add ngIf to conditionally show this if the input value is wrong.
Well this gives us one additional problem though, how do we determine whether this input here or this
control here does hold a wrong value.
We'll take a closer look in the next lecture.