We're now outputting our loaded post,
we can re-fetch them here by clicking fetch, though
we of course don't really see a difference here because we fetched the same posts and we have no indicator
for whether a request is currently on its way or not
whilst we're waiting for the response. Would be nice to have such an indicator and that can be easily
implemented by adding a new property, which you could name isLoading which initially is false and you
want to set is loading
or maybe let's name it is fetching because I only want to use it for fetching posts and you can use
is fetching and set it to true whenever you start fetching posts,
so here at the beginning of this fetch posts. There, you can set this is fetching to true because now
we are starting to fetch posts and once we're done, so here in the subscribe function, we can set
this is fetching back to false.
Now what's the advantage of this?
Well we can show a loading indicator whilst we are fetching posts.
So back here in our template, we want to show no posts available if we have no posts and also important,
if we're not currently fetching because if we are fetching posts, then we want to wait for that result
and not show no posts available too early.
Of course, we also only want to output posts if we're currently not fetching too.
So here, I also will output this only if we have posts and we're not fetching.
This of course means we have a third scenario now, that we are fetching and we don't care about whether
we have posts or not
and for this, you could output simply loading or display a nice CSS spinner if you wanted to, by using
ngIf equal is fetching.
Now let's have a look at that,
let's reload and you see loading here
and if I click fetch post, again you see loading.
Now unfortunately kind of, Firebase is really fast and therefore, you only see this for a fraction of
a second but you see it does work
and if you had a slower server, you would of course see it a bit longer.