Now how should that logic look like in the shopping list reducer? First of all, we got two new cases,
that's the simple part.
The first case is that in the shopping list actions, we encountered the
UPDATE_INGREDIENT uppercase though, the string identifier,
the second case which we need is the DELETE_INGREDIENT case. Now in both cases, we need to return a new
object which will reflect our new state,
so far so simple.
Now we need to update that state
and let's start with updating ingredients.
As always,
you should copy your existing state first and then overwrite ingredients because that is what we work
with here with a new array and that new array will basically be the old ingredients array where we edited
one ingredient.
So that requires a bit more logic,
let's write it here above the return statement,
first of all let's get that one ingredient that we want to edit. So I'll get it here,
my ingredient is equal to state,
that's my old state right,
that's the state I'm getting as an argument,
so it's the previous state before we updated it now.
So state, there ingredients and then we can simply access the index because we get the index as part
of our action.payload,
right,
so action.payload here will be indexed or will have an index.
So that's the ingredient I want to edit
but remember that we always have to add a data immutably here.
So simply setting ingredient amount equal to action.payload ingredient amount would be incorrect because
that would edit the old states object or data stored in that old state object and that is not allowed
and absolutely not the pattern
ngRx wants you to use. Instead we should create a copy and I'll name this updatedIngredient which
is an object because ingredient is an object where I copy the old ingredient, so I copy the name and
the amount. And then I know that my action.payload also has an ingredient,
right because I set it up here when I defined the types of data I get here.
So I have ingredients here as well
and therefore I can simply just copy action.payload ingredient because that is an ingredient and this
ingredient I get here has of course the same properties as the ingredient I'm copying.
So essentially, I'm copying the old ingredients properties to then overwrite them here,
obviously we could therefore not copy this and simply just spread our incoming ingredient data into
this new object
but for cases where for example you have an ID on that existing ingredient which you don't want to
overwrite, it would make sense to copy all the old data so that you keep things like an ID or anything
else that doesn't need to be overwritten and then you just overwrite what needs to be overwritten. Here,
we actually overwrite everything but for demo purposes and to understand the general pattern, I still
like copying it first and then changing what needs to be changed. Now
that's the updated ingredient
but we need an array of the old ingredients and then this updatedIngredient being replaced.
So for this, I'll add a new constant, updatedIngredients,
so plural, where I copy all my old state ingredients, so I copy the ingredient elements from my old state.
So the array, the updatedIngredients array is now a new array,
it's not the array in the old state, it's just a new array with the data of the old states array. So
updatedIngredients is therefore an array
I can safely edit, so updatedIngredients can be edited by selecting the index where we want to update
the ingredient with the help of action.payload.index and then assigning a new element or overwriting
the existing element at this index with a new element and that new element is of course the updated
ingredient.
So I'm replacing the old element with that index in the copied updatedIngredients array with the copied
updatedIngredient and now updatedIngredients is an array of ingredients where we overwrote one ingredient
that that was the ingredient that has to be edited and therefore now the ingredients I set here in the
state I returned is simply my updatedIngredients array. So that's the logic for updating an ingredient,
might look like a lot of work but in the end, this just enforces this immutable logic
and whilst this might look strange at first,
it really is a good pattern that will prevent unexpected bugs where you accidentally edit some old
state too early and therefore, your @ngrx/store state gets out of sync with your rest of the
application state
that doesn't expect such immutable mutations.
So therefore, always edit your data immutability like we do it here, return a new state
and if you need to edit something inside of that state, copy it first and then edit the copy.
Now of course, we also delete ingredients and there, we also return a copy of the old state and then
we set ingredients equal to a new array and just as before, this needs to be an array of ingredients
where we basically have all the old ingredients but we removed one and this is relatively easy to do,
you simply set ingredients equal to state ingredients filter. Now filter will always return a new
array, so it will automatically give us a copy and filter is a function built into Javascript that will
take an array, run a certain function which you pass in as an argument on every element in the array
and if your function which you pass into filter which we'll do in a second, if that function returns true,
then the element for which it's executing this will be part of the new array filter returns,
otherwise it will not. So the function we have to pass to filter is a function that runs on every element
in the array
you call filter on,
so on every ingredient and this function will automatically receive every element
therefore, hence we can name it ingredients here or just ig
and then I use an arrow function and this is now my function body here and in there, we have to return
true or false
deciding whether we want to keep that ingredient we're currently looking at
and again this will run for every ingredient in that array or not
and I want to keep my ingredient if its index is not equal to the index we're looking for here,
so which is part of our action.payload.
And the good thing is the filter function or the function we pass to filter does not just give us every
element for which it executes but also the index of every element.
So we also gets the ig index or whatever you want to call it,
so we get two arguments by default,
that is how filter works, how this built-in function works,
it's not Angular,
this is vanilla Javascript.
We get the element for which the function runs,
so every element in the ingredients array and then always the current index of the element we're looking
at
and I want to return true for every element where the index is not equal to the index we're looking
for because if I return true, then the element will be kept, if I return false, it will be filtered out
and I only want to filter out one element and that is the element with the index we're trying to delete.
So I return ig index not equal to action.payload and action.payload already is the index for this action
right here,
it's already a number,
so that is what I'm comparing.
So if my action.payload, if the index I'm getting is equal to the index I'm currently looking at, then
this is the element I want to remove and therefore I have to return false which is what happens here
so that this is not included in the new array filter returns.
So that was again a lot of talking,
let's now make sure that this also gets dispatched. For that,
let's first of all go to the shopping-edit component,
we already dispatched our own action for adding an ingredient,
let's now also do the same for updating it.
So now we can call this store dispatch new shopping list actions.update ingredient
and there we need to pass in an object which has an index property, which should be the index of the
element we want to remove and
we get this here with this editedItemIndex and we also have to pass in the new ingredient which
we want to use instead
and that is the new ingredient argument here.
So this dispatches the update ingredient action,
now we can also delete ingredients and there, we currently call this shopping list service delete ingredient.
Let's get rid of this as well and let's use the store instead and dispatch a new shopping list actions,
delete ingredient action where we now also need to include the index of the element we want to remove
and that is the this editedItemIndex here,
so let's dispatch this as well. Let's give this a try,
if we go back to the application and I select tomatoes and I delete this, they're gone
so this looks pretty good.
If I reload, they are of course back,
this is how this works. I mentioned that your current state stored in your application would be lost
if you refresh and therefore, our update of course also is lost,
we didn't save this change to a server but it works. Now does updating work? If I change the amount to
10 here, looks pretty good. If I remove an s, also looks pretty good though
I'm also back to 5 then,
right?
So let me show this again. I update this to 10,
now I lost the Apple s and if I update that again, I removed the s,
something is going wrong because you might see if I click on this, actually the old state is loaded, apples
and the amount, it's not loading the state we're seeing down there.
So updating only partly works and let's see what's wrong here.