So we added our routes for the edit component,
now let's go to that component and retrieve the ID and therefore determine whether we are in editMode
or not.
I will inject the ActivatedRoute in there as you learned it before from @angular/router and in
ngOnInit,
this is a good place to now retrieve the ID. As before, I want to do this dynamically,
so I will use my route and the params observable and subscribe to that
and here I will receive my params which are of type params and here I then want to retrieve the ID
on which I'm currently working.
I will store the ID here in a property named or not named, named ID but of type number,
so here I will set this ID equal to plus to convert it into a number, params ID because that's the name
of our dynamic parameter in our route set up, right?
With that, we retrieve that ID here
but I also want to find out whether I'm editing the recipe or creating a new one.
I actually want to store this information in a new property, editMode
maybe, I'll set it to false initially,
so initially you could say we assume that we are creating a new recipe,
we are not in editMode.
Now I will check this whenever the parameters change,
then I will assign a new value to editMode
and here I will simply assign the value of the following check,
I want to see if params has an ID property. So if it has one, then this will actually be a string with
the ID, otherwise it will be undefined.
So by comparing it to null and checking if it is not null, I'm checking
does it have the ID because params and that there, the ID will only be not undefined if we are in edit
mode because then an ID will be present.
If this check returns true,
so if the ID indeed is undefined and therefore equal to null, this will return false because I'm checking
the opposite and therefore, we are in new mode. And we can check this by simply logging it in the console
here, editMode,
let's see if this works. We're at zero edit here and it returns true
and now we're at new and it returns false.
So that seems to work,
this is a nice way of checking in which mode we are.
So with that, we are able to retrieve the ID of the element we want to edit and to find out whether we are
in editMode or not,
now I want to make this edit link here work and the new recipe link because these are both things which
are not working as of now,
let's work on this next.
And actually this is a nice challenge for you, make these links work.
Make sure that when we click this link or this button, we get taken to the recipes new page or the recipes
edit page for that respective recipe we had loaded.
It's a nice challenge for you, in the next lecture we can view my solution together.