We finished for now all our recipes components, let's work on the shopping list now.
Now the shopping list component,
if we have a look at it here in our files, here in the HTML file, we already added some content to its
template here
but instead of saying the list, I want to output an unordered list of type list group or of the class list
group I should say, so using this Bootstrap class
and in there, I want to have clickable list items,
so I'll add an anchor tag pointing to just hash for now again to make sure it doesn't reload the page accidentally
and then add some Bootstrap classes or one class to be precise,
the list group item class to make this look like an item in this unordered list and I'll even get rid
of the anchor tag here, of the ref
I should say and therefore set an inline style to enforce a cursor which looks like the pointer.
The reason why I'm removing this is, I will later use this like a button and therefore, I don't need this
ref element there,
it would simply lead to unwanted behaviors.
So that will be a single element, a single item on our shopping list.
Now to display something here, we need an array of ingredients though.
So what I'll do for now is, I'll add my ingredients property here to the shopping list and this will
be an empty array
but now just like with the recipe, we're going to use ingredients a lot throughout our app,
also in the recipe section, so we probably should also create a model for this.
Let's do this in the next lecture.