Sometimes you not only want to pre-populate a default the user entered but you also want to instantly
react to any changes.
Right now, everything about this form here only updates once I click submit,
then I get this form object where I can retrieve the value.
We don't use two-way binding, ngModel is either used without any binding or with one-way binding
but sometimes you instantly want to check something or simply repeat whatever the user entered,
let's show an example. For this question here,
I'm going to add a new form-group, Bootstrap style here below the dropdown,
I want to have a text area let's say to also introduce a new input,
let's name it
questionAnswer. I don't need the ID here, don't need columns,
I want to have three rows let's say
and I'll also distribute this over multiple lines
and now we could add ngModel to get access to whatever the user entered as a reply
but maybe for some reason, we instantly want to repeat this reply. So below this we could say your reply
and now we want to output the answer to the question.
Well for this, we could still use two-way binding on ngModel here and bind it to the answer property
here,
of course we need to introduce this answer property then there
and answer could be an empty string by default.
With this in place, let me also add a CSS class to the text area, form-control to give it some nice
styling.
If this reloads, we see our text area here and if I enter valid data here, for my first pet let's say,
a rabbit named Nelly, you instantly see that here. So you can still use two-way binding
and actually if I submit the whole form and open up the developer tools, you'll see in the value object,
this is still part of this value object,
it just is updated with every keystroke
but of course if we submit it, we will get a snapshot of the value at a point of time we hit submit.
So two-way binding is still possible,
you can still use ngModel with two-way binding and with that, you saw all three forms. No binding
to just tell Angular that an input is a control,
one-way binding to give that control a default value and two-way binding to instantly output it or do
whatever you want to do with that value.