Before we dive into optimizing lazy loading, let's add more lazy loading though. Let's make sure we
also lazy load the shopping list and the auth module. Of course feel free to pause the video at this point
and do it on your own,
thereafter we'll do that together. Were you successful? In the end,
we just replicate what we did for recipes.
We add a new path, shopping list and there we add load children and we point at the shopping list
folder and there at the shopping list module, without .ts and thereafter with shopping list module
or whatever you name the class in that file.
Now important, if we have a look at that shopping list module here, this one,
again make sure you are using the right name here in your route config and of course make sure that
here you have a route setup where now, you remove the path name and you have an empty path because the
path name now went in to this global route config where we set up lazy loading.
Now let's replicate the same for auth, therefore here the path should be auth and then we again
use load children, we point at /auth, then at the auth module without .ts and then here, at auth
module and again, in the auth module file,
make sure the path is now just an empty path.
With all of that in place,
again restart ng serve to be certain that these changes are picked up, sometimes they can get lost
if you don't restart the build process and therefore now with that all reset, go back into the app
module and just as before,
make sure you remove the auth module and the shopping list module here so that you're not eagerly loading
that, also remove the imports, save again to trigger a rebuild and now let's wait for that to reload
here in the application,
this looks good.
Now you see that here, the auth auth module was loaded for me which is only 10kb,
the main module shrank to 54kb which is great,
even the vendor module shrank a bit because some parts we previously imported, there are now only imported
by modules, so some parts of the Angular framework like the forms module are now only imported when that
component that uses it is imported and therefore now when we do login here, we go to recipes,
now the recipes module is coming in.
If you click on shopping list, now the shopping list module is imported here, you see these imports popping
up on the right and that is lazy loading in action
and even though the effect is not that large in this app, we can see it and of course it becomes bigger
and bigger the bigger your application is.