Our form has evolved quite a bit.
Now let's say that on the value object we get when we submit the form, we want to group some things,
for example we want to group the secret and the questionAnswer and the username and e-mail to just have
some structure in our object because for a very big form,
we might want to have such a structure.
This would also be nice if we could then validate the validity, the status of our individual groups of
inputs,
turns out that's easy to do with the template driven approach. Here
on our first group, the username and e-mail, I already have a wrapping div with the ID userData here.
Now you can simply place another directive on it,
the ngModelGroup directive like this and this will now group this into,
well you guessed it, a group of inputs,
however ngModelGroup needs to be set equal to a string.
So for example, the userData,
this will be the key name for this group.
So now if I save this with ngModelGroup added, If I enter value here and here and hit submit and we
have a look at the value of the form, you'll now see that we have a userData field here which holds
another object where we now have e-mail and username.
Now not only did we add this extra field in our value, we also now have a different set up here in controls,
here
we also now have a userData control with all the properties you know on those controls, like valid and
so on.
So if we now simply inspect our HTML code and this div with the ID userData, you'll see that there also
we got the ng-dirty, touched and valid classes added.
So you can now also check the validity of this overall control here for example
which might be a nice feature in your form.
You can also get access to the Javascript representation by again adding a local reference to
the element which holds the ngModelGroup directive,
here for example userData would be a fitting name and then setting this equal to ngModelGroup.
So just like we did before with e-mail which was equal to ngModel, I'm now setting this reference
equal to ngModel group to get access to this Javascript object
and this would allow us to for example output a message if this whole group is not valid.
So we could simply output a paragraph here, userData is invalid which we add if userData, this is the local
reference created here,
if userData is not valid
and let's say it has been touched,
so userData touched is true. With that if this reloads,
you see that we don't see any message
but as soon as I click into one of the fields and then leave it,
you'll see userData is invalid was shown.
So now you really got a very finegrained control over your form with all these tools.