Let's use our newly created ingredient model,
so just like with recipe, we can now define the type for our ingredients array and this will be of type
ingredient array and of course for this, we have to import ingredient,
so let's quickly do this from
and now we have to move up one folder so that we are in the app folder and then we have to go into the
shared folder and there, it's in the ingredient.model file, without the file extension.
With that, we can now create one first ingredient,
so let's use our ingredient constructor and we have to pass name and amount here.
So the name could be apples and we want five let's say and then let's also say we want to have some
tomatoes, maybe 10.
That is our shopping list for now,
now we want to output it here in the component. So we get an anchor tag here which represents a single
item and now you could put this into its own component too
but since this is going to be such a straightforward easy item, I don't see much sense outsourcing it
into its own component, though it wouldn't necessarily be bad to do so
but I also don't see a great advantage,
there also isn't a lot of business logic attached to this.
So I will place ngFor on this anchor tag to loop through all the ingredients,
so ingredient of ingredients and now we can output the ingredient data here inside our anchor tag.
So it makes sense to output the ingredient name I believe
and then maybe in parentheses thereafter and these parentheses here are no Angular syntax, that is
normal text here I'm outputting, inside the parentheses,
I'm going to use string interpolation to also output ingredient amount. With that if we now save this,
we already see our shopping list here at the bottom,
the last missing piece I want to add is this shopping list edit section here which should display us
an input field which then allows us to actually edit our items or add new ones, at least later in the
course,
it will add this functionality.