In the last lecture, we added our array,
now I want to clean up how it looks,
some styling but mainly, I want to add a button which allows us to add a new ingredient to that array.
Well to work on the styling, all I really want to do is I want to have some spacing between the
rows.
Well, there are a couple of ways of getting this style, what I will simply do is I will add an inline style,
a normal style, no Angular style, no ngStyle directive, a
normal style where I say margin top and set this to 10 pixels maybe
and with that, it looks much better.
So that's all I wanted to do for now,
the more important part is that we're able to add new ingredients and for this, I'll simply add a new
button at the end of this array area,
so outside of the div which is responsible for my individual form groups, I'll add a new row with a new
column inside of it
and here, I will simply add a button which says add ingredient which will be of type or which will get
a class of btn btn-success maybe.
So now it sits directly at the bottom,
maybe let's simply add a horizontal line between rows and that looks pretty good.
So now we get this button, let's now also hook it up.
I will add a click listener, onAddIngredient
and here in this method which I'll add to the TypeScript file, I want to add new control to this array
of form controls.
Now I can simply do this by accessing my recipe form, there I can get my ingredients control and I know
that this will be a formArray but Angular or TypeScript to be precise doesn't know this.
So I will explicitly cast it with this cast command here basically by enclosing the type I want to convert
it to between smaller and greater than signs and then enclosing this all in parentheses
and now the part here between the parentheses is treated like a formArray because I know that it
indeed is one.
So here I can call push and I want to push a new FormGroup because remember, we don't push a control
here, we need two inputs,
so a group of inputs and there again, I will have a name which is a new FormControl and I will have
an amount which will be a new FormControl and we don't need to provide any initial values because I
don't want to have any.
So if I save this and we go back to the application, we should indeed see that once this reloads here, if I
click add ingredient, we add a new line,
however I also submit the form with each click as you can see here on the right.
This is quickly fixed by making sure that this button receives the type button
and now it shouldn't submit the form anymore,
so now it just adds ingredients. This is all working, this is great,
now before we make this form submittable or we do something upon submission, let's make sure that we
add some validation to it.