Back in the application, let's actually create a new dummy service to highlight what's going on.
I'll name this logging.service.ts file, that's the file name and I added next to the app
module,
though that doesn't really matter.
There, let me export the logging service and first of all, let's provide it by adding @injectable with
the object passed to it where we set provided in to route.
Now as you learned, this will provide the same instance of the service to the entire application. Here,
I'll add a last log property which is a string and initially it's undefined and then I'll add a print
log method here, where I get a message which is a string and first of all, I simply console log that message
but I also set this last log equal to the message and prior to setting this equal, I do log the last
log,
so the old last log
therefore. So we took the message and what was previously in the log
and then we overwrite what's previously in the log with the new message.
Of course, this is just a demo, not important to this application but important for understanding the
different service instance of things.
Now let's call this in app component in ngOnInit, there
let's simply inject the logging service, which is of type logging service,
make sure to add the import path here and in ngOnInit,
we can now call this logging service, print log hello from app component
ngOnInit.
Now let's also add it in our shopping list component. There in the shopping list component,
we also have ngOnInit,
so let's inject the logging service here as well, again make sure to add the right import path and in
ngOnInit, here
let's simply set this logging service, call print log and there I print Hello from shopping list component
ngOnInit.
OK, so I've got two places where I use that service,
now let's switch to the console in the dev tools and actually logout and reload the app.
OK,
so now we see hello from app component ngOnInit and then we see undefined, undefined is simply
stemming from that last log which I'm printing here,
now let's navigate to shopping list. You see hello from shopping list ngOnInit and you see
hello from app component ngOnInit because this is now our last log which was stored,
right
we do store it here,
so we're printing this the second time print log is called. This kind of proves that we're using one
and the same instance in the entire application because we're using the service in two different components
and yet, we're using the same object, otherwise last log would be undefined here as well. It isn't
and therefore we have proof that it's the same object as before. Let's change this by not using @injectable
with provided in root here but let's instead provide that service in the app module,
there, we can add providers and we provide the logging service. Let me switch back to authenticate and
reload, same output as before,
let's go to shopping list,
same output as before
because providing in the app module has the same effect as using @injectable. Let's get rid of that
as well,
let's now use an eagerly loaded module,
the core module, that is eagerly loaded because we import it here into the app module. There,
I already do provide services here so I kind of think that proves the point
but let's now add the logging service here, add the import as well,
save that, go to authenticate and reload, same output as before, go to shopping list,
same output as before.
Now let's change that,
let's remove logging service from the core module and let's instead provide it here in the app module
as before
but let's now also provide it in the shopping list module. There,
I'll add providers and I'll provide the logging service as well.
So now I'm providing it in a lazy loaded module,
the shopping list module and in an eagerly loaded module, my app module. Let's go to authenticate and reload,
same output as before,
let's go to shopping list,
oh now the output is different, because we're now using two different objects, two different instances
of that same service.
We're using a separate instance in our application in general for the service provided in app module
but since the shopping list module brings its own instance by providing the logging service again here,
the shopping list module and all the components in there use a separate instance of the logging
service, they don't use the application-wide available instance, they use their own instance created
by that child injector.
Now if you need that behaviour, definitely use it,
nothing wrong with that,
this is not a bug,
this is an intended feature but in general, you should think twice before you provide a service in any
other module than the app module because often, it's not the wanted behaviour and you then suddenly
have strange bugs when you're using different instances in your application.
So if you need that behaviour, use it but generally be aware that there are differences in the instances
you get when you provide services in lazy loaded modules.
This also includes modules that you import into lazy loaded modules, for example
if I comment this out in the shopping list module and I comment this out in the app module, let's provide
the service in the shared module. The shared module here in the shared folder, the shared module of course
is also able to add providers and let's provide the logging service here now.
Now the shared module is imported by the app module and there therefore it is an eagerly loaded module
but it's also imported into the shopping list module.
Now there, the shared module to the shopping list module is also eagerly loaded but the shopping
list module itself is lazy loaded,
turning this here in this place, the shared module in this place also into a lazy loaded module.
So here the shared module is both, it is lazy loaded in the shopping list or through the shopping list module
and it's eagerly loaded into the app module and the effect is that if we reload here, that works and
we see the output here on the app component but we have the same issue in quotation mark before because
the shopping list module still use its its own instance because it imports the shared module into it
and that is the most problematic bug
you often end up with when providing services in other modules. You might be providing a service in something
like a shared module, where you think yes I'm going to put all my shared services into this but you
might still have shared services that should use the same instance across your entire application.
Well as soon as you're importing your shared module into a lazy loaded module, the services provided
in the shared module will be recreated for the lazy loaded module and all of a sudden, you might have
a behaviour you don't want.
So whilst providing a service directly in the lazy loaded module might be something you control deliberately,
providing it in a shared module is a common gotcha where you think you use the same service instance
in the entire app when you don't.
I know this can be difficult to wrap your head around but this is a crucial thing and a common source
of bugs and therefore the rule of thumb is that you provide services through @injectable or in the
app module, if you do it differently, you should have a strong reason and you should either be able to
rule out that this module you're adding the service in is loaded lazily or you deliberately want multiple
instances.