So that's the first basic set up,
of course we can improve this app,
for example I don't want to have recipes and shopping lists component on the same page.
We will fix this soon, first temporarily and then with a real good solution later in the course
and I also want to have my components communicate with each other, so that we can actually store the
content of the items in our recipe-list in their own component, that we can select a recipe here and
load it in the detail section and so on.
For now though, that is how far we can go with the knowledge we gathered, the blocking thing right now
is the component communication
and that's why we're going to dive into this in the next course section.
See you there and then see you back in this project later in the course.