No matter how you handle your error, what can be useful is a special operator that can assist you with
handling errors and that special operator needs to be imported from rxjs/operators and it's
named catch error and it does exactly what the names suggests.
Now let's say here when we fetch posts, where we already pipe some data, we got an error and
we want to handle that.
Now we can simply add the catch error operator here, we get our error response in here, so we get exactly
the same data we would get in that second argument of the subscribe method
and in here, you could now do stuff like send to analytics server or anything like that,
so some generic error handling task you might want to do. Maybe not related to the UI, though of course
you could use the subject
and next the error message here too
but maybe you have some behind the scenes stuff you want to do when an error occurs,
log it somewhere, send it to your own server, your analytics server, anything like that.
And once you're done handing that error, you should pass it on though, it definitely needs to be able
to reach subscribe, just as you need to pass something here in map as well.
So we also now need to create a new observable that wraps that error
and for that, you can import something from RxJS and that something is throw error and that is a function
that will yield a new observable and it yields a new observable by wrapping an error.
So here, we can now throw the error response,
you could also throw a new custom error which you generated, whatever you want.
Important, you need to return that observable which is created by throw error.
And now with that, this of course doesn't do anything useful here but it's just an idea that you could
consider using catch error if you have some generic error handling task
you also want to execute.