So with the token added to fetch recipes, obviously we also want to add it to store recipes.
Now we can use the same logic we used in fetched recipes in store recipes but since we're using the
Angular HttpClient, we could also use another feature offered by that client because what we
do here in the end is we manipulate all these outgoing requests in the same way and
what could we use here? An interceptor.
So let's add such an interceptor here to use that interceptor to manipulate our requests instead
of manually doing it twice.
I'll add it in the auth folder because I'll name it auth-interceptor.service.ts
because it is an authentication-related interceptor and the class name therefore will be auth interceptor
service and since I'll plan on injecting something there, let's add @injectable, like this and import
injectable from
@angular/core.
Now important, don't add the object with provided in root here because we will provide this differently
as you learned in the HTTP section, we have to provide it such that Angular understands it.
Now this service should implement an interface provided by the @angular/common/http package
and that interface would be the HTTP interceptor interface here, so let's add implements
HttpInterceptor here and that forces us to add a intercept method and that intercept method actually
needs to get two arguments - the request, the HTTP request which is a generic type of type any, so we don't
know which data all the requests will return and we have next which is our HTTP handler and you
need to import these types from @angular/common/http and definitely watch the HttpClient
module to learn more about that.
Now there, you also learned that you need to return next handle and pass in your request.
However, not the request like this but actually, I want to edit the request and add my token.
Therefore, let's add a constructor and inject the auth service here, which is of type auth service
and that service needs to be imported,
so let's import auth service from ./auth.service.
And with that injected, we can now reach out to the auth service, to the user which is a subject and
therefore an observable and subscribe to it.
Now, we have the same problem as before though, in the end here, we need to return an observable,
this also is an observable and therefore I'll solve this problem in the same way as before. In the data
storage service, we used pipe take one exhaustMap and so on.
It's pretty much the same now,
I'll grab this code here, with the exhaustMap and the pipe method and we'll fix it here in a second
and go to the auth interceptor and use this code in that place, close all parentheses, import these operators
from RxJS of course, so import take and exhaustMap from rxjs/operators, so that this works
and now since we got the user in here, in there we can return next handle request and we can edit the
request based on the user here now and we return this overall chain which just as before will be a
chain that in the end has this handle observable being returned because we swapped the user observable
with that one in the map function here, in that map operator.
So all we have to do here now is, we have to clone our request and update it, so the modified request is
created by calling request clone and to clone, we can pass on an object where we can update the params
by setting them to a new set of HTTP params which is imported from @angular/common/http,
where we call set and pass in the params. So auth is the name of the params we need and user.token
is the value. Now of course, we should handle the modified request
and with that, this interceptor should add the token to all outgoing requests.
Now let's make sure we provide that token in the app module, here under providers
I want to add a new object
where I add the provide keyword and use HTTP interceptor which is imported from
@angular/common/http.
This is the identifier for this provider, then use class and there I'll use the auth interceptor service and
for that, we need to import that service here at the top.
So let's import auth interceptor service from
the auth folder and there, the auth-interceptor.service file and last but not least as you learned,
set multi to true to allow for multiple interceptors
even if you're only using one. So now with that, the interceptor is added here,
now we just need to fix the data storage service again because now, we don't need to use the logic we
had in there a second ago because we now move that into the interceptor,
so now we directly return this observable and we simply call pipe there and pass in map and so on into this
pipe, we don't add the params here as well.
Now we should use this interceptor for outgoing request.
If we now go to authenticate and we login again,
we get an unknown error,
do you have any idea what could be the reason for that error? It becomes clear if we inspect the outgoing
request here.
We're trying to login,
so let's retry this here with the cleared request tab and somehow, no request gets sent at all.
So our request fails before it even gets sent
and that is actually stemming from our auth interceptor because there, we are using that logic for every
outgoing request, including our sign-up and login requests.
Now when that happens, what we try to do is we subscribe to the user service and we get null as a user
therefore because this is what we initialize our user
at the beginning, here it is null when our app loads. So user here is null
and therefore when we try to access the token, this fails because we try to access token on null,
this throws an error and the request doesn't even get sent.
How do we work around that?
Well, we can add a check here and check if we don't have a user,
then we just return next handle for the original requests, so we don't try to modify it,
we only try to add the token if we have a user.
Alternatively or in addition, you could also check the URL of the outgoing request and only add the
token for a specific URLs or exclude certain URLs
but here
this should do the trick already.
So now if you try logging in again, this looks way better and now if I try fetching data, this also still
works
but keep in mind that this now uses the interceptor.
The advantage of the interceptor now of course is that this also automatically works for storing recipes
because this uses the same interceptor automatically.
So if I delete a recipe and I click save data, you see this also succeeds,
otherwise we would have an error down there and we can also prove it by fetching data
again. This doesn't change,
so we are not fetching a third recipe because we overwrote them on the server with our save action.
So that's the interceptor in action.