Well there are two things we should definitely do,
three actually, we should enable this delete button and when editing a recipe, no matter if creating a
new one or editing an existing one,
we should make the cancel button work and upon hitting save,
we should navigate away.
Actually that's the same which would happen when hitting cancel.
So that would be a challenge for you again, make all three buttons work, save and cancel to simply navigate
away
and then also the delete button to delete our recipe.
Here is my approach.
What I want to do is I want to start with the delete button. For this,
I'll start with the recipe service and add a deleteRecipe method,
where I will get the index of the recipe which should get deleted
and in here, I will then use my recipes array, call the splice method and splice at the index one element
to remove it,
thereafter I'll call recipesChanged and enit a copy of the updated recipes, like this.
That's the first step.
Now I can call deleteRecipe from the recipe detail component which is where we have this delete button
by adding a click listener, onDeleteRecipe and here I will copy that and implement it in the TypeScript
file, here onDeleteRecipe and I simply want to reach out to the recipe service, call deleteRecipe
and now we also need the ID here.
So we used that earlier in this course to have this more complicated way of navigating
but for deleting, now we really need it,
so here we should add this ID as an argument.
So before we test this, let's also make the cancel and save button work and let them navigate us away.
So in the recipe edit component which is where we have these buttons, here
we should hook them up to an event listener, so cancel we should hook up, the other one already is automatically
triggering the submission event. When we hit cancel,
I want to execute onCancel and in the recipe-edit.component.ts file,
we don't need that import any more so we can remove it but the thing I wanted to do is I will add the
onCancel method and in onCancel,
well here I simply want to navigate away.
So for that, we need the router of type router, so let's inject it here,
make sure to import the router type from @angular/router and with that injected in onCancel, I
can simply access the router and navigate and I want to go up one level.
If we were editing, this will take me back to the detail page,
if we clicked on the new button, it will take me back to the recipes page.
So for this to work, we need to tell Angular what our current route is and we do already inject it here,
the activated route.
So with that, we can pass the second parameter relative to this route.
So that happens if we click the cancel button,
I actually want the same to happen once I submit the form.
So here, I will call onCancel even though it sounds wrong but we are done at this point,
we can simply navigate away.
Let's see if that all works. If I click cancel,
we're back to our recipe, the same for this one
and if I do change something and hit save,
we're also back to the updated recipe and if we create a new one and I hit cancel,
we're back to the place like the recipe state which makes sense and if I enter something here and click
save,
we're back to this state too. So this is our application working fine here,
all these buttons working,
let's see if we can delete this recipe now.
Looks almost OK but we still see it here in the detail view, even though we deleted it. We can demonstrate
this again for the schnitzel,
see it, it's still here even though we removed it.
So that is something we need to update before we are finally done with this section.