For that, I'm back in the course project and the part I want to handle with dynamic components is here
on the login when I enter incorrect credentials, at the moment we then have that spinner and then we see
that error message there.
Now nothing wrong with that way of displaying an error,
it's perfectly fine,
you don't have to change that but to demonstrate how you could load a component dynamically,
I will change it.
I will not use that box here but instead, we'll build a very simple alert box which is presented as an
overlay here on the screen with a nice backdrop that hides the background and in that alert box, we
can then simply click OK to get rid of it and have another try here.
So that's the idea.
Let me now go back to code and here,
the goal now is to first of all build such an alert and I'll do that in a shared folder.
I'll name that alert and in there, I'll create my alert.component.ts file where I
want to build that alert component.
Now my alert component here will be a simple box that is loaded as an overlay on the entire screen
and therefore, let's here export a class, alert component like this and give it that @component decorator.
Now in that decorator, I'll assign a selector, app alert and add the template URL where I want to
point at an external template, the alert.component.html file which we therefore also have
to create in that same folder and that is my basic component for now.
Now the alert component here then receives of course some markup
and here, I will include both the backdrop and that overlay box in one and the same component,
of course you could also split this into multiple components.
So here we'll write some custom CSS actually and I'll add a div with a class of backdrop, that will
be the backdrop,
so basically that thing in the background that blocks access to the rest of the page and ensures that
the focus is on the alert box and that box is the second div I'll add here.
I'll give that a class of alert box, something like this, to not interfere with the alert class provided
by bootstrap because I don't want to use that and in that alert box here, I'll keep this really simple,
I'll just add a paragraph where we can output the message with string interpolation
and that is referring to a message property we haven't added yet to the component, we'll do that soon
and I also want to have a button to close that alert and therefore I'll add another div here, I'll
name this alert box actions,
so that's my class name here and in that div, I'll add a button with class btn-btn-primary.
Now I'm using Bootstrap classes here again to get that button styling
and here we can just say close. So this could be an alert box, it's missing some styling, so let me add
an alert.component.css file here as well and point at that file in our component declaration here,
so style URLs receives a pointer, an alert.component.css. So far, so good.
Now in the alert component, I do have that message property which I want to output and therefore in the
alert.component.ts file, we need that message property and that will be a string and it should
be settable from outside.
And therefore, you learned that we can add @input here and input needs to be important from
@angular/core to make this settable from outside.
With that, the alert component is almost finished,
let's now add it to the app module here, add it to the declarations there, the alert component
and now let's see how we could add it.
Well, we could go to our
auth component, to the template there of course and there,
right now I do have that alert box which is shown when we do have an error.
Now I'll comment that out and instead use app alert here and there, we have to set the message property
which we made bindable with @input and I'll set this to error and I'll show the entire alert box
here with the app alert element only if we have an error.
So now we're simply just showing our own alert component,
so far, nothing too fancy of course.
Now this custom alert component now will receive some styling and I'll start with the backdrop,
so the thing in the background. That will get a fixed position, top 0, left 0, a width of 100vw
actually which is the viewport width, so not the percentage, to not take the container width but the entire
viewport width, a height of 100vh
to take the entire viewport height as well, then a background of RGBA 0, 0, .75 which is slightly
transparent black background color. A z-index of let's say 50, to be above all the other elements that
could be there
and yes, that should be it.
Now the alert box, this is the other element we have, should also get some styling.
First of all, this will get a position of fixed too, top here
could be let's say 30vh to have it 30% inside of the viewport, to not have it sit right at
the top of the viewport.
The left will actually be let's say 20vw, the width of this thing here will then be 60vw because then
we have 20 to the left and 20 to the right to center this nicely.
I'll not set a height, the height should be determined by the content that's in there and I'll give it
a padding though of let's say 16px, a z-index of 100 to be above of the backdrop, a background color
of white and a slight box shadow with these settings here to hopefully make it look good. So that's
my alert box,
now we also have that alert box actions class which holds that button where we can close everything
and there, I just want to add the text align right to push this all the way to the right.
Now of course, you can adjust this however you want.
Let's see this,
let's wait for this to reload and then enter some incorrect credentials here
and here is our alert box. This is this nice modal now
and of course you could go way more advanced here,
you could use ng content to pass dynamic DOM into that box here, whatever you want
but this is our box, of course at the moment we can't close it though
but creating that is the first step.
Now how can we load this dynamically
and of course also, how can we then close it?