Welcome to a new model for this course we learned a lot about English too.
But the one thing we haven't covered is testing unit tests to be precise.
While the reason for this is that I really wanted to focus on the angle to code and not confuse people
with mixing in some non-English to testing code.
That being said testing is something.
Wait.
A lot of people might want to do in their project which actually improves your project and hence I will
give you an introduction this module and that is important and introduction you will learn how you can
write your task to have the Angua Seelye.
You will also find resources for non-C like projects.
You will learn how a task generally works and why you might want to test and which tasks and utilities
to office you.
I will give you or it will explain some example tests.
For example we will test a basic component a service and a pipe but thereafter it's really up to you
to use the resources I also provide to dive deeper into it because testing alone won't be enough content
for let's say a 15 hour course and it's not what this course is about and it's not what discourse should
be about.
But with.
Let's dive in