So here is the course project in the state we last left it, ng serve is already running in a terminal
and now I want to add routing.
Now let's start with the root routes, with the routes for our overall application before we then dive
into the child routes. You learned how to add such routes and therefore, here's a challenge for you,
try implementing the main routes of your application, so to load the recipe page and the shopping list
page on your own.
So right now, I will give you a couple of seconds to pause the video and try this on your own,
then we'll implement this together.
So were you successful?
Here is my solution. For the root routes,
I will add an AppRoutingModule as shown in the routing section.
So let's add it in the app folder, the app-routing.module.ts file.
Now in there as you learned it, we're going to export a TypeScript class which is called AppRoutingModule
and this module has only one purpose,
it will provide the routing to our application,
it will bundle all the routing functionality so to say.
Now here, we need to add @NgModule to this class to transform it from a normal TypeScript class into
an Angular module
and for this we also need to import @NgModule here at the top.
Now @NgModule takes a Javascript object in which we can configure it in greater detail,
however we won't need to configure that much for our app routing module,
mainly we will need to register our routes.
So let's set them up first.
I'll add a constant named appRoutes and this will be of type routes, just like that.
Now routes needs to be imported from @angular/router and as you learned, routes simply is just an array
of Javascript objects where each object represents a route,
so let's add the first route.
Now which routes do we need?
As mentioned, a route which loads our recipe section and a route which loads our shopping lists section,
so let's start with the recipes.
I'll set up a path of which will be displayed in the URL and which will allow us to go to that route
and let's say recipes
sounds like a good path for this, so that you can visit your domain and then /recipes to reach
this route.
Now when we visit recipes, I want to load the recipes component. So I'll assign that component here,
the recipes component
and of course we need to add the import of that component.
So make sure to add this at the top pointing to the recipes folder and then the recipes.component
file.
That's our first route added,
of course one route is not everything we need here,
we also need a second route. So I'll quickly duplicate this
and here, I now want to target shopping list,
so let's set up this route too.
And here of course the goal is not to target the recipes component but instead, we want to target the
shopping list component,
our second main route and as the recipes component, we need to import this and add the import statement
at the top.
With that, we get two routes to load
and we also get a problem. When we first visit the page,
we will navigate to neither of the two,
we will just visit the path with basically an empty path,
so just our domain slash nothing,
therefore we should add another path here, another route. Here I want to target an empty path,
so basically the path we will reach when we load the app for the first time and here, we could now either also
load the recipes component but that's not really what I want to do,
instead here I want to redirect to /recipes. So I will redirect to and now /recipes,
now let's try implementing it like this. In my @NgModule here,
I now will import the router module, like that.
You have to import it from @angular/router. On the router module, we can call forRoot and here, we should
pass our appRoutes to configure this router module Angular ships with. With that, our routes are now
configured and added to the @angular/router.
Now since we are in an extra module here and we want to get this into our main module, into our app
module, I need to export this readily configured router.
So I will add the exports array here and simply export router module.
Now important, here without calling forRoot because we already did that,
now its really all about exporting this configured router. With that configured and exported here,
we can go to the app module and here in the imports array, we should import our AppRoutingModule and
of course also add this import here at the top, so that you make sure to import AppRoutingModule from
./app-routing.module, from this file. With this, routing was added to the application,
now we need a place for Angular to render our routes.
So that is something I will set up right now in the app component, here where we currently use our ngIf
trick to decide which route should be loaded,
well here I will remove this approach and instead add the router outlet to mark the place where the Angular
router should render the component we should load depending on the path we are at.
With that, we get a place to load our routes.
Now we get no links as of now,
we will add them soon
but let's first check if this all works.
So with ng serve running, I will save this to trigger the recompilation and then I will have a look
at the running app. Here we get an error and the error message gives us a hint on how to fix this
but what's the issue?
The way we configured it, we will always redirect the router because the default matching strategy of
the router is for the path, it will see if it's a prefix of the current path and the empty path which
is our redirect route if you check it here,
this route here uses an empty path and therefore, this is part of any route we visit because again, the default matching
strategy is prefix,
so it will check if this empty path is a part of the total path
and of course it is,
it's part of every path.
So that wasn't a problem when we were redirecting from, let's say something to somewhere else because
now we had a very specific path and of course, we would also redirect something/anything else but
it would not be part of every route.
Well, an empty path is the path of every route.
It's easy to be fixed
and actually the error message told us how to do that,
we have to add the pathMatch property here and set this to full, this overrides the default of prefix
and says now only redirect if the full path is empty,
so we won't redirect on any other paths. With this if we save this and we reload the page,
here we see
this now works
and we were redirected to recipes.
I can demonstrate this if we reload the page, again we're gone to recipes
and if I try loading the shopping list path, that also works.
So navigation works,
now the goal is to hook up the links in our navigation because that of course right now is not working
anymore.