That's the project you can find attached to this lecture here,
it allows us to define a server name here and then some content for the server and then we can either
add a server or a blueprint
and as you can see, both look pretty similar but the server is bold and red or has some bold and red text,
the blueprint has some italic blue text.
So that's the difference here.
Now this app is all running in one component
as of now, in the app component, here in the template, we got a lot of code and we can do better, we can
split this up because that's not ideal having all that logic in this component here, maybe splitting
it up makes sense because that would also allow us if we build a bigger app to reuse parts of that.
So how could we split this up? We could create a new component for this whole cockpit here where we enter
a name and content and click the buttons
and of course we could also create component, a component for an individual server
and with that, we should have a much leaner app.component.html file and we would bundle our business
logic better into individual components.
Now we learned how to create new components,
I will use the CLI,
you could of course also do it manually and I will create new components with ng g and then let's say
the first component could be this cockpit here,
so I will simply name it cockpit component.
Now as an addition, we can type --spec false to make sure this spec, this testing file is
not getting created,
I deleted it all the time anyways
and then I will repeat the step for another new component which I will simply name server-element,
server-element because it could either be a server or a blueprint
in this example.
So with that, we get two new folders in our app component,
so two new components,
thus far nothing you don't know.
Now we can of course take our code here from the app.component.html file from this template,
so for example this first bootstrap row here, cut it here and add it to our cockpit, like this.
Now of course if we remove the template part here, we also have to remove or we have to move the methods
we're calling here,
so onAddServer and onAddBlueprint.
So in the TypeScript code here, I will copy both or I will cut both elements here and move them over to our
cockpit and we'll soon also come to ngOnInit
and what this does as a side note. Now of course my issue is that I try to push these two arrays or to
an array which doesn't exist here,
serverElements, that array is still in the app component.
We could of course move that,
oh and maybe I should also move that closing curly brace. We could of course move this serverElements
array
but then we would no longer have it in our app component and we will need it there too because
there we still will need to replicate the serverElements to create the servers we output here.
So as a first step, what I can move of course, cut and paste are the two properties which are used here
with two-way binding, so I can move that to the cockpit
but we will have to see what we do about this serverElements array.
For now let's go back to the app.component.html file and take a single server here,
so this panel
div here.
So with that, all we have here now is the row and the column and the other part will go into the HTML file
of the server element because that is a single server.
Now here of course, we have this loop and that's not what I want to have in here, so
I will get rid of it there because I still want to manage my array of serverElements in the app component
because we somehow need to be able to manipulate from the cockpit and then replicate it in the app
component to create multiple instances of this server element component which is only a single server.
Keep this in mind, this is not the list of servers.
Of course you could set this up differently but this is the approach I will go with and this approach
won't work right now,
we also tried to access an element property now inside of our server element component which we also don't
have.
So a couple of things to fix,
I like the general way we split up our app and that we now can add our app cockpit here where we before
had the full HTML ccode we moved over there and that we can add our app-server-element component here
and that we could also replicate this with ngFor, let serverElement of serverElements,
so we can of course also place ngFor on a component as you already learned before.
So I like that but I don't like that the app is broken and if we have a look at it, that we simply
get an error that a couple of properties are unknown.
So we somehow
and that is a key part,
need to get the new server
we add in the cockpit to this array of servers in our app component,
so we kind of need to inform our app component that one of its child components, the app cockpit changed
or that something changed there to which we should react,
a new server was added
and then we also need to get the data we got from the cockpit,
so this new server which is managed in this array of servers in the app component, we need to get to
individual server of a single loop iteration here down to the app-server-element.
So we need to pass data between components and that of course is a super important task
we haven't touched yet but we will dive deeper into right now.