So let's add some services manually.
Now we should place the services next to the feature or in the folder holding the feature they belong
to.
So if we create a recipe service, the recipes folder looks like a good place for it.
So here, I'll add a recipe service
and of course the file is named recipe.service.ts due to that and here I'll simply export
a class which is named recipe service.
Remember, a service simply is a TypeScript class,
you don't need to add any special decorator to it, at least not if you don't plan on injecting a service
into the service.
Well and the same for the shopping list service.
I'll place it in the shopping list folder, here
I'll name it shopping-list.service.ts,
that's the file name
and then inside the file of course, I'll export a class named shopping list service.
So these are the two service files.
Now let's start working on the recipe service first,
let's start working on it in the next lecture.