Of course the obvious first question is, what is application state?
Why do we need a state management solution? Doesn't Angular already have one? What is this state thing?
Well, consider this simple Angular application,
it's not the application we worked on in this course but of course this could be just another application
you have where you have the welcome component, then a couple of the training components here because
maybe you're building like a training application, something where people can do workouts and save them
and you have your training service.
Now in this application, the service would be there to manage the core data
these different components need to work correctly,
for example you could be fetching exercises or once the user is done with the exercise,
you could store that exercise result here. Well and all that data
which kind of is important for your application because this data is in the end controlling what's visible
on the screen, that is your application state and this application state is lost whenever your application
refreshes,
so whenever you reload your Angular app, your website.
Now this simply is the case because this entire data here is managed in a service and in components
but all that together is just a Javascript app in the end, right, your entire Angular application is
compiled into a Javascript bundle in the end. So it's all in Javascript and therefore, it's managed in
memory by Javascript and therefore whenever your page is reloaded, the Angular app restarts and the other
app is basically dumped, it's lost and the memory is cleared, that's why it's refreshed
but that's not the problem
NgRx helps you deal with because that is not per say a problem,
that's just how Javascript works and to solve that refreshing problem, we typically work with a backend.
Like in this course, when we added our recipes and we don't have a database on the backend where we store
that data,
well then we would lose all our recipes and all the changes we made to them whenever our application
reloads and therefore, we typically also interact with such a backend where we store and fetch data too.
This is so-called persistent state and it's persistent because it survives our page refreshes as it
is stored on the backend. So state in a nutshell could be translated with data that's important to your
application and that influences what's visible on the screen.
State is not just data like stored exercises or recipes, state could also be things like "this app is currently
waiting for some data to be fetched", so the app is in a loading state, it's showing a spinner maybe.
So basically, any data, any information that controls what should be visible on the screen, that is state.
OK, so that is state and thus far in this course we already managed such state, typically in services but
tiny pieces of state are even getting managed inside of components,
let me show you examples.
Here is our application as we built it and if we have a look at the shopping list service, this would
be an example of a service being used for managing state.
Here, our ingredients which we have here, which we can fetch, where we can add new ingredients,
that's in the end data
our application needs to work correctly or at least parts of our application need that to work correctly
but that's not the only kind of state we have.
If we have a look at our auth component here, there
we also have some state.
Here we have the isLoading property inside of that component, not stored in a service and we use that
isLoading component to change it
once we are starting the sign-up or the sign-in process and then we use it in a template to show a spinner
for example, here.
Now that's also state, maybe not application state because it doesn't affect the entire application or
larger parts of the application but still, it is state,
you could call it local state, it's local to this component but to this component, it doesn't matter
but again it's data,
it's information that controls what we see on the screen and therefore
this would also be state. Well and if we have a look at the recipes service, there we also manage state,
we manage our recipes and we also store these recipes, not in the recipes service but in the data storage
service, we store the recipes on a server and there we persist that data so that it doesn't get lost.
This is how all these things work together and
that is how we already use state in our application.
Now what's the problem with this approach?
Well simpler apps and that includes our course project to
be very honest
so I should maybe say smaller apps. Typically are fine with how we already manage state, by using components
and services and actually, you can get very far with this approach only,
even bigger apps can be managed with just services and components but the bigger your app gets and the
more complex your state gets,
so maybe an app like this where we have a lot of components and service that interact with each other,
if you have an app that becomes bigger and bigger and your state depends on many components at the same
time and many components depend on the service and so on, then you could end up in state management nightmare.
So you could end up in an application where it's hard to maintain the app because it's hard for you
to tell
where exactly am I managing this piece of information
and maybe you're even changing a piece of information, like the isLoading state of a component accidentally
from another place in the application simply because your code is structured such that this is possible.
Well we already have a remedy to that and that is rxjs, at least partly. RxJS already allows
us to create a streamlined state management experience. With RxJS and there specifically with
subjects, we can react to user events in the user interface or to application events like some data fetching
finishing, we can react to such a state changing event, so to an event where we want to update some
data or some information in our app by using observables or as I said, subjects and we can emit or next a
new data piece there and maybe use operators to even transform data in the way we want it and then
listen to such state changes in other parts of the application where we need it to then update the UI
and we're doing this already as well.
If I dive back into the code and back into the recipes service, there indeed, recipes are managed
with the help of these recipes changed subject here.
Now keep in mind that this subject in the end is used to emit a new copy of all recipes whenever the
recipes did change,
so for example when we overwrote our existing recipes or whenever we added a recipe.
And why does this matter?
Because this then can be used in other components,
like the recipe list component where we set up a subscription to that recipes changed subject to update
our recipes in that component and therefore indirectly update the user interface of that component
whenever our recipes do change.
So here we are already using a quite good pattern of managing our state by using subjects and using
that push subscribe mechanism where we have a clear stream of data, a unidirectional data stream. It's
for example not really possible or not easily possible to update our recipes outside of that predefined
flow of using these methods in the recipes service where we then emit a new event where we then subscribe
to.
Yes, you can always hack your way around this but of course if you want to break your app, you can always
do that.
But what I want to say here is that this approach of managing state using RxJS and subjects is
already pretty good, it might be all you need and that includes bigger apps,
so even bigger and very large apps, you can definitely work with a setup that only uses services, components
and such subjects to manage this state but that can of course be tricky because it really forces you
to have an eye on providing a good structure and a clean setup and ensuring that really all services
and all pieces of state are implemented in a good way
and that is where NgRx steps in.