What are modules?
And with that, I mean the Angular modules. You will also hear the term module where you are talking about
the imports you have in your files when you import something from another file into another
file,
that also is sometimes referred to as modules but these would be Javascript modules, they're totally
not related to Angular and they're not
what I mean.
I mean that NgModule thing that we have in our app, like the app module or the app routing module.
So modules in the end are ways of bundling Angular building blocks together,
that would be components, directives, services, pipes.
You have to group that all together into such Angular modules so that Angular is aware of these features
because Angular doesn't automatically scan all the files in your project,
it doesn't search all the code you write and automatically detect all components and services,
instead you need to tell Angular what is a component, which components do you have and you can then bundle
them together into modules. Every Angular app needs to have at least one module, that app module,
you can't have an Angular app without it.
So Angular analyzes these NgModules to understand your application and its features, you use them
to define all the core building blocks - components, directives, services, pipes and so on and app as I just
mentioned requires at least to one such module, the app module
but you may split it into multiple modules and we will do that in this core section.
You also have core Angular features that are wrapped into modules, things like the forms module which
we added in the course already,
so Angular itself also provides certain features grouped together into such modules, so that you don't
have to declare like 10 different forms directives, instead that forms module gives you all these directives,
that is how you can think about that. And important also,
you can't use a certain feature or building block without including it in a module. How you include it
if you add it to declarations or providers depends on the feature you are talking about.
So let's have a look at our app module and what we're using thus far.