Having the auto login in place is great but what about an auto logout because our token will expire,
it has an expiry time of one hour
once we get it and therefore right now, we have a bug in the app because this token will never expire
or the token will expire
but our application won't reflect that. We will automatically log the user in forever because we now
have that snapshot here and we never cleared that snapshot
and sure we could clear it when we logout and we should do that and we will do that but it will never
clear automatically. If the token expired after one hour,
nothing changes in our application and that of course is something we have to change.
So first of all in the auth service, we should make sure that since we store a snapshot upon on logging
in, we also clear that snapshot here in the logout function because if a user logs out,
we certainly have to clear everything about that user in our application and that includes the local
storage.
So here, we should take our local storage and we can simply call clear, to clear all the data and the
local storage,
that however only makes sense if we have no other data in there,
if we do have, then we clear that as well, so it's better if we don't clear all the data
but instead if we call remove item and we just remove that user data key and the data that's stored there.
Now that's step number one, that we do actually clear the data when we logout
but now we also need to set a timer when the token is stored or when we first get a token
so that we know when to invalidate that token at a later point of time. And for this, I'll add yet another
method here which I'll call auto logout,
we have auto login for automatically retrieving user data and logging the user in,
now we need a method that sets a timer and manages a timer for automatically logging the user out. Auto
logout should get the expiration duration here which is a number as an argument,
so this will be the amount of milliseconds we have until the token is invalid let's say, of course you
could write this in a different logic but I will go with milliseconds which we get as an argument here
and then we can use set timeout in here to set that to that duration and after that duration here,
I want to call this logout,
so the logout function we have here should be called automatically after our expiration duration.
Now the important thing is that when we do logout, we clear that timer because if we logout automatically,
then it's no problem,
then the timer expired but if we logout manually because this button is pressed, we also call logout
and then we still have the timer in the background which calls logout again at a later point of
time.
Now we don't want to do that,
if a user logs out on his own, then the current session
so to say, the current lifetime of the token we have ends anyways and therefore we should also clear
that token expiration timer when we logout.
Now clearing that timer is not too hard,
we simply store it in a property which we can name token expiration timer but you can name this however
you want and that this will actually be of type any and now let's store our timer down there, set timeout
returns a reference to that timer, so we can simply store that in token expiration timer and in the logout
function, we now just have to clear that timer.
So in there, in logout, we should check if we do have an active timer because maybe we don't,
maybe it expired anyways then we can't clear it but if we do have an active one,
so if this is true-ish, then we should clear our timeout here and set this token expiration timer
or pass this token expiration timer into clear timeout and this will clear the token expiration
timer and thereafter reset token expiration timer back to null manually.
So now we cleared the timer when we logout and we also set it here,
now of course we just have to make sure we do call auto logout because currently we aren't doing that and
we need to call auto logout to make sure that this timer actually starts.
Now where do we need to call that?
Basically whenever we emit a new user to our application, so whenever we use our user subject
and that would be the case here in handle authentication and also in auto login.
Now let's start with handle authentication, there
we do emit our user. Now right after doing that or right before doing that,
doesn't matter,
we should call auto logout and pass our current expiration time into that auto logout function.
Now the current expiration time of course is our expires in value here which is in seconds
times 1000 because we expect milliseconds in auto logout, since expires in is in seconds
times 1000 gives us the amount in milliseconds. Now that's handle authentication, in auto login,
it's a tiny bit more complex. Here when we know that we do have a token and we therefore emit our user
to the application, there
we also want to call this auto logout
but here, we now have to calculate the remaining time.
We do have our token expiration date after all
and of course we can always find out what the current date is.
So our expiration duration is basically this timestamp here,
so the token expiration date wrapped into a date in milliseconds which we get by calling get time, minus
the current timestamp which we get with new date, in milliseconds with get time.
So future date, the token expiration in milliseconds minus current date in milliseconds gives us the
difference in milliseconds and that is the duration we have until the token expires
which we should pass to auto logout. Therefore now, this reloads and we're logged in, now if I call logout, we wipe
our data and application and we are logged out of course
and now let's try if our timer works correctly and to simulate this, I'll manually set this to two thousand,
only temporarily so that this expires after two seconds, so that we can really see if it works.
Let's now login and we see our user data snapshot here on the right and now it's gone and we're redirected
because now we logged out after two seconds. So auto logout seems to work,
let me now reverse this to the expiration duration which we of course want to have here,
we don't want to have to add extremely short horizon here,
instead let's log the expiration duration and see what we get there. If we do login again like this,
then we see this here is one hour in milliseconds
and if I reload, you see now it's a shorter value,
this comes from auto login and that is the remaining duration we have.
So this doesn't look too bad, this looks like it's working correctly,
still there are things we should improve,
for example we can still visit the recipes route when we are not logged in, I can just type it here and
here I am.
This is something we definitely want to prevent in our application.