In the last lecture, we added our own recipe, spaghetti and we recognize that the image preview is not
working. Well that makes sense because if we have a look at the recipe edit component, here where we try
to preview the image, we're not binding the source.
We should do this,
I'll add a local reference named imagePath to that input because I want to get access to the input
inside of this template
and then I'll bind the source here to that local reference, so to imagePath value because that is exactly
what I want to display here. With that, if we now create a new recipe and paste in our old link, now we
immediately get a preview of this image.
So now this is working as expected
and now if I add my spaghetti recipe,
very tasteful, with my new ingredient, spaghetti 100 and some tomatoes,
and if I hit save now, here it is.
Now we can see it,
now we can edit it,
multiple exclamation marks make it more meaningful.
We can send it to the shopping list to find our spaghetti on tomatoes there,
well we already have tomatoes here so we can delete these here I guess
and we lost it.
Where are our spaghettis?
If I go back to recipes, spaghettis are gone.
So that seems to be another bug we need to fix.