So how can we prevent that
users can visit /recipes if they are not authenticated?
Do you remember the routing section? There we had a look at route guards and that is exactly what we need
here. A route guard allows us to run logic right before a route is loaded and we can deny access if a
certain condition is not met
and this is exactly what we need here. For that in the auth folder,
let's create a new file and I'll name it auth.guard.ts
and that will be my, as the name suggests, authentication guard and in there,
let's export a class, auth guard which should implement the can activate interface.
Now this is imported, not from this path but from @angular/router
and since this technically is a service
and of course you could name it export class auth guard service therefore, since this is a service we
need @injectable here, injectable like this which is imported from @angular/core
and here you can use provided in root to provide this application-wide if you want
again you could also add it to providers in the app module. So that's the
auth guard, since we add the can activate interface here, we now have to add the can activate method. The can
activate method has to be implemented in a certain way, it receives the currently active route which is
of type activated route snapshot and you can by the way see this if you press command or control and
click on the interface, then you can see the definition here.
So we get two arguments, the activated route snapshot and the router state snapshot, so that's the second
thing here, router state snapshot,
both imported from @angular/router and can activate then has to return either a boolean or a promise
that eventually yields a boolean expressed here by using this generic promise notation or an observable
which eventually will yield a boolean and for that you also need to import observable from RxJS.
This is how can activate should look like and right now, we're getting an error because we are not returning
anything when we are expected to return a boolean, a promise or an observable.
Now what can we return here?
We want to return the status as we can derive it from our auth service.
So here, let's inject the auth service which is of type auth service and which you need to import from the
auth service file and then in there, we can find out whether the user is authenticated or not by looking
at that user behavior subject.
So here, we can access this auth service user
and now don't subscribe here but return it instead
because this already is an observable, it's a subject and therefore also an observable, however not an
observable that returns a boolean,
instead it is an observable that in the end returns a user object but this can be fixed easily,
we just add pipe and use the map operator which is imported from rxjs/operators to transform
the observable value here.
So we get our user and we want to return true or false, so we can simply return
!!user
which is that trick which converts a true-ish value, like an object,
so anything that is not null or undefined, to true,
so to a real boolean or that converts false-ish value like null or undefined to a true boolean, so
to false in this case.
So now we have an observable that really will return true or false and that should allow us to use that
activate guard in front of the routes that we want to protect.
So now with can activate added here, let's go to the app routing module and here of course, it's this
path here, the recipes path which I want to protect.
So in there, we can add the can activate key which is an array of all the can activate guards we want
to register for this route and here it's only one guard, it's the auth guard which
you also need to import of course. With that changed, let's save that and let's see if it works, that doesn't
look too bad, we are kind of stranded here and we should take care about that but at least, we can't access
/recipes, though is this really the right behavior?
Let's have a look at application. This is empty,
so let's try logging in now like this and we can visit recipe,
so here we are granted access, this is looking good
and now let's reload the recipes page and this also works.
So indeed, this works and it gives us the right data, the guard works correctly here.
What we should make sure though is that when we logout and we manually try to go to /recipes, that
we actually redirect the user to a page where he can do something, like the authenticate page and to
do that, we can go back to the guard, in there we are returning true or false
but now if we have a closer look at the can activate interface by command or control clicking on that, we
see we can actually return more than just observables or promises or booleans.
We can also return a URL tree or a promise or an observable that yields a URL tree.
This is a relatively new feature and it was added basically for this exact use case for authentication,
it was added so that you can redirect users when the URL they're trying to visit is blocked. So for
can activate, for this guard which you often use in connection with authentication, you have now a more
convenient way of redirecting users. In the past with older Angular versions, you had to manually redirect,
so for example here, you would have added a tap rxjs/operator which you need to import by
the way
and there you would get that isAuth information because map gives us true or false, is the user authenticated
or not
and then here you could check,
if not is auth, you know
OK
I don't want to grant access, then you would inject the router,
the router like this from @angular/router of course and with the router injected in here, you would
call this router navigate and go to /auth for example and this works. If I save that and the app reloads,
we see if I type recipes here, I automatically go to auth.
Nothing wrong with this but in some edge cases, this could lead to race conditions with multiple redirects
that kind of interfere with each other and therefore, instead of using this approach, you can now also
use a different one and not return true or false here but return true if you want to grant access but
not false otherwise
but this URL tree.
So here, I'll store the result of my conversion here in isAuth and if we have isAuth,
so if this is true-ish, then I will just return true,
otherwise I want to return a URL tree and now such a URL tree can be created with
the router which you still need to inject therefore but there, you can now call create URL tree
and there you can simply pass in your normal array of segments, of route segments you want to navigate
to,
so for example /auth. I'm getting an error here because the types I edit here don't include the URL
tree, we just need to update this to meet the specification of the interface and yes, a URL tree
is allowed there, you just need to import that type from @angular/router and then it is fine to return
an observable that either yields a boolean or a URL tree, the same for a promise and also instead
of a normal boolean. So returning a URL tree or promises or observable that yield URL trees
are OK, we're doing that here and therefore now if we save that, we get the same behavior as before. If
I visit /recipes, I'm forwarded to auth, if I just try to load localhost 4200,
we also go to auth because if we just try to load the page as it is there, first of all we get redirected
to recipes but there we then have the guard which then continuous redirecting us to auth.
So now we have an auth guard in place that should do its job and that makes sure that we really can only
reach the recipes page if we are logged in but there, we can reach it without issues even if we reload
the app because we're using auto login but also auto logout to clear everything once our token
expired.
Now with that, we're almost done with the guard but there is one thing I want to edit in this auth guard.
Right now, we're subscribing to our user service here, we're mapping that value into true or false and
we are returning a URL tree if it is false and if we want to redirect. The one issue we have here is that
we essentially set up an ongoing subscription here though. This user subject of course can emit
data more than once and I don't want that here,
this can lead to strange side effects if our guard keeps on listening to that subject,
instead we want to look inside the user value for one time only and then not care about it anymore unless
we run the guard again and therefore here just as in other places too, we should use take one to make
sure that we always just take the latest user value and then unsubscribe for this guard execution so that
we don't have an ongoing listener to that which we really don't need and therefore here, you need to
import the take operator, the take rxjs/operator and add it here in front of map so that we
don't have an ongoing user subscription.
With that if you save that, you see I can still visit recipes here after reloading, so the guard generally
still seems to work but now I have a logout and I try to access recipes, we fail as we should,
if I now login again, we succeed.
So the guard now still works as before but now, we avoid nasty bugs which could occur due to us rerunning
the logic in the guard when we really don't want to rerun it.