You can not only configure the observe mode here, you can also configure the response type. The default
here is JSON, which means the response data, so the data in the body of your response is JSON
and that tells Angular that it should automatically parse it and convert it to a Javascript object.
You could however also tell Angular the response side will be text and please keep it as text, don't try to
convert it to a Javascript object.
It could also be a blob if it is a file
for example, the official docs of course are the place where you can learn all about all available response
types.
So if you use text here and I add a new post here, send it first,
then you still see of course that I get null here because we had null before and even if this is interpreted
as text, it still prints null.
However we can clearly see it is treated as a text because it is now wrapped in quotation marks, before
it was treated as the null object that exists in Javascript.
It becomes even clearer if we try using that here when we get posts.
There if I switch the response type to text, we'll see that our application even breaks because it won't
work
if we tried to work with the text response and I even get an error here because I am using that generic
assignment here and I'm saying, "hey the data that is returned here is actually of type Javascript object
that in the end holds a nested post",
TypeScript is smart and detects, "well if you tell me that my response data will be of that format,
then it needs to be convertible to a Javascript object,
if you then also tell me that the response type down there is text, then you have to be lying somewhere"
because it can't be both,
it can't be a string which is simply not in that format and such a Javascript object at the same time.
So to make this work, we would have to get rid of that generic type assignment and now we are allowed
to save this
and now of course you see this breaks here if I try sending a post and I fetch my post, it breaks and I
just see these lines because my response here is in the end
now treated as a text and not as a Javascript object and actually here,
it even breaks because the way I try to handle this is not correct.
So I will revert this and I will revert this back to JSON, which is the correct data type and which
now works but it is important to also be aware of this option which you can use to tell Angular in case
you are really getting back some text and you don't want Angular to parse it to a Javascript object
or maybe you are getting back JSON but you still don't want to let Angular parse it because you want
to parse it on your own at a later point of time or anything like that,
for this you can set the response type. The default is JSON and most of the time, like in probably 99%
of all cases,
this is the type you want to keep.
So typically, you don't need to overwrite that.