So let's start adding effects and let's start by adding a login effect
and of course we'll thereafter also add sign-up and so on. For this,
since it's auth related, in the auth store folder, let's add a new file, auth.effects.ts and in
auth effects, we need to export a normal class,
you organize your effects in classes. The name should be auth effects, matching the file name and inside
of auth effects,
we now need to inject something first of all and that something is coming from the @ngrx/effects
package,
so from @ngrx/effects, we have to import something and that something is actions.
Now we imported action from @ngrx/store before, for creating our actions,
actions here is something different, it's a different kind of object.
It allows us to inject actions and the convention here is to write this with a dollar sign at the end
but this is totally up to you,
this entire name is up to you and actions is of type actions.
Now what is actions? Actions is one big observable that will give you access to all dispatched actions
so that you can react to them,
you just react differently than in the reducer because in the reducer,
you of course also get access to all dispatched actions as you learned, here in the effect class, in the
auth effects class,
the idea now is that you don't change any state but that you can execute any other code that should
happen when such an action is dispatched and that you then can simply dispatch a new action
once that code, which also may be asynchronous, is done.
So this is just a stream of dispatched actions
so to say and again using that dollar sign,
I haven't done it before in this application,
I got other observable injected where I don't add this, some like to add a dollar sign after every observable
so that it's clear that this is an observable. In a lot of the official docs, you will see that dollar
sign especially for the actions,
hence I leave it here but it is up to you if you add it or not,
it's not required.
So the actions are injected here, with that injected, we can register our first effect,
so our first action handler so to say. You add such an effect as a normal property in your auth effect
class and I will name this auth login, the name is totally up to you though, you can choose any name here,
it should kind of describe which kind of effect you're handling though. Now in here, in auth login,
I now assign a value and there, I use my actions. So I'm referring to the injected actions
property here, like this.
Now actions as I mentioned is just an observable and therefore we can call pipe or subscribe.
Now don't call subscribe here, @ngrx/effects will subscribe for you, just call pipe instead and what
you need to pipe here is now a special RxJS operator which is not part of RxJS but which
is provided by @ngrx/effects, it's the ofType operator. ofType simply allows you to define a filter
for which types of effects you want to continue in this observable pipe you're creating, in this observable
stream here because you can have multiple effects by adding multiple properties to your class here
and you can simply define different types of effects that you want to handle in each chain.
So here for example, we could handle the login effect or to be precise, the login action since we're basically
reacting to all dispatched actions here and this is a filter to allow us to define for which exact actions
we want to continue in this chain
and now I need more actions.
Thus far, we only had login and logout but now since we actually want to send the HTTP request
here from inside our auth effect,
we need a new identifier which could be login start and the value here could be auth login start.
Of course you could name this login success but I don't want to rename it everywhere where I used it,
hence I will keep that named login. Login start however is basically the point where we want to start
sending our request.
So here in auth effects, we now import everything as auth actions from these auth actions file and here
in auth type, we can then refer to auth actions login start here and what this says is only continue in
this observable chain if the action that we're reacting to here is of type login start, all other actions
will not trigger this effect here,
only login start will
and you could add multiple actions here by the way if you want to run the same code for different actions.