So I hope it became clear why we must not return error,
still the question of course is we're creating new observable here in catch error, in map, what should
be inside of these observables?
Well keep in mind that I said that you typically want to dispatch a new action once you're done with
the code in your effect,
so what should be in here is your new action.
You don't need to call dispatch because that's also partly done by add effect here, your entire chains
result here will automatically be treated as an action by @ngrx/effects and therefore will be dispatched.
So here you just need to return or add an action object and @ngrx/effects will automatically dispatch
it for you
and that means that here, we can of course create a new action.
Now we have no action for the error case,
so for now let's simply try to avoid this and not create any errors until we add proper error handling,
for now, I'll just return an empty observable. Here in map
however, we can return a real observable
and of course here, I want to return an observable that holds my login action,
so not the start, the login start action but the login action because now at this point of time, I
have a successfully logged in user and I want to reflect this in my application by reaching that login
reducer code
and for that, we need to dispatch that login action. Hence
here in AuthEffects, we're already importing auth actions,
so down here let's create a new auth actions login object.
Now there we need to feed in an object with the e-mail, password and so on. In auth service, this is all
data we forwarded here to handle authentication since we got it from resData and in handle authentication,
we then did some additional things like calculating the expiration date. In the end, I'll just copy that
calculation here, like this,
go to the AuthEffects and now do this here in map data. resData holds all the data I need,
for example in resData, I find the expiresIn key, TypeScript is just complaining here because map here
will by the way also execute after a catch error since we don't return an error anymore but a normal
observable, hence we should switch order here, then map will be skipped in case of an error and catch
error will kick in but when catch error executes, map will not run again
and now I also need to convert this to a number by adding a plus here to avoid errors.
So now we're calculating the expiration date and now here to login, we pass in the e-mail which we get
from resData,
there is an e-mail property we need to pass in into user ID which we also get from resData, there
it's that local ID key. We need to pass in the token which we also defined in resData,
it's the ID token property and expiration date is our expiration date
constant we just worked on.
So now I'm returning this new action here and this as I said automatically gets dispatched by
@ngrx/effects.
OK, so that was a lot of talking,
let's ignore the error case for now and signing up and so on,
let's now make sure that we take advantage of our effect here for logging in and for that, we have to wire
everything up now. To wire our effects up, first of all we have to go to AuthEffects here, to our class and
add @injectable here, like this. @injectable or the injectable decorator needs to be imported from
@angular/core and it is required here not to provide this in root, so don't add this, it will never
be injected itself so it doesn't need to be provided but it needs @injectable so that things can be
injected into this class and we are injecting actions and the HttpClient, otherwise we would get errors,
so @injectable is needed here so that things can be injected into AuthEffects. Now for registering
all the effects and this effects logic globally, we have to go back to the app module where we also
registered our store module and after registering our store module, we now register, well you probably
can guess it, an effects module which we get from @ngrx/effects. Now that effects module here
also has a forRoot method, like this and to forRoot, you now have to pass an array of your root
effects, that means of your effect classes and here, that is the AuthEffects class which you therefore also
need to import AuthEffects imported from the auth folder from the store folder and from the AuthEffects
file. So registering this class here as a class that holds effects, we're forwarding it or we're
passing it to effects module and @ngrx/effects does the rest and sets this all up. The missing piece
for us now is to dispatch a login action. Now we have our login start action I mean, we have it here
in auth actions and therefore all we have to do is we have to go to the place where we do call login
on the auth service and that is our auth component. Here in onSubmit, I have an observable for logging
in or for signing up and now here, when we do login, I don't want to use the same logic as before,
instead here I now want to use my store, so let's inject store of type store, as always store is imported
from @ngrx/store. It's a generic type and therefore, it needs information about how our
AppState looks like,
so let's import everything as from app from our
app reducer and here, then have fromApp.AppState.
And now when we do login here, let's comment out this old code and let's instead use this store and call
dispatch and now we just need access to our auth actions as well.
So time for another import, import everything as from, not as from but as auth actions from the store
folder in the auth folder and there from the auth actions file and with that imported, we dispatch a new
auth action which is logging start here. Now that needs two pieces of information, in an object it needs
the e-mail which we have as a constant here and it needs the password which we also have as a constant.
So let's forward e-mail and password here and with that, this gets dispatched.
Now one important side note, dispatch here does not give us an observable which is why I can't store
this in authObs. This also means we're not notified about
once this is done, this login process and hence resetting, loading and navigating away won't work for
that moment,
we'll have to check the network tab for whether this whole login process in theory works correctly
and thereafter we'll have to find out how we get information like, are we still loading, out of our store.
So for the moment, let's still test it like this though,
let's save everything and let's go back to our application, logout and let's try logging in. Now as I
said, this here simply fails and that is to be expected because we haven't updated all the code
but let's check the network tab here for requests that left our application and there indeed, we see
verify password, we did send a request to this path and that indeed is the login path and we've
got a 200 response back
and indeed in the preview we see we got success data here.
So the login request was sent and it also looks like it generally succeeded,
however the rest of this application is not really working,
it basically broke down,
we have an error and therefore it's now broken, our app is broken.
That of course simply is related to the fact that here, in our auth component, we are trying to subscribe
to authObs and that is simply not set in the login mode,
it's still undefined here because here I'm not setting it anymore because dispatch doesn't return an
observable to which I could set it.
Instead we'll have to find a different solution for being notified about whether we're currently waiting
for a response or whether we were successful or if we have an error.