Now that we're able to submit a form,
let's actually add some validation to it. In the template driven approach,
we would simply add required here for example to make this field required.
It doesn't work like this
in the reactive approach because keep in mind and that's key, you're not configuring the form in the
template, you're only synchronizing it with the directives, formControlName and formGroup but you're
not configuring it here, the TypeScript code, that's where you configure it.
That is why FormControl takes more than one argument,
this constructor here.
You cannot only set the default value,
the second argument allows you to specify some validators. So you can either only pass one validator
here, like for username where I only want to make sure that it is required and you do this by adding
the validators object,
make sure to import it from @angular/forms and there, you get a couple of built-in validators you
can use, for example required.
Now make sure to not call it, to not execute it, so don't have parentheses after it because you don't
want to execute this method,
it is a static method made available by validators here,
instead you only want to pass the reference to this method.
Angular will execute the method whenever it detects that the input of this FormControl changed,
so it just needs to have a reference on what it should execute at this point of time.
So this is the required validator
but as I said, this is only one option,
you can also add multiple validators by simply passing an array of validators.
So here to e-mail, I'm going to pass an array of validators because I want to have the required validator,
just like on the username but I'll add another validator too here, I'll add the e-mail validator and this
again also doesn't need to get executed,
we just need the reference.
So here, I now also pass my validator and now we do have validation in place.
If we now go back to our form and we inspect and let it reload and we inspect the e-mail field here for example,
it's invalid,
if I enter something here, it's still invalid,
if I enter an e-mail address though, it becomes valid and the same of course for username, it's invalid
right now,
as soon as I enter something it becomes valid because it's now not empty anymore.
So this is how you can add validation to this approach.