The solution to the problem we're facing here is that we need to manage more of our authentication related
state and also the state that only matters to this component here in our @ngrx/store, to be precise,
we should at least manage whether we succeeded or failed.
Well we are managing the success case, here with the login action which leads to the reducer creating
a user object,
we should also add a login fail
action.
Let's expert a new constant, LOGIN_FAIL, the value can be auth login fail here and let's create a new
class for that as well,
export class login fail implements
action
and here, the
readonly type will be equal to login fail.
We might also want to have an error message, so let's also add a constructor with a payload and the payload
here is just a string, it could just be our error message.
Of course you could always use an object with more data here if you wanted to, whatever you want.
With the login fail action added here, we also have to work on our reducer and what we managed in the
state here, a potential login error should be managed here
since we also have that login error action. Hence I will add a new property to my state here, auth
error, which should just be a string here,
just a message
and here in the initial state, auth error therefore could just be an empty string
but I will go with null,
so initially we have no error. Now in the reducer,
when we did login successfully, I also want to set auth error back to null in case it was something
different and I want to do the same
when we start logging in. So it's time for a new case where we access our auth actions and use login start
because whenever we start a new login process, I essentially want to copy my old state and I want to
set auth error back to null because we have a new chance of logging in,
of course we don't want to start with an error right away.
Now to avoid this error which I'm getting here, I have to go back to the auth actions and add all these
new actions to the union type down there so that they can be handled in the reducer without errors,
so here we have login start and we have login fail. With that added here, in the auth reducer we get no error
anymore,
we added login start, now of course
we also need to handle the fail case now,
so the login fail
case here.
In that case, we also should return a new state based on the old state, where we probably want to set
the user to null because logging in failed,
so I see no scenario where we have a user and then set auth error equal to action
payload like this because payload already is a string,
it already is the message I want to use.
So now we're handling that in the
reducer, this login fail case and the login start
case, we have an auth error property in our state
therefore, hence
now we can simply subscribe to that in the auth component to be informed about potential errors
we're getting. For this, instead of subscribing to our auth observable here, I'll comment this out,
therefore signing up will for the moment not work but instead of doing that, I will select my auth part of
the store and subscribe to that
and of course here, we get our auth state object and we could use a map operator before that to extract
the data we want. In that auth state object here, we get the current user and we also get our error
if we have any. Now I will actually now revert a bit and actually manage the loading state here in the
reducer or in the NgRx state as well, so loading is a boolean here and initially, loading is false
and I'm managing it here now because this simply makes it easier and less error prone to update the
UI correctly
and now the idea simply is that
once we're done logging in, I'll set loading to false,
so when we are done, I will also set loading to false
if we are done with an error because even then, we're done,
we have an error but we're not loading anymore
and just when we started, I'll set loading to true.
So now loading is also managed in the NgRx state and that makes it now easier here in the auth component
to update the user interface correctly because then we should not subscribe to our store here
after we submitted the form but instead in ngOnInit. So let's implement onInit which needs to be
imported from @angular/core, so therefore we now have to add the ngOnInit
method here and in there,
I set up my subscription to the store and now we can set up this isLoading and set it equal to auth
state loading because in the auth state, we'll always have the latest loading state and an error can also
be set based on the auth state,
so here we have our auth error and I stored it in my error which I then use in the user interface.
Please note that for example is login mode would also be a state that affects the user interface,
that is not managed inside of NgRx because it doesn't affect any other part of the application,
logging in of course does but whether we're in the login or sign-up mode and which form to display,
that really only matters to this component,
so there is no sense in putting that into the @ngrx/store,
you could do it but you don't gain much by it.
Managing this entire auth flow in NgRx however is a different thing because that does impact the entire
application in the end
and therefore here,
now we're updating the UI based on the current state we have in our @ngrx/store,
we are dispatching our login start here.
The missing piece is that we redirect once we are logged in, so once we do have a user and where would
we now do that?
We could of course try redirecting whenever we have a user, so we check if auth state user, if that is
true-ish and then we use this router navigate and we navigate away but we could also end up in weird
scenarios where we kind of visit the page with a user, even though that shouldn't really be possible
and we have a strange redirection and you could and that's more important
also see navigation as a side effect.
Of course it impacts your application but it doesn't impact your state, the state of the application
and what the user sees,
yes but your data, your data state so to say, that's not really impacted.
So let's redirect with the help of @ngrx/effects as well.