So that's it for the HTTP module,
quite a long module where you learned a lot about the Angular HttpClient.
Now the most common task you will do is of course that you send requests by using post, get
and so on by adding a URL, possibly a request body and maybe some request headers.
This will be your bread and butter thing and therefore this is the task you should practice and you
should feel confident about. Always remember that these methods, like get and post give you back an
observable to which you have to subscribe to actually kick of the request and to send it. Since it
is an observable, you can use operators, rxjs/operators to transform the data, log data, catch
errors or whatever you want to do but ultimately, you need to subscribe and you can do this in a service
or in a component depending on where you need to work with the response and in the subscribe method,
you pass in a function to handle the data you get back and possibly also an error handling function,
like this one.
This is how you generally work with HTTP requests.
Now you've got advanced features, like the possibility of setting what you want to observe if you are
interested in the response or just the body of the response or all the events, which type of data should
be returned,
you can set query params and you have that very useful features, auth interceptors which can really help
you save time and code if you have some header that needs to be appended to every outgoing request for
example
and as I already mentioned, we'll see interceptors in action again later in the course
once we add authentication. For now, this is it,
let's now move on to the course project and practice using these HTTP requests there.