In the last lecture, we learned how to pass static data,
now let's say we have some dynamic data we have to fetch before a route can be displayed or can be rendered.
For example here on the servers, let's say the servers
already have been loaded but once we click a server here and maybe I should login to demonstrate this,
I want to load the individual server from some back-end,
so we are going to simulate that this takes a couple of milliseconds or seconds.
So how could this work? If we have such a use case, we need a resolver,
this also is a service, just like canActivate or canDeactivate which will allow us to run some code
before a route is rendered.
Now the difference to canActivate is that the resolver will not decide whether this route should be
rendered or not, whether the component should be loaded or not,
the resolver
will always render the component in the end but it will do some pre-loading, you could say, it will
fetch some data the component will then need later on.
Of course the alternative is to render the component or the target page instantly and in the onInit
method of this page, you could then fetch the data and display some spinner whilst you are doing so.
So that is an alternative but if you want to load it before actually displaying the route, this is how
you would add such a resolver.
So let's say for the single server here, I will add it in the server file, my server-resolver
and again this will be technically just be a service, so I'll export my class here which I'll name
ServerResolver
and now this has to implement the resolve interface provided by @angular/router. Resolve is a generic
type and it should wrap whichever item or data field you will get here, will fetch here in the end.
So we will fetch a server here and therefore we should define the type here,
now you could outsource thist into an interface or a model in general,
so we will know that a server will have an ID which is of type number, that it will have a name which
is a string and a status which is a string.
So this is simply a type definition of the thing this resolver will give us in the end, to what it will
resolve in the end.
Now the resolve interface requires us to implement the resolve method and this resolve method here now
takes two arguments, the route,
so the activated route snapshot which you already know, which you need to import from @angular/core
and it will also provide us the state snapshot,
so the router state snapshot which also needs to be imported from @angular/router.
These are the two information pieces the resolve method gets by Angular and in the end,
this then also has to return either an observable which you need to import from rxjs/observable.
This observable will then also return this type here, so we can copy this but since we're creating a
lot of overhead here, we can also quickly define an interface here
and it would of course be better to outsource this in its own file
but let's quickly do it here.
So the interface for the server which has an ID of type number and then the name which is a string and
the status which is a string
and now this allows us to simply use server here as a shortcut for this type.
So the observable should in the end give us back such a server
or we get a promise which in the end will return such a server or well, just such a server
synchronously.
So this is what we will get back here in resolve,
so now we need to implement the logic to get this back.
Now we have our servers service here and there, we have the getServer method which will give us back
a server.
Now this clearly is some synchronous code,
it will run instantly here,
so there is nothing wrong with this code,
we will resolve this instantly
and as you saw in your resolver, that's fine,
one return possibility is to instantly return the data.
So the easiest thing we can do here is reach out to our serversService and for this, we need to inject
it,
so we should provide our serversService like this,
that's a real hard word for me,
ServersService, like this
and of course if you want to inject a service into another service, you have to add @injectable to it,
make sure to import this from @angular/core,
also make sure to import your own servers service and with this, the easiest way to use this resolve
function is to reach out to your service and there, we call getServer
and now we need to know the ID of the server
we have to fetch because that is what we do in the server component here in the end, right? There in
onInit
we're getting this server right now.
So now we want to outsource this because let's say we want to do it before it loads,
the good thing is we do get the route here, it only is snapshot but this service here will actually run
each time we rerender the route,
so the snapshot is all we need.
Unlike the component itself, again this is executed each time, so no need to set up an observable or something
like that.
So here, we can access our route and there the params and then the ID and make sure to cast it with a plus
sign in front of it to an integer. This is the easiest way of using this resolver which will do the
loading of our data in advance and now this would also work if this were to return an observable or
a promise,
so with asynchronous code, for example an HTTP request.
So this is our resolver, with this resolver in place,
we of course now have to add it.
So first thing is in app module, we should add it to our providers, our ServerResolver, like this,
make sure to also add the import at the top and with that added
now, we want to add it to our routing module. Here for the route where we want to use it,
so let's say for this component here, we add another property, the resolve property.
This takes a Javascript object and here, we map all the resolvers.
This is different to the other guards, there we use arrays
but for resolve, a different approach is taken and you will see why in a second.
So here, we have key-value pairs of the resolvers
we want to use,
so for the server and this name of the property is totally up to you,
we will use our ServerResolver,
like this,
make sure to import it here at the top.
This will now map the data
this resolver gives us back and remember, it gives us back some data with this resolve method.
it had to implement, this method will be called by Angular when this router is loaded. So the data it gives us
back here will be stored in this server object
we will then have available or in the server property we will have available in this to be loaded
component. So in this to be loaded component, in our server component,
right now we get the server like this, using the params.
Well I will comment this out because now we use a resolver for this,
that's the goal of the resolver
and it makes even more sense if this is some asynchronous task of course,
so here we can easily get our server by binding the data observable.
So just like static data which you passed with this data object here, with this data property you could
add to a route, the data returned by your resolver will also go into this data baggage in this data
object you have in your to be loaded component.
So here, we can listen to any changes and I'm setting up an observable here or I'm using the observable
here I should say because the server can change while we already are on the page, as we have this side
menu,
this is why we also had to set up our route params here dynamically
and here, we know we will get back our data of type data as learned before,
make sure to import data from Angular router and now, we know that we can simply assign our server, this
server property in this component by binding to data server and now this name here is important,
this server here, this name here of course has to match the name you use here
when you assign your resolver to some property,
so if you change the name here, you have to change it when you retrieve the data.
Well with this in place, if we save this with ng serve still running, if we login and go to
servers and we click on a server, you see this still works as intended,
it still loads the server, like before but now not using the params here in the server component but
instead using a resolver before this, again of course especially important when using asynchronous data.