As mentioned at the end of the last lecture, I want to start by building our first service here, a service
which takes over this logging task here,
so a service where we can log data.
Now how do we create a new service, how does this service look like in Angular? Creating it is super simple.
First we have to choose a fitting place
now since this service will do some generic task, I will place it in the app folder,
you could also create a shared subfolder there,
I will again place it right in the app main folder and I will simply name it logging and the file name
should be logging.service.ts to follow this convention of being pretty clear about what's
in a file.
So here, this file will hold a service so that's why I'll name it like this.
There, I will export a TypeScript class and I will name this class LoggingService to again to be explicit
about what this class does.
Now a component becomes a component because we attached this @component decorator,
a directive becomes a directive because we attach @directive,
you could think that we now simply add @service right
but we don't do that. A service is just the normal TypeScript class, like this,
this can already be used as a service.
So here, we could create a helper method, logToConsole and simply pass the message
but since we know that we simply want to log the change of account status here, I will simply say log
status change like this and take the new status which will be a string as an argument.
Here, I can then simply copy the code
I do have in one of my components right now, this console log code here and copy it into my logging
service here, of course account status now is just status here,
this argument we're getting.
So with that, remove the semi-colon,
with that I centralized this code,
now we need to use the service in our other components,
so everywhere where we console log.
Now you could think that we simply use it by importing it at the top of our file,
so here we could import the loggingService from
and now let's move up to the main folder
and then here from the logging.service.ts file and then we could simply create our service like this,
new logging service and on our service here, we could call log status change and pass the new account status.
And actually, if I get rid of this code here,
this will work, let it recompile
and if I now create a new service here, you see I do log it to the console.
So this would work and still, this is wrong, this is not and this is super important, this is not how you
use a service in Angular.
The reason for this will become more clear throughout this module
but generally, Angular provides a much better way of getting access to your services and therefore, you
should not create the instances manually.
So let's get rid of that import and of that instantiation and let's learn in the next video which tool
Angular offers us to get access to our services.