So here's the application we built, this project we worked on, the folder structure you already know and
let's assume that our code is already optimized and that we tested this thoroughly and therefore, the
only thing that's missing is that we deploy this application.
Now before we do that, let me dive into that environment variable thing which you saw on the slides and
that is a feature that's actually built into every project you build with the Angular CLI. In the source
folder, you have your app folder, there
you also have an environments folder. In that environments folder, you have two files,
environment.ts and environment.prod.ts
.
Now we're not using these files but what you could do here, you see you have an exported constant
in the
environment.ts
and in the environment.prod.ts file, it's the same constant with the same name,
you can add key-value pairs to that constant.
For example if you were using an API that requires some API key and actually, we are using something
like this and hence I will show you how to use this environment variable in a second, if you are using
something like this, then you can store that API key here, you can import that environment constant here
into your files to use that API key and what the CLI, the Angular CLI does for you is that it
will automatically swap these two files when you are building for production.
So during development, this environment.ts file and the value you have in here will be used and during
production, this constant will be used instead
and this is swapped automatically,
you don't need to write any special code for this behavior to occur.
Now why is this useful?
Well you might have certain values that differ from development to production.
You might have some API keys that are meant to use during development and then you have different keys,
which maybe are more restrictive, for production or any other value.
You can store anything in here, any value which you need in your other files and you have the option
of using different values for production and development. Now as I mentioned, we are using such an API
key, we are using that in our auth service. In the auth service, we're sending requests to the Firebase
back-end APIs here, to sign a new user up or to log a user in and there, I'm referring to that key thing
here,
right,
we're using that Firebase API key here. Check the authentication section where I add this in case you
haven't seen this code before.
This key is the same here for signing users up and for signing users in and therefore, we could of course
manage it in a constant inside of this file
but especially if we were using that in other files as well, it's definitely worth moving that into this
environment file in the environments folder.
So here, I'll name this Firebase API key,
the name is totally up to you
and the value is then just that key-value here. Now with that stored in the environment.ts file, we
should also copy that into these environment.prod.ts file because this is the file that will be
used when you build for production
and now with these keys added here, you can go back to the auth service and there, you now need to import
these environment values.
So here, you can import environment, which is the name of that exported constant, from
and now you simply point at the environments folder and there the environment file, not environment prod
but just environment
and again this will be swapped automatically for you by the Angular CLI when you build for production.
Now you can use that environment constant here and in the places where we are using that key, here for
example, you get rid of that key and instead, you add environment.firebaseAPIKey to that string
and therefore, use that as a key-value.
The same of course here for signing users in, remove it here and add this environment.firebaseAPIKey
thing.
Now that's a tiny thing but the advantage here really is that you can swap values from development to
production, here
we're not doing that but of course that would be an option and it's a powerful tool that can really
help you with development.