So in the last lectures, we learned a lot about the creation and configuration and usage of our own forms.
Now let's use another cool feature we can easily implement when using the reactive approach, adding our
own validators.
Thus far, we always used the built-in ones and to be honest, with all the built-in ones,
you should be able to cover most of your use cases
but let's say we have some usernames we don't want to allow the user to use.
In this case, I will go to my TypeScript file and here I'll add a new property, forbiddenUsernames
for example and in this array,
I'll add Chris and Anna as forbiddenUsernames if written like this.
So now I want to create my own validator which checks whether the username the user entered is one of the
two usernames it specified here,
now a new validator can be added pretty easily.
A validator in the end is just a function which gets executed by Angular automatically when it checks the
validity of the FormControl and it checks that validity
whenever you change that control.
So a validator is just a function,
let's name it forbiddenNames.
Now a validator to work correctly needs to receive an argument which is the control it should check,
so this will be of type FormControl, a validator also needs to return something for Angular to be
able to handle the return value correctly.
This something should be a Javascript object
and now the following notation might look strange,
it should have any key which can be interpreted as a string and this is just TypeScript syntax for saying hey
we want to have a key-value pair where the key again can be interpreted as a string which is true for
a key in an object in general.
More importantly, the value of that key-value pair,
that should be a boolean.
So this function here should return something like let's say an object where we have name is forbidden,
this would be the key name which is interpreted as a string and it could be true.
So this is what this function should return in the end
for example, the message itself, the key name is up to us and therefore we can now add the logic in this
function. In our case here, I want to check if the value of the control is part of this
forbiddenUsernames array.
So I want to check if this forbiddenUsernames indexOf,
so if it contains a certain element and the element is the value of our control we pass here, the control
we're checking. If this is the case, I want to return an object
where I say name is forbidden,
any short error code you want, is true.
Now in the other case,
I want to return null
and now this is important,
if validation is successful, you have to pass nothing or null,
you should not pass this object with false.
This might sound counter-intuitive but that's just how it works,
it should be null
or you simply omit the return statement.
This is how you tell Angular that the FormControl is valid.
Well then this is all, we created our own form validator, our own validator here.
Important, it receives the control and it returns this object with an error code and then true
for example if it is invalid.
So now to add this, I'll go to my username and actually we now want to assign an array of validators,
so I'll change this appropriately and I will now add a reference to my forbiddenNames function again.
Don't execute it,
only pass a reference
and now if we save this, we get an error.
Now this can be a tough one to spot, what's going wrong here?
This error has something to do with the way Javascript handles this. In forbiddenNames,
I'm accessing this here.
Now this might look all right because I'm in this class and I access this forbiddenUsernames
but think about who is calling these forbiddenNames.
We're not calling it from inside this class, Angular will call it when it checks the validity,
at this point of time, this will not refer to our class here.
So to fix this, I actually need to bind this, the good old Javascript trick to make sure that this refers
to what we want it to refer to.
So with this in place, if we now let this recompile,
the error is gone.
Let's now check the validity of this input
here, it is invalid
but if I enter test here, it stays invalid.
The reason for this is that right now I'm checking
if control value is part of this array, this will return -1
if it is not part, well -1 is interpreted as true though.
So we need to check if this is not equal to -1.
So if this is not equal to -1, that means we did find it,
that means it is invalid.
So now with this in place, if we go back, inspect this again and type test here, you see it becomes valid,
if I type Anna here, it becomes invalid,
so our own validation here is working fine. Now
in the next lecture, I will have a look at this strange error code and how we can use that.