We're almost done with the NgRx effects for authentication, which is quite complex because it involves
many different things
and the missing piece now is the invalidation of the token.
We're doing this with auto logout, which in the end just takes an expiration duration and where we then
set a timer to basically call logout once it's done.
Now you could come up with setups where you do this all inside of @ngrx/effects but I'm not actually
biggest fan of this because in the end, my goal here is just to dispatch the logout effect once a
timer expired.
So once we could certainly come up with some observable magic to yield that effect, I think it's easiest
if we simply clean up our auth service quite a bit, remove auto login, remove logout, remove these injections
which we don't need anymore, leave the store injection, leave the token expiration timer, remove that, remove
all these unused imports here,
so all that stuff which we won't need anymore,
remove handle authentication and remove handle error so that in there, it's really just a service that
is about managing that logout timer. I have auto logout and I will rename it to set logout timer because
that is what I ultimately want to do here and in here, I want to simply call dispatch and dispatch a
new auth action, the logout action because that is handled through NgRx and @ngrx/effects and
I want to add a second method, clear logout timer and there, all I do is I check if this token expiration
timer is set and if it is set, then I will call clear timeout for this token expiration timer and then
set this token expiration timer equal to null.
Now that's a way leaner service here and how can we use that service? We can use it from inside auth effects.
There, I can now inject my auth service,
just as you're used to it, of course make sure to add an import to auth service therefore,
here it is and now in all the places where you want to set a timer, you do it. That would be in handle
authentication but that is a function, not part of our class hence we can't access the injected object
here, we could turn it into a class method but if we can also simply go to our map method here for example,
where we handle authentication, add a tab,
operator first which is imported from rxjs/operator, where I also get my response data but
which does not change it and then call this auth service in here and set the logout timer equal to
response data
expires in, add a plus here though and we need it in milliseconds in the auth service.
If you have a look, we set the expiration duration here, set timeout takes the amount in milliseconds
though, this however will be in seconds so we need to multiply this with 1000 and I do just the same, add
the exact same step here for signing up,
so before we map let's also set the logout timer here. Let's also set it when we logged in automatically,
so here where we know that we have a user and we do authenticate the user, we use the auth service and
call set logout timer
and simply forward our expiration duration which we're calculating down there,
so let's reactivate
that code here, like this,
forward the expiration duration here to set that timer.
And last but not least, when logging out here,
of course now I will call this auth service
clear logout
timer like that.
That should do the trick and to see if it really does the trick,
let's go to the login
effect, this one here
and let's not multiply this with 1000 so that it should expire after 3.6 seconds effectively
and let's try logging in and let's see if we are logged out thereafter.
So this works and now let's wait for the 3.6 seconds and it's a bit hard to see because we stayed
on the same page here but we were actually logged out,
just a redirection, didn't really work. The reason for that behavior is that we do have our redirection logic
here
but actually we have kind of a race condition between our logout in the reducer, where we do clean up
our data which is important for the auth guard which decides which page we ultimately see and our effect.
Now the easiest solution to avoid this problem is to simply remove the logout action here from the
filter for this general redirection and instead, go to our separate logout action
and then here, add a new redirection where we specifically target /auth. And now with that, if we wait
for this to reload and we login again, now this should redirect us after 3.6 seconds, logout
was already working. So this now works and with that, let's revert this little hack here and let's
multiply expires in with 1000 again to have the correct logout timer.
And with that finally, our effects setup for authentication is done
and now we have a really lean auth service which only manages our timer in the end and all the rest is
managed by NgRx.