For debt I created a brand new project with the Selye again at the end of this module you'll find a
lecture where they also link to the official docs actually which we have a great article on testing
and not only does this article dive really deep into it and explore some use cases for a lot of use
cases.
I don't cover here.
It also will give you a set of instructions how to set up the well testing and wireman for example with
System chair as well.
Back to the Selye case though we do have this app component and by default we do have the app component
spec file which is not empty which has this code instead.
This is a unit test for actually it are a couple of tests each block beginning with it.
Here is a test and the before each at the beginning.
Well as you might guess execute some code which should be run before running each test.
Now we're seeing a lot of code here which we haven't seen before.
We're using a couple of Angua to specific test utilities here to make our tests work.
But before diving into them let's understand how should a test theoretically work.
If we think about it logically we do have are and what you application with the Marchal and the up component
.
And that runs in the browser.
Somehow we need to run the same in the testing environment and the testing environment in the end is
just just a script running over it.
So that order to simulate the same behavior we also need to bootstrap our application we need to set
up the app module and then we need to execute certain tasks the user might do or see and that is what's
happening here and then I think it's a great start to simply analyze this file to understand how Anglo
to unit tests work.
So at the top we import two things from at angular core testing that's the testing packaging let's you
shifts with which has a couple of utility tools for example test bed and async.
I'll explain both of them in a second.
Then we describe our to be tested unit in this case which is our app here we want to test the Abdy up
component at Marchal of course.
We then have a closure does function executed here.
This is part of the described function here and that will all be executed by the task runner we're using
and we'll use the Selye with a command I'll show you in a second to run these tests.
But you could set up any testing and Larpent typical test rather is karma simply a package you install
.
It is installed here which runs our tests.
The script was referring to.
Well then we first execute before each so we do something before each of these blocks here is executed
because important.
Even though these blocks here follow well after each other each block is executed totally independent
of the block before it.
So this block is not influenced by the code in this block and this block doesn't care about the first
two blocks.
Therefore before each is the only thing which will be executed before each individual block.
And here we configure a testing module estus method on the test bed and test bed is basically the main
angle or two tasks and utility object.
So this allows us to configure the modules for our testing and what we do here is simply declare which
components we want to have in this testing environment which is our rap component.
So this clearly looks like the app marshal with the declarations but it doesn't have the imports provide
us or the bootstrap.
And that makes sense because you know we want to focus on part of the application.
We're not really running it in the browser.
We only want to focus on the app component and the rest will be simulated by our testing environment
.
So this is declared and initialized therefore And then we got a couple of tests.
The first one checks of Diablo's properly created we always need to create a component in each block
since each block is contained in itself.
We do this by using create component on the test bed and then we store this new component in this fixture
variable.
That's just a name you'll commonly see fixture.
For this created component this testing unit we were looking at Woller trading component and of course
we passed as an argument which component we want to create the up component here of course.
Well then we can get our app by using this fixture which holds our created component the debug element
.
That's just a property we can access to get access or to a couple of well elements we can now have a
look at for example the instance of the component which was created which is our application in the
end.
And then we always end our block here by using the expect method.
No that's not coming from English to as is before each and it by the way.
These are all testing packaged so karma related or Jesmond to be precise which is the testing package
testing package related methods.
So expect basically says we expect whatever we pass years or app.
We expect our app to be Driffield which means yet to kind of exist and this is how we can read it.
We have it then.
This string is purely up to your choice so it should create the APIs basically human readable and then
we tell what do we expect when we should create the app while we expect the app to be Truefit to be
somehow existent in the next block.
We check if we say it should have a title which says app works because as the set up right we got the
app works property which we output here with stringin tribulation.
So it should have this title and we check it here again Ettridge component.
We get access to the instance and then we say well we expect this app to have a title property.
So this property here which equals app works.
This string of course is only true as long as we don't change or remove this title.
So that is how you write your test.
You have to reflect your actual application.
Well finally deferred or already existing tax year is instead it should render and age one tech.
We created again.
Now we call detect changes to trigger change detection.
That's the only way to do it.
It won't run automatically since it doesn't run in the browser.
So we detect or we trigger change direction manually so that the template gets rendered gear the native
element which gives us access to our template.
And then we basically say well Andaz compiled template we expect D.H. one element we get in with a normal
javascript query select or since this is a normal javascript object decompiled variable here we expect
to change one element to have a text content which contains app works.
These are the three already existing apps and this is the logic how this file gets executed how it uses
the what to testing utilities with test bed and a sink.
I will come back to this second and the default testing environment method slide it and expect to well
basically describe what we would like to see and how it should work.
Now this is the theory in the next videos.
I want to dive deeper into this show some examples for testing a pipe testing a number a component which
also has a service and check that into it.
And what is a sync thing here actually does as well as what our utilities Jagland to testing package
offers us