So I promised you a custom observable, to understand its internals and what I gave you was interval.
Now it's closer to a custom observable because it's not coming from some Angular feature but still, this
of course is kind of a utility function that gives us a predefined observable that fires a number every
second.
Well actually, we can rebuild this manually.
Let's comment out this code and let's build a real custom observable now.
I'll store that in a constant and I'll name it custom observable or custom interval observable,
you can of course pick any name you want and to create a new observable,
we can simply import observable, the type itself from RxJS.
Now you can use observable and call a create method on that and this will do what it sounds like,
it creates a new observable.
Now create actually takes a function and I'll pass in an anonymous arrow function here, like this which
will get an argument automatically, RxJS will pass in that argument for us
and that argument is a so-called observer.
Now what's an observer?
Now you heard about the observer in the first video of this module. The observer in the end is a part
that is interested in being informed about new data, about errors or about the observable being completed.
Now our job here is to tell the observer about new data, about an error or about the observable being
completed. Here,
we're not responsible for listening because the observer is the listener, here
we get that listening part as an argument and we need to tell it
once we're done, once new data is there and so on.
So in this anonymous function, we can now use the regular set interval method and set an interval of
one second let's say as before.
Now this again receives an anonymous function,
it's the normal set interval method, nothing special about that and inside of set interval here, we can now
call console log or do whatever we want
or simply use our observer
and there, we now got methods like next. We can call next here to emit a new value
and that is important.
The observer has a couple of important methods,
next is one of them,
error is another of them, so that would be the one you use to throw an error and complete is one
to let the observer know that you're done. Here however, we use next and to also have an incrementing
number here,
we can simply introduce a variable, count which starts at 0, inside of our set interval,
we then simply pass this on to next and we then increment count by 1.
So now here count starts at zero, we increment it by 1 whenever set interval fires and we let our observer
know about that new data here.
Now we can also subscribe to our custom observable and I'll do this in the same place here,
in ngOnInit,
of course you could do this in other places too
if this were stored in a service or in a property of that component simply. So here I can call subscribe
and to subscribe,
you pass the same thing as before, a function that simply accepts that data we're emitting.
So in this case, we could name it count again or to avoid naming confusion, simply name it data, whatever
you want
and here I will now console log that data, just as before.
Now let's save that all and let's wait for this page to reload
and again you see the same result as before
but now we built our own interval observable and this is roughly what's happening under the hood here
for the built-in interval observable too.
It's giving us an observable, which will essentially fire for every x milliseconds we defined and it
lets our observer know about that new data and that's what's happening here too
and if I navigate away, then we got a problem here because I tried to call unsubscribe of undefined
because I don't store my subscription of course that should be done here,
so in my firstObsSubscription, I'll now store that subscription again, simply by storing the result of
subscribe and its subscription again.
So now with that, if that reloads and I navigate away,
that works without issues again,
if I go back, a new observable starts.
So this is working and this is a real custom observable and this shows us how to emit new data
but what about errors and completing the observable?
I mentioned this as well.