Now let's dive into using Angular's HTTP features
and for that, we need a back-end.
Now as I mentioned before, we'll not write our own server-side solution here because you would do that
with a server-side language and not with Angular and therefore this is of course not the scope of this course.
By the way if you want to see how to build a complete Angular front-end and a custom back-end,
My Mean Course which you also find here on Udemy or on my page, academind.com, is a great place to go
but here, we'll simply use Firebase. Firebase
sounds like it's a database only,
instead it's a whole back-end solution which gives us a REST API as well
and it's a perfect solution for this course in this module because it's free to get started with and
we can send requests there, we can send different types of request, we can easily see the changes we make
through these requests and we can store data there and therefore, it's perfect.
Now you need a Google account for that,
once you got that you can go to the console on firebase.com and there, simply click on add project.
Now give that project any name you want
and you can leave the other default settings and then check both checkmarks here.
Now this will create a new Firebase project for you
and again, getting started here is free,
you can of course check the pricing pages of Firebase to learn what else you can use for free
and when it would start cost money.
Now once it's loaded, you'll see an interface that looks something like this and here, we'll go to database.
Now again, Firebase is not just a database, it's a complete back-end solution that also offers the database
but it's not just a database,
it's not an alternative to MongoDB or anything like that,
it's more than a database,
it's a complete back-end service.
Now here, we'll not use Cloud Firestore but instead if you scroll down, we'll use that real-time database,
it's a bit easier to use and gives us a nicer visual feedback.
So click on create database here
and important, start in test mode,
that's important.
Later, we will add authentication
but for now we'll use that test mode to be able to send requests and work with data without being restricted.
Normally, you are of course protecting against unwanted access,
here we are temporarily disabling this so that we can interact with that without issues. Now
and that is our basic setup we'll need, the
URL you see here will already be the URL
you can send requests to.
So let's do that and let's make sure that we now use that to store data by sending a post request.