So we can store data,
how about fetching?
Because obviously, we can delete recipes right,
we can get rid of all of them
and in that case, we got a problem here and we want to be able to fetch data in that case, so that we
can load all the recipes we have on the server. For loading data, we can again use the data storage service,
which makes sense because if we started using that for interacting with the back-end, we should definitely
stick to it and there, we can now simply add a fetch recipes method which should be triggered when we
click that other button in the header component,
so this button, the fetch data button here. Let's already add that click listener and call this
onFetchData or whatever you want to call this method which gets called and that method needs to be added to
the component body of course
and in there, the goal now is to use the data storage service and call fetch recipes.
Now of course, right now in fetch recipes, so we're not doing much,
so let's change this by again using the Angular HttpClient
and there we can now send a get request.
Now obviously, the URL to which you want to send that request is that same URL we are using
up there,
so let's add that URL here and let's send a request there to get our recipes.
Now just as before, the question is, where do we want to subscribe?
And the answer is, where are we interested in the response?
Are we interested in the header component?
Well not really in my opinion. What would we do with the recipes here,
we're not using the recipes in the header? So I'm not really caring about the recipes here and hence
there is no strong reason to subscribe here.
Instead, it would be fine to just subscribe in the data storage service where we already inject the
recipes service because maybe we can do something with the recipes service then to push or to move our
fetched recipes into that recipes service which in the end is the place where we do manage our recipes.
So let's subscribe here and we should be getting back our recipes here, though let's first of all console
log this to get an idea of the format of data we get. So we got everything in place, let's save that, go
back to our application and this reloaded in the meantime which is why the recipes are back here and
let's click fetch data and that's looking good. We're getting an array, note the square brackets, we're getting
an array of recipes.
So since these recipes already have the right format, we should be able to just set our currently loaded
recipes equal to these ones to overwrite them with the fetched recipes and for that, in the recipe service,
we now just need a method that allows us to overwrite the existing array of recipes because we have that
starting array of recipes and we have a function to get the recipes which means return
them from the recipe component, from the recipe service to another component and then we have the
same for a single recipe and so on but we have no method to overwrite that array of recipes here and
it's time to do so now.
So let's add a new method in the recipe service, which we can call set recipes and there, we should get
an array of recipes, so let's make it really clear by adding that type
and the idea here is simple, this recipes should be set equal to the recipes we're getting as an argument
here and this will overwrite our recipes here with these recipes.
The important thing here just is since we're changing the recipes, we should then also call this recipes
changed next and push a copy with the slice method of our recipes there, so that we inform all interested
places in our app that we got new recipes, just as we're doing it when we're updating a recipe or
deleting a recipe.
So with that, we're setting the recipes equal. Now in the data storage service, instead of logging the recipes,
we can use the injected recipes service and call set recipes to forward our recipes there. Now we're getting
an error here because TypeScript does not understand that the recipes we're getting here really are
an array of recipes and that makes sense,
it just understands that here, we have the body of an HTTP response and that could be anything and therefore
to inform TypeScript about the type, we should indeed add the generic annotation to the get method
here, where we can make clear which format our extracted response body will have.
And therefore here, I will add recipe array and that now requires me or requires us, if you're following
along, to import the recipe model here from the recipes area, so that we can use that type in the data
storage service
and now TypeScript does not complain anymore because now TypeScript understands that the response body
will indeed be an array of recipes and therefore, we can validly forward this here. With that out of the
way, let's give this a try,
let's first of all delete all these recipes here and let's now fetch them and that's looking good.
Here they are again
and if we send this to the shopping list for example, that all seems to work. So we can now manage our
recipes
and now, we are indeed storing them on a server.