Whatever.
So we had a lot of interface's Let's jump to the next point generic as well this is a rather short file
because I could talk a lot about generics but we don't use them that often and this really will be something
for real Types Of course.
So you might look up documentation if you want to learn more about generics.
Here is a quick introduction.
Generics allow us to well be flexible regarding the time certain objects use.
So to say might sound strange.
Let's look at the example here I've got an area of number theory and I'm assigning it to type 3.
No area on its own is a type but it's a really useful type if we say what should be inside this area
because it's just an object.
Classes say.
But it has to be something inside this error that values this area holds no general and the Array class
theory is able to hold numbers or strings or whatever we like or we might feel the need to explicitly
tell it that it should only except let's say numbers in this example.
So the class area is a generic class which will work for a broad band with for basically all types are
able to limit it to on runtime say this Pacific area we store in this variable should only be all able
to note numbers.
Therefore this is valid an area where we assign just a number every.
But if I comment this out and comment this in this area holding a string on and you can already see
it's red.
It's having this red underline.
And if I'm copilot's generics file here you can see we get we're getting an error because well we're
trying to assign a string value to an area which should only be able to hold numbers.
That's really it about race or about generics.
There is more to it than the one side but this is how we will use Trotter's words to tell certain objects
like an array or an event emitter or an observable which kind of value will you hold or turn or which
ever interaction is that we have with this value.
I hope this is clear why and how we used to generics you see in the next video by