So now the alert will not be shown here
by using ngIf and hence I'll comment this out as well
and I'll not add anything to the DOM here,
for now at least. Now my goal is to instead create that alert component dynamically and show it dynamically
and dynamically is the wrong word
maybe, I mean programmatically, from inside code.
Now for that, we first of all need a new method because now we have to write some code to show the error
alert
and I'll turn this into a private method,
show error alert.
I added this to the auth component and show error alert has to be called whenever we have an error.
So here, when we set the error, we now have to call this show error alert
and of course we could now also change the get general flow, to not set the error globally on a property
here but instead, pass it here into show error alert
and that is what I will do here.
I'll still set it globally because we use that in the past
but we wouldn't need that now because this error property now has no real use because we're not using
it in the template anymore.
Still I'll leave it here because we used it in the past but you don't need it anymore for this approach.
Instead, show error alert will receive the message,
so let's accept it here, it will be of type string and in here, the goal now is to dynamically create our
alert component. Now for this, you manually need to instantiate a component.
Now a simple approach you could take would be that you import your alert component here,
so you go to the shared folder, import it from the alert folder and then from there, you import the alert
component.
Now we have access to the alert component which we defined in that file and now of course, you could
think that you simply create an alert component and save it in an alertCmp constant maybe by calling
new alert component,
it is a class after all.
Now this is a valid TypeScript code but it is not valid Angular code,
this will not throw an error if you compile it but it also won't work in any way.
You can't work with that alert component then in the way Angular needs to work with it because Angular
does a lot more than just create an object when it instantiate a component.
It needs to wire it up,
it needs to wire it up to change detection into the DOM,
this here would be a normal Javascript object and that is not what Angular needs. So therefore, you can't
create your own component like that,
this here won't work.
Instead, you need to let Angular create this component and for that, Angular gives you a tool, the component
factory. To get access to that tool,
you need to inject something and you don't inject the component factory itself,
instead you inject a component factory resolver.
Now of course, it is up to you how you name that argument
and again I'm using that trick here where this automatically gets stored in a private property.
It's up to you how you name this but the type thereafter is component factory resolver and that's really
important, it has to be the resolver, not the component factory itself. Component factory resolver is then
imported from @angular/core.
Now with the component factory resolver injected, in show error alert, you now use that resolver
to get access to a component factory,
yes, sounds strange right?
But this is how the flow works.
So there, you now use the component factory resolver and there, you have a resolve component factory
method which gives you access to a component factory as provided by Angular.
Now to that factory, you have to pass the type of your component, which in our case here would be the
alert component.
Now you don't instantiate this,
you don't have new in front of this or anything like that,
you just pass in the type
so that Angular knows where to look for that component which it then should create for you. This method
here will return a component factory or to be precise, an alert component factory, not the component itself,
just the factory.
So this now is essentially an object that knows how to create alert components, which is a great first
step at least.
Now with that factory, we can use that factory to create a concrete component
but for this, we also need a place where we can attach it in our DOM and we don't have that place yet.
We need to tell Angular where we want to add that component and now you could think that you use some
way of getting access to some element, let's say here we want to add it, so we added div with a local
reference
add here and with @ViewChild, we could get access to that as you learned earlier in the course but this
is not how it works.
Angular needs a view container ref which you might remember from the directives deep dive section. A
view container ref is essentially an object managed internally by Angular, which gives Angular a reference,
a pointer to a place in the DOM
you could say, with which it can interact and this object has more than just like the coordinates where
it sits,
it has methods like "hey, please create a component here" and we need something like this. Now to get access
to such a view container reference,
there is a nice trick or actually not a hack, it's the official approach for getting access to it,
we can create a helper directive. Now that directive could be named placeholder, you can name it however
you want and I'll name it placeholder.directive.ts,
that's the file name and in there,
we export a class, I created this in a shared folder by the way. I export a class, placeholder directive
and that will receive the @directive decorator of course.
Now this @directive decorator needs one thing and that's the selector. The selector here should be an attribute
selector, so that we can add this directive as an attribute to any element and I'll name this app
placeholder, like this,
following the naming patterns you should use for naming directives with this camel case notation.
So we have the placeholder directive and now this directive needs to do one important thing,
it needs to inject the view container ref and you learn this in the directive deep dive section.
You can inject a view container ref like this,
you need to import view container ref from @angular/core and this automatically gives you access to
the reference, to a pointer at the place where this directive is then used.
So this will allow you to get information about the place where you use the directive
and as I said, that will not just be coordinates but the view container ref has useful methods, for example
for creating a component, in that place where it sits.
So you essentially get access to the place where the directive is added to and you not just get access
in the sense of where is this but also in a sense of please add something there.
Now, we need to turn this into a public property, using that TypeScript shortcut where this argument is
automatically stored in a property of the same name
and this property is publicly accessible, so that we can access that view container ref from outside.
Now why do we need that?
Because now, we will be able to add the directive to some place in our DOM, in our templates and then
get access to it with @ViewChild and then get access to the public
view container ref to work with that
view container ref of that directive.
Let's implement that step-by-step. Before we can do that,
let's make sure we also declared that directive in the app module, here
the placeholder directive,
make sure to also add the import of course
and now, let's continue.