Now to fix that,
there are a couple of ways. One way would be that
we simply import the router module like this, without for root
but just like that and also add the import statement up there into our recipes module.
If we do that and we go back to our application, now we still fail because of app recipe item that uses
ngFor and doesn't have access to that
but we don't get that routing error anymore.
Now still we get an error and this error is related to ngFor, here
the same logic as with the routing applies. You don't magically have access to all these core Angular
features. You did thus far because we had everything in the app module,
we declared all components in the app module and we have important imports here in the app module that
import core Angular features into the app module and therefore, any component declared here has access
to these features, components declared in other modules don't
and for example ngIf and ngFor are provided by the browser module.
All the forms related things are provided by the forms module or the reactive forms module. HTTP related
stuff is imported by that HttpClient module,
though this is kind of an exception, this only provides services and no directives or components and
services work differently and therefore are indeed available application-wide even in modules where
you don't add this but as soon as you use something that's not a service and I'll come back to that
services thing later,
as soon as you use something that's not a service but that offers real directives or any features you
use in templates,
as soon as that's the case, you only have access to what you import.
So to be able to use ngFor in the recipes module, besides the router module, we probably also need
the browser module.
However, this is now just a special case and the only special case. The browser module must only be used
once and that is in the app module because it does more than just add ngIf and ngFor, it does
some general application start up work that only has to run once. Instead of the browser module,
use the common module in all other places, in all other modules where you want to get access to ngIf and
ngFor.
So here, you add the common module and that is imported from @angular/common. Now with that imported,
we unlock ngIf and ngFor and therefore now if we save this, we again get an error but a different
error. This time,
the problem is the form group directive and as I mentioned, well you only have access to what you import,
we're not importing the forms module or here actually, the reactive forms module because we're using
reactive forms in the recipes area
and as soon as we do add it though and of course for that, you also need to add the import statement up
here from @angular/forms, as soon as we do add this, we can save this
and now we see that it finally loads again and our application runs again and if I login, I can indeed
go to my recipes, I can fetch my data here and that all works.
Now we outsource this into a separate module and the core takeaway you absolutely have to understand
is, whatever you declare here and whatever you use in the templates of these components, has to be imported
in that module,
it's not enough if you import it in the app module.
The only exception to the rule are services,
these only need to be set up once in the app module and you can access them in your whole application,
even in components which you added to feature modules but anything that's used in a template, so components,
directives, pipes, these things need to be declared or imported into the module where you plan on using
them.
It's not enough to use them in another module,
even if you export your things to that other module, even then it's not enough, Angular treats and parses
every NgModule standalone.