Now, the work we did on the recipes module was a good start but of course the only thing we're doing
thus far is we're outsourcing our recipes component declaration in a separate module so that the app
module is a bit leaner.
Now that wouldn't be the worst reason to do it,
it's absolutely fine to restructure your app to have leaner modules that are easier to understand and
to manage,
yet we can actually do more than that.
We can also move the recipes related route configuration away from the app routing module,
so I'm talking about this branch here essentially, away from the app routing module and into our recipes
module. For that, here in the router module,
you could add forChild now. Now for root is only used once essentially, here in the app routing module
where we use for root to configure our root routes. In a feature module which you then plan on importing
into your app module, you would use forChild and this will automatically merge the child routing configuration
with the root routes.
So therefore here, we can use forChild and pass in that same array of route configuration we pass
to for root. Now to keep this file leaner
and this is totally optional,
I'll again create a separate module,
the recipes-routing module and therefore I'll export
this class, recipes routing module, which will receive the @NgModule decorator and I only do that
to focus on the route set up in this file and not clutter the other recipes module file with that.
So here, we have our routes which are of type routes which is imported from @angular/router and which
is an array and in that array, you add all recipes related routes
and in this case, if we have a look at the app routing module, that means I take this single route, this
recipes route with all its nested routes, I take that, cut it from my app routing module and move it
here into the recipes routing module.
So now here, we have that route file, that route setup. That of course means that all these imports have
to be added and I will add all missing imports here, so all the recipe components and also the auth
guard,
that's also important,
we use that here too, so that this file now has a correct route setup and now in NgModule, we add
imports and import the router module from @angular/router
and as I just explained, on that module, you now call forChild and pass in your routes and then just as
before, you export this router module here and we export it in the recipes routing module so that in the recipes
module, we can actually import our recipes routing module and again of course for that, you need to add
an import path, so import recipes routing module from the recipes-routing.module file.
So now we're adding the routes here in the recipes area.
Now with that adjustment, in the app routing module, we got one route less, we got all the other routes
but not this route
but now in the app module, we do import the recipes module and since we register our recipes related routes
there, they should still be part of our general routing config. The config, the routing config is
now just split across two files.
That also means that here in the app routing module, we remove all these unused imports,
so that they don't pollute this file anymore.
Now let's try saving that and this looks good. Here I'm in the recipes area and I can navigate a route,
I can go to new recipe, so all these recipes related routes
they still work just as they did before but now with our split up route config and again here, the idea
can be that we make sure that we have a leaner app module and a leaner app routing module and we manage
all recipes related things in our recipes module and nowhere else.