With the placeholder directive added, let's go back to the auth component and now we need to add a new
element here.
Now you could add a div but there is a better element, you could should use ng-template here.
This is a directive Angular ships with, which will not actually render anything to the DOM but still
is accessible in the Angular templating language.
This is great because we don't add the overhead of an extra DOM element here,
instead we can now simply just get access to a place in the DOM. To ng-template, we add app
placeholder like this, this new placeholder directive we created. By the way, you don't have to create
it here,
you can also create it outside of that row here if you wish to, anywhere here.
So now we have that ng-template element added which is considered by Angular when it parses the
template but which does not render a real element to the real DOM which is great but we will be able
to get access to this place in the DOM thereafter,
it's simply remembered internally by Angular
you could say. So now we have that, how does it help us?
Well in the auth.component.ts file,
we can now get access to that directive with the help of @ViewChild which you already learned about
in the component deep dive section. View child is imported from @angular/core and to @ViewChild, you
pass a selector.
Now you could pass in the name of a local reference as a string but that's not the goal here,
instead you can all also pass in a type and it will look for the existence of that type in the
template.
So if we pass in the placeholder directive as a type, it will automatically find the first place where
we use that directive in the template of this component.
So here, I'll add placeholder directive and this needs to be imported from your placeholder directive
file of course and I'll add it as a type like this
and as I mentioned, @ViewChild will then find the first occurrence of that directive in the DOM.
Then we can store this in a property of that component,
like alert host would be a fitting name because it will be the place where we host our alert and this
will be of type placeholder directive of course.
So we get access to that directive we use in the template and we store that in alert host.
Now that alert host can be used in show error alert.
We have our factory down there,
now we can get access to that
view container reference of our host.
So here we can get access to this with host view container ref for example
and this simply is the view container if we find in our alert host which is that directive
we selected with @ViewChild view container ref because our host has that view container ref property
because it is just the directive we're selecting in our template and our placeholder directive of course
exposes view container ref as a public property here.
So therefore since we expose it there, we can get access to it here in the auth component and I'm storing
it in new constant, you of course don't need to do that,
you could continue working with that.
So now I store a reference at that view container ref property in the host view container ref constant.
Now the next thing is that we clear anything that might have been rendered there before by simply calling
clear on this view container reference.
As I mentioned, the view container reference is not just like a pair of coordinates,
instead it is an object that allows you to interact with that place in the DOM and clear simply clears
all Angular components that have been rendered in that place before
and I want to clear everything before I render something new.
Now we're almost there,
now we can use our component factory to create a new alert component in that host
view container reference and this is done by simply now using our host view container reference
and calling create component. As I mentioned, you have methods for creating things in that place.
So here I create a new component
and this now does not need the type of the component but it needs such a factory,
so here I pass in that alert component factory we created earlier and this will now create a new component
in that place.
Let's give this a trial, save all the files and let's wait for this to reload
and now let's try logging in with fake credentials and I get an error. I get an error that no component
factory found for alert component, did you add it to NgModule entry component?
Now what is that?