I'm back in my Firebase project and as with the normal HTTP requests, I really want to emphasize that
you of course don't need Firebase to add authentication to an Angular application.
You can add it with any back-end, be that a REST or a GraphQL API. Your back-end just needs to offer
endpoints you can use to create new users and to log users in to get such a token
therefore. If your API supports that, and most APIs do and if you're creating your own API, you can of
course add your own auth logic, then you can use that API,
you don't need Firebase, I'm just using it because it's easy, free to use, doesn't require us to write
server-side code,
that's the only reason.
And with that, let's go to the authentication page here and there,
we now have to set up a sign in method.
Well actually before we do that, let's go to the database again and there,
let's go to rules and under rules, previously we unlocked this by setting read and write access to true for
everyone.
This means that everyone can read our recipes, get our recipes and store recipes, everyone can interact
with our database here.
Now this was required in the past because we had no authentication in place, since this is about to change
now, it's about to change these settings and therefore you should now change this to auth unequal null
here, for both read and write.
This will tell Firebase that only authenticated users should be able to read and write data.
Now of course if you were using Firebase for your project, you can set up more sophisticated rules for
different resources and the official Firebase docs are then the way to go. Here,
I want to lock down everything, my entire Firebase database if users are not authenticated. Publish these
rules to make sure they have an effect and what you will already notice
now with these changes, that if you go to recipes and you fetch data, you get an error here, a 401 error
that you're not authorized.
Now of course, we could handle that error in a better way by displaying a nice error message here or
anything like that but we won't even reach that page soon because we will lock down access to it in
our front-end to provide a good user experience and avoid that a user is able to visit a page where
he's not going to be able to do anything anyways.
So for now, we can go there and we can fail but soon this will change
but now, we need to go back to Firebase and enable authentication so that we can slowly add the logic
to be able to visit our authenticated routes again.
So here under authentication on Firebase, click on setup sign in method and choose e-mail and password
and click enable here, only that top one. Now click save
and now you got that built-in Firebase authentication active where you can send requests to certain
endpoints offered by Firebase, to create users and to log users in and you'll then see your users here
under authentication in the users tab.
Now which endpoints are that though?
Let's start with signing users up.