We're almost finished, our application is taking shape and services really improved it.
Now I want to do something here on the recipe section, I want each recipe to have some ingredients, so
we need to implement this and thereafter, I want to make these two shopping list buttons work, so that
we can send our ingredients to the shopping list. So to do this, what I will do is first of all, I will
work on the recipe model,
it should now also have ingredients.
So this will be of type
ingredient array, ingredient of course needs to be imported from the respective model file in the
shared folder
and when we create a new instance of this model, I expect to get some ingredients here.
Again, this will be of type ingredient array, so that here we can assign ingredients equal to the ingredients
we get as an argument here.
So with that, we are prepared to have some ingredients, now in the recipe service, I also need to add some
here.
So when we create a new recipe and I simply structure this over multiple lines to make it easier to
read, I also now will pass an array of ingredients, the same for the second recipe here
and now I guess it's time to also turn this into some real recipe,
so let me quickly do this.
So I quickly changed the pictures in the text to have a schnitzel and a burger here and now let's add
some ingredients here in this array of ingredients. We can use the ingredient constructor for this
and of course we need to import the ingredient type here from the model file located in the shared folder
for that
and now for the Schnitzel, let's say we need the meat, with an amount of one maybe
and then we also want to have some french fries here, now let's say exactly 20, with one extra it would probably
not taste
well I guess. So
now with the array for the burger, here we need a new ingredient, we need the buns,
so the bread basically, let's say 2
and we also want to have the meat here, of course
feel free to add more ingredients.
So now that we added that in the recipe detail component, here where we have this ingredients placeholder,
we can actually now output them here.
So let's add something here, let's add an unordered list with a class of list-group
and now here I want to add a list-group-item. This item here will actually be replicated because again,
this will of course be my ingredient.
So here, ngFor and now I will loop through all the ingredients, so ingredient of
and now of recipe ingredients of course because remember in the recipe detail component, we have a recipe
and that has some ingredients since a couple of seconds at least.
So now, we can simply use string interpolation here to output the ingredient name and then maybe separated
by a dash, the amount,
of course any format you like.
So that's the first step,
now if we select a recipe, we see a list of ingredients at the bottom.
Now I want to send these to the shopping list
if I click this to shopping list button.
So that is what we'll work on in the next lecture.