All the first thing you can do and for that I'm animating this.
Excuse me I'm commenting on this out if you want to use the same timing.
You don't have to duplicate is and simply write highlighted to normal here.
Instead you can use one line and simply make an arrow point in both directions.
Now this means back and forth use the same animate function.
So in this case use the three hundred milliseconds which now means we have the same timing.
That's one thing.
But also you might have a more complex animation where you want to control the styling this has during
the movement.
So not the beginning and not the end state only during the transition.
You might have some extra styles at this place or at this point of time too well to simulate this.
Let me copy this trigger here so that we keep the simple one two and I will name it wild state because
it's getting more wild now.
So the wild state should now be applied to a new.
I'm copying here Q which is now bound to that new wall state.
It still uses my state property.
Don't get me wrong but here it now uses the wildside.
Now with that I'm handing it to the wall state animation trigger.
I also want to set up a new property I'll name it wild state and therefore here in my component of duplicate
normal and set this to wild state so that I have two different dates where we can see two different
things.
Now how does wild state work or how do you want to control this.
Well I still want to have my normal and my highlighted style and I will leave to styling I have here
but I want to set up a third state.
This is the srong state let's say.
So I'm able to shrink this square the background color let's say should then be green and we transform
it such dead.
We want to translate it 100 pixels but we want to scale it to zero point five let's say and no let's
actually translated 0 pixels so at the starting point therefore in the average You state you want to
scale it to 1.
So that's again normalcy is a set up here.
And with that we set up the different states.
Now when I go back to where the two directions highlighted two normal and normal two highlighted have
different durations like we had before.
So like this you have just commented this out anyways.
Now i also an injustice and also hook up is on Szeryng method here does shrink button.
So on shrink show now I assigned this wild state to be shrunken that is that third stage set up appear
shrunken in on any mate.
I therefore also want to set this wild state equal to or for us compare it.
If it's equal to normal and if not well I basically want to do the same as year.
So let me quickly capitis and replace this.
So you're I'm not using the shrunken state that's something I'm only setting here now with this set
up I can of course reload my application and once it does reload we should see a new square below the
first one or maybe let's introduce a little divider here like a line break so that we can clearly see
the difference and now if it like animate.
They both move with different speeds of course because it changes but shrinking still happens instantly
.
So shrinking is not really animated.
And that is something I want to change.
So back in the up component we basically need a forward transition because we're only targeting normal
and highlighted and we're not using shrunk now to do that.
I can use the fallings transitional where a transition from an to shrunk and now from anywhere.
So I don't care if I have normal or highlighted no matter which of the both states it is.
I want to play the same animation.
And for that I can use the wildcard character which means any state.
So shrunken to any state and shrunken from any state should play the same animation here for now.
And we made it over 500 milliseconds so that we can see something before I then find this.
So after reloading this find our shrink get you see shrink down.
And if I animate you now see it switch and animate correctly.
So now we are animating days and the wildcard character here is the key to all.
Give us the flexibility that we don't manually have to specify any possible state and an application
where you maybe derive a state dynamically.
You might really not know which states it could have.
And they're the wildcard character is what you need.
Now in the next few I want to dive in how to manipulate this animate function and have some in-between
styles during the animation