In the last lectures, we learned a lot including the creation of a new component by hand.
Now there also is an alternative to creating it manually. When using the CLI, you can open a new terminal
window or command line, leave the ng serve window running,
that's important, don't close it
and in this new window we can use some CLI command to also create a new component.
Let's say we want to have our single server components here in another component, so nested into
another component, a servers, multiple servers component.
We can create this manually by adding a servers folder with our component or we use the CLI with
ng and there we have a generate command, which allows us to generate some elements, some elements
supported by Angular.
One such element is a component, so we can create a new component with ng generate component and
then passing the name, servers like this.
You can also use a shortcut and instead of ng generate component, you could say ng g c which does
the same.
So if you hit enter, what this will do is it will give you a new folder in your app folder with the name
of your component, servers
and in there, you basically find the same files as you had for the app component, HTML, CSS, TS and this
spec file which basically is used for testing.
Now I will remove this,
we will later have a section about the testing and we'll have a look at the styling later too,
for now let's say it is in this servers component that we want to output our single server.
Well we already have this selector, app server,
so in this template of the servers component, we can overwrite the default text with app server and maybe
simply replicate this so that we have two components because remember, components are reusable.
We can use the same component as often as we want by simply using its selector as often as we want.
So now we have two servers here and with this in our servers component, you need to make sure that you
also update the app module.
Now the CLI should do this automatically which is why you already find the import and the declaration
in this file
but make sure you really do have it here.
With this, we can go to our servers.component.ts file to check the selector which is app-servers
and then we can go to our app.component.html file and update the selector to use
this new component instead of the old one.
With this if we now save this and go back to our application, it looks almost the same as before, we see
our single server component twice
but if we inspect the code here in the developer tools of Chrome for example, you'll see that we have
this outer app servers component, this newly created component
and in between, we have two single app server components.
So with that, we learned a couple of important things about how to create components manually or with
the CLI, how we can nest them into each other, that we can use components selectors in any other template
of any other component and how we can replicate components by simply using them
multiple times, using their selectors multiple times.
Let's dive into how we can actually style them, what we can do regarding the style and the template
of components.