We're almost done for this section but we have a bug or not really a bug but a behavior which I want
to get rid of.
If we are on a recipe detail page, like this here, recipes/2 and you reload, you get an error,
you get an error that it can't read the property ingredients of undefined and the bigger problem here is
not related to the ingredients but simply that we tried to load the detail page for a recipe which doesn't
exist because we're fetching our recipes from a back-end and if we haven't pressed fetch data before,
then we simply have no recipes,
so accessing the details of a recipe is doomed to fail.
Now there are different ways of making this work,
one of course would be to simply add a guard that prevents us from accessing recipes/2 or the
added route which also an ID encoded in the URL when we have no recipes loaded and instead
redirects us to just /recipes for example.
That would be one way of doing it,
we could use such a guard but we can also use a guard but another type of guard,
we can use a resolver which I also covered in the routing module.
A resolver is essentially some code that runs before a route is loaded to ensure that certain data
the route depends on is there.
That sounds like a good idea to me.
I'll add it in the recipes folder next to the recipes component and I'll name the
file recipes-resolver.service.ts because it is a normal Angular service in the end. In there,
let's export a class which should be named recipes resolver service
and this will get the @injectable decorator because it is injectable in the end and injectable as
you learned needs to be imported from @angular/core and this will then get the provided in root object
here to provide it application-wide automatically.
Now the recipes resolver service now needs to implement the resolve interface. Now
resolve is also imported from an Angular package of course, it's imported from @angular/router. Now resolve
is a generic interface which means we need to define which type of data it will resolve in the end and
in our case, that will be the recipe data,
so an array of recipes and for that, let's also import recipe from the recipe module here.
So our resolver will in the end run some code that loads some recipes,
we now need to inject our data storage service here because that is the service that will make the HTTP
request. So I'll name it data storage service here, of type data storage service which now also needs to be imported
up there
from the shared folder and there the data storage service file and now the resolve interface forces
us to add a resolve method here which gets data about the route, the activated route snapshot which is
imported from the Angular router and which gets the current routing state, which is of type router state
snapshot which is also imported from @angular/router.
From there, we could get information like the ID we're requesting but I'm not interested,
I want to load all recipes anyways,
otherwise things like editing them won't work correctly because we need to reinsert them into the
array and so on and therefore now here,
the goal is to return either an array of recipes which we can't because we need to load it first or an observable
that will in the end yield an array of recipes and that is something different,
that is something we can offer. For that, let's have a look at the data storage service.
There we have
fetch recipes
and right now, we subscribe in here,
we just have to tweak this a little bit.
I still want to set the recipes in the recipes service from inside fetch recipes but we can simply do
this by adding another rxjs/operator, the tap operator and the tap operator also needs to be
imported from rxjs/operators. The tap operator allows us to execute some code here in place
without altering the data that is funneled through that observable.
So in here, we will get our recipes array indeed and I will simply set the recipes in a service then
as before
but now I will not subscribe here anymore but instead, return this call to this HTTP service
and that means that in the header component, we now have to subscribe here and you don't even have to
pass in a function if you're not caring about the response anyways.
So therefore here in the header component, this change of course is a bit redundant but it's now really
helpful here in the resolve method because here we can now return this data storage service fetch recipes.
Now please note that I'm not subscribing here but I'm simply not subscribing here because the resolver,
this Angular feature will subscribe for me to basically find out once the data is there. You can ignore
this error,
it's my IDE not understanding that this is valid.
So now, we should have a valid resolver that loads the data before this page is loaded.
So let's now fetch data, open the summer salad and reload and we still fail.
Now obviously because we're not applying the resolver.
So let's now go to the app routing module, where we have our two paths that rely on a recipe being loaded
and on both these paths,
we now have to add the resolve key which is an array of resolvers and there, we should add our recipes
resolver service and that now needs to be imported,
so let's import recipes resolver service from ./recipes and then there it's that recipe resolver
service file.
Now let's add that same key here to the recipe edit component and now Angular
will run this resolver before loading this route.
So now if I reload this, this looks much better
and now that data is here because now what we do in the end is we run, through that resolver,
our data storage service fetch recipes method whenever this route gets loaded and that is super helpful
and important here to ensure that our data really is there when we need it
and therefore even when editing this, if I reload this edit route, this also works. It takes a bit longer
to load because the data needs to be fetched first but since Firebase is super fast, this is no issue
and now we prevent nasty bugs by us loading data which is not there because now it is there and as you
learned, of course saving data and fetching data also works, so that now we can freely delete our recipes
as we want.
We can always fetch them again, unless we save it again after deleting of course.