We of course added navigation to our page
but one issue is that
whilst it does work fine, we get no visual indication of what the currently active route is.
It would be nice if the selected tab would change and that of course is only a CSS thing because
if you check your app component here, you'll see we get this active class on the list item which determines
whether this is marked as active
if this link gets the right CSS classes or not. So it would be nice if we could dynamically
set this class.
I will remove it from here and how can we now set it dynamically? Angular gives us a specific
directive for this,
the routerLink active directive and the convenient thing about this directive is, you can add it to a
wrapping element, like we do here, to the list item or also of course to the link itself
and it will attach the class you specify in between here, for example active,
so this should be a string, to that element
it sits on. Now active on the link itself wouldn't do anything
when using Bootstrap, here for these tabs look we need to add it to the list item
but this of course depends on which package or which CSS code you are using
and here you could specify any class you want,
like my active class or whatever that is.
So here, it is active to make it look nice in Bootstrap's world and I will add it to all my links
here.
So now theoretically, all my links should receive this active CSS class once they are clicked or when
they are active.
So if we have a look at this, it seems to work because we still have homes set as our active page, even
though we remove this class, this active class we had there before. If I click servers, it gets marked as
active too
and the same for users, so this works but somehow, home is always marked as active.
So that does not seem to work correctly,
what's wrong here?
Well the routerLink active directive does one thing,
it analyzes your currently loaded path and then checks which links lead to a route which uses this path
and by default, it marks an element as active, it marks this
CSS class if it contains the path you are on or if this link is part of the path which is currently
loaded.
So for the /servers link or the /users link,
this is of course the case once we click servers or users. For the slash nothing link, which is the first
one, the home page,
this is always the case,
we always have slash nothing at the beginning of our path here,
so if we are on /users, well there is this empty path in-between you could say, the same for servers
and the same for just home of course.
So the empty path segment is part of all paths,
still we don't want to have the home being marked as active all the time.
So to fix this, we can add some configuration to this routerLink active directive and I will split this
up all over multiple lines to make this a bit easier to read. So we can add a special configuration to
our routerLink active directive,
so on the same element as routerLink active was added to, we can add routerLink active options
and this now needs some property binding because we don't just pass a string there,
instead we pass a Javascript object and that would not work without having our square brackets.
So with square brackets, we can pass anything which will be resolved dynamically, like this Javascript
object
and here, we can basically add one important configuration, say exact and set this to true. So exact is
a kind of a reserved property on this object you passed to routerLink active options
and this will now basically tell Angular only add this routerLink active class,
so this active CSS class in this case,
if the exact, the full path is well whatever does link leads to,
so only if everything is just slash and not if it is only part of the path. So with this in place,
now you see it still is marked as active on the empty path, at the starting page but if you go to
/servers, now only servers is marked as active because now we fixed this, we change the default behavior
to make sure we only mark this if the full path is whatever we have on our routerLink.