In the last lecture, we learned how we can submit a form created by Angular and how we can access to this
object
Angular created for us.
Now we had a look at the value property which stores the input of the user in key-value pairs,
we see that we also have a lot of other properties and that's pretty cool about this Javascript object,
about the form handling by Angular,
it allows us to really understand the state of our form
We can see which controls we registered here on the controls object, e-mail, secret and username and
each control is of type FormControl, of course a type made available by Angular where each control then
has a couple of properties, mostly the same properties we have on the overall form though
and therefore let's go back to that overall form,
for example properties like dirty, disabled, enabled, errors
and most of the properties should be pretty self-explanatory. Dirty for example is true because we changed
something about that form.
If I reload the page and submit it now, you will see that dirty is false because I didn't type into any
input, so therefore of course dirty is false.
Disabled would be true if the form was disabled for some reason, invalid is false because we haven't
added any validators,
so it isn't invalid,
it is indeed valid.
You do have the valid property down here too,
so the form is valid right now,
we will later learn how to add validators to make sure that a valid e-mail address has to be entered
for example.
And we also have touched for example to see did we click into some of the fields, the difference to dirty
would be that for dirty, we have to change the field, have to change the value of a field, for touch we simply
have to click into it and now it would be touched and you will later learn how these properties can
be helpful in
changing the user experience, for example disabling the submit button if the form is not valid,
I will come back to this later.
It's important to understand that you have all these properties and definitely feel free to dive into
the output we logged here and understand which properties you have, how they change, which properties
the individual controls have and so on.