If I do fetch my recipes and I try to edit one of them, for example I want to add an exclamation mark
here,
you'll see that these changes are not saved and
the reason for that is the resolver which is used whenever we visit the recipe detail route.
It fetches new recipes from the server and that simply overwrites our existing recipes, including our
changes to these recipes.
Now the solution is to first check whether we do have recipes and only fetch new ones if we don't.
So I can inject my recipes service here
like this, import it from recipe service.
With this injected, we can get our recipes from this recipe service get recipes
and now we can check if recipes length is equal to zero,
then this means we have no recipes and we should fetch them, otherwise
if this is not zero, we can just return these recipes because then, we do have recipes so no need
to fetch them again. With that change, we can still reload the page whilst we're on it but we can also
of course reload the app somewhere else and just fetch data
but now if I edit this, indeed the changes are saved. If I reload and I
then get my old data because I didn't save them to the server before my changes but they were saved
locally and if I would have chosen save data, we would have also saved them on a server.
So this is a tiny adjustment which we should make to avoid strange bugs.