In the last lecture we added some ingredients,
now I want you to make this to shopping list buttons work.
You can come up with some ideas, some solution on how you can send these items to the shopping list
so that once we go to the shopping list, we see them here.
Think about informing the component that something changed
and also think about how to add more than one item at once to the shopping list.
I wish you luck with that,
time to pause, in a couple of seconds,
we'll do it together.
So were you successful?
Let's add the shopping list items together.
We already have this button in the recipe detail component,
so the first step of course is to hook this button up.
I will remove the ref here and instead add an inline style to still have a cursor which looks like a
pointer but then here on the click listener, I'll call onAddToShoppingList,
of course you can choose a different name. Now that will be executed here in the component body, in
the recipe-detail.component.ts file
and here, we either need to get access to the shopping list service or to the recipe service
and then the recipe service accesses the shopping list service.
You can find arguments for both,
you could say we're in the recipe section therefore we should mainly work with the recipe service,
you could say why would we take this extra way, this extra step,
we can directly access the shopping list service, again
arguments can be found for both directions,
I will choose the route where we use the recipe service.
So I will inject the recipe
service here, type recipe service of course,
make sure to add the import
and now I need to add a method in the recipe service.
This is the addIngredientsToShoppingList method,
of course you can also pick a shorter name if
this one is a bit too long for you. Here
I expect to receive my ingredients, so that will be of type ingredients and before we continue working
on this in the recipe service,
let's call this method.
So in the recipe detail component, I will access my recipe service,
call this brand new method with the extremely short name and pass on the ingredients of this recipe here,
so these ingredients.
So with that, these ingredients are passed to the recipe service,
now here we need to access the shopping list service. Now for that, we need to get access to the shopping
list service in this file
and if you want to inject a service into a service as we want to do here, you need to add @injectable
to that service,
make sure to import it from @angular/core. With that added here, we can inject the
service now in the constructor of this recipe service class.
Here I'll add the slService, so the shopping list service, to which you'll need it to add an import
at the top pointing to the shopping list folder and then the shopping list service file and with that added,
we can now reach out to that here, slService
and here we need to add a new method.
So let's go to the shopping list service and let's add an addIngredients method, like that.
Now in here, we will receive our list of ingredients, so of type ingredient array and now we need a logic
to add them.
Now a quick and easy way would be to simply loop through them, so let ingredient of
ingredients, like that and then we could simply call this addIngredient for each ingredient
and that would be absolutely fine,
the only downside probably is that we emit a lot of events.
Now it won't be too bad because even a recipe with like 30 ingredients wouldn't blow up our app
but still, there are a lot of unnecessary event emissions.
So that is a viable option but I'll comment it out, a different one would be to directly add all ingredients
in one go and then emit our event.
So we could access our ingredients here and call the push method and now we can use an ES6 feature,
the spread operator which allows us to basically turn an array of elements into a list of elements because
the push method here is able to handle multiple objects.
However, it is not able to handle an array or to be precise, it can handle an array but then it would
push this array as a single object to the other array.
So by adding the spread operator which is simply three dots, might look strange but that is how the operator
looks,
we can now simply spread our ingredients into a list of single ingredients which are now pushed without
issues to our ingredients array and then don't forget it,
we have to emit that our ingredients changed,
so why don't we simply pass a copy of it.
So with that now, we get a method we can call, addIngredients.
So back in the recipe service on the shopping list service, we can now call addIngredients and pass our ingredients
to that service.
With that let's save this and let's simply check this. Right now we only have the default values of apples
and tomatoes on our shopping list,
now on the Schnitzel we got meat and french fries,
let's click to shopping list and let's go to the shopping list and we see meat and french fries,
awesome, that looks really great.
Of course if you click this multiple times, it will duplicate it and you can of course write some logic
to check if an item has already been added and then group it together by name,
I won't do this in this application.
The main thing here is it works,
we can send data around through our app by using services.
We took a major step forward, now in the next section, we're going to have a look at routing and thereafter,
we're going to add routing to this application to now get a proper navigation and also to make this new recipe
button here work. So I'll see you there.