In the last lectures, we learned how we can register controls and how we can submit the form and also which
properties this form has. Now
right now, we submit the form by passing the form which we get via ngForm here to the onSubmit method,
this is absolutely fine and probably the approach you will use in many use cases.
I just want to bring some other approach to your attention.
You don't have to submit it here.
Remember the components section where we learned about @ViewChild which allowed us to access a
local reference, an element controlled or which holds a local reference in our TypeScript code.
Well in the end, we do just have such a local reference here
and whilst that might not point to an element ref but to the ngForm object, it still is a local reference
in our template so we can also use @ViewChild here.
So I will simply comment out this onSubmit method here so that we have it in the code you can find
attached to this module and show you an alternative approach. In this alternative approach,
I will use @ViewChild, this decorator you learned about in the component section, so make sure to import
it from @angular/core
and I want to get access to the element which has the local reference f on it.
So I pass f as a string, as an argument to @ViewChild
and then I could simply store this in a variable named signupForm, any name you like, which will be of
type ngForm of course. Now in onSubmit,
I could output this signupForm, like this
and you should see that if I now submit this again, we still have this form
and I can also enter something so that we can see that this works too if we have a look at the value.
So this gives us access to the very same form without passing it to onSubmit,
this is especially useful if you need to access the form, not just at the point of time when you submit it
but also earlier
and I will show a use case for this in a later lecture.
For now, let's keep in mind that this is another way of getting access to the form in our TypeScript
code, a perfectly valid way of getting access and before diving deeper into why this might be useful
or when we could use that, let's actually understand how we can control the validity of the form.
So to determine whether the form is valid, if we entered a valid e-mail address here or not because right now
I can submit anything, no matter if this is invalid, if this is empty,
it would be nice if we could add such validation and take advantage of the tools Angular
gives us there to possibly also enhance the user experience by placing a red border around invalid elements
or something like this.
We'll have a look at validation in the next lectures.