What does this course offer you? We're just getting started and we just built and edited our first Angular
application.
But of course we didn't fully understand what we did there.
So that's why in the next lecture we're going to dive into the basics of Angular. What are components?
What did we do there with this two-way data binding and how does that all work.
This section will answer it and we'll take a very detailed look at it. We'll also explain how all
these files you saw in your project are connected to each other.
Then we're going to look at components and data binding; two important key features and we actually
saw both already in our first application. Angular apps are built up from components and data binding
is simply how you output data in your DOM in the end and, as you will also learn, react to user events.
Angular has another  key feature; directives. ngModel, which we used with two-way data binding,  actually
is such a directive. You will learn more about the built-in directives in this section and, also very
important,
build your own directives; nice little helpers (instructions)
you can place in your templates, in your HTML code, which will then do something at runtime depending on
the commands you wrote in there. Well, after having a look at this, we're going to learn more about
services and dependency injection;
a core feature of Angular which makes it really easy for you to have your different pieces in your app
communicate with each other, to centralize code and to manage the state of your application.
Once we're finished with that it's time to have a look at routing because, thus far, we will only have
been on one page.
Well, we're always on one page since it's a single page application,
but to the user it really looked like one page. With routing, we introduce the management of different
URLs so that, to the user,
it looks like we're switching pages even though technically, we will still remain on that single page.
Sounds great!
It is
and routing shows you how it works.
Then it's time to have a look at Observables; something which will make more sense once you've been through
the routing section.
It is a concept allowing you to work with asynchronous code. Angular embraces it,
it's really powerful
and this section explains how it works.
Then we'll have a look at forms, because handling forms, handling user input is a key task of almost
any application
and this section takes a very close look at it. After we're done with forms
we're going to have a look at pipes; another nice feature which makes it easy for you to transform the
output
(what you display on the template at runtime). Well, we're nearing the end, but not before having a look
at HTTP.
What if you need to reach out to a web server?
What if you need to store some data in a database?
Angular can't connect to a database directly, but it can connect to a server which is able to and the Http Section
shows just that.
Thereafter, we'll have a look at authentication. What does authentication mean in an Angular application?
How does it work? While we're at it, we'll
implement it in an application. Then we're going to have a look at some optimizations we
can put into place and how we can manage different modules in our application;
something you will really understand once we are at this point. Then, we're going to deploy an application,
learn how we can get our Angular application from our local machine to a place in the Internet where
we can view it.
And if that's not enough for you, we're also going to have a look at animations and testing Angular applications.
Besides that, throughout the whole course, we're going to build a real project putting all these things you'll
learn in the individual sections into practice and, therefore, see how they are used in a real project.
So with that, I feel very confident you're going to be an Angular Master after finishing this course
and I can't wait to start this journey together with you.