Our directive is looking really great,
we're almost there but there's one other thing I want to add,
one functionality I want to add, right now it's dynamic in a way that we can mouse over and then move
the mouse away
but we can't decide which colors get used.
Now if that were a directive we want to ship with, like say a third-party package we're offering, the
user, the developer using this directive should be able to dynamically set the value.
Maybe we even want to do this on our own app because the color we want to set changes depending on some
other parameters in our app.
Right now, the color is hardcoded in there, transparent by default and blue if we mouse over it.
So that is something we can improve and we can improve it with a tool we already learned, custom property
binding. As a side note, custom event binding also works in directives
but you probably won't use that that often.
So how can we use custom property binding then? Let's add two properties to which we bind. I'll add it with
input here and I'll name the first one
defaultColor and set it equal to a string and even assign a default color which is transparent.
Now @input of course needs to be imported from @angular/core.
I'll duplicate this and I'll set this to highlight color, that will be blue by default.
So we do have some default values to use but that can be overwritten from outside.
So now by default here, I will assign my highlight color for initially setting this and in my host listeners
here,
if I mouse over it, I will assign my highlight color, excuse me, here it should be my default color at the
top of course,
so default color when we initialize this and then highlight color once we mouse over this and
then default color again once we move the mouse away,
so here, default color.
So with this, it should still work just the way as it did before but now we can actually bind this from
outside.
So in our app component where we use the better-highlight directive, we can now bind to default color
and maybe set this to yellow, should be a string though, yellow and we can bind to highlight color and pass
a string which could be red.
And now if we save this, notice that appBetterHighlight, the directive itself, the name is not enclosed
in square brackets,
now you see it's red and yellow here, though we also detect a bug, initially before we mouse over, it's
white.
The reason for this is when we assign default color here, it's just not set here.
So to prevent this from happening, what we can simply do is we initialize it here in ngOnInit instead, that
also before anything has been rendered
but after our values here are available.
So here, we can set this background color to this default, this default color and now it should work fine,
now we have yellow by default.
So this now works and now we are able to overwrite this,
there are a couple of interesting things we can observe regarding the way we pass down these values
though.
The first interesting thing is that we have two extra directives-like looking things on the paragraph
and that is just property binding.
Now how does Angular know if we want to bind to a property of paragraph, which of course doesn't have
a default color or to a property of our directive?
The answer is it just figures that out,
it simply checks our own directives and so on first before it reaches the native properties
of elements.
That's an important takeaway,
we can bind to properties of our own directives by simply placing them on the same element,
these properties I mean, enclosed in square brackets of course.
Now for ngClass, you'll see that somehow the directive itself is enclosed in square brackets
and that's a typical use case especially if you only have one property to bind or at least one main
property, then you can provide an alias and we can do this here for, let's say the highlight color and
set this equal to your directive selector,
so appBetterHighlight in this case.
If I set this as an alias for the highlight color,
now this assignment here won't work anymore, so I will remove it, instead
now I can enclose my main directive into square brackets and set this equal to red.
So now we should still see yellow and red
but now we're having this same style of enclosing the directive itself.
And it's important to understand that this is only an option,
you can set such an alias but that's not something you have to do
and by default as you saw before, the directive name is not enclosed in square brackets, that really
only happens if you want to bind to a property which has the same name or alias like your directive
selector. One other thing about how we pass down data, one other thing which is true about property
binding in general. If you pass down a string, like now we use square brackets and then single quotation
marks, while you can take a shortcut,
you can remove the square brackets and remove the single quotation marks
and that is a special case
if you are passing down a string. You can do,
you can add property binding without square brackets if you then also omit the single quotation marks
between the double quotation marks and that should work as it did before,
no error. You can use this,
you will see me use this later in the course with official Angular directive,
be careful that if you use it, it's really clear that this is property binding, that no one thinks that
this could be a real attribute existing for the element you placed it on,
then there is absolutely fine to be used. And this is our directive finished, with some extra features
like @HostListener, @HostBinding and dynamically setting values from outside.