In the last video, we created this filter, pipe here, which allows us to filter our servers for their state
and it seems to work great.
We do have a certain issue with it though, if we allow the user to add a new server and I will quickly
add this functionality by going to my template and by adding a line break and then a button with the
classes btn and btn-primary where I say add server which will execute new method, onAddServer like
this and then in the app component, I will quickly add this method, onAddServer and here, I will simply take
my servers, push a new server on it
and of course this will just be a generic server here which will have the instance type of let's say
a small, a name of new server,
let's keep it super simple here,
a status of stable and started could be new date
and then the same date as all the other servers here, this is not the recording date
as a side note, just like or the way you want it.
So with this, we are able to add a new server
and if I now click onAddServer, you'll see it's getting added here. If I filter for stable though and I
hit this button, you don't see it getting added here but it is there, you can see if I remove the filter
altogether.
So I added a couple of servers and now we can filter for them again but they weren't added whilst we had
this list filtered
and this is actually not a bug. I'll quickly reload this and filter for stable again so that
you can see this, if I hit enter here,
as mentioned it's not getting added but it's there, you can see as soon as we clear our filter.
Now the reason for this behavior is that Angular is, thankfully I should say, not rerunning our pipe on
the data
whenever this data changes.
So as soon as we change what we enter here and even if we would only add a blank space and then remove
it, we would update our pipe again as you can see.
So adding the input or changing the input of the pipe will trigger a recalculation, really will
trigger the pipe being applied to the data again but changing the data won't trigger this
and this is a good behavior because otherwise, Angular would have to run this pipe or rerun the pipe whenever
any data on the page changes.
This would be really bad because that would cost a lot of performance
and this is also the reason why no built-in filter pipe exists because filtering you would say is a
pretty common task
but the Angular team decided against adding such a pipe because you typically have a high performance
cost
if you want to enforce it being updated even if you are in filter mode.
So by default, it doesn't work here but we can force it to work
but again, be aware that the following change will make sure that whenever we change data on the page,
our pipe is recalculated you could say.
So this might lead to performance issues,
so you should know what you're doing which is why I'm really emphasizing this.
You can force this pipe to be updated whenever the data changes by adding a second property to the pipe
decorator,
it's called pure and you can set it to false. By default,
this is true and doesn't need to be added.
Now if you do this and the app reloads, let's filter for stable servers and add new servers
and now you see they get added here too.
The reason simply is that the pipe now gets recalculated whenever data changes
and as mentioned before, this can lead to performance issues but might be what you're interested in.
So it is fine to use it,
this is what is pure property is therefore, you can set it to false which basically means this is not,
you could say purely focusing on whether the pipe arguments changed but now it will also be recalculated whenever
anything changes on the page
and again this might be a bad behavior, I'm just emphasizing this because it's so important to understand
but if you know what you're doing, if you do need this behavior,
definitely go ahead,
set pure to false and you are good to go.
And with that, we now get a working filter pipe
with this little downside of potentially hitting performance issues
if we have a very long list here.