Time to fire that sign up method,
for that let's go back to the auth component and here in onSubmit, before we reset the form, instead
of logging our values,
I want to extract my e-mail which I can by accessing form value
e-mail and the same for the password,
so my password will be form value password,
of course you could also add an extra check first of all where you check if the form is not valid
by adding an exclamation mark and then you just return.
Normally, this method should not be triggered if the form is invalid because we disable the submit button
but if a user should hack away into that and kind of manually enable that button which you can do with
the browser developer tools of course,
well then we still have this in line and this still gives us an extra validation step. If the user disables
this as well which would also be possible,
well then the data, the incorrect data will simply be sent to the back-end and will fail there. If a user
wants a bad user experience and forces himself into that, we can't do anything about this
but having that extra step makes sense I guess. More importantly though, we are extracting e-mail and password
and therefore now, we need to inject the auth service into the auth component so that we can call that
sign up method we just added. For that, let's add a constructor and store the auth service in a private property
named auth service, like this, of course make sure you do import your auth service therefore and with the auth
service injected, in here,
let's call this auth service sign up and forward that e-mail and password which you extracted and thereafter,
we can reset that form.
Now in the auth service in the last lecture, we set up that sign up method such that it returns this prepared
observable which is ready to send this request here and therefore we have to subscribe to the response
or to the return value of sign up which is that observable. Now in that response here, we get our response
data if the authentication or if the sign up succeeds,
so here let's simply log the response data for now and of course we might also get an error and for
that, let's grab that error and console log that as well
if one should occur. Good, with all of that out of the way, this should actually be working.
One thing that's missing by the way, now that I look at this we'll add it later, is the login mode currently
is not respected. At the moment we always send a sign up request here,
of course we want to change this and actually let's implement it right now already,
let's check this isLoginMode.
If we're are logging in, then at the moment we can't do anything because we only added the sign up logic
thus far and therefore right now we can only do something in the else block, in the else block
I simply want to send this HTTP request, here
we can't do anything at the moment, resetting the form is something I always want to do.
So now with that out of the way, let's go back to our user interface and let's enter our e-mail and password
and let's try logging in
and that should actually not work and indeed, we see no output there.
So now let's try signing up by switching to sign up and entering our credentials, you can enter any credentials
you want, click sign up and this looks good,
we get back a response which has that kind response, which has that e-mail expires in, that token which
is this cryptic string, local ID which is that automatically generated user ID,
that looks quite good. If we have a look at our Firebase web console here under users and you click
that refresh button,
you also should see the user here,
so this is looking really good and this seems to work. Now as an additional check, if you use that exact
same data again or at least the same e-mail address again,
now you should get an error because that user already exists and therefore here I get a 400 error
where if you dig into that error field, you see I got a code 400 with a message of e-mail exists,
which is kind of a code Firebase gives us telling us that this e-mail address already exists.
This is something we can now use to handle that error
and I also want to show a loading spinner whilst we are waiting for this to be submitted.