We had a look at feature modules,
now let's dive into shared modules.
Now what's a shared module?
In this hypothetical app here, we got two feature modules and of course, we would also have an app module
but it's not important for the shared module here.
So we got two feature modules - products and sales
and as you can see, these two modules only differ in one component.
The products module has the products component, here on the left and the sales module on the bottom right
has a sales component. All the other components and directives they use are essentially the same.
Now you can put such shared features, shared components, directives and other modules even into a shared
module which you then import into both other modules,
this again is a great step to avoid code duplication and have leaner modules.
Now let's see this in practice in our application. In our application,
we have no real shared features across our feature modules.
If we have a look at the shopping list module and the recipes module, the only thing they have in common
is in the end the common module which unlocks ngIf.
Now we could put this into a separate shared module and we will actually but this alone would not be
worth it because then we just import our shared module, which exports the common module instead of just
importing the common module, so we wouldn't win much by that. But in theory in this application, we have
more shared content,
we have the alert, the loading spinner and the placeholder and the dropdown directive. The data storage service
not because services are special as you will learn soon.
So therefore here in the shared folder, I'll create a shared.module.ts
file and you can have multiple shared modules and therefore, they don't have to be named
shared.module.
If you only have one, it makes sense,
otherwise you should give them a name that kind of summarizes which features you're grouping in there.
Now here I'll name it just shared module and export a class, shared module therefore and just as before,
this is a regular Angular module and it therefore will receive the @NgModule decorator like
this.
Now the idea here is that you still now declare and import anything into this module
that might be used by other modules but since every module works standalone, to then also make these
things then available in other modules,
you will also export all these things which you're importing. So therefore here,
for example here we add a declaration to declare our alert component, to declare our loading spinner component
and make sure you also add the import paths at the top, to declare our placeholder directive and our
dropdown directive
let's say and again, make sure to add all these imports and this would be it
and let's now also say we also want to share some services, like the common module, not services,
excuse me I mean modules, like the common module which we import from @angular/common, so I add this
import here too and then, since we don't want to use these features in the shared module but import the
shared module into other modules, we can export this here and we export the alert component, the loading
spinner component, the placeholder directive, the dropdown directive and also the common module and now the
idea is that wherever we import the shared module, we have access to all these features which we initialize
here.
So in other modules, where we want to use one or all of these features, we don't have to add them to their
modules, we just import the shared module and we got access because we're exporting all these stuff.
If we wouldn't export it, we would not have access. So let's now use the shared module,
let's go to our shopping list module
and there, we can at least now replace the common module, although that alone would not be worth it
but to demonstrate it and we replace that with the shared module.
Now as I mentioned and that that's really important,
it's not worth it here because the only thing we really need from the shared module in the shopping
list module is the common module and therefore we replaced one module import with another
but if you would use the alert component here or the placeholder directive or the dropdown directive,
then we would gain much more from that because now, we don't have to add all of that to declarations
here, we just bring in the shared module and we got access to all the things declared in the shared module
and exported there.
So in the recipes module, we can do the same,
we've got the common module. Now we can remove that here and instead, simply bring in that shared module.
Again here, not super useful but to practice this, of course we can now remove the common module import
here and just import the shared module.
Now with that if we try to save that, we'll face an issue though. As the app reloads, we get an error
that the dropdown directive is part of the declaration of two modules and that is now another super
important concept you gotta understand about modules. You can only define or declare components, directives
and pipes once, you can't do that multiple times. You can import a module into multiple imports. So it
is fine if we import the router module here in the recipes module and also in the shopping list module,
imports are OK but declarations are not. If you declare the shopping list components here in the shopping
list module, you must not declare it anywhere else, even if you need it in another module, you must not
declare it there.
The solution then instead is to export it here and import that module into another module and
that's exactly what we're doing with the shared module.
Here, we are declaring and exporting stuff,
so anywhere where we use one of these features, we now have to bring in the shared module because double
declarations as we currently have them here in the app module where I again declared a dropdown directive
and so on are not allowed.
So instead here, we now have to remove the dropdown directive, the loading spinner component and the
placeholder directive in the alert component, we have to remove all of that here and therefore, we also should
remove these import statements here at the top, like this, all of that has to go, also remove the alert
component here
and now cut entry components and add this to the shared module.
Now the app module is cleaned up and now we just have to make sure that we import the shared module
here because we still need access to certain features,
we need access to the dropdown directive because we are using it in the header component which is part
of the app module.
So now we need to import the shared module here into the app module because that now declares features
like the dropdown directive and with that if we save that,
now this is looking better. Now if we reload and so on,
this seems to work.
Now if I test my alert component again, this also works again because this is also declared in the shared
module,
there we also have our entry component which is still required
and since I export the alert component in the shared module and I'm importing the shared module into
the app module, the app module which at the moment is the place where we define our auth component which
in turn is the component that uses the alert component, that all works but only because we respect the
rule of only declaring things once and then using export and imports to share them. Multiple declarations
of the same thing are not allowed.