I'm not sure if you noticed it in the last lectures, with our working application,
if I add servers and blueprints, something changed. Our new server down here in the blueprint as well
as the paragraph right at the top no longer has a blue color.
Now it was colored blue before because in the app.components.css file, we define that paragraphs should have
a blue text color but both paragraphs were removed,
they are no longer part of our app component here.
The first paragraph is part of the cockpit and the second paragraph, that is inside of our server
element
but isn't that strange? Here on this CSS definition, we just say paragraph,
so it should affect all paragraphs in our whole app.
Now you might say, well no it's in the app.components.css
file
so clearly it only belongs to this template
but is that so clear?
Because the way CSS works, it doesn't really care in which CSS file
you define a rule,
it simply is applied to the whole document normally.
So this actually is a behavior enforced by Angular which is not the default behavior of the browser.
So whilst of course this CSS files
have the goal of encapsulating styles for the component they belong to,
this again is not a default behavior,
Angular gives us this behavior and it's a great behavior because with that, we can make sure that whichever
styles we define in a CSS file will only get applied to the component they belong to.
However here of course, this means that now we would have to copy this blue color here to all our other
components where we want to use it.
Well I never wanted to use it on the cockpit
anyways but I will copy it to the server element
and if we now change this and let it reload and enter something here and add a new blueprint, now you
see this is blue again.
Now it's interesting if we inspect this text here in the developer tools, you see that if you have a
look at the styles,
clearly here we assign a blue color
but do you see that? The selector changed, before
we had just p here, just paragraph,
now it's paragraph and then this very strange attribute, _ng-content-ejo-2
.
Well I don't know about you but I didn't add it.
You can see this attribute here on the paragraph,
that is why this style gets applied here because this style definition says make every text blue which
is in a paragraph where the paragraph has this attribute, something which is true for the paragraph holding
this specific text.
Now the other paragraph we have in app cockpit here in the div,
this paragraph does have a different attribute, _ng-content-ejo-1,
down here we have ejo-2.
That is why the styling gets not applied to this paragraph and all these strange attributes which
you can see all over the place here,
all these strange attributes are applied to their specific elements by Angular. Angular
as I told you enforces this style encapsulation and it can't do that magically,
so the way it does it is it simply gives the same attribute to all elements in a component.
So all elements in this cockpit component have ng-content-ejo-1
attached to it as you can see and it does this for each component with different unique attribute
names, ejo-1 and ejo-0 and ejo-2
and with that, it can make sure that once it changed your style selector, it automatically adds this
attribute selector to all your styles defined for a component, that these styles get only applied to elements
of that component.
This is how it enforces this behavior.
It kind of emulates the shadow DOM, the shadow DOM is a technology not supported by all browsers where
each element has its kind of own
shadow DOM behind it, where you then could assign styles to each element
but as this technology is not supported by all browsers, this is how Angular emulates it
and that is the default behavior of view encapsulation in Angular.