I'm going to stop my server just so it doesn't continue to auto deploy my
code while we make our changes to our test and controller.
Then I'm going to open up our RestController and scroll down to our
TestCreate method where you can see we have this line of
restTemplate.put for our object to this URL.
I'm going to change this to say ride = restTemplate.postForObject.
And the syntax for this method signature is a little bit
different than the other in that we say that we want to post for
a specific object and then we pass the type of that object in,
so I have to say Ride.class.
Now we have everything we need in here to accept an object and return that
back rather than get a null response back for this ride.
Now we can go to our controller, and inside of our controller
change our request method type from a PUT to a POST.
Now everything is in place for us to now go ahead and modify our
CreateRide. Let's look at what we're going to do to change that to return that object for this create method.