We are now to a point where we can modify our
RideRepository to utilize Spring JdbcTemplate.
Let's start off by giving ourselves a little whitespace, and I'm
going to leave that return null down below because we're going to
change that out later with a select statement.
I'm always caught off guard a little bit by Spring JdbcTemplate
in that we use the update method to insert,
update, and delete records.
The only thing we don't utilize it for is reading records back.
So we're going to go ahead and create some basic SQL inside of here
and say insert into ride, and we're going to pass in name and
duration, and then we'll say values ?,?, and this uses the standard
prepared statement approach of substituting in values into those
question mark fields.
And we'll pass in var args here by saying , ride.getName and ,
ride.getDuration, and now we've actually created everything that we
need to to insert a record into our database.
If our SQL is all correct and our object gets populated correctly,
everything is here to insert that record into our database.
Let's go ahead and test that now. I'm going to save this code, I'm going to
exit full screen. Make sure your server is started up.
Once that's up and running,
I'm going to go ahead and go to my RestControllerTest and we'll
right‑click on that createRide method, Run as, Unit Test.
Once this completes, we come back with our green bar, we should
have a record into our database. Now we can test that by going to
our MySQL Workbench and saying select * from Ride and execute that,
and we should see that we have the Bobsled Trail Ride in there with
a duration of 35.
If you want to test that again,
we can go back to our IDE, go into that unit test and
change this name to something else.
So we'll say the Willow Trail Ride, and it was a duration of 30,
save that. We can right‑click on that test,
Run As, Unit Test.
Once that's finished running, we can go back to our database,
execute that statement again, and you will see that Willow
Trail Ride with a duration of 30 is in there.
Now if your IDs don't look exactly the same as mine, that's because it's an
auto‑incrementing field and if you've ran it a few times and deleted a few
records, that auto‑incrementing field will continue to increase regardless of
whether you've deleted those rows out.
So, on mine you'll see that the Willow Trail Ride has an ID of 4, and
that's just because I ran this a couple of times testing it.
So, now you have an end‑to‑end example of our code that will call our database.
Really from beginning to end we have our unit test here that calls the
RestTemplate and does a put with an object of the Willow Trail Ride with a
duration of 30 that goes through our controller and our service tier and our
repository until it finally gets to our createRide method where we then pass in
our values into this prepared statement using the Spring JdbcTemplate of insert
into ride, name, duration, these two values, and this is just using var arg
syntax to say ride.getName and ride.getDuration, and it inserts those in there.
Very slick, very clean,
very succinct code. I am going to show you how to use the simple JdbcTemplate,
but I will tell you up front that this is the approach I like to use.
This is the smallest amount of code and it feels like you're just in the
database and you can get done exactly what you need to.
The other approach does feel a little bit more like an
ORM and maybe that's appealing to you, but this is my default and my first choice when I'm doing this type of work.