To change our CreateRide method,
I'm going to first start by making sure that my server has
stopped so it doesn't try to auto deploy our code while
we're making changes to it,
and then I'm going to go ahead and go to my RideRepository.
Inside of our RideRepositoryImpl,
you may remember we have all of this commented out code.
I'm going to go ahead and remove that commented out code and paste it into a
text file to save it for later because we're going to use it later and I don't
want to have to go through and retype all of that.
So I'll paste that into this notes.txt that I have in my project,
and it can just live out there while we make changes to our RideRepository.
So now inside of our RideRepository,
I'm actually going to also comment out this jdbcTemplate.update because
we're going to compare what we had before to what we have now and also be
able to utilize that same insert statement.
We want to start off by creating a KeyHolder and the
KeyHolder is what stores the key that gets retrieved from
our database while we do an insert.
And we want to use a Generated KeyHolder, and a Generated
KeyHolder is because we have an autoincrementing field that's
automatically generated for us.
The next thing that we want to do is also use a udbcTemplate update again, and
that will enable us to use the PreparedStatementCreator.
So, we'll say new PreparedStatementCreator, and if I use Ctrl+spacebar to
choose this type, it says it's an anonymous inner type and it will
automatically add our method that it needs to be generated through that
IntelliSense. Now I can come down inside of here and get rid of that TODO,
and inside of here I want to say PreparedStatement and this is just a
prepared statement from java.sql, we'll say ps = con.prepareStatement, and
here's where we get to utilize that same string that we had up above here.
That's why I didn't just delete this out of here. We'll copy that and we will
paste that in here. And now we're going to do something a little bit
different. Instead of us putting in the var args like we had before in here,
we can actually say comma new string, and it's an array, and we'll pass in an
array syntax of id, and this is referring to the column in the database that
we're going to return as a generated key. So yours should look something like
this. It should say new String [] {} with an id in there for that array
syntax.
Now we can populate that string and say ps.setString, we're just going to fill
those values in our PreparedStatement. And we'll say at position 1 we want to
do ride.getName and we'll do ps.setInt, and say at position 2 we want to do
ride.getDuration, and then make sure you change that return null to say return
ps for our PreparedStatement.
So now that we have our PreparedStatement set up, again we added
that array syntax on to the end of it, we want to go ahead and now
say , keyHolder on the end of that anonymous inner class, and this
is what tells our insert statement to store that generated ID back
in this keyHolder.
Now, we can go down here and say Number id = keyHolder.getKey, and
it will store that key into a number for us.
And we can replace this return statement with a
method that we're going to create.
It currently does not exist. We'll say getRide id.intValue and say that
now we can go below this method and create a new method,
say public Ride getRide, and it's going to take an Integer id, and
we'll just say Ride ride = jdbcTemplate.queryForObject.
And this is a new query statement that we haven't
used out of JdbcTemplate just yet.
And inside of here we can do a select * from ride where id = ?, and
the syntax is a little bit different here. We're going to use that
externalized RowMapper that we created.
So we'll say new Ride RowMapper and then we'll just pass in our ID as a
var arg and then return our ride at the end of it.
So we'll say return ride, and save that.
Now all the pieces are in place with that PreparedStatementCreator and the
KeyHolder to now query our database and get the object that we just created and
return that back to our UI. So let's exit full screen, start up our server. Now
that that's running, we can go into our RideControllerTest and I'm going to
change this to another name just so we can see that it did in fact execute
against our database and our ride is going to return our Ride object down below
here, we can go ahead and right‑click on testCreateRide and say Run As, Unit
Test, and once this runs, we can see that it created a ride and our unit test
was of course successful, but now we can come up and test our GetRides and see
that it did in fact insert that into the database.
So let's right‑click on GetRides and say Run As, JUnit Test,
and you can see that the fourth one that had entered in down
there is the Sagebrush Trail.
So now we have changed our RideRepository to utilize that
PreparedStatementCreator to get that key back. Again, I didn't show this in
the create method because it's a little bit more complex and you really
only care about it if you want to retrieve that object that you just
created out of the database with its ID, and this is the only way that you
can grab that ID using this approach. Let's look at an alternative approach that you may find a little bit simpler