Since the addition of var args to the JDK,
a lot of people don't know or think about using named parameters.
Named parameters allow us to lose the numbering of parameters in our SQL
statements and instead pass in a map of names with values.
This is especially useful if you already have a map for some
other reason in your application and just want to modify the
database with that information.
I should note that named parameters can be used for almost
every function that we have done so far.
So if you like this syntax better,
you can use it instead of numbers in any of the SQL
we've done in our repository tier. Let's change our delete to implement this now.