To demonstrate how a transaction can help us roll back changes
if we're partially through a transaction and want to undo
anything because an error occurred,
the first thing I'm going to do is start up my server.
Then we're going to go through a series of changes inside of our test
just to prove out this functionality so that we don't have to write a
lot of extra code just to show you this demo.
First inside of our test, I'm going to execute our createRide method.
So I'm going to right‑click and say Run As,
JUnit Test, and once this runs, you'll see that it's ran successfully,
I'm going to switch over to our database and run this select * from Ride.
You see inside of here I have two rides at the bottom of my database,
you may only have one because you just executed it,
but notice how they have no ride data in there,
and that's because when we created our createRideTest,
we didn't have it adding the date, we updated those dates in the batch method.
Let's go ahead and go over to our code now and open up our service tier,
and inside of our service tier let's find that batchUpdate method.
You can see here, we have all of our code in place to get all the rides,
pull them back, get a name value pair of the date,
ride id,
we have this batch method where we grab all the rides and create a list of
object array pairs of the date and the ID to update.
Let's go to the end of this method and throw a new DataAccessException.
And what this would simulate is that as we got partially through our code,
something happened and we would want to roll back those changes.
So we'll just put in here a string of Testing Exception Handling and save that.
And now when we go to execute that batch service,
it should go through and roll them back rather than update all of them.
So let's scroll down in our application and find that testBatchUpdate,
and there's mine.
I'm going to right‑click on it and say Run As, JUnit
Test. Now if things were set up with transactions, it
would roll back all those changes.
Let's execute that and see what happens to our
database. It's successfully completed.
I'm going to switch over to our MySQL Workbench and run that select
statement again, and you'll notice that all of my rides have now been
updated even though that exception was thrown.
Let's go ahead and fix that so that it doesn't do that.
The first thing that we want to do is open up our src/main/resources
jdbc‑config file, and we're going to do two things in here.
First, I'm going to go down to the Namespaces tab and check the tx
namespace so that it adds that to the declaration in our XML file. Then
I'm going to switch back to the Source tab, and now I can come in here
and add two beans inside of here.
The first one we're going to use the tx prefix of
annotation‑driven, and it has an attribute of transaction‑manager,
and we're just going to pass in transactionManager.
The second bean I'm going to add is using the bean prefix, and I'm going
to say id=transactionManager. And I'm going to type this one out because
there's a few things I want to show you in here. And there is a class
associated with this that is
org.springframework.jdbc.datasource.DataSourceTransactionManager.
And then inside of the bean tags, make sure you're in between the angle brackets,
there is a property that we're going to add to it, and the property
name is dataSource, and we're going to do a reference to our data
source, so that is dataSource as well.
Now, our tx annotation‑driven and our transactionManager are defined.
Yours should automatically try to deploy like mine has here.
Now everything is set up inside of our XML file to handle transactions.
The only thing we need to go back and add to our code is at the top of
our batch we want to say that it is @Transactional.
Now you may be wondering why I didn't have to include another JAR or anything
like that to get this functionality, and that is because this is automatically
included as a transitive dependency in Spring JDBC.
So these classes were already available because we
are using Maven. Now to test this,
I'm going to go through and do the exact same thing again. I'm going to
go back in our RestControllerTest and I'm going to scroll up to our
testCreateRide because, remember, we don't have a ride now that doesn't
have a date associated with it.
So I'm going to right‑click on testCreateRide and say Run As, JUnit
Test, switch over to my database, run that select statement again, and
I should have one at the bottom of here that does not have a ride date,
and I do. Then I'm going to switch back and run my batch, but this time
that transaction should be rolled back. So I'm going to right‑click on
testBatchUpdate and say Run As, JUnit Test, it successfully completed.
That is because we have an exception handler in there that caught
that exception instead of dumping out a stack trace.
But if I go check my database again, we will see that it did not save those
changes. So our transaction did in fact roll back. If you question that, you
can test that by going back into your RideServiceImpl,
going down to your batch, and either comment that transactional up above or
comment out that throw new DataAccessException and save that.
It will redeploy, and we'll go back to our
testBatchUpdate and run that JUnit test again.
Now it should have saved those to our database, our test was
successful. Because we didn't throw that exception again, it should
commit them, and it did. So quite simple.
All we had to do was inside of our application we added the name space
for tx so that we could put our tx annotation‑driven transaction‑manager
in there, and then we added a bean for the
org.springframework.jdbc.datasource.DataSourceTransactionManager that we
wrap our data source with, and then inside of our code all we had to do
was throw a DataAccessException to test it,
but add that @Transactional annotation to our code to say anything
that takes place in this unit of work, I want to be inside of a
transaction. Very easy to do, and now you're starting to see the
full power of why you have a service tier that calls multiple
functions from inside of it.
Think of a more complex application. If I was updating
three, four or five database tables,
all I have to do is still put that one annotation at the top
and it will roll back all of our changes if an exception is thrown somewhere along the way.