Hey guys,
In this video,
we will be looking at putting in functionality that allows us to view one records details
at a time.
In our previous video,
we will have configured this speed.
This is on screen here by the name of view record thought ph.
B On the purpose of this page was the list all of the records currently in or databases or
at least the attendees table.
Now the task up ahead is toe alot us to be able to click on one record and view only
details related to this record.
To do this,
we will be building a new page,
and we will call it view dot PHP on the sole purpose of you is to receive on I Devalue,
as printed here in this I D column,
or the unique identified from the database on Bring Back the Record with all the details.
For that I d.
So back in our project,
we go ahead and build and create a new file on.
We call this on view dot PHP as usual to maintain consistency,
we need to make reference to over header and footer soldiers copy these blocks from an
existing page on at the header on the footer cord.
Then,
having done that,
we would just rename the title view record.
So we have you records,
which is bringing back all of them in a tabular form in viewer accord.
We intend to only see one record at the time,
so I'm going to just remove this court reference that is calling.
Get attendees because they're going to need a new function to get one record everything
else.
Canada,
me and as you still need the header and we still mean require over database connection.
Next,
I'm going to go ahead and go back to our view record speech on I'm going to add an
additional column so this one will be called actions,
some adding an additional table hitter on I'm going to call it.
Actions on actions were for this video.
We will be putting one button there,
but eventually we'll want to put in functionality to see the view,
the details that we're about to do but also edit and delete per roll.
So we have the column that say's actions,
but then we're going to modify our role cord,
and we're going to add a new column to be added with each row for each record,
some just opening and closing the TV on.
Then in this space,
what we want to do is print on anchor tag that has a sole purpose off navigating to view
dot PHP on passing in our query string with the I D value.
Now all of that was a mouthful sake and just pay attention and I'll go over it again.
So first we start with an anchor talk and I'm just going to open and fills my ankle tag on
and meet the riff B E full tour.
And they were going to see view start PHP on.
I'm just interrupt the text of you,
and then I'm going to want my uncle tired to look so sort of like a button.
So I'm going to put on my boots,
start classes,
someone to say,
class equals how we're going to use Bt and for the button on.
I wanted to be a blue button somewhere to say primary now,
As it stands,
what would happen is that it's going to generate for each rule that we would have seen
before.
No,
we're supposed to have another column on that column is going to have a link called view.
So if I refresh the page after making all those changes and sieving,
then we see exactly that.
No,
we have an actions column,
and we have a button that says View.
And if we click on view,
it navigates.
The are newly created view pitch.
The problem here is that everyone off them is seeing just view dot PHP view dot PHP so all
of them would never get to the same space,
which is fine up to some extent.
But what we really want,
his ability that toe print out all of these leaders on that articular page.
Now the scenario is that it's because you have a small table working with with only 56
feels it's fine.
But if we weren't printing out,
see the person's date of birth in this list on baby,
we're ensuring their contacts number In this list,
you would have to go to view details to see the rest off their profile.
Then that is where this view page really comes into play.
So just to drive home the context,
I'm I'm going to remove the e mail address contacts,
number on the date off birth from the listing.
So when we goto our view,
records stable to view all who are have listed that they're going to attend always sees
their first name,
their last name and their specialty,
and then we'll get the option to view more details.
So I'm just going to remove the table headers on that.
I'm going to remove the corresponding table columns that would have come up for each of
those records.
All right,
so having done that,
we see that we have fewer columns than we had before on.
But the expectation is that when we treat view,
we see the person's full profile,
just like when,
when they would have completed the registration on,
they would see that bit off information being presented.
So what I'm going to do is borrow the cord that would have given that representation so
that coal was on the success speech where we can have created like that little card with
their information,
some distant will borrow all off this HTML here on,
I'm going to put it on my view page.
So at the end of the day,
what we need to do is make sure that the corresponding values per well for the print coat
off the person's details.
We need to make sure that we're fitting the values for contact,
number,
email,
address,
date of birth and everything else.
Now that we've done the client side stuff,
the interfere stuff.
To some extent,
what we're going to do is also get our hands dirty on.
Go into our fraud dot PHP,
which is where we're storing all of for database related functionality on.
Then I'm going to create a new function on.
I'm going to call it public function,
get attendee details,
and then this one is going to take a parameter called I D on just for so I like to group my
court.
I like to group all the cool that's related.
So we have inserted and these appear.
We have get attendees here,
so I'm just going to write this one here above the get specialties because I like to see
where all the related functions are.
Now that we have set up the skeleton for our function,
the court is going to look similar to the function above it.
Forget all attendees where we have a variable called SQL And in this variable we're putting
in the quarry where we say select star from attendee The stable name Where on then we need
to pass in that previous holder.
So we're going to say attendee,
underscore idea because that's a name of Porpora.
Murky column is equal to that place holder i d And then having done that,
we're going to prepare the statement.
So next we prepare it.
So I'm going to say STM t is equal to on we call on our object.
This points to DB points to our narrow Onda.
We call our function prepare and passed in our SQL statements.
And then after that,
what we need to do is bind the perms.
So we call back or object s TMT,
and then we call the function in that one that's called Bind,
Haram.
So I hope you guys see that this is really just a pattern.
If you've done it before,
which we did already,
then it's pretty much the same pattern every time you need to do it afterwards.
So we're passing in over i d placeholder on binding it to the value that came in through
our parameter on then after all that is said and done,
we want to store the results.
Someone to say result is equal toe ste mt on.
Then we execute.
So just to review this,
we have our SQL statement,
which is getting all the columns.
So select star from use.
Get me all the columns from this table where the attendee id's equal to some place holder,
which we would have kind of defined before.
No on.
We should have an idea store those placeholders are for And then after it prepares that
statement,
we bind this placeholder toe.
Water of value came in in the parameter.
Now the expectation is that the value coming in from this parameter should much the i d for
the column that we wish the view.
So if it is that we wish the View Column five or roll number five or the record with idee
five.
When I click view,
we expect that it should invoke this phone shown call passing five,
then running this select worry to get the attendee record with i D five on,
then return it toe result on then the end result is that we need to return whatever comes
bark in this object so know that we have the SQL and the the heavy lifting pH B part out of
the way.
The next thing we want to do is go back to view records on make sure that our view link
actually sends over that idea.
So what we're about to do is use what we call a query strip.
No,
we would have looked at Cory Strings earlier when we looked at how they get function works
for forms.
Remember that they get from show would have passed a whole bunch of things in the URL on
those variables,
we could have gotten the values associated with those durables using over get super
variable.
So the thing is,
you can actually create your own query string.
So in this situation,
we have HR equals view dot PHP.
What I'm going to do is create a question by using the question mark on,
then creating a variable names.
Someone's going to call it I d on.
Then I'm going to say this I d needs to be equal toe some value.
So the value that it needs to be equal to is whatever the attendee idea is for the rule
that is being printed.
Remember that this is a per roll for parole cord.
All right,
so for each room that's it generates.
Or Prince Old this attendee i d column on the first in the last name and the name.
I wanted to give me an anchor tag that is going to navigate to the view page on passing the
query string variable i d.
With the value that is,
Well,
phone here in attendee i d So I need to make sure that in after the i d equals portion,
the next thing that comes out of that should have the same value as what would have been
printed in the number column for that rule.
So I can actually just t this speech feed block that is echoing that value.
Copy it and place it right here inside off the quotation marks.
So once again,
this is going to generate a link on the HF is going to be viewed dot PHP on we're creating
our own query string.
So I'm seeing question Mark and then some very big names so you could call this anything
you want.
If you'll feel more comfortable seeing attendee underscore,
I d there.
That's fine.
Just to remember that that is the variable name that you need to look for on the next side
.
So I'm calling it I d on that.
I'm saying that it should be equal to and that I'm just going to put in my PHP block
because I can stick those almost anywhere on,
then echo the value that is actually coming back for that role.
So the same value that is printed out still left,
that is visible to the user.
If you decide to keep it there,
you could take it off.
It doesn't really matter.
But whatever that value is should be upended.
Toe the u R L Once this on Qatar is generated.
All right,
so let's test that theory.
I'm went to me.
Those changes See those changes Refresh the speech on then if you hover over the button and
he looked at the bottom left corner off my screen,
you see local host sensitive in slash view that Ph B ID equals two.
So notice that this one says to this number is,
too.
If I go down to the one that says nine noticed that I d number in the URL is not If that is
too small for you to see,
I just inspect elements that we can see it more clearly and you see view dot PHP ideas.
Nine.
So it is very relative on pearl.
It's going to have a different value.
So this one is five on so on and so forth are so know that we have the idea being passed
into the view dot PHP page we no need toe retrofit our view dot PHP page Teoh,
run the query on,
then get all the values that are coming back on by extension print them now back on our
view page,
Understand?
To modify this comments,
understand?
To see,
get a 10 d by idea.
All right,
so that we know exactly what we're doing on.
Then I'm going to start off by saying if he is set.
So this is a nice function that allows us to check if they,
if some variable exists on,
is usually used when moving between pages and use really use when you have Cory strings.
We would have looked at it when we were doing our success,
not PHP,
where we said if he set submits then do something right.
So it's the same concept.
So in this case,
I want to check if the get variable has some subscript by the name off i d.
So if he set get I d meaning.
If this subscript exists in this variable,
right,
that's what that's a saying.
Then we want to take some form of action else.
We want to take another course of action.
So if it's there,
then we want to proceed to print all the persons details.
So if not,
I want to just read that,
if not,
scenario first.
Sorry.
I'm just going to echo so I can just equal to the screen.
Uh,
possibly an each one Tug that as an error.
Someone to see,
please check details on.
Try again.
So we're giving them an error message that Okay,
maybe you got here by accident.
So that's that's what the person should get if they just typed in view dot PHP because the
i d.
Doesn't exist.
So it's wrong.
All right,
on.
I'm going to put in the text.
Sorry.
The cross for danger.
Text someone to single course for that part.
So bigger and text to see you got here incorrectly.
Now,
if the I d value does exist than what we want to do is call on our crowd.
Object,
Andi.
Well,
firstly,
we need a variable.
So we're going to see the results.
Are are something Is he going to be equal?
Toe crowed and they were going to call our get attendee Another school back here and make
sure directing the function properly says,
get attendee details Understand?
To copy this.
Get attendee details on.
I'm going to put in the get superhero by personally,
I delight in it.
I like putting the variables.
Sorry,
the super very providers in another room.
So I'm going to declare a variable I d on.
Then I'm going to meet this.
I'd be equal to whatever value is coming over.
So it's going to be equal to a lot of our values in the super variable here on then.
I'm going to use that variable in my form.
Sean calls.
I think this looks a bit neater.
You would work either way,
but this is just me opining on horror.
Think it should look so now that we've done all of that and we have results,
what happens that results is no or Ari or are variable,
that is,
honoree,
that has all of the values.
First name,
last name and specialty.
So I took the court from the previous page where we were posting that data.
No,
I'm actually going to replace that post with the result variable.
So this was a Skopje NPS score.
You don't have to write the post than right result.
Instead,
I'm just telling you that no,
instead,
off using the post were using results because results is hosing the data coming from the
database.
It's understand to go ahead and replaced all the posts here.
But we're still echoing on.
We're still interacting with each value viol.
It's it's subscript name.
So now that we've done all of this,
we're going to go back to our page and look on.
That is what we get on.
That is what we should be getting because I left out a step.
So just work with me.
No,
we have crowd that PHP on ditz in that there's an error online 46.
If I go back to the crowd file and look at Lyon 46 I did indeed miss a step so what I
should have said here was result.
So we had result is equal to execute on.
If we did that,
that's all we started off with.
Then we would have gotten nothing coming back.
All right,
So what we need to do is actually take this result equals take Take that part off the court
coat on.
Then what we're going to do is create another line in Lyon actually lying 46 and the result
is equal to on.
We're going to see ste empty.
Andi,
call the phone son called fits.
All right,
so I'm going to explain it.
So what would have happened is that all of this would have executed or quarry on.
That's all fine and dandy.
But then because you only want back one role really and truly were taking just this one
record where the ID's equals that we have to use this function called Fitch,
which is actually just going to give us that one thing.
So that's that's one thing,
toe.
Remember,
when it is,
you're using video.
So when you're looking at multiple than just doing execute,
that's perfectly fine.
But otherwise you want to see Fitch and you put Fetch,
you fetch the record in tow one variable,
and you return that variable on,
then in the view part.
Well,
whatever is fetched and put in tow on returned by.
This function is put into this variable,
and then we use that variable throat.
So when I go back and I refresh,
I'm now seeing at least some data about some other Ariz.
And these arrows are because they're saying that we have an undefined index in the view.
Because while I'm talking about specialty and talking about you,
b and so on,
remember that these are database.
So this is the old post cold where we're looking at the feels from the farm coming over?
No,
I'm using the same court in the view part,
but for the view page,
we need to use the data BCE related names.
Seconal.
Just go back to PHP my admin and refresh myself.
And that is date off birth and email address and contact number on.
Then we have the specialty.
I d situation here.
So let me just go ahead and change all the birth,
the managers and contact number.
All right,
So I change those old so results bit off birth email address contacts number on.
Then I refreshed my page and I see here that at least those are fixed.
But I still have that error on specialty.
So recall that with specialty because it's in another table.
What we're really going to see when we select star from that 10 detail is just the i d.
So we need to do an inner join on our quarry that were passing up.
So I'm just going to kind off copy.
This was done in the above one for all attendees.
That is the same quarry.
But the inner join always has to come before the were are so in SQL we always do inner joy
anywhere is almost always the last thing to come up.
So let me just go through the change.
I mean,
select star from attendee on,
We give attendee and a list.
I'm calling it a and then we see inner join specialties with an alias off s on both tables
in that speciality idea and it's not special.
The idea is that this is what the two tables have in common.
That's a nice way to look up when how to energy in tables.
What do the two have in common?
What they have in common is especially I d column on.
Then we say we're or attendee I d is equal to or boned our place older.
So then I go back to view on then I know that well,
when the whole inner join is done,
the value is really going to be called the name on Just to recap.
If we go to the specialty stable,
we see name.
So I'm listening to quickly do that SQL statement here so that we can see exactly what
happens so that we're not too confused.
So I'm just going to copy out this SQL statement on in PHP My admin.
I just went to the SQL tub.
I went to replace all that was in there with our SQL statement except on which actually
give this a value and I'm going to give it the value five on.
Then when I say go,
we see the full record coming back.
So that is what that rule looks like.
We see attendee i d the first name last name date of birth which ran those zeros.
Email address contacts,
number the specialty i d in the attendees table.
The special The idea in the specialty table on the name being name off the specialty.
So if we wanted name to be printed,
then we have to make reference to name in our courts are going back to the view pH I'm
making reference the results with subscript name.
So after doing all of those changes,
I can no well,
back to my view record.
And if I refresh once more than I see the correct value being printed right there No,
I just noticed that I was slight misalignment with my foot or my footers appearing inside
of this card.
That should happen.
More than likely I don't have on there we go.
So in my view page,
I copied it over only.
So if you're experiencing that,
you can speak.
Sit with me on.
Do we just close this Dave properly on?
Then I re first on the order is restored.
So let's just review all that we did.
We modified our attendees age or view it in the speech where we're printing out every
single attendee that has registered to date on.
We put on off on action.
But that allows us to view the details on that specific attendee.
This view button is really just on Uncle Todd.
Firstly,
on DIT is linking to our view dot PHP page on it is passing over a Cory string in the URL
called I D.
So when we click it,
the expectation is that we're looking to see if I d came over in this query string on If it
did,
we get the value run on SQL statements that looks similar to this and bring back the
resulting data on then print it back to the screen.
No,
we did put some chord in to see if the I d value was not in your A something else should
happen.
What we did was to see Prince the error soul I'm going to remove.
So if we look in the euro seaview dot PHP and the query string,
if I remove just the query string and leave you dot PHP and print,
then we see our error message coming.
Please check details and dragging on all of this.
Arum Well,
everything that it's trying to buy into it can't buy into.
So actually,
as a last act,
am goingto flipper on this if statement,
so I'm going to see if not is set.
Meaning if he said if this doesn't exist,
right.
So when you put not too,
you're doing the negative.
So if not you said he set that,
then I want to a cool these statements.
All right,
so I'm checking for the negative First else.
Meaning otherwise that it is there.
So if not is that means those if the get i d super if they get idea in the Super Variable
does not exist.
Then we echo this error message else.
We want to do all of this,
and I'm going to actually move this disclosing breeze.
And I'm going to end this whole if block after this devious printed someone to go after
this def on,
then I'm going to start a PHP block,
and I want to say PHP on close.
The brace on then close appears to be block.
Know what this is going to do is actually just say,
if the get i d doesn't exist,
just prints the era message.
Otherwise,
if it exists,
which is what we're hoping for,
meaning it's in the URL.
Then we get the value and we get the results,
Andi,
In the same if block because it hasn't closed it all off.
This HTML will be rendered on everything.
Up until this closing,
um,
breeze will be done.
So if you look,
I'm clicking this Bridgestone here and it's gonna highlighting the breeze up here so these
braces are connected.
So when I refresh this speech,
if the girl isn't is empty,
then we're just going to see the era message.
We're not going to see any other nasty messages about anything not existing are are missing
or anything like that on.
Then If I put about the query string so I say ideas five,
then we get back.
Oh,
are red card now?
I encourage you to player on with the speed you can customize.
You make it into a profile page,
whatever it is,
put some more issues elements in their Andi.
If you had more details to the database and I have,
then you would have off more full details Page and I do.
But essentially the concept for me is the same.
You pass in.
The idea is a query string.
You get the value,
your in your query and then you print out your results,
I will be found.
This Listen valuable.
Andi,
these just remember to have fun as you modify this and customize it's to your liking.