Hey,
guys,
In this video,
we will be looking at how we can go about adding functionality toe edit our records.
The context for why you would want to edit your records are well up deity in terms off the
acronym fraud,
which would be the U for update,
would be that maybe in current information was was entered initially,
and you need to make a change.
So,
for instance,
with the Mary record,
if we view the details,
we see that the date of birth is 00000 It's a bunch of zeros on that might be wrong.
All things might be incorrect.
Maybe her name was built in currently,
or the email address.
What?
The fact is,
you want to be ableto update the report from this screen.
So in this tutorial will actually be going ahead on adding an edit button on building off
that functionality.
Now back in our view record speech,
we would have already added off column that said actions and this actions column is really
just going to be holding all off the buttons that would effect actions.
So the first action that we would have worked on is the view auction,
which we have a line here by this anchor talk.
But what I'm going to do is expand this problem.
I'm just into Indian so we can see where the problem starts and stops.
So inside of this TD,
I'm actually just going to add another button or another anchor tug.
So just duplicated this land with control de on.
Then the second anchor tag is going toe.
Have edit dot PHP instead on then what we want to do.
We want to retain the father.
We're printing all this idea as part off the link because it will be necessary on we are
going to change the class from BT and Primary made.
My anybody would be art and someone to say warning for an orange button on then that takes
that is printed should see it.
But if I go back to my page and refresh,
then I should see my new button here,
which says that it on the link should look very similar to the viewing where we're seeing.
And it's not Ph.
B.
And in the query string,
I d equals two.
Next,
we need to do the edit screen.
So back in visual studio code,
Understand?
To create a new file on this one is going to be called reddit dot PHP.
Now,
usually the edit screen looks just like the create screen,
and we can policy here for a little context.
Our registration form has all of the fields that need to be filled votes.
I'm just going to go back to a registration form which,
remember,
is our home and we see first name,
last name and all of the values that need to be filled out on.
Then we submit.
Essentially,
these are all off the values that we also need to be able to update it just in case.
So really and truly,
our edit page is going to look just like our registration page.
Maybe Beiring the title.
So having created the edit page,
I'm actually just going to use my code real quickly,
and I'm going to go to my index page,
which is very destruction form.
I went to copy all off this on then,
with the pieced it in the Edit start PHP page.
We need a few changes.
Of course,
I'm going to change this one toe edit record for that's name off this speed,
that's a title on.
I'm also going to change that each one tug,
tow,
edit record.
So if I navigates toe reddit dot PHP and I can just go to the girl and type in PHP,
then I will see that it looks identical.
But the Texans any record the title is different,
and we can change that text in the submit button to see if something like Submit changes or
save changes on maybe use a different button color on now.
Use success to get a green button.
All right,
so that's what are edited Page looks like.
Oh,
are edit page looks like,
So I'll go back to my list on the expectation once again is that once I click this edit
button,
it will navigate over on.
We see that is already party in the chorus to know what we need to do is actually execute a
quarry that gets the record with the I d.
Being passed in on.
Actually,
Prince,
these values here for us to see now back in or cold,
we need to get busy with some PHP.
Firstly,
we're getting results on this results,
variably storing the old put off this function.
I'm just going to remove this coming from the speech.
All right,
so we're getting the old put off our crowed get specialties and remember that we need this
function and the results to populate over drop down list for all the specialties that are
in the specialty table.
However,
what we also need is the add some function call that is going to call the function that is
going to return the one rule that we're looking for.
So if the I devalue off to is passed in to this page,
then we need to bring about the record with i d volatile on actually prints the values toe
first name,
last name,
etcetera,
text boxes so that they actually appear inside off our form for editing.
So we already have a function that we would have defined instead of for crowed file on.
We call it,
get attendee details,
so we call to get attendee details on what we're really doing is just getting the I d.
On getting back.
Whatever details there were about that attending this function can actually see the Syrian
purpose.
So the same function that got us the details can actually serve the same purpose for 18
because we really need are the data points from this query.
So back in or edit page I'm just going to create another variable.
And I'm going to call this one attendee.
So that's attendee.
Meaning this is the data for the attendee on.
We're going to call our objects crowd on.
We're calling the function Get attendee details on then Well,
I skipped a step So before we can you do that?
Because remember,
we need to actually pass in this parameter apartments are there.
So what we need to do firstly is check if they were flipping over during the bad first
sourcing If is not,
he's set gets on We're looking for the parameter i d.
So once again this is seeing if they get super global Variable does does not have a
subscript i d.
So that's what this is in.
Does that exist?
If not,
then I want to print some error message seeing arrow So I get back to this end Make it
fancy later on aren't else What do you want to do?
Is go ahead and gets the attendee data All right,
so firstly we always use a variable first,
so I d is equal to And then we're getting that value from the get super global called idea
with the subscript idea.
So we get that value,
we store it in this and then we're passing that as the parameter.
So once again,
we get the value from the get parameter.
We start in this variable,
and then we passes variable into our function.
Now,
what we also want to ensure is that we only see the form if if we actually got an idea in
the parameter.
So I have the if statement to see echo on arrow.
If the perimeter doesn't exist else,
we want to actually start a process on then printed forms.
I'm just going to move this closing breeze from this speech B block on,
then create another Ph B block at the end off the form to close that statement.
So that means all of what happens in between If the else statement on this closing briefs,
it will only ever happen if the gets parameter,
the I d parameter actually exists in or forestry.
So we closed the brace.
Close our PH B block on,
understand the fix my indentation,
Andi,
so we can proceed.
So let's recap.
Once again,
we have our I devalue coming in from our parameter and then were running the choir to get
all the choir details on.
Then we want to store that result inside off a variable called attended.
So what we want to do to actually get these values printing out inside off the creditable
reasons of four form would be to echo inside off the value attributes.
So inside off inputs for first name,
I'm going to put value is equal to on.
Then inside off this,
I'm going to create a PHP block open and close on.
This speech we blocked will have a core overact,
Indy variable.
And remember that this variability is acting more like an area.
So we need to specify which part of this area it is that we intend to print on since we're
in the first name textbooks.
Then we intend to print the value coming back for first name.
And then once we do that,
we see if we just refresh our page,
we see that Mary will appear because it was Mary with I d to if I put nine and refresh,
then that Clarence again.
And then we see the new value for record night so we can just go ahead and do that for each
off the text boxes at the very least,
second of Skopje,
the Value section.
And then I'm going to piece that inside off last name.
And then instead of her friends in first name,
I'm winter reference last name so relative to whatever the textbooks was far.
Do you want a reference that corresponding value?
All right,
So I proceeded to do that for all off the text boxes on Defy Refresh.
Then this is what it should look like.
You should see the corresponding vice if you get any era.
Just make sure you check your spelling on the series in the CART column names.
And if you see a Miss much ensure that your friends in the car it's column inside of the
cart.
Creditable reason.
No,
What I didn't do was bind the era off expertise from the drop down list to the one that's
coming back from,
or Query.
So do recall that our quarry and I just jump over to Ph.
FEMA admin.
If I around that quarry I will be seeing specialty I d three.
So let me enemy edit this.
We're looking at record nine here,
so I'm just going to see where it's equal to.
Nine.
There will go quickly on then.
This one is bringing back.
Well,
it's database.
I want to find an attendee who wasn't a database at MIT and that would be attending number
six.
All right,
so let me just reload this page with I devalue being six.
So you know,
what is that?
The database admin did not change everything else she in just relative to the new record
except the drop down list when the drop down list,
in fact should change,
since the specialty ideas really six and Web administrators should be what is selected in
the drop down list.
So we have to make sure that the selected value for the drop down list looks like it's it's
clearly representing the cart one.
So we're going to have to get a bit creative with our select section on.
What we're going to do is for each option we're going to have to do on each statement
subject if they specialty I d being printed by this wild group is equal toe the specialty.
I d being returned inside of this attendee.
Hurry!
So to get this process started,
I'm just going to bring some lions here,
someone to echo in the next line and then put the option below that so that we can see
exactly what is happening.
Clearly so inside of this stop option tug.
Where?
Open adoption target.
I'm printing that.
The value should be specialty.
I d I'm going toe after that quotation marks,
start another PHP block and then inside the speech B block,
I'm going to have an if statement.
So this is just highlighting the dynamic nature off beach.
Your whole dynamic your Web applications can be when you can insert Ph.
B at will for whatever purpose.
So in this case,
we're going to see if on our statement is going toe ask The question is our specialty I d
some person to copy this if this value that is being returned from this very subscript on
this iteration off the while loop,
if it is at any point equal to and I'm just going to reuse that.
But I'm checking for attendee this time.
So if at any point,
The value that is being returned for this particular iteration off the while loop on it is
being stored in our specialty,
I d if at any point it is the same value that is being brought back by this attendee record
and if that is the case,
then we want to echo.
And we're just echo the text selected because in regular HTML,
if we wanted on option to be selected would have just literally typed the word selected
right here inside that option.
So that option would be the selected option.
So what we're doing is seeing that if this condition is met So this highlighted your
statement.
If this condition is met,
then we want to just echo the word selected on were still inside off the option tout.
So it would be echoed in a fashion light.
This So having written that chord,
I'm no one to go back to the issue of pitch on when we refresh for idee equal six.
We see that know the selected value is Web administrator.
So if I go back to view attendees on Die click edit on Mary its database at me if I go
again Andi believe it waas the last one or the second to last one.
Right now we click edit,
then we see Web administrator being brought back.
So that means our if statement is actually looking to see what specialty I d came back with
this person's record on.
Then it is seeing if it is the same value that is being printed because it's printing four
values right now.
If the idea that is brought about much is which of ideas being printed just made that one
the selected one.
So it appears here.
Now that's half off the battle done.
If you want this fire,
that's excellent.
Now the objective off this would be to make sure that when we change the beats like,
for instance,
we will have the date here being 0000 where they establish that that's not really what it
should look like.
So maybe this person should be born in 1973 on October 2nd.
Part on.
Obviously,
the first name doesn't mean what,
since ah changes the Archibald on this last name would be Thomas On the email address would
be a Thomas at gmail dot coms off course.
All of this is fictional,
but I want to show you what the update is really four.
So at the end,
off making all these changes on putting in a more realistic contact number,
I expect that when I click save changes that when the next speech is going to show me that
all of the changes that I just need were meat and registered inside my detail bees.
So,
in evaluating our next steps,
we need to remember that what we're doing is using a form on the form uses a method on also
some action.
So success,
not PHP is the action,
meaning once we click submit,
it will try to never get the success that BHP No,
we already established that success,
not Ph.
B is the auction page for our registration,
meaning after they fill the form the first time,
Then they should go to the space.
So what we want is a different action page for our edits.
Some just want to create a new file,
and I'm going to call it Edit Post,
not PHP.
On the purpose off edit Post that Ph.
B is just to receive the data from our post actions.
So that means on the edit page on when to set the action to be edit Post Doc.
Ph.
B on what happens is that we're going to send over all of the data that was entered on this
form imposed on edit courses going toe except this data on Then run the database operation
toe,
insert the records or obey the records in the database after it does them that operation.
We don't need it to display anything.
So we're just going to redirect toe.
Our index was not in expiate our viewer record speech.
So I did some comments so that we have a guide as to what is being done at each point.
No,
firstly,
getting the values from the post operation.
I'm actually just interview school that their authority.
So I'm just going to jump over to the success that PHP peach on then really just wins a
copy All off this cord listed here.
So the thing is,
we're using the same form on,
but we didn't change any off the names off the elements on this forms all of the names,
the email on the car,
on the phone for reds.
That's the name right all of those things remain the same.
So really and truly the same Holstein cool that we used for success on the registry.
Some pH we can use that same post scored for the action on the edit post off course.
I still want you to appreciate the fact that if you make any changes to the forms may be
left out one of the fields or your added feels or whatever it is you did,
you need to be ableto understand and appreciate the differences on the nuances between the
two,
but for nowhere,
reusing most of the cord so we don't have to make many adjustments.
Another very,
very,
very important thing we always should have on our edit page is the i D.
So the actual I devalue that we're getting here,
we need it because we need to actually send it over in the post action.
Because when we're doing that update query,
we need to update where I d is equal to whatever record it is that we were anything.
So the easiest way to get that I d.
And you don't necessarily want to display this.
I devalue to your users because on the form putting I random six.
This is I devalue six.
So you want to put a random value six somewhere here.
They really don't need to know the I d off this person.
But what you can do is use a hidden field.
And that's a very common practice of user hidden.
Sorry.
We use our form elements off type equals shouldn't on.
Then we can set the value just the same way we set the value for every other ones.
I'm just inte Bara.
This scored from the first name block set the value and echoing attendee I d instead.
All right,
so we have the value off or hidden inputs.
Sorry,
I don't know why attempt for him input.
Apologies for that.
So we have input type is hidden on.
We have the value being attend the I d on.
We can disclose that so that when we post our data,
we actually are maintaining the value going across the pages.
So a lot of the times people leave Oh,
the or neglect the father.
You need the i d.
In the speech and then went to get to the posting.
It's not working and they don't know why.
So I'm just going toe either.
So that's one of those minor adjustments that I'm going to make than that's the difference
.
One of the differences between the create on the edits because upon creation there's no I d
but orbit prior to creation or other.
There's no I d.
But upon anything and I d would have existed already.
Some just want opposed this.
Oh,
when setting up the elements,
we need a name,
so name is equal to number soon to call it i d on dso when I'm posting ideas equal to post
super super variable post subscript Heidi.
So I modified my statement.
All of this needs stopping inside the statement If if if the post exists,
then we want to extract the values,
call the crowd and redirect else.
We will print that arrow court so I'll get back to printing the era Court on.
On that note,
I hope you've realized I'm neglecting to print early each time because they neglected to
printed here and I'm neglecting to printed here.
The fact is,
we can probably make an include speech,
right?
That just has,
you know,
a standard arrow message that we know,
print across the speeches,
so we,
instead of printing echo each one every time we have an includes or with the sprint echo
each one and then we just included right here in the else statement.
So at the end of this activity,
I'll actually do that on opiates.
All the side are the pages in our website with that coat.
Now we need to call our crowd phone,
son,
but there is no code phone son for anything.
So,
like all the times you have to go over the crowd on,
then I'm going to create a new function.
So those are to get someone to create a function right on unease,
Insert attendee,
and I'm going to call us on public function it it attendee on.
Then we're taking a parameter i d.
And then inside this function,
what we really want to do is just right on update SQL statement with the placeholders on
the value.
So I did say only I d.
But I d is not the one a perimeter.
We actually need all of those values coming over from the form which would be F name l
Neiman,
all the other ones.
So I'm just going to copy these parameters.
Since they're the same parameters,
the same set of values on I'm going to include them in the perimeter,
listing with ideas.
So have I.
D and all the other fields that were expecting inside off our table on then because at the
end of the day,
we really don't know which one is going to be edited.
I don't know which field the person is going to change in the edit field,
but once I click save changes,
I need to be prepared to make sure that any changes made across anyone off these will be
captured Onda stored.
So I'm just interested An updated statement.
So we always start off with an SQL variable and then we have the update statement and then
I will be realized.
I know also that SQL is not really case sensitive.
So sometimes I'm writing in uppercase.
Sometimes in lower case on off course.
Once you're in adults,
you can always go over till your PHP My admin,
Onda,
Look at what it would look like as an upbeat statements.
They opened this up.
You goto attendee can go over two sq well on then you can click on the orbit on,
then the update statement.
Can they?
Can I give you that template?
Well,
you can copy this on Pace it inside off the SQL variable off course,
replacing each value sex son with the placeholders.
And so I'm actually going to just do that.
So I copied that on inside of the SQL statement on pasting it earned on.
Then each place I have that value in square brackets.
I have the place older.
So the thing is,
though,
this can be misleading because we're not updating.
We're not setting a new value for idee.
So according to this update statement,
it's asking to set attendee I d to be equal to some value.
We don't need that because we're not setting that in the value i d.
What we need I d for is the wear clothes or we say,
where one We need to say we're colon ideas.
I'm using a placeholder there,
but the update statements is basically the word update than the table to be updated on.
Then we say set.
I know these are not single courts,
so I would have used them in a previous but video where I copied it from from PHP my admin
.
And then you would have seen them.
Those are not single courts.
Those are what you call apostrophes.
All right,
So the foster is basically are a little secret talking inside off my sq als SQL syntax.
But they don't conflict with double courts are single courts arts.
I just want to everybody to be clear on that.
So we up the it the table,
and we set column is equal toe value on value.
Here would be cool on f name Andi for as many columns as you're sitting values.
You have them distance.
So we're doing it for first name.
We're also doing for last name on each one is separated by a comma the date off birth.
I'm going to set this place order to be deal be on email address sitting the placeholder to
be email and I do the others so quickly.
Once again albeit table set column equals placeholder Kama Kama column equals placeholder
fires militants as you have columns and values are place holders to be set on.
Then we end it all with a where clause were something So we want to see where a 10 d
underscore idea is equal toe the placeholder I d.
So this is no going toe.
Find this record with that idea water I devalue.
It is our passing in,
which is the I devalue that would have been hidden in our form on post it over on,
then passed into our phone shown on Then it's going to find that record on then update all
of these columns with the values that would have been coming across in our parameters.
So now that we have that SQL statement written,
we need to do the binding.
Some just go into this.
Copy this because it's pretty much a CNN cord.
All right,
on,
I'm just into pieces here and then,
just like we did before,
over creates our insert attend.
You did a track that so I'm actually just going to do a try catch because it's good.
Practise the trans action on,
then catch the exception in case there was an error.
So I'm just going to rattle that try catch block on,
went to try to do all of this,
and if it was successful,
I returned True.
That speaks my invitation on.
Then I'm just going to literally Skopje all of this because pretty much were just repeating
on a number of things on DWI.
Want consistency with whole.
We look for errors and deal with them should they arise.
So you'll see that your edit on your inserts operations tend to look very similar in terms
off the fields that are being captured and the options being done.
The only difference is maybe the SQL statement on the father.
You have to account for the i D.
Passing between fields or between screens when editing.
So know that I have my crowd function defined.
I can go back to edit post on actually call it.
So I left out of step.
I did not make reference to my connection file.
So in every other page that we made some database call I had required my devi con I did not
do that here.
No,
I didn't need that Ah header file because,
well,
this speech is not really supposed to be displayed.
It's like edit and it's an intermediary.
So it just does its operation and then read ARATS so you won't really see the edit.
Poor spit.
So that's why I'm not making this much of an effort to actually have the aesthetics there.
So I'm going to make reference to my d.
B.
Khan because obviously I'm going to be doing some database operation.
And I remember that once this file is in view off the page,
we can just call on our crude objects.
I'll see results equals on.
I went to call on micro object on inside crowed.
I'm going to call my function,
which is edit attendees and understand the copy all of this Andi piece here.
So because I'm using the seam variable names as a permitted you see,
it's easier at the Skopje and paste,
so you don't have to.
But I'm just showing that made this this probably five minute operation off,
typing out all of this into 30 seconds.
All right,
so once we do all of that,
we can then see if on going toe check if result,
remember resulted store in the old put off.
This function on dysfunction is returning to a force I'm seeing if results meaning if this
is true,
so this could be rewritten as if true.
All right.
But I'm just in to see if results then we want to redirects to the index speech or redirect
code looks something like this where we say Header on,
then hitters,
a function that takes a link So the link is index dot PHP.
So if this was successful and we want to redirect to the list else,
we can probably print on Eros,
so echo error on,
we will revisit setting up these generic error per insult printouts on standardizing them.
All right,
so once this is in place,
the expectation,
once again is that once you click,
submit on this speech are,
well,
our button sensitive changes.
But it's still a summit,
but it's in the same.
Is going toe posed over all of the data that may or may not have been modified but had been
present as values inside off each of these controls on.
Then it's going to hit this page as the action where we connect or databases get all of the
values and then go ahead.
Andi,
call our operation,
which is going to run the opiates statement in our database on if that was successful than
we just redirect to the home screen.
Otherwise,
we print some form off arrow message So let's try that.
So I'm going to go back to the form and I'm going to re fresh and I'm going to me.
These changes some putting Archibald Thomas on the other details,
changing his date of birth toe 1965.
Whatever it is.
So I'm just making some changes to make sure that I can see them reflected after I click
save changes.
All right,
so because they're using email as the data type here or the input type,
it's telling me that my email address is wrong.
So I had a common set of a full stop.
Let's try that again.
Are we're getting a PDO error here and it's seeing inviolate perimeter number.
Oh,
I know why I've boned everything but the ideas.
So because I copied the buying programs from the top part,
I didn't remember that I have this additional parameters that needs to be boned.
So I'm just going to duplicate that line and change this the I d and bind it to the idea
coming in on.
Then I'm going to just try that again.
So if I f i V will say that the form re submission will take place meaning it sent up to
reports the data,
and then we continue.
I understand to go back.
Andi,
I'm going to look at my cord.
Ah,
the location.
So sorry that we should have said location,
comma,
colon index dot PHP my butt.
So the header tix the text with the word location Colon on,
then the page.
All right,
So everything was successfully able to dinner you,
Derek.
So let's try that again.
Someone to resubmit this form on git redirected to the index speech.
So I had forgotten that the index pages actually the registration,
please.
That's not what we want.
We want to goto view records that PHP and we see here that the required was indeed edited
so we can be confident in the fact that our edits court works.
But I'm just going to change that.
Read,
Eric,
because I wanted to go to view records dot PHP.
All right,
so once of me that change the fact teams mirror pop ing's,
I'm going to edit Mary Poppins.
And she is really a software developer,
not a db Admin on guy.
Say that change.
Then when it comes back,
it redirects toe our view records and I see Mary Poppins with her new specialty.
So that is so.
You go about adding any functionality to your PHP application.