Hey,
guys,
In this video,
we will be looking at how we go about adding functionality to delete records from or
application.
The objective of this video is to ensure that we have a button beside or view and edit
buttons that say is delete on unclean.
It will proceed to remove whatever rule was selected.
Now the first teams I'm going to make is,
in my view,
records that PHP pH where I'm going to add another link,
which will go under my actions column some distant to duplicate my edit button on.
Then I'm going to change the text to see defeat on.
I'm also going to change it to Bt and Danger,
which give me a red button,
all right,
and then for my eight year,
if I will have delete that PHP.
So after making that change and refreshing I know,
see,
that's have a red button on recall that all of them are printing,
wrote the attendee i d.
For the rule based on the iteration off that while loop so each off them would have the
same idea value At the end of the difference is that they're navigating the different pages
.
Now we can see that we have.
Ah,
spam record here.
Record number nine.
This person.
This This is not a person as far as this information would indicate.
So this is my target role for this operation.
By the end off this video,
I should be able to press the lead and remove this rule from the records.
So since our Borden is targeting a page called the Lead PH.
B,
we do what we have learned to Dubai.
No,
and go ahead and create a new file call.
It deletes dot GHB on then in this file where we'll just copy the most essential things
which are really just the require for the Devi connection.
So really and truly there two ways to handle delete.
Some people actually do a prompt.
Some people navigate to a page showing all the details of the record,
their bloated little and ask you once again if you're sure you want to delete on some
people want to click delete then that they just run the command and refers to a page on the
deletion would have happened.
So we're entity.
That third option,
Andi,
I challenge you to put in functionality that would actually have delete Load a page that
shows all the details off the record about to be deleted on,
then have another button that once it's clicked,
it will actually action that delete Kinton.
How you get that donors to use a form because on submit,
you could go to a post page where you actually get the i d and proceed to delete.
But for no,
I am just going to proceed with the simple my third,
where I'm just going to have my PHP block.
Andi,
I'm going to require my connection to the detail BCE on.
Then I'm going to check if the get variable exists.
So if it doesn't exist to remember,
we check for the negative.
So that's actually according pattern.
We check for the negative first,
take some action on the action on quantity or moment mixed up my braces here.
Action.
I'm going to take if the i d.
Sorry if I d doesn't exist in the get parameter.
I'm just going to print error on Remember that this is going to be part of our final
touches where we're going to create some construct that is more consistent with the error
message that we don't have to keep on typing it over and over.
But otherwise,
if it does exist,
so that's else,
then I'm going to get that idea value and place it inside off a variable called I D.
Then what would be nice is to call the crowd function that will remove the record on,
then redirect to our list.
So I did some comments here so that as it puts in the cool,
we know exactly what's happening.
But the point is that when it hits this speech,
we just want to get the i d.
Run the court to delete it from the database and then redirect wants that operation was
successful.
So we need a function in our crowd up in our crowd class that handles deleting.
So we have insert,
we have edit on.
We have some gets so on.
Anything gets,
I'm going to put the delete,
so I'm just going to write up the public function.
Delete attendee on this function is taking a parameter called I d Onda.
We will be Skelly be doing very,
very similar things.
Once again,
you see that all the patterns kind of repeat themselves.
So we're declaring an SQL statement where we're going to see elite from on the table.
Name is attendee were attendee underscore idea is equal toe are place holder i d After we
write up or SQL statements,
you know that we need to prepare its understand to copy that copy and paste,
so don't have to re type on that.
I'm going to do the same with the binding off the I d parameter.
So most of those things we're doing our in over get attend the details,
Right?
So these stop three or these two in addition toe the execute on,
then we can return our results.
All right,
so well,
we didn't wouldn't be clear results,
So we really don't even need toe return anything at that point,
we'll could just return True.
So once again,
it's always a good idea to have our try catch.
So I haven't been very consistent with that,
but in our finishing touches,
we will definitely tighten up on those things.
But for no I'll just say try on do all of what we just outlined the snow on.
Then once that is done,
we return true on.
Then I'm just going to borrow the catch freeze from another function on.
We want to tear up the same operation to catch any zero that may occur in between while
we're turning falls.
So then I can see back on my delete page that we want to call or should objects?
Well,
we want to assign the results.
The all come off our form shown call toe the delete attendee function in our fraud objects
.
So I pass in the i d parameter as we got it from the gets on.
Then we see if result Then we redirect So redirection is hitter Onda we open and close
parentheses And then inside of this report a text which has location,
colon and view records that PHP because you want to redirect toe our list stuff reports.
So if if results are successful,
then we want to do that else.
We want a print,
that generic aero message.
All right,
so let us try this operation.
The point once again is that once it hits the speech,
it's going to connect to the database.
Get the well check if there is a value coming over in the quarry string.
If not,
then he's going to print an error on.
Then we're going to see if there is a value.
We want that value.
Then you want to call the delete function on.
Then we want to redirect The view requires once that's done so it would almost be
transparent to the user is complete.
And the page should refresh toe after this operation happens rather quickly so we can just
go back over here.
I would just look with three fresh and they were targeting this rule.
So let's see,
before court works,
we pressed.
Delete Andi,
I have a spelling error here,
so I'm going to go back into my crowed function on and I have attendee with one t in my SQL
statement.
So that was the error.
Someone to try again on notice.
All the your looks.
It is the lead.
PHP i d is nine,
but I'm going to go back and I'm going to start over some clicking.
Delete on.
There we go.
It's removed.
So it didn't prompt it didn't show the details off the record once again,
That's that The simplest,
quickest way to delete a record on off course deletes are not reversible.
So if we wanted a least putting a prompt because sometimes users me miss click.
They think they're clicking at it and treat delete.
But we don't want to just remove it upon an accidental click.
We can actually just use JavaScript and insert a quick prompt into the peace without when
it's clicked.
There is bare prompt,
a default prompt so,
you know,
confirmed the quick action.
So back in our court,
back in the view records page,
I'm going to edit the uncle Time for the delete on.
I'm going to add a JavaScript function called on Click on the value that will be assigned
to this will be returned and then confirm.
So this is,
ah,
javascript function called confirm where you actually pass in some text here.
That would be like a promise they be something like,
Are you sure you want to delete this record?
All right,
so the expectation is that when they click this link,
they're going to be prompted through some beef,
all of javascript.
So this is almost built into the browser,
writes Amy,
look different from Brazil,
bro's.
Or but the fact is that on click,
it will show the confirmation prompt.
Are you sure you want to delete this record on.
It won't go any further until the difficulty.
If they could cancer,
then the operation is The quick operation is canceled so it would not navigate to the next
page.
All right,
so we can test that.
I'm going to refresh after making that change on.
Then I'm going toe accidentally.
Click the lead beside Mary Poppins on Look at that,
it's asking.
Are you sure you want to delete this?
Reports.
I can always cancel on cancer the operation.
And if I click okey,
then Miri's required would be deleted.
And ironically,
deleting records is pretty much the easiest and quickest thing you can do on recovering
from.
It is probably the most tedious and time consuming procedure,
but that's it for this video on That is So you go about completing your crowed operations.
We did creates.
We did read.
We did updates on this one is delete