Hey,
guys,
welcome to this video where we will be applying some finishing touches to our application
meeting will be cleaning up some cold,
cleaning up some off the visual elements and just look handsome little key concepts that
could help us be a bit more modular.
So I'll get straight into it.
And the first time thing that we want to do is to add more,
try catches toe our code.
We would have had some functions where we didn't put in all the track catches.
So I'm just going to go into my crowd,
file my crowd class and you notice that some functions tried and caught exception.
Others didn't.
And so what I'm going to do is just wrap each one inside off a track at someone to start
with,
get a Cindy's and remember that all we need is a word.
Try on then,
Considering that we already have tries and catches all over the place,
we're really just trying to catch the same type of exception,
which is the PDO exception.
Second,
just really write the word try and copy and peace to catch on just weeks my Indian t shun
on.
I want to do it for this one function.
So I challenge you to go ahead and do it for the other cell,
completely others off screen,
and then we can reconvene.
All right,
so that I would have completed it.
Andi,
every function has that try catch?
No,
some of them me returned.
Mixed results.
Meaning you're returning results as well.
Results from a query on,
then in the catch here,
returning fall.
So the thing is,
because PSV soul kiss Orwell type insensitive,
rather or loosely typed,
it doesn't really matter.
So if I checked if results,
that would actually return a true on,
def,
I'm returning false than it would literally return force.
They can still kind of use that The fact that it's not returning the same data type,
right?
Um,
but on the other side,
you can actually check the variable.
So if the variable has data and it's not returning anything negative,
then it would be a true regardless off the content on,
Well,
the function would return falls either way.
Now that's the first and possibly the easiest thing that we have to do.
The next thing that I want us to look at is setting up success and aero messages so we can
go to our success that Ph b ah file.
And here we would see where we were echoing a success message versus a failure message.
No,
What I would want to do is actually just kind of have a generic arrow message on the
generic success,
Mrs.
So without being toe specific.
Because then based on the page,
you're going to have to re type this every time.
On we saw that we can off ran into a little blood,
our got lease,
and we just started echoing arrow instead off echoing actual error messages.
So what I'm going to do is create and includes while filing the includes folders are click
on the ankles folder on.
I'm going to call this one error that PHP on.
I'm also just going to create another file.
Same time success,
well,
success message.
So let me qualify it as message because I already have a file called Success,
Not Petri.
So success message that PHP on.
I'm just going to right click on error on Rename it to error message dot PHP.
Now these two will just have on each dinner block where I'm just printing.
Well,
I'm actually going to go to Bootstrap.
And instead of using the H one tags by themselves,
I'm actually going to prints on alert.
So both sharp has alerts component on this is what they look like.
So I want our green alert whenever it's a success and,
ah,
red alert whenever it is on error.
So I can just copy their code and I look for the one that's a success.
So by no hope,
where are comfortable?
The fact that most things in bootstrap that are green are success.
The color The naming is pretty much consistent across all the controls.
But I'm just going to take this thief class.
Place it inside my success message that PHP file on.
I'm just going to reward this,
Andi,
if I want,
I can probably make it on each one,
but I'll just leave it a Leave it as default.
So success messages going to just give a generic success to say operation has been
completed.
Andi,
I'm going to see an error message.
I just use this one to danger.
So it's the same alert constructs just with danger.
Instead,
on the error message will say operation and confident error.
Please retry.
All right,
so you can put your own messages.
But the fact is you want some level of consistency instead off.
I mean,
if you want custom messages per screen,
that's fine.
That's totally fine.
I'm not saying it's wrong or bad.
I'm just modifying my own so that I don't have toe continues to be typing all these things
.
So what I'm going to do is when I would have printed an error,
actually,
just include the file that gives me that are a message.
So right here,
I'll just include Andi,
I would say includes which is a folder slash error message dot PHP.
All right,
So the expectation is that if I navigate to this speech and this is the edit page,
if I never get to this speech on,
there is no I d.
I would have printed an error.
But instead,
what I expect to see is the error message well,
coming up as an alert.
So let's test that theory.
So if I go to my page and I click on the edit,
then the expectations that we see the formed it,
it's Mary Poppins is record.
But then the Aramis.
It should come up if there is no I d parameter meaning somebody just went up here and type
in the URL to the edit page but did not put in the query string.
So when I do that and press enter,
then I see my ERA message coming up on This is what we would have embedded in our page
through our includes.
So what I'm going to do is go through each file that would have printed an error on where I
would have had an error message.
I'm going to replace it with my include.
So then off making these changes,
I would have made the change to edit edit post op,
Ph.
B View,
B even myself,
says speech,
where I had been printing error viewer record with No other one was skipped on delete.
All right,
so all of those pages would have been updated on in the same way that ended this for the
error.
I just do that for the success message file,
so I just go back to well,
wherever I would have had success and I would have had success being printed on this screen
where you have been registered.
So just replace this with success message on anywhere else.
You would have been printing a message to say something was successful.
You can go ahead and just include that file.
The next thing I want to do is to prevent people from actually navigating to this speech
without the presence off the choir strings.
So one way to do that would just be to say,
if there is no choir string.
If I d doesn't take this,
this redirect back toe some page that everybody would see.
So if they tried toe type in edit dot PHP by itself,
then it checks.
It sees.
There's no question,
and it just re navigates toe.
At least view records,
a PHP.
So an easy way to accomplish that would be to go to our page like Edit on did in this part
where well,
we just change Toto print the error message.
But I could easily just say header on inside of that.
We just put the location colon on,
save you.
Records start PHP are So what this would do is if there is a navigation attempts to this
page,
which is our edit page on the header.
Well,
the under idea is not in the query stream.
Then it just redirects.
All right,
So we could actually do that for,
you know,
for the edits.
Who could do that for a post Anywhere that you're concerned that people should not end up
without having the cart informations under that for they header Andi Well,
for delete.
So somebody tries to go to the lead page to the lead page without putting in the query
string.
Then we will just redirect.
All right,
So those modifications have been easy enough.
Another one that I would want to do is put some space between my felt navigation bar and
the content that comes immediately after.
So you'd have seen with the error message that it was actually seemingly attached to the
nut bar,
which I don't want,
So I want a little space there,
So I'm just going to go to my header file on.
What I'll do is at the bottom off the nav bar.
I'll just put a PR chug right.
Remember that this is rendering on a per page and it's rendering the top part off the issue
Mill contents or enough bar on.
Then I wanted to also render a space all the time.
So what's going to happen is that when I navigate between these pages,
we know CS space,
so the table is no longer seemingly attached to enough bar.
I would have said that good website design would have all speak every page reachable from
every other peach.
So in other words,
if I go to the details speed,
I should be either be able to go back to the listing page or to any other page on DSO.
What I'm going to do is add buttons here that would actually allow me toe head back to the
list or edit this record or delete this record from this view.
So I'm going to go to view dot PHP on.
Then we will modify over html toe,
reflect what we require.
So in my view,
Ph.
B page at the end off that card,
I wanted three buns to be printed,
so I'm I'm just going to bar these three buttons here from view records on what they are.
Well,
one is back to least one is any 23 leads.
I'm just going to borrow them on me.
The changes accordingly Go back to view,
piece them underneath.
Or maybe I can.
I'll place them under the dif so we have the card and then we have the three buttons asking
you which direction you wish to go.
So the 1st 1 I'm going to see this one should be back to list.
And I'm going to meet that one BT and in four.
So it's a light blue like a teal.
All right,
so this one would say about two list,
which means that the H ref should be view records,
not Ph.
B on viewer cars does not require any form off idee query string on so we can remove all of
that from the eight riff on.
We just have the button to go back to list.
Next we have the edit button on de everything else can hear me in the same except I'm using
the variable results in this speech toe represent any off those values.
So I'm going to just change this are to result so without changing the Alami explains.
So I'm printing on Uncle Tug on the trip is reddit dot PHP on I'm passing in the quarry
stream,
just like I would have done from the view record speech passing a query string on the value
for the i.
D.
Variably inside of that query string is going to be that 10 d I d.
Now the reason I changed it from our t the word result is I copied the button.
From here on in the viewer records file are is the designated variable.
However,
in our view file,
we see that we're using the variable results everywhere we're referencing a value.
So I'm just going to make sure that I'm echoing results with the subscript attendee I d
into that query string area on.
Then I'm going to repeat this feat for the delete,
which is right below on some echoing result.
Attendee i e no.
When I refreshed my page,
I see my three buttons And if I hover,
I see that this one goes back to viewer cars.
This one goes to edit on this one from's for a delete.
Andi,
I'm just going to add a br tag in between.
So one br tag after the div so that it's not,
you know,
attached.
All right,
so there we go.
So these are action buttons so if we click view,
we can always go back to the list.
I click view again.
I can go straight to the edit If I go back to the list and notice are edit.
Page doesn't have a button to go back to the list.
It only has something to save changes we may not want to see.
It changes all the time.
Probably just clicked it to see if it worked.
I don't know.
I want to go back to the list so you can feel free to add that back to list button.
So the edit record just the same.
Andi,
if we go back to view and I pressed the lead that is going to promise me and ask me if I'm
sure if I click OK,
then we would have removed Mary from over database.
The last thing I want to look at is form validation.
No,
we didn't put much,
if any validation in tow.
Our form,
the validation that would probably be there is based on the input types that we would have
selected.
So if I go to my index speech,
which is my registration form page,
I well,
I did not enforce which values would be required.
So I can actually using HTML five just right in.
The attribute required on what this will do is actually force the browser to see that that
field is required.
So if I click submit,
it will prompt me to say,
please follow this field because it is required so I can go further.
If it is not,
Phil does.
All right.
So that's the easiest way to enforce some form of validation and informs.
I'm just going to be the first name on the last name required Onda.
Well,
this one is kind of implied because of value is always going to be present instead of for
select but at least an email address.
So we need at least your first name.
Your last name of specialty and any military you don't need your phone number on.
Those are the required fields for this form.
So if I had put required in all of these places Onda save and then refresh when I tried to
submit,
Okay,
first name is required.
I tried to submit again.
No,
it was on to second the last name on.
Then I tried to submit again and email address is also required on I'm just going to go
ahead and fill in this person's data.
Andi,
meet them a part of a system just to make sure that we didn't break anything in our cord to
submit on.
There it is.
So operation has been completed on mere waters has been added.
Now there is another level off form validation,
which is services.
What we're doing here is client side validation.
But there is also service at validation where we can actually scrutinize the values a bit
more.
Andi,
conduct all operations right there would have done what you call a self posting.
Meaning instead,
off posting toe a different page,
we would have posted to the same page that the forms information is being submitted from on
.
Then we would have carried out all off operations in that same page.
However,
I won't go through that for this exercise,
at least,
right?
No.
You should be proficient enough to build a form on build out.
All of the crowd capability is required for this form on.
You should be able to well,
do it end to end and incorporated with bootstrap.
I hope you've had a fantastic journey open to this point.
If you have any difficulties,
feel free to let me know on that the next video we will look at adding all of for work.
So I get hoper posit Torrey.