Hey,
guys,
Welcome back.
Let me start all this video by congratulating you for making it this far.
By this time,
you should have already completed your THB forms application as well as all of the crowd
operations that are required for supporting it on in this video,
we will be uploading all of for hard work to get up.
So just to review,
we would have built this entire application and we know want to put it into a remote
repository.
No.
While I'm doing this at pretty much the end off all of for work,
it is actually advisable that you do this as early as possible because as we were working
on it before,
machine crash would have only had one copy of it and that would have been on our machine.
There's also no tangible way to track all of the changes that we've made the files on.
Any changes that may be our colleagues or co workers would have also made so get being a
source control mechanism is an excellent way to track all the changes and keep ah spear
copy off your project at all times and especially with the availability off remote
repositories such as Get tub.
We can have multiple copies off our project as we work towards the end.
Now,
in this video,
we're going to use ghetto for desktop so you can just find that on by No,
I'm assuming that you would have already installed and configured that in Get up,
Best up.
I'm going to goto file on.
I'm going to add local repository.
Now I'm going to navigate to the project that we have So our project is in season Ishi
docks are wherever you installed some but in HD docks is where you should have had your
attendance projects or Justin to select that folder on.
Then it's going to warn us that there is no repository in this folder.
Would you like to create one?
And we will just take that Created on dso We get this screen where we can just go ahead and
click create.
Once that operation is done,
our get repository is created locally and then we'll be asked if we want to publish it.
Toe,
get up So you can just go ahead and click Publish repository.
We maintain the name and I'm with the antique The part that keeps the school private
because I wanted public.
So everybody who has followed these lessons can have access to the court.
And then we publish Repository.
Now I go to get hope Web on drug in,
and I will see my repository listed right here for access so I can just click it on.
Having done that,
I will see all off my files nicely put down on this remote storage space while we're here,
though,
I'll just use the time to add a quick description to the project so that when you come
across that you know exactly what it is.
All right?
So we just added our I decided a description real quickly.
Andi,
I think that's it.
That's it for adding or project to get up to.
Remember that from here we can track all changes.
So I didn't make a change,
and the change I didn't make was to add the button for a buck to list toe our edit pitch.
So I'm going to meet that change,
right?
No,
on what I'm going to do is duplicate this button on with the TECO Bt and block because I
don't want it to stretch right across But then this one I'm going to have back to list to
the left on going to the save changes to the right.
And this one is going to be BT and default.
Onda.
Well,
well,
actually this should all be an uncle Tug.
So there he just changes quickly.
All right,
so change the button.
Completely toe on Ankara tug On day the truth will be back toe the listing speed riches,
viewer cars or PHP on.
I'm using the class beating and Bt and default.
So it retains the look off a button.
Onda,
What I'm going to do is save all of this on then refresh the page and that's what it's
going to look like.
Someone toe have my edit page on then my link to go back on day the other one to see if
changes are so.
I just made this change.
What's going to happen?
No is that it is tracking these changes on once again.
This is the benefit off using ghetto.
It is tracking these changes.
So when I bring up,
get up.
This up is showing me what was changed and what it was changed to Andi.
I can commit this the master Master being that final branch that you know it's production
ready.
Andi,
I can no push the origin.
No,
I'm going to have a different tutorial on how to manage gets using branches on promoting
court.
But in this situation,
since we're the only ones building this,
we can always push the master.
You know,
that's not the best idea at all times on DSO having done that,
commit on push toe origin are pushed to get up.
If I go back to my repository and I refresh then looking at the edit page will show that I
just didn't edit 32 seconds ago.
All right,
so once again this is a great collaborative to where everybody can see what changes are
being made along the way.
Having done all of this,
the next step is to publish our websites toe Hiroko So stick our own as this chapter is
coming to a close