Hey,
guys,
In this video,
we're going to be looking at deploying our registration application on Hiroko and also
setting up remote my SQL database.
Before I go any further,
I think it's worth stating that my machine actually crashed.
So the machine that was being used for all of the tea tourism pointed at this point
actually died sometime this week on.
So I had to recover another machine and also all of the court that was being done in the
previous tutorials.
Onda,
thankfully get up,
rescued me.
So I was able to go on,
get up,
flew in the database.
Sorry,
the files back to my machine on provisional new machine with all of the court and all of
the tools that were being used.
And so this is the new machine that were on.
So if there was never a compelling reason for you to use source control than let that guide
the advantages to using it now in this video,
we're going to be on heroic.
Also,
if you don't have a ah heh Rogo account,
you can always check my earlier video setting up a free heroic or cones and then that
should get you up to speed with getting a heroic account,
and then you can follow the rest of the steps as we go along.
For those of you who already have a heroic or cones,
this would be a return trip to your Haruko.
And you would notice here that there some zed signs,
which indicates sleeping beside my previously reported deployed ups and you probably have
them also.
So the thing is,
when an up because they're under free plan and up tends to go to sleep,
Perico puts them to sleep because where they're free,
Andi,
they weren't necessarily in use.
So if I attempts toe navigate to my PHP,
that's trying Primer Dash Trev up.
It's going to take a while to come up on.
That's because it was asleep.
So what had to happen is the dino itself had toe reawaken.
And when I refreshed the PG notice that it's no a week,
all right,
so that's going to happen if you realize that you're trying to never get to your up and it
takes a while,
it's because because there's limited to no traffic coming to that application off the
Dino's get kind of deep revision until they're requested on.
Then they would awaken and serve the content.
All right,
So I'm just letting you guys know that that is why you would see those visits anyhow.
Or mission today is to deploy our new applications.
I go to new create a new up on,
then we're calling this one attendance cash register.
Remember,
you don't have to have the kind of the same name as being here is an example.
Already have attendance that's register as an up on Hiroko.
So they're telling me I can't do this one.
Someone to call this one.
PHP dash attendance.
I bet nobody has that name out there.
There we go.
So you can always copy this name and just put something else in there to make it unique to
your situation on.
Then once you're done with that,
you can go ahead and click.
Create up.
No.
With our up created,
we can go ahead and scroll down to deployment method where we can just click connect to get
up.
I'm already logged in to get up in my brother.
So it's knows it's me.
If not,
then you might need to put in your get tub credentials.
And then once that is done and you're connected,
you can just go ahead and search for the report.
And I believe that my report was called Tendons are search on.
There we go and then I connect and then once I connect,
I know have the option to automatically deploy or manually deploy someone to choose manual
deployment.
Andi,
I think I explained the reasons for that.
In a previous video on DSO,
I go ahead and click Deploy Branch and then give it a few moments while it runs its magic
on.
Once that is done,
we will see something coming up deployed to Hiroko with a green tick and then I can go
ahead and click view,
which were then load my page.
But then look at this.
If you do or call our index speed should have a form Andi or View attendee should have a
table off.
All the persons would have filled out that farm.
Neither is loading on.
The reason for that is if you go back to our chord in visual studio.
If you look at our index page,
we see that it is calling Khan.
And if we look inside of far can file Khan is actually trying to connect to our local host
database on our machine.
Well,
this I p really means local toe water,
A machine it's on.
So that means if I put it on your machine and you I didn't have this database than it would
have been an error.
So likewise,
there is no database,
local toe Hiroko that hoses any off the connection details being aligned here.
So all we need to do is set up a database that heroic who can see across the Internet and
can quell these problems so heroic Oh,
actually allows you to add a database.
Ah,
it'll be a server off sorts.
You can go to configure Adan's on Look for clear db my SQL The don't sides of clear db my
SQL is that even though it say's free here,
you have to provide your credit card information on then actually,
provisioning the database isn't really free.
The database hosting itself is not free,
so we're not going to take that route.
But instead we're going to look for an alternative.
Andi,
I actually found a website recently on it is re morte,
my SQL dot com on day actually offer free my ask your postings.
Ofcourse,
free comes with limitations.
But for the purpose of getting through this video and showing you how you deploy a fully
functional,
data driven application to the Internet and specifically Hiroko,
then we will use it if we're doing it.
To see Pinelli would be a much easier ordeal.
But because off Hiroko and the cost constraints,
I just want to keep this video as cost free and effective as possible off course.
If you're going to production,
then you could proceed with clearly be keep everything more homogeneous on more stable by
just having everything inside.
Heroic cool.
So in remote my school dot com,
we can go ahead and click Log in.
Which off course will ask you to create an account or I'll again say can go ahead and
fellow this basic later and create an account.
Another tool you're probably going toe want is my SQL were pinch,
which is it's a desktop application that allows it to manage remote my SQL databases and
the relevance off my using the word remote is that peach FEMA admin manages the local
databases that are local to your zump installation.
When you have workbench,
he can connect to that one.
Or it can connect one across the room or across the Internet on considering that we're
actually going to be setting up this room or to my SQL that which is across the Internet
and we need a tool that can actually connect across the Internet.
And so my SQL weren't Binge is a wonderful tool for that.
So you can go ahead and go full of this girl,
which is in the resource is for this video.
And you can just navigate their and click download and have that installed on your machine
.
No,
I've been created our remote,
my SQL database account.
What we want to do is go over to databases in the stash sport view on then.
Well,
we can't just let me get through all these advertisements and go ahead and click.
Create new database.
They go,
dear.
They would then show some information showing us boats are created.
Database the user name the database user name the database name.
Sorry.
The password.
The server on the port.
So with that information,
we can go over to our workbench,
and I'm sure you've installed it by the time you get here and then we can click this
possible.
But now I have two cards here because I had work pins installed before.
But if you didn't,
then you probably end up with one card and that's fine.
But then we want to create another one.
So we went to go to the plus sign on.
Then we can call this one remote SQL.
So that's just a connection name so that when we see it,
we know what it is for.
On then the host name would be what they call the server.
So you see remote my SQL love calm,
which we can just copy from the website and paste inside off workbench.
Off course,
we don't want any species to come up,
so we can just remove any space is at a space before my are on.
Then we go back and the user name is this block off text someone to copy that.
Go over on going to pay us that in the user name on then our password is that block of text
.
So I'm just going to go ahead and repeat that procedure.
But for pastor graft is a store involved.
Give it the password.
Click OK on,
then the final.
Actually the database name,
Which is that name we copy that is it defaults,
Kira,
we can test the connection.
And having done that when we see this messaging successfully made my school connection that
we know that we're actually connecting toe remorse.
My SQL Not because it's called remorse,
my SQL,
but remote means it's not on your machine.
It's not local to you.
So it's on the internet and we're connecting to it.
Successful star click OK,
and then click.
Okey on then I see my remote s your connection here can double ticket on.
Then this will grant me access to their servers.
No one you're connected.
Then you'll see the database that left and you see an empty square window on.
Then you may see this Mitchell message tables could not be fetched.
I'm not entirely sure why,
but if you re first you see that it's remains connected and they try to fit on.
The state can be fish.
But that's fine.
That's off little consequence.
What we're about to do,
you know what we want to do is migrate our database.
So we had our database in our development machine.
I know.
We need to put it over into the production machine.
So what we need to do is find our database and we know that we built it using my sorry PHP
my admin.
So we go ahead and go to local speech.
FEMA admin on.
Then you will see a 10.
Ddb,
remember?
Had to rebuild my database so I won't have the data that you guys have.
So when I migrate,
man,
it's still going to be an empty database.
You guys are going to have your data,
but it's to see him set off steps.
Next we after clicking the DB we goto export.
This was then launch of it a window asking us a bunch of stuff about templates.
We don't have to go through all of that.
We can just go ahead and click former.
So under the four months you see sq A so we can leave that because I want to do is export
our tables and their contents on sq a file so I can go ahead and click goal,
and then that will actually give me on sq a file which I can open up in any editor.
So I went to my downloads folder by default.
I'm just going to right click it and open it up in no part prosperous because I don't want
to open it up in any heavy software.
So once it's in no part cluster second,
just copy its select all control.
See to copy on.
Then I go in tow workbench.
And in this antiquity window,
I pieced on.
Then once I've pasted,
I can actually no just click the execute,
which is this lightning bolts looking icon here in the toolbar on.
Then this will run a set off commands.
So,
like I said,
I have no data in mind.
So I Your your query,
your query file that is generated is going to look a bit differently from mine.
But essentially,
the net effect should be the same.
And then once that has run and you only see green ticks below in that that what I have a
few pero files here airlines here.
But that's fine.
Those are related to the fact that the tables could not be finished.
But once I refresh the schema or to this right and left inside.
Then I see my two tables lifts that.
So even though it says tables could not be finished,
I still get my tables.
And if you had contents than you would have gotten contents.
So that's step one.
Know that we have replicated or data beast or more to my SQL server.
What we want to do is go back to our visual studio cord.
Andi,
open up.
Our con dot PHP file on actually changed all these values relative to this new database.
So what I'm going to do is take a copy off all of this.
Since that has all of the connection data,
I'm going to comment out the development parts and I'm going to put the noticed in
development connection on.
Then I'm going to put in another comment down here and see remote it abi's connection.
All right,
so that means whenever I'm ready to work on my local machine,
I can just un comment this and come in this part on vice versus in this situation because
we want toe work remotely,
want to deploy remotely.
I'm going toe change out these values so host would be and we can just go back to remote.
My Eskil dot com on reuse these values.
So server is the same as host,
so it's remote.
My ask UAL not this I p address anymore,
but remote.
My school dot com database would be this block off text no longer attendance TB.
The user name would be that block off text andare pastors.
You know what?
We have a password this time.
First,
we didn't have a password,
and I said that I would be fine for development,
But for security purposes,
they always give us a password when we're going remote.
Now,
another cool thing about this is that no,
that I set up our Moz database on.
I have it here on my local development.
You know,
in my local government file,
I can actually collaborate even easy more easily with my colleagues because the database is
no longer isolated to my machine.
So I did see the remote database would be on a machine that is not your computer.
Because if all of your working on this project,
then it will be hired for everybody to be able to pitch in for database changes.
If the database is only on your computer However,
if it is at a remote or a central place that everybody has equal opportunity to connect to
,
then it's easier for everybody toe work with the database.
So by deploying your database toe some remote server,
whether it's across the Internet or maybe it's on a network where you are at your school or
your work,
please,
if it's on a network machine there.
The fact is that everybody can use these connection details and have visibility on this
same database,
the same data that everybody's seeing on Dwork even more seamlessly.
Now,
just to drive for my point,
I'm actually going to navigate my local host applications.
I'm just going to go over to my brother,
go to Loca host on Goto.
It is attendance.
And then when this index fire Lord's properly realised that the connections are working,
everything is in order.
You notice I don't have any air of expertise because my data bases empty.
All right,
But remember that we had set up this drop down list to actually read from the database,
so I need to go back into my database and refill this table with the different areas off
expertise that are available for selection on then would see them.
But the point is nowhere connecting to our database.
If I view attendees,
there's nothing there.
But that's because once again,
my data bases empty.
If you did this and you will never you migrated all of your data and all of the objects,
then you're going to be having an entirely different experience from me on Do you will be
seeing all off your attendees,
so I'm quickly going to quickly just put in all of the specialties.
So where bench allows me to just click on the table on day?
You know,
this icon that launches a select query from the database on,
Then they give me an editor.
So I'm going to put in Web administrator on the database administrator on I.
I'm sorry.
I'm not remembering the other ones,
So I'm just going to put networking engineer Andi.
I believe the other one was other.
I know that I've entered all of those values.
I can just go ahead and click.
Apply to the lower right corner on.
That would actually generate an insert into statement per value,
which I can click apply on that gets executed on all of these are no in my specialty stable
.
So when I go back to my form and I refresh and it connects to this database,
then you'll see that all of what I just put in,
including the new one networking engineer all off them are no being pulled.
So it is successfully connecting from my local host toe the remote server that we just set
up.
And so the expectation is that once I deploy this to Hiroko,
he will be looking at the same data beast that I just set up in my local development.
So we're going to go ahead and redeploy someone to go to get hub on.
I'm going to push the changes and hear all the changes get Toby showing Arsala machines
that we just made in our con file.
So I'm going to come into master,
and I'm going to see added remote my SQL connection details on.
Then I'm going to commit that to master on,
then push.
And once that push has been deemed successful,
I can go back to my up in Hiroko Goto overview.
No,
Sorry.
Deploy my bad on,
then go ahead and deploy branch once that branches deployed successfully.
Then I will click view on.
The expectation is that our farm lords Onda we can see that a query is being done
successfully and I'm going to put in the first attendee.
So this is my actual up here on the Internet.
So this would have been Reno presented to the user for the first registrants.
So I'm going to register first for my I T conference on my deeds off birth is actually the
28th but then the year is wrong.
Well,
we leave the year on then I am a Web administrator,
more or less.
My email address is indeed that on my contact number is not fully accurate.
But we work with that,
and then I click Summit on.
Then we're seeing that the operation has been completed and those are my details.
If I go to view attendees and we remember that we did a select Scurry to get back these
details so it's reading directly from idea to based.
And if I go back to work,
Ben's just to verify if I look in their 10 de table on die,
click this icon here that will launch all of data in there on the slate quarry.
Then I see that my application is really talking to my remote database Somewhere in the
Internet on that is all you would go about deploying an application to our more database
and to Hiroko No.
Once again,
it is ideal in ah real production situation that we keep everything inside off.
Hiroko.
It's easier to maintain is easy to manage on.
It's easier toe.
Well,
everything disconnects better.
But then we see here that we're hosting in Herro co hosting our coding heroic about hosting
our database on remote.
My SQL dot com on this concept could have been applied basically with any remote hosting
agents,
So everything doesn't have to be one place.
The database can be one place and the court another place,
but we know how to connect them.
Once we have the cart,
connection details are so I I'm challenging you.
Just repeat these steps,
deploy our application on If you run into any difficulty along the way,
feel free to let me know,
and I'll be glad to help.
Thanks for watching