you guys in this video,
we're going to start modifying our applications such that unauthorized users won't be able
to see certain parts off for website.
Now,
the scenario is that this registration form for conferences,
public facing everybody should be able to come on a register on move along.
However,
nobody should be able to view attendees and meet modification store databases at will.
So what we want to do is kind off put in mechanisms such that you have to get authenticated
to make sure that you're authorized to see the speech.
Andi,
do any further modifications to the data now back in our code?
Um,
we'll just start our modifications with our con files.
So I'm going to switch over to my development database,
um,
distant comment about the remote database connections and on comments,
the local database connections that I'm creating a new file inside of my DB folder on I'm
calling its user dot PHP and then use it up each.
Be no has on start up with a Ph.
B block on.
It has a class called user.
So class user on,
then we're just going to go over to crow dot PHP and borrow the first bit off court,
which is where it initially initialized a private variable called DB and then use the
constructor to give it the values.
So this is generic.
This needs to be done regardless so that we can keep the same object or into dynamic across
all our files on.
Did I just borrowed that?
Put it there on the next mission will be to implement some functions.
So the first function I'm going to put in is public function.
Insert user.
All right,
so inserts user.
Well,
that's function one.
I haven't defined the user table yet,
so I'm not going to proceed with that just yet.
But I want another phone shown.
That's well,
maybe get user.
Alright,
some just swear framing of this class for no on.
We'll just leave it at that.
So I don't want to insert use.
I want to get user at some point,
but what we also need to do is actually define or user table.
So I'm going over to PHP my at mean taking my attendance db and creating beauty with
quality users.
Andi,
I only want three columns you can put in more if you want what my three columns are really
going to be i d which is going to be my auto implementing primary key.
Andi,
I need using him on the password,
and these two will be var char and I'll give them a size off 50.
All right,
Once I've defined those that can just go ahead and click save create my my new table on
then No,
I know I need using human passwords.
So whatever columns you put in,
I'm sure you put in more,
but at the very least,
you should have using him and password.
Or maybe use email address on password,
but you need at least these two have ah,
sensible user till our so know that I need I know what columns I need.
I can better define my functions.
So I'm going back over to my phone,
shines and insert a user.
I can expect that I'm going to get the user name on the password off the user to be
inserted.
So I just put those in use any imposter word.
Those are my two parameters on,
then to into an insert.
I can go over to crowd.
Now we can borrow the same logic that was used to insert our attendees understand to take
this entire block off court on.
Then we're going to make some slight adjustments relative toe our new context.
First change I'm going to make is to the court so we can retain the verbal name SQL.
But then the quarry should be inserted into users,
since that's our new table name and inside off or user class.
So inserting to users on the columns that were inserting into our user name on the password
and remember ideas also implementing so we don't need to provide a value for i.
D.
I don't have all of these.
Maybe you do,
so you can tweak it accordingly.
But I don't so remove them.
All right on then,
values on the values are the parameters that go into the values are using human passwords.
I'm writin the colon and putting back the same using human password on.
Then I'm going to remove all off the extra parameters to be boned on.
Just make sure that I retrofit all of this school to be used.
The name on the password.
All right,
so that's so you can reuse Cool that you've already we already did quite a bit off,
quoting instead of crowd,
I know we need similar court instead of users unders.
We're using it,
Andi,
Essentially,
what we're doing is the same thing.
We're just inserting a user so this could be used when somebody's registering for your
website the same way that we accepted all of this data from somebody.
Sorry,
insert into attendee were accepted all of these theater points,
and already it was inserted into the table.
That's essentially the same thing you're doing with the user.
So any time you have a database interaction where they put something in the database,
let this be a general template as the whole it can be accomplished.
Next up,
we have get user,
and this first gets user.
I want to get the user with a using him on password that much,
whatever is being passed into our parameters.
So I want the user name and password to be passed into the apartment is,
and then I want to check if there's a user with that somewhere to go about two credit and
see if I have any a similar function to this and I do in the form of get attendee details
granted,
it was on the i D.
But the concept for me is the same.
Someone to copy this cord on the east.
It's here and then we just modify.
So we say Select star from on going to kind of clean out everything after the table said I
wouldn't have a confusion so it selects star from or users table were on then The first
part of the wear condition is the user name should be equal toe the parameter user name.
And so we want this use or whatever user it finds most have.
I use the name that much is whatever is coming into the parameter Onda password matching
whatever's coming into the past the department or so password column as a value that much
is the parameter password on then I already have the prepare command.
I have the buying power Rambo to spending for I D.
So I don't want to buy and for idea I wanted to bind for user name on the value should be
looking for is using you from the parameter on also for password on the values looking for
is from password on.
Then we executes then we fetch the results.
Meaning if a user is phone we fetched that user on.
Then we store it in results and will return the details about that user toe.
Whatever was calling that function.
Now,
having don't know that I'm going to introduce one more function and this one is going to be
get user by user name.
So I'm going to on the knees.
Get user Just introduce a new function.
Public function gets user by using here,
and I'm passing in the using in value Oh,
our parameter on.
Then,
inside this function,
I'm going to kind of do the same.
Try catch on.
This time I'm just fetching for user names.
I'm going toe just we write this scored quickly on then what we're doing in this one is
where selecting the number off users where the use any much is whatever is passed in the
parameter.
So let me say that again,
or select Parisienne Select won't star and I mean you could use a column name there,
but we just say star cones has no meaning.
Return A column called gnome,
with our value off the cones from the user stable,
were there is a user name.
That much is whatever use the name is coming in through our parameter.
And then,
of course,
everything else kind of looks just like that.
Get user function territory executes,
and then we fetch the results on store it.
Return it,
art.
So the purpose of this one,
this dysfunction,
is to make sure that we don't enter tool users of the same user name.
All right,
so this is really it could return a true or false.
What?
I'm just going to leave it as is on.
I'm going to kind of modify this this this insert user function toe always call this
function first on,
then,
based on what this function returns taken action.
So if he returns anything other than zero meaning zero would mean that there is no user by
this user name.
Then it should go ahead and insert if it returned something other than zero.
Meaning there is a user by that using here,
then we just don't do anything.
All right.
Someone to retrofit dysfunction on.
What I'm going to do is introduce a variable,
and I'm going to call it results on.
It's going to be equal toe this so because we're in the class after user,
this keyword so that we can access the sibling functions on When I say this arrow,
I'm going to call,
get user by user New.
All right,
So my intelligence self made a little bit there on then inside off this parameter and
passing in the same user name that the requests just came in to create the user record for
All right,
So what's went up in his once I call insert user passing and using him on password.
It's no going to meet this phone Sean Call,
which is supposed to check the database Azzawi designed on here to see if there's any user
with that user name and return home.
Many.
So then what we need to do is see if our results and result is what storing that won't
right,
You've result.
Onda results would represent the whole roll,
which has ah,
column called gnome.
All right,
remember,
we said we wanted to return some results set with a column called Gnome Worth of value Off
phoned.
So if if the value inside off results square bracket gnome is greater than zero,
which means that there is a user by that user knew.
Then what we can do is this return falls.
All right,
so we just returned falls if that user exists,
And essentially we don't want to do anything without falls,
because ofall serious,
but ah,
false here is bad.
So we just returned falls on.
Then we just see else we want to proceed with all of four beautiful,
wonderful court that is actually creating our users.
Just fix the farm.
Utting indentation there.
All right on then,
at the end off all of that.
One second.
What's going to happen is that we call in certain user passing to user name and password.
It's going to first meet that check to see.
Okay,
give me back home and users have this user name.
If there is at least one,
then we don't want to do anything.
Otherwise,
we want to proceed with the user creation.
Now,
one more modification I want to meet to this.
Dysfunction is the way it handles the password.
So the pastoral as it stands,
would be whatever pillion takes the user types into the form when they're logging and so
sure it's obscured from over eyes because you know that in HTML that's come up or some
simple scallop instead off words,
but then wanted passes over here.
It's playing text.
It's really just,
you know,
as you typed it when we start in the database,
we don't want anybody to be able to look into the database and just see Oh,
that's what the pastor it is because we didn't obscure it.
So we want to introduce over call encryption,
which will obscure the way the password looks in the database and make it fire more
difficult for somebody to sit down and figure out what to your password is.
So I'm going to above the else before I even get into the SQL statement,
I want to define a new verbal on.
I'm going to call its new on a square password on the new password will actually be like a
concatenation off password on what we call assault on.
And that's salt,
as in salt.
All right,
so assault is like a random block off text that we used to further up obscured what the
password might be.
So sometimes people define a static salt,
and then they use the static salt toe upend our pre penned every password.
So every time somebody typed in the password,
it's used as a qualifying agents.
Um,
I want to be a bit more dynamic someone up in the user name.
So this password text are so by using the user name toe up end to the password,
it's far more dynamic.
There is no static.
Salt is somewhat off at the salt,
which is used.
The name changes every time it's a different user on.
Then,
even if they use the same password to password should never look alike in the database
because the salt would have been different.
Because we're you know,
every user name,
at the very least should be different.
So having upended them on seeing new password,
the next thing I'm going to do is actually encrypted,
because right now it's still playing English.
It's just two words,
so I'm just going to say MD five,
and I'm wrapping this concatenation text inside off the parent disease on this is an
encryption function,
so it's probably the most prop popular.
PH be built in encryption function there,
quite a few.
This is very popular on It is probably the least secure,
since it's so popular,
But off course you try your best to me.
Whatever it is you're encrypting as dynamic and foolproof us possible.
So they're moving forward.
It's harder to crack.
So let's go through this again.
I'm defining a new variable called new password Andi,
I am hushing are combined text off the password on the user name some combining using him
and password in tow.
One continuous string on.
Then I'm using MD five toe hash it on.
Then I'm storing all of that inside off new password,
which then means instead of passing password as the Param,
I'm going to pass new underscore password.
So this is what will get stored in our database.
And this is what needs to be often today authenticated against each time going forward.
So then,
of this exercise,
I'm feeling pretty confident that we can insert a user.
We check and make sure that this user name doesn't exist before Andi We,
if it does,
does not exist.
Then we can go ahead and create a hash password and insert this new user with its brand new
secure password.
Now have a few more changes I'm going to make and I'm going to meet them to the conduct PHP
file where I'm actually going to Winston.
She it first requires understand,
require once users dot PHP.
So I'm just requiring that new DB file Andi in that same Vietnam went to declare a new
object off called user off type user.
And it's getting the C M PDO object that curdles getting,
which is why we re used the constructor bit off cord from crowd because we expected to be
here the same way that crowd behaved.
All right,
no conduct PHP is included on every page,
which means that if we need to access something for the user,
we can access it.
If we need something from crowd,
we can access it and every other objects that are class that we build that should interact
with the database will also could also be included right here in the conduct PHP and
utilized according to their different patterns and different ways.
Often in this,
this is just one of the paths off least resistance so that we can understand the foundation
off it.
Now the last teams are going to make is I'm going to call the function insert user,
which is inside off my user objects.
Right?
So we just declared the user objects on same time.
I'm going to put it to use,
and I'm going to call the insert user,
which takes a user name on I'm putting this as admin onda password off.
Well,
password.
So it's a very simple,
um user.
So our admin users admin imposter know the reason putting it right here inside the con file
is that the confines gets loaded on every peach.
When we go to the index speech and the Khan forgets loaded and it loads all of this,
it's no good to insert the admin user insert.
Users want to call the phone,
son,
get user by using him to make sure that there is no other user by that user name on then,
Well,
it's going to be our first user,
so there will be no other user by the user name admin,
so this will get executed.
You will go to another page and it reloads and it recalls dysfunction.
What will happen the second time when it passes in admin as user name on.
Then this reviews that there is.
I use a by that name.
It will just return falls and do nothing.
So this user should get created at least once.
Well,
should be there once.
Andi,
if he gets deleted once the website is Lord and he will get recreated so you could do it
one time and then commented Oh,
sorry.
Could leave it because we already quoted in a defensive manner.
So this user should never appear twice in our database.
All right,
so if I make all these changes and save and then go ahead and re lord or form man see whole
our changes fear,
it's understand to refresh this page.
And as you can see,
everything loaded,
nothing seems to have happened.
But if I go back to pitch me,
my admin Andi,
reload my user stable.
Then you'll see that we have a new user called admin on.
If you look at that pastor,
the looks,
nothing like the word password.
All right,
so that's our hushed password.
And if I never get to another page on,
come back to homes,
remember,
each time we never gets loading Khan and it's making that function call.
If I go back to my user stable,
I'm still only seeing one instance off admin.
If I delete admin.
Andi,
I just removed.
That means so there is no user by the name at me,
and I go to another page on day I go and refresh.
Add.
Minnery appears with a new I D.
Yes,
but the seam add mean using name and password.
All right,
so that exercise was just to show you how you could go about putting in at least one user
so that when we start locking down our pages,
we actually have a user to use toe log in.