Hey,
guys,
in this video,
we're going to add some Coto our pages to make sure that we check to see if there is an
active user session.
When somebody tries to navigate to that page,
if there is,
then we allow them to go to the page.
If not,
then we redirect them to log in screen.
Now,
on our website,
we have a few pages that would want this kind of restriction on on day all start with well
,
the view attendees.
So view records that PHP on Dover.
Add Andi delete and update pages.
I don't have any attendees here in my database right now,
so I'm just into when and quickly at one.
All right,
So I just created a new attendee on.
I just did that so that we could see the view at its end elite.
So once again,
none of these pages should be accessible as view records that PHP viewed our ph.
B reddit dot PHP and deletes that pH be The only way somebody should ever get to those
pages is if they are authenticated users on.
So we're going to make some minor chord changes to accomplish this on the first thing I'm
going to do is on includes.
So because it's the same kind of change that we're going to be doing across multiple pages
instead of rewriting this scored each time because the court is going to look pretty much
the same way.
I'm just going to create a new includes file on.
I'm going to call this one off on the score.
Check that PHP.
All right,
so in off check off course of this customer,
we start off with our PHP tags and inside this off check,
I'm just going to do Ah similar if statement what we did in our header dot PHP files so in
are headed out.
PHP file.
We kind of didn't your statement to see if there is a session that exists on this.
We'll see if the session for user idea exists or does not exist.
Then display the log in button.
Otherwise display the hello user name on Laval balls.
So,
in this situation,
I'm doing a pretty similar thing where I'm just going to see if on going to check for my
session.
Andi,
I can use user idea can use user name,
so I just use user I d since of the used last time.
So if Andi I should be seeing,
if not is set So if this session does not exist because you eventually we're checking to
see if it doesn't take this.
So I'm saying,
if not is set if that If whatever doesn't exist on the thing that we're looking for the
existence off is or a session with,
ah with a subscript called user i d if that does not exist meaning that this has not been
created at any point.
That means the person is not love Been so I'm going to say header and then set the Loki
your son to be log in dot PHP car.
So this is just doing a sympathy.
If the center statement,
if there is no active session with that user name with that session I d or its subscript
rather then we just want to relocate Teoh our log in page and know that I have this set up
in the off check.
I can no include its anywhere that I need this check done so I can start off with viewer
records.
Andi,
at the top off this speech after I require hitter on Require Didi Conn and remember that
header would have included decision starts or whatever amable to do have to do after
include hitter because header just bring up the whole quickly.
Includes header that PHP my header has the session starts.
Anything having to do with a session I have to do after my session start which is in my
session that PHP So I'm just going to see back in my view records file after I include the
header which would have included the the decision starts.
I'm just going to include with I wanting once our require someone to require underscore
once my off check on by off on the score Chick pH bees were just going to see.
Is there an active session?
Read Eric.
So that means after I include the header and all those wonderful things is just going to
check quickly and say,
Is the person who is navigating here authorized or right,
or is that personal well being?
If the person is logged in,
then while nothing happens if they are not meaning,
if this variable does not exist,
that session subscript does not exist,
don't want to relocate them to the log in dot PHP peach are on.
Then I can do this same check on pretty much every other pit,
so I can just sort of view that PHP and I'm going to go ahead and include it right there.
Success.
That's fine.
We're already deals with success we want to restrict and it some just including it onto the
header each time I want it on delete.
So nobody should try and believe a page or our record someone to do that first.
So remember,
the Leeds was very simple.
We didn't put it anywhere,
really.
Give it a header and a footer.
You just have that peers doing that operation and relocating.
But then the fact is,
nobody should be typing in bleat passing in an I d on.
They're not authorized to do that.
Right?
So we're putting in this off check before it even checks for the presence off the I D.
If you remember Hole,
that's core was written.
All right,
so we edited Delete way changed it It,
um Andi,
I believe Owen view and view reports,
so that should be enough.
Let us refresh the page.
Andi.
Okay.
I'm getting an error Oh,
my.
That was about Miss take off mine.
I'm sorry.
I did not try to includes slash.
All right.
So the errors that the final part was wrong.
So I just Go ahead,
Andi,
update all of the files that I would have put the bag.
According so have the includes slash off check and not just off check.
All right,
So once they do that,
then we should be able to refresh.
And then we see just by refreshing it went straight to the log in screen.
So let me believe from stretch.
So I'm I'm here on the public form And then and went attempts to click on view records.
The off check would have known that I am not loved Insiders redirected me So logging that
PHP If I type it in directly in the URL it's the same effect.
If I tried to go toe edit that PHP,
it's the same effect because off check is running on each of these speeches.
If I long in and I put in my admin user and the password,
then I will be redirected on.
Then the off check would know that I am loved in each times I tried to do something right
then,
if I love boats,
even Norman view records when I click Love Boat,
it's just going to redirect me to index on.
Then restrict me once again from getting to the pitch until I log in.
That's a nice,
quick and easy way to kind of shut down who can see what's on your website.
You can push the envelope a bit by maybe including rules on,
then in the same off check you Ken.
Well,
you probably wouldn't write that if you went into rules.
You probably wouldn't write all of that court here,
but in off check,
at least you're checking.
Is the person logged in on?
Then,
if they're logged in any kind of further logic to say,
OK,
watch role.
Are they in as a user on?
Then restrict them accordingly.
All right,
so that's a nice,
quick and easy way to kind off.
Restrict who gender what's on your website