Hey,
guys,
in this video will be setting up an email dispatch for our i T conference registration
system.
Now,
the context for an email dispatch is that when somebody feels all this form or they get is
a a success speech,
you just get a pay.
Justices Hey,
thank you for registering,
but they don't really have any tangible proof.
And the easiest way to give somebody tangible proof or filling out an electronic form would
be to send them an email confirming that they have completed action successfully.
And so in this video,
we're going to be configuring our attendance application.
Such a.
When somebody clicks submit,
they will load the success speech and also dispatch on email to whatever email address they
would have provided during the registration process.
Now,
when it comes to PHP,
there quite a few options you have.
You can actually go into your PHP that I and I file that is phoned.
If you go to some and in the Apache row you to config on,
then you would see the PHP that I and I file on in this file.
You can actually set up some SMTP settings.
So in the NFL.
I just search for S m T.
P.
On it brought me to where the male function can be configured.
You can set up that server name on the ports,
which is by default 25.
But what you really want changes local host toe on actual SMTP server on maybe went into
other configurations on that would allow you to dispatch leverage that SMTP server to
dispatch emails.
Another way would be to use the send me a library,
which is a popular PHP library.
But once again,
this is kind of unique to your Zampa and you're leveraging on SMTP server like maybe G meal
or yahoo if not one that is,
you know,
local to your context In this tutorial,
however,
will be using this third party library called Send Grid,
which is actually an add on that we can get in Hiroko.
So remember I mentioned that we want to keep our application as homogeneous.
That's possible or,
you know,
a single using a singular technologies as much as possible.
So send grid is ah is another on that Haruko offers that allows us a few emails I'm on for
free.
So for the purpose off this listen will be using that free service just like aware using
Heracles free service on.
Then we'll see how we can integrate with that third party email slash SMS dispatch software
.
You know our PHP application.
Now,
if you haven't already done so,
then you need to get composer,
which you can get back frozen,
too.
Get composer dot org on There's a previous video seek and his head back up in the videos
where I show you how to install and set up.
Composer There's not much to it.
You kind of slick don't Lord,
and it will give you a ah file Execute herbal,
which you can just run an install composer on your application.
And then,
having done that,
you can always just go to the command prompt on Just type in the word composer Andre.
And if you get this,
that means it's not installed.
So I just remember that this is my recovery machine,
so I'm actually going to go ahead and install it for you to see.
So we back at get composer dot org can district on Lord Andi If you're on a Windows machine
,
just get that windows installer.
Go ahead and run that executes herbal file,
and it's pretty straightforward.
You just need to click next.
Next.
We'll ask you where the PHP environment is on.
Do you really don't need to do much except click next,
and once you're finished,
you just like finish on.
Then you can bring a pure CMD and tap the command you may need to re started if you had it
open before.
So once you re open it and you type composer,
then you will see Well,
once you're seeing this,
then you know it's installed properly if you don't see this than there's something wrong.
All right,
so now that we have composer installed,
what we want to do is use it toe,
acquire the code that will help us.
The access that third party service called send grid,
which is a part off Heracles.
Um,
I don't offerings.
No,
the purpose of composer is package management.
All right.
So from time to time,
you may need to use third party libraries that are not built into PHP.
Andi,
they you know,
they're accessible over the Internet.
But then,
instead of going and hunting them down and trying to integrate them what composer lows you
to do is just run a few commands here in the command line.
And actually it was Go out.
Source.
The latest version off that third party delivery.
Ondo.
Nobody's into your project.
So to get this process started,
we need to find our way over to our product,
which is in C zam,
at least in my context.
It seeds some HD docks on,
then inside off HD docks.
It's attendance.
All right,
so know that I mean attendance.
I'm going to type the command composer require on the name off the library is send Grid
will just say that sin,
greed slash send grid And then once we press enter,
you can watch some magic happen.
Now,
if you see if you get this kind of result where it is installing and 100% that means that
that process was completed successfully.
If you bring up your project in visual studio code or if you bro Stewart and explore,
then you see that some new fast have appeared.
So you'll have a composer dot Js on file,
which is Well,
this is our package management files,
so essentially what we can do it Each time we you use composer to acquire 1/3 party library
,
it will add a line to this file saying that this is a library that we know half All right,
So if I wanted a lesser version,
I could change this version and then run a composer file,
and it would automatically go and source the version that I wanted and,
you know,
discard this one and acquire that one.
So composer makes sourcing libraries on versions very,
very easy.
So we get a composer,
Jason file.
We got a composer dot lock file.
You have to spend much time trying to understand what's in this.
And then we also got a vendor folder,
which has another folder with all off.
The dependence is for our our send grid activities.
All right,
so know that we have don't loaded the library's locally.
Let us head on over to Hiroko on add this library to our ups,
understand the type in here.
Oh,
cool.
Not com on.
Go ahead and log in.
All right.
So I'm going to select the up that we're working with,
which,
in my case,
it's PHP dash attendance on.
Then we go ahead and configure ad on So on the overview PUC installed Adan's and you can
click Configure Adan's On.
Then we can Search Send.
Great now.
Once that comes up,
we can district provision in on Douala No sin.
Grady's apart off your hero Go up.
But we still have a few steps,
so we have to click on send grid which will launch a new tab.
Andi,
I love us to go into the send grade dashboard.
Now the senator dashboard will actually ask you toe verify your activities here.
Identities.
Andi Well,
we can skip to the party.
And if it doesn't,
then if you go to settings on,
then FBI keys,
which is what we're really interested in,
it will prompt use IR I already have on a p I key,
but it will prompt you to verify your email address.
And then that may take a few moments.
You wait on that email and you verify yourself,
and then you can follow these steps again.
So once you're in centigrade,
what you want to do is goto settings on a P I keys on.
Then I'm going to discard this a p I key on.
I'm going to create a brand new one just for us to complete these activities.
So on this page where it says getting started with a P.
AKIs,
you go ahead and click create a P I key,
which is in the top right corner.
This will launch a little mortal asking us what what exactly you want so we can give the A
P I key and name someone to just call it email.
Something simple doesn't have to be a fresh name on.
Then I'm going to use restricted access because I really don't need every single feature
that they have the offer.
I really just want the simple stuff to send an email.
So I'm went toe thick,
restricted restricted access and then under access details,
I'm going to drop down mail send on,
then I will select meal sinned on.
Then I'm also going to select email activity and I'm going to click that one.
So once it becomes blue,
you know that you have selected it on then at the end off that I'm going to say create and
view on then this speech here displease my a p I key so you can just click in this space to
copy its by clicking.
It will copy it,
but they do say for security reasons they won't show it again.
So make sure you store it somewhere safe.
Otherwise,
you're going to have to repeat that step if you lose this key because they won't show it to
you again.
So either copy it and stories here,
or if you forget that you have tow,
discard it and then do it over.
All right,
so once I have that copy,
I can click done.
And I'm just going to store that somewhere safe for future use art.
So Backdoor project.
I'm going to start off by creating a new file on.
I'm going to call this file.
Send e mail dot PHP on,
Then I'm going to go ahead and put in my customary PHP tags on the first line of this fight
is going to be a require on.
We're going to require a new file that would have come with or composer called Also Lord,
which is found in our vendor folder.
Know that we've included over composer files and this file will actually give us access to
certain Send greed specific files,
which you'll see a Z go along next,
I'm going to create a class on.
I'm calling this class and email just like the file this class.
I won't have an instructor,
but that construct,
er sorry.
But instead I will have a singular function,
which I'm going to make static someone to say public static function.
And I'll explain what static means in a bit on.
Then I'm going to call this function,
send mail,
not send email,
but send meal.
No,
a static phone shown pretty much it does not require us toe in Stan.
She it on object on object off type,
Send email.
All right,
so if you remember,
every time we use the class,
we had to see classes or some object is equal to a new instance of that class,
and then we can access the functions when we make a static function instead of class.
We don't have to do that whole new part,
but we can just call the class name and then use a local a scope resolution operator to
just access the Function directory.
But we're going to see that as we go along.
No,
to keep our phone son dynamic,
I'm going to put in three parameters.
We want the two,
which is where this email should be sent to.
We want subject on.
We want content.
No,
The reason I'm doing it this way is that I want this function to be generic enough that
it's used in multiple,
you know,
operations.
So maybe when we create a new user,
we dispatch an email to that user who has been created.
When we create.
When somebody registers for our event,
we can use the same function to send off that email so I don't have to write the court
every time we need it.
What?
We just call it a static functional.
We take the two as a perimeter we can send over and you subject based on the context.
On Dwell,
the content of the email can be dynamic.
Also now,
in this function,
the first thing I'm going to declare is the is a variable for our key.
Now they're probably more elegant ways to do this.
But I'm just using apart off least resistance,
so I'm just defining the key in this variable on.
Then I'm going to use this key to send the access in grids process are part Fung son.
I'm going to use this key to access send grids,
send email function,
but the first thing that we need to do or will the second thing you need to do is build on
on object off type new on.
We're going to use a backslash and say Send grid,
or is it a forward slash?
I'm not sure which one that is.
What Sin grid slash meal slash meal open and close parentheses.
So this is a class that we know have access to because we included our auto loaders Ph.
B.
So we can no access this glass,
which came over through our composer installed off.
Center it on.
No,
this email object is an instance off our sin grid meal.
Klaus.
So next we can say email annuities are narrow and then we sit the from So you say,
You know what email addresses this coming from You can pretty much put anything there,
so I'm going to put my own email address.
So if if we were running a real conference,
then you probably put the email address off the conference or the Enterprise putting on the
conference,
and you can put on something here to see the name off the person or the enterprise friend.
So if it was a no reply,
but you didn't want no reply to show up,
you could still write I t Conference Enterprises.
But it's a no replies that I t can conference dot com,
you know,
just for argument.
See?
All right,
The next thing that we want to do in email is set the subject so we can say Set,
subject.
And then right here we can just pass in our subject.
Whatever coming is coming in as a parameter value here,
we can pass it into the set subject on.
Then we can do the email object again and then add to where we're adding to.
So whatever we're whatever value came over as the email address to be dispatched for the
email to be dispatched.
Tow was in this parameter on.
Then it gets added to the emir object,
using that phone son,
and then finally,
we can add content.
No,
the content variable requires tool parameters.
The 1st 1 is the type of content so I can see text slash playing.
If I'm just sending,
you know,
like a regular sentence or regular string if it was supposed to be HTML than I would have
to see,
like text slash html instead.
All right,
so you can choose what kind of content you're sending over.
Just not if you choose text slash playing,
but then you send additional content.
Then the channel will not render in the email,
so people will actually be getting tugs on each one times any charters.
If you chose text slash html and sent over a shingle,
could you will actually form at the HTML such that it gets rendered in the person's email
just the way you intended it to be rendered.
But for this example,
I leave it a stakes slash plane on I'm going to then give it the contents that would have
come over in that phone call.
The next step,
having built over email object,
is to call our send grid class.
So I'm going to create a variable.
I'm calling it Send really can call it the variables anything you really want.
But then it's new,
and then it's slash send grid at Scepter s Capital G on.
Then we're passing in that key value.
All right,
so you see a number of examples online.
Some people create what you call an environment file and then put the key in the file and
then load that through the modified auto.
Too low that environment,
key in tow,
Arson grid.
So their number off ways to accomplish this.
What?
Once again,
I just want the nice Quick,
quick,
quick.
So I'm just helping you to phonics to this service quickly.
So as usual,
we put in our try catch to make sure that and if anything goes wrong,
we catch that exception and we can debug it.
So I'm just going to leave exception as generic.
I won't these special guest.
What kind of exception?
We're looking for Andi.
Off course.
What we want to do if we catch an exception,
is echo the exception on the message.
All right,
so this in this one of a bit more verbal someone to say.
Email exception.
Cots.
All right,
so then we print the message and return falls,
so whatever it's called in dysfunction,
otherwise we want to try on.
I'm going to call a variable called We'll create a variable called Response on.
Then this response variable is going toe have send greed iroh on the phone shine,
Send on What we're sending is our email object.
So let's go through this again.
We have our key because this key will give us access to our FBI.
So don't share this key with anybody.
And by the time you're doing,
this tutor of this key won't exist anymore.
So I suggest you get your own and do it yourself instead of trying to copy this one.
But you said the key on then you build the email object by in San sheeting a new object off
sen grid meal on meal on.
Then we set the from we set the subject.
We said the tool and you can add as many tools as you need so you can have multiple,
too,
Um,
cause with different values hopefully safe,
you have to send the multiple persons at once.
You could at as many as you need to on.
Then we add the content,
and once again the content can be clean or can be.
HTML is understand.
To copy this on comment,
it'll just to show that we could send html also on,
then we Instead,
she it send grid as a new object.
And then we call the function send and understanding that inside off response on what I'm
going to return is the response Object.
No,
Http has different response courts.
The most common ones are 404 which is when you have ah,
request that was not phoned or 200 when everything was okay.
I think sin grid was sent back to to,
which is also an Okay,
that's like,
that's a good response.
Tohave.
So we will be looking for a tool to response upon a successful function car or our action
from this function call.
All right,
on.
If we get anything on that until two,
maybe 300 or 404 100 is better quest in case something is wrong.
So we'll be looking out for all of those things Now the next step is to modify our success
paid.
So I'm just going to go and find success that PHP on dine need toe off course,
make success aware off for a new kid on the block which is send email a PHP so I will
require send email under the DB con.
I'll just change that old send email that PHP on then,
having done that,
I can just modify the court that says his success meaning has the attendee Bean added to
the database successfully.
If yes,
then we will show the success message.
But I'm just going to dispatch that email right before.
So no,
I can say Send e mail.
All right.
Suzie Intestines is helping me along on then my two Coghlan's,
which is that operator I mentioned earlier on that we can just call the function send meal
.
So this is me doing calling that function in this class without needing toe.
Create a whole new object.
Andi operate that way.
All right,
so that's the advantage of our static class.
So the send meal form Chantix three parameters,
it experimenter one,
which is the two.
So I'm just into passing or variable email,
which is where we want to send the email toe it takes.
Let me just remind myself quickly it takes a subject.
So I'm going to write the static text you have successfully,
all right,
that she instead I'm sorry.
So it's welcome to AT T Conference 2019 for the subject on then our content will what text
you want?
You have successfully registered for this year's I T conference and notice Have that back
slash onda a posture well,
single court here because without the backslash,
it would kind off miss up the flow off my string.
So when I want to put a single court inside off text,
that's starting and ending with single puts,
I can use my back slash.
All right,
So the expectation is that once somebody has filled out the form on,
they've moved on to the success speech that we find that success well,
fire that email onda that would be transferring to the user.
They would just get that success message.
Anyway,
One thing I'm going to fix,
though,
is that specialties because specialty showing that I d.
Based on the data base,
I'm actually just going to fix that quickly before we test this.
So to quickly fix that,
I'm just going to go over to crowd Andi.
I'm going to find the function.
Well,
I think I would have to create a function to get specialty by i D.
So I have one that says,
Get specialty someone to quickly create one just to get the specialty by I d.
All right,
So I call this one,
gets specialty by I d Pass again and I d parameter modified the SQL statement a bit to see
you get from get start from specialties were special.
The idea is equal to just I d on then I did.
Although the wonderful things that you do where you prepare,
bind all parameters and then execute your statement,
Andi Then in the success speech,
I modified it Obits toe include the phone shown called right under the East Success That's
really much.
Or where you put this as long as you're you're passing in earlier calling the function and
you're passing in that I d that it needs on then the final change.
I mean,
it was instead off echoing the posts like we were before.
I'm no echoing the name column coming back from that result that was stored in specialty
name after making that function cop.
So those are the changes.
I just mean,
So we're going to go ahead and fill out this form on,
or we can just give it a quick re fresh so that everything is nice and fresh on.
Then I'm going to go ahead and fill out this form.
All right.
So Archibald Douglas has putting all of his information.
He's,
ah,
system administrator on his email addresses.
Loan procedure one.
Any night at gmail dot com,
whatever it is.
And then we go ahead and take submits so we can see here that at least our quarries running
,
cause we're not seeing the one artistry or the number.
But we're actually seeing the word system administrator on this would imply that the
operation has been completed successfully.
No,
you can give this a few moments,
but what I wanted to do is go over to send grid on,
verify that the email was despite so you can go to sin grid on.
If you were at the dashboard before then you can go toe activity.
So if you click on activity to the left,
then it will bring up all of the emails that were dispatched by the cones.
Using your a p I key,
Andi will show you home.
Any emails you've dispatched for the month under that are cones.
So I have quite a few here because,
well,
I use the service.
So,
you know,
I would have quite a few,
you may not see as many,
and if you don't see any as yet,
then you can refresh until you see it.
In addition to checking your email,
you may also want to check your email because it would probably go to spam.
So you want to if you don't see it at first sight than you want to check spam just to make
sure that it was really dispatched.
Andi.
If all of that feels,
then you may want to check your firewall because there are times when firewall settings
will prevent the emails from being dispatched from your local machine for maybe I should
say that a different way.
Sometimes firewall settings prevent the A P.
I call from being successful,
so that has something to me before.
But I usually get resounding success.
When I attempt this through.
We will,
having hosted application on Hiroko.
All right,
so by way of confirmation,
here is the email that was just sent.
It's seeing welcome Toe Eddie Conference as a subject that we set it sent to my email
address on the text that we set in the email.
So that's just confirmation that it worked,
and this was from my local machine.
Once again,
you can always check your firewall settings or published a heroic or to make sure that it
works.
So to wrap up this video,
I'm going to publish the heroic ooh published to get a published A miracle on Just test it
once again.
So the first thing we're going to do is bring up,
Get hub for that Stop.
No,
this is a few videos since I've published anything seriously,
that I have quite a few changes 182 to be exact.
It is always recommended that you make as you make changes and you confirm that your
changes work.
You check in your court so you shouldn't never get to the point where I have 182 chickens
to me just because you weren't checking in your court.
All right,
so that's my recommendation.
But for the situation,
I'm going to make one big check in on.
I'm going to have a huge summary where I added user authentication since the last chicken
on die also added e mail dispatch feature.
All right,
so that's that.
That's the chicken that I'm about to make on I'm going to push that to master on.
Give that a few and then after I push it the master for my local reporter push toe origin.
So it goes to get up itself on.
I just realized I remember that it that prematurely I need to update the con Fess,
Remember that Khan is looking to our local development database.
So I'm just going to come in that oh aan den on comments the settings for our remote server
.
Alright,
so they're more elegant way somebody Just what?
Once again,
this is a basic course.
I'm not trying to make things too complicated So we just un commander more database
connection on.
Then we can just go ahead and change that and you see that gets off for this up kind of
gives you a little takes.
The artists understand to work with that orbited con put come into monster and then push
the origin on.
Then we bring up herro coup where we go to our up I'm already in the opsec and go to the up
,
then go to deploy on.
Then you select the branch Will the branches early must and the new deploy branch all right
,
so we can give Hiroko a little time to cool off,
cause after deploy,
its not accessible the same time,
at least not on our free plan,
so we can give it a few moments.
But once you go ahead and view on,
I'm seeing that I haven't ever here at.
That's because I didn't copy over my user stable from the last few videos.
So I'll just do that quickly in the background.
All right,
and that's done in order is restored to our application.
So let's try and fill oat a new user,
and I'll just reuse the same arch ball.
Less data that I had,
since that user would not be in over remote are in my remote database on Submit,
and I see where the operation was completed successfully.
And if I check,
send grid and refreshing a couple times on a couple refreshes later there we have our email
that was dispatched to our new registrants,
So I'm back in my court and I'm looking at the success that PHP page where we called the
email function.
The fact is,
we could kind of personalize this email we could say Welcome first name last name.
You know the person's name toe conference.
We can include virtually any information that they just submitted.
We can actually include it in our email just by,
well,
con fascinating are using interpolation to get that variable into our string.
Another fun fact is that sin greed is powered by twilio,
which is a powerful estimates dispatching service.
So if we wanted to dispatch an SMS to them,
we would have gotten there,
therefore number in the process.
So all of those options are no available to you through this third party service.
Andi.
It's all easy to duel using or newly acquired Ph B skills and heroic cool hosting
capabilities.
I hope you guys enjoy this video,
and I'm very interested to see what you guys will use this new superpower to accomplish.