no starting from scratch on Didn't deliberately haven't shown you a preview off anything
that is to come because I want us to be in this journey together on we can all work towards
,
then seat as it involves.
I know that we are the ones accomplishing all of this.
So the first thing that we want to do is find our server folder having already installed
some on we go toe see zump HD docks on.
Then we create a new folder inside off this folder.
So each time we have a new site or a new Web application that we're going to be building,
we want to create a new folder on that folder will be our baseline for everything else to
come.
So the first thing I want to do is create this folder on I'm going to call it attendance.
All right,
so that is our new project attendance.
The next thing I want to do is open this project in visual studio court.
Someone's going to open a visual studio code on get that synchronization underway Now.
I had a previous project open and that's fine.
You may have been doing other things that's OK but you can always get started by going toe
file goto open folder on.
Then you find the folder which is sees some Ishi docks and then you select the one that you
know.
Is it going to be your baseline on?
Then you select on.
Then you let visual studio cord reorganize itself accordingly.
We have a very empty folder.
So this is what your interferes is going to look like at the end of it.
No,
by this stage,
already comfortable with the pH B pattern,
Andi,
if not you can always backtrack to my previous videos where I went through step by step
with whole pH.
B interacts with each hole.
We get everything working now,
the first thing that always goes in tow.
Any PHP website is and is a PHP page called index.
So Index is always going to be your first file should always be your first file on that
would represent maybe your home pitch.
But once again,
every Web server always looks for a file called index to Lord first.
Next,
I'm going to go ahead and build all the full of structures because for other files that
aren't necessarily website faster don't want everything happening at the same level,
so I'm just going to bring them out into different folders.
So I'm going to add a new folder just by clicking this new folder button here in Visual
Studio Court on the first folder I'm going to add,
is what we call includes.
So my includes folder will have.
Well,
we went to include and require.
What happens is that sometimes we have external files,
maybe helper files with,
like,
a Class or Leo Files.
We can put them in here,
and then we just referenced them as we go along.
So haven't includes folder.
I'm going to create a CSS folder because maybe we'll have style sheets.
I'm going to create a scripts folder on Be careful when adding Fuller's because if you have
the polar selected and you click new folder,
then it's going to turn at it.
Underneath that,
so is so just a click.
Make sure nothing is selected and then you click new folder.
All right,
so I have scripts because maybe we'll have J query or JavaScript code running in our sight
on going to create one and call it db db Short for database aren't because well,
maybe I want the court files that will be interacting with the database specifically in a
folder.
So that's why I'm doing this separations.
Anything I you see at the root here or call the route off the folder would be a director
upset file,
and everything else in a folder is just for referencing purposes.
But once again,
this delineation is occurring because you don't want everything in one place.
Now the first thing I want to do is start doing my nails for my Petes.
So in previous videos,
I would have mentioned that you can always do ish email call on five and you get what I
call the HTML skeleton that every webpage should have,
at the very least,
fire.
But then I want to take this a step further,
and I want to use bootstrap for my loads.
So just as a reminder,
we can go toe boots,
get bootstrap dot com.
Andi.
There you will see all of the documentation relating to bootstrap chicken is Go ahead and
click that on.
When you want to documentation.
You see all of the all of the documentation as it relates the bootstraps,
so I could actually just use this skeleton where they're giving me the same tugs assist
under.
But they're also giving me the stash.
She references that I need four bootstrap so that once I put that in my sight,
any shim a piece that I have that many interference of these automatically has bootstrap
built in.
So I'm going to go ahead on and copy this cord from the bootstrap website.
Andi,
I'm going to replace it.
Use it to replace the existing code in visual Studio court on dso.
No,
I have Ah,
bootstrap.
Ready in decks page.
Now,
once again for every piece that I would like to have these styles and all the bootstrap
cord,
I would have to actually copy and paste discord each time on day.
One way that I'm going to reduce the need for that or eliminate the need for that is to
start using My includes someone to create to file Syrian.
Includes on going to call one hitter dot PHP on the other one on,
still in the includes folder on went to call their own.
So you can always click the folder to make sure that you're selecting the folder so that
when you add new file,
it goes directly into that folder.
On the other one is footer dot PHP No,
I want my loads to be a one time activity,
meaning I want to set up My reference is one please.
And if I have to sit up enough by,
I want everything to be one police so or do it one time.
Rather,
So instead of doing it every time I have a new page,
I'm just going to do it one time and make a reference as necessary.
And so I put the cord in my index speech.
But what I'm going to do is remove it on segmented into the relevant pages.
So my head adare Ph.
B.
Should have called.
That goes at the top off the page on the footer dot PHP should have called.
That goes at the bottom of the page on this court should be called.
That doesn't ever change on a page,
so you'll notice that most of says they're consistent.
Every piece enough bar looks the same on the footer looks the same.
I had The filter is the last part off the beach.
Most websites are standardize that way.
So we're going to join that revolution on.
We're going to make sure all four sites are standard or or site right now is standardize
with awe again across our Peter.
Sorry.
So what I'm going to do is take from body because every p it starts with body.
What comes in between body is unique to the page.
Alright?
Someone to take from body were all the way up.
So from doc types of body,
I'm going to cut from the index speech on understand to place it in the header peach.
All right,
so every page that references header is going toe automatically have that at the top of it
on then in the same fashion.
I'm going to take everything below.
What?
Whatever contents are in our content is just Hello,
world on.
That's fine.
But everything below that should also be standards.
I'm going to take everything below.
Whatever the content would be caught that and place it inside off footer.
All right,
I understand the species don't a bit.
So all of these javascript files need to be referenced on the page on all of these tags as
well as the style sheet for bootstrap.
They all need to reference on the page.
So then that leaves the question.
Where are the references?
So what we're going to do is open a PHP tug at the top on inside this speech,
Be talk I'm going to see require.
So we looked at include and require on the differences that include will try toe,
find the file.
And if it doesn't,
you just use a warning and say,
Hey,
you know,
I tried and I didn't find a fire.
So I'm sorry,
whereas require will stop your website and see Hey,
I can't find this file sandwiches require and then you have two options are requiring two
options for include which would be the once they have include once and they have require
ones.
This means that if by some mistake I accidentally required to are included,
two files are the same.
Fire other twice.
Then be if you will actually try to include it twice.
However,
if I say include once or require once even if I repeat this directive to require the sea
and file elsewhere,
you already included it are required it so it won't do it a second time.
So That's the difference between the the require and require once and the seam is for
include and include one.
So I'm going to go ahead and see require once because I really only wanted one time on.
Then quotation marks on I just in with a cynical done so that I don't forget.
But inside the quotation marks,
I'm going to put the path to the file that I'm requiring.
So at the top off the page,
the first file I'm need to require before anything else,
even if I have other things I want to require.
The first thing I should be requiring is my hitter,
because I hit her has in the top part off May each dimmer body on Bush,
potentially whatever content comes at the top off the page,
All right,
so I'm just going to require once and I'm going to say includes because that's the folder.
so the files header and footer are currently inside includes Fuller.
So to get for them,
I have to see includes on then say slash on then hitter.
Not PHP on then I can just copy this because it's the same concept for the footer on I'm
requiring once the footer.
So I'm just going to change this reference the footer dot PHP So as many times as I have
are as many files as I have in the includes folder that I need on a page.
I can just reference them in this same fashion off course at the appropriate points.
All right,
Another thing that I want to do is make sure that I'm setting the title across all the
pages because it's set one place here on.
That's a static sitting here.
But if I have another page like when we get to actually building the register and viewing
stuff and so on,
each page is going to have a different title,
they all can say hello,
world,
Someone to me that the dynamic by introducing a variable that I'm going to call title at
the top on I went to see Title is equal to on this Oh,
I'm sorry.
I'm declaring it outside of the Ph.
B.
Todd.
So you notice that the color coding was not There was just white takes because he would
have rendered in HTML.
So I need to actually put this in between the PHP tags All right on,
then.
I'm going to be clear it before the require on that is because remember,
in programming,
everything is done in sequence.
So if I referenced title inside here,
which I'm going to do,
I'm going to say I want to print title and I can always just pretty static text.
Well,
I can't.
Just pretty tight.
That would literally print dollar san title Softworks after I want to put my static take.
So this is attendance that's up Name and then I'm going to see it dash.
So that's a static text.
But in the dynamic parts,
which is title,
I need to wrap it inside the PHP thugs.
Someone to see open that Ph B Echo title on Echo.
So you print.
So I want to print to this.
Tug the content off this variable,
and I'm just going to close this quickly.
All right,
so they're all married.
Lines are gone,
so I'm going to always have attendants dash,
but then relative to the value off title,
whatever comes out to the dash is prone to change.
So on the index speech,
my title is going to be index on.
I declare it and set the value on then I require this so that by the time it includes this
file title would have already been declared on initialized.
And so it knows exactly what it is.
The echo in this statement.
Another thing I'm going to add to this project while we're on this topic is a CSS file.
So there are times when we want our or little flare that bootstrap in its native Andy for
state will not provide.
It does a number of things,
but it doesn't do every single thing.
So what I'm going to do is add my own CSS file,
and I'm just going to click on the CSS folder,
Click New File on.
I'm just going to call it site side,
not CSS,
And you can use any special characters in the fire naming society,
not CSS.
All right,
I know it's blank and I leave it blank because I haven't found any use for it just yet,
But I'm still going to include it in my header that BHP.
So I'm going toe underneath the bootstrap section.
Add a link link row equals style.
She it All right on,
then the interests is going to be the past to the file,
which is CSS slash onda fire Name is site dart.
CSS are.
And then I can close this.
I don't need all of these attributes.
These are the two major attributes that you need when you are including a star.
Sheets are so having done all off that When I lowered my index page,
I expect to see reference being made to bootstrap reference being made to my style sheet.
The title should be reflective off whatever value I put their aunt they were going to see
Hello world Onda.
We should see a foot or so.
I'm going to modify the footer a bit on.
I'm going to add,
uh if Andi I am going toe print inside off this Div.
Let me see what's good prints.
I'm just into put the PHP tug on,
then went to echo copyrights.
Andi,
I think I can do something like it's why.
All right,
I'm going to contact you.
Needs used to use a full stop some printing the word copyright on then I space and then I'm
calling captain eating the year the deeds,
right?
The year so be it.
Why should give me about the year.
All right,
so that's what I did there.
And then I'm just going to close this def.
So I'm going to preview this site as it is.
I'm bringing in my browser,
open a new tab on,
Then I'll navigate the local host.
Which brings me to my some dashboard.
But that's dashboard.
I don't want dashboard.
The up I'm looking at is my attendance up.
All right,
so attendance on,
then that should Lord.
All right,
so we have on error here.
Oh,
I made an arrow in defining the deeds command.
The era was that I should have put this in quotation marks,
so I just fixed that,
and then we go back and refresh on.
There it is 19.
I guess 19 is 2019 right?
So you can look our own the the manipulation commands.
And I have a video on that.
You can backtrack to my video on the D time manipulation to see exactly how we can get
different values printed out,
has released the deeds.
Now we're going to make one more adjustment on that is toe actually not have our content
stopped onto the left margin like that.
So What we want to do is make use off bootstraps.
Uh,
they call it the Container.
So I think in layout,
you see something about how we can use a continue narrative class that actually,
you know,
kind of center lines are content in between the margins.
The extreme margins off our page aren't on most most websites kind of flew by that.
I don't always go extreme after extreme right there.
Like leaves some space in between.
So I'm going to just modify my header on footer to accomplish this.
And there is someone to do both.
Is this What would happen is that I could say give here,
Andi,
close the div.
So my content is in between these lives on.
Then I can say class equals container on what this would do is actually invoked that class
our own.
Hello,
Also,
when I refresh you see Hello world move on The copyrights did not move So my footer
contended moved But my page content moved the this please find this works But then the
don't side of this is that when I have another page and I need to seem effect after keep on
saying give class equals container on,
then put in my content.
So what I'm going to do is actually take this old.
Since this is going,
how is going to repeat?
And I always want our pages toe Have this court in it.
I'm going toe cut this and please it as the first thing in my body.
Tug.
So we're opening the body tug here in our hitter on.
Then after the body talk,
I would have put this contain a class anyways,
So I put that inside the hitter so that every time I include ahead or require the header,
this is implied on off course.
I need to close it.
So I'm just going toe always close it as the first thing in the footer.
So,
uh well,
yeah,
I want to put their content also get pushed away.
So this is inside.
This would be my footer.
So if I just give it up on i d So I know what it is.
A boat I'll say footer.
So on ideas.
An excellent way to identify what your elements are.
Four.
So I just have a random Dave Andi,
I just to go out to remember what it's for So if I say Dave on,
just give it an I D footer,
I'll always remember that old that's what This devious four.
So that's the Po off using ID's.
But further to that,
I'm going to put this closing live after the filter tive all right and understand the
tablets.
They can see where everything starts and stops.
So this closing give seems random in this speech.
But then when you look at it relative to the header,
it's opening here on its a glass container on its closing here in the Footer on DSO.
When I refresh my page,
I expect to see that my foot or content will also join Hello,
world also inside that container.
Alright on,
then just still close this out.
I'm just going to make reference to the paid source and we see that everything fits
together.
Everything is snapping together as if we had one big Asian appears.
So all of this from line to straight up the line 17 would have been a referenced inside the
hitter dot PHP file and then we have our content inside off index and content content
content on.
At the end of it all,
we have or closing part,
which is all constant in our footer PHP.
So once again,
the poor off doing Leo's this ways that you can make the change one time in one file,
and it ripples across every page that makes reference to this one file.
Now that we have our Leo,
it's don't.
The next thing we want to do is start designing a form and start looking at the different
methods off submission.