Hey,
guys,
in this video will be modifying over attendance application toe alot,
potential attendees to upload a picture.
The scenario is that when somebody sending for a conference,
you want to give them the option to upload a picture,
maybe a self portrait,
so that maybe we can put it on the i.
D for them when the conference comes.
If they do not upload a picture because it's completely optional,
then we want toe.
Make sure that we put a default picture instead.
To accomplish all of these objectives,
we need to modify our form or database and are supporting court.
Let's start with the form.
So the support of file upload we need to include a file upload control from on our form.
So I go to the court for our form,
which is index dot PHP.
And then I am just going to duplicate one off the existing form groups and then make the
changes accordingly.
No,
for a form we still need over label on going to see four avatar on what it will print is
upload image,
and then I'm going to put in brackets optional so that they know for sure that they don't
have toe next.
The import type that we need to use is off type file and then or class.
He's not going to be formed control this time,
but I'm going to use our custom class given to us Bible trip,
for that's his custom bash file bash Input.
This will kind of give us a a slightly remixed version off a file input control.
Also,
go ahead and change the idea and name Toe Avatar.
So that's everything on.
I don't need this attributes area described by salty.
That's oats on.
I don't need this label underneath it either.
On.
Then,
I'm going to include a class custom file in our def.
So instead,
off form group on when tohave custom file Onda Finally,
I'm going to have a label below.
So all of this is just required for the custom files Understood.
Duplicating this label on goingto have four.
Instead,
I'm going toe Have class equals cost,
um,
dash file dash label.
So if you actually look up on the internet for bootstrap custom forms,
you actually see some references to these kind of custom labels that I'm talking about or
classes rather on the the text inside off this label will be choose file.
So you see where this label falls into place when everything is printed.
So the class that sorry Dave,
is custom file as a class.
Then we have a label because you know,
every form control has its label.
And then we have the input off type file class cost on file input with an i D and name.
Now let's see what that produces.
All right,
so that's what it produces and notice.
We don't have the top label appearing here,
and also when we click,
it's not working.
I'm clicking it right now.
It's not working.
So I got a bit overzealous.
And firstly,
in a custom situation,
we don't have that label here,
at least not for the file and put somewhere to take this label.
Haute.
Since we already have that,
Bottomley will seem to file on then for this label,
I'm going to have to put in the attribute for avatars.
Remember that all the labels have the four on the control that therefore,
based on the I D.
So if ID's of attire,
then choose who I choose.
File is four or avatar control and since we have no real visual cue.
What I'm going to do is modify.
They set up similar toe our phone where we had this small text being printed that showed a
little help.
So I'm going to just put underneath it something to say.
The file upload is optional so that people who don't wish to blow the final know that they
don't have to write on.
I'm going to change this to maybe text dash warning so that it pops a bit more.
So when I refresh,
I'm so no text off warning doesn't look very good to understand,
to say danger.
So it pops on the screen and they're so far abilities,
options.
So that may not be the best choice off because the second arrow he can find a better one if
you in your context.
But I leave that for no on that.
Just put a slight br in between these two controls.
So that s Oh,
that looks a bit cleaner on.
Then notes when I click,
it brings up that fire search.
Ballack.
Now the fire search dialog is going to be displaying every single post civil file on these
air.
Some script plaza on this machine.
I don't need script files being uploaded as avatars.
I need images,
someone to make one more adjustment to this control.
So the input on went to add an attribute that says except and then equal on.
Then the value for that will be image slash star.
So that means I'm limiting the type of fires that this control will accept.
Toe image types with its JPEG PNG.
You can always list them out if you want more limitations.
But I just leave star.
And so when I refresh and try that again,
notice if I go back to my desktop I'm not seeing any of the script files because,
no,
I'm only limiting it toe image files.
So no,
that's step one is completed,
and we are allowing the person to be able to Bro's,
their computer selected image and submit.
We no need to modify what happens upon submission.
So to do that,
we need to go to our or action page,
which is success like PHP,
and makes a modification.
Still,
our post processing court here will be introduced to a new super global variable called
files,
so I'm just going to make some space here on.
Then what I'm going to do firstly,
is I'm going to define a directory Orwell a target location for anything that is uploaded.
So I firstly created a director called Uploads that has created a new folder.
Did that our screen.
So I created a new folder called Uploads.
And then this is where all of my uploaded files will be going so you can go ahead and
create that folder and then you can continue along on,
then till to set the target directory.
I'm just going to define a new variable on.
I'm going to call it a target on the score the i R.
Short for directory on.
Then I'm going to set its value to be uploads.
Sorry.
In string uploads slash.
So my target nurture is my uploads folder.
Next time went to build a string that will represent the name off my file.
So to build the string,
I'm going to first start off with the target directory.
So that's Dallas and targets on the score directory.
And then I'm going to conduct attorney that onto the name off the file,
which I'm going to get by seeing this name,
which is a PHP function on it receives some file path or find him so inside off base name.
I'm going to then reference my super global variable called files and then finance has to
worry sub scripts.
The first Ari subscript would be the name off the control.
So just like with Post,
only wanted the value coming from the first name control.
We reference it by name.
So in this case,
we want the file coming from or file upload control,
which in this case,
we called Avatar on then the attributes off the father we wish toe have.
So in this case,
I want attributes Name.
So the attributes is just like when you right click Ah file.
You know,
Windows system on.
Then you see the name the date created the size.
All of those are five attributes.
So in this situation,
I want the name.
Now that's have the name off the uploaded file.
The next thing to do is to actually move the file somewhere to say moved uploaded file,
which is a PHP function on.
Then This one takes to permit is itics.
What files should be moved as well as the destination.
So to me.
This a big cleaner.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to create another very book and call it original file are
five,
and that will be equal to the original name coming through our post.
All right,
so art file is storing the file,
the name off the AB attire or the name off the file coming through our of attire control on
.
Then I'm setting the Tirlea character to be uploads on.
Then I am determining that this is my destination.
So really,
actually,
I could have called this one destination so much really in that destination,
because what this will do is act as the destination path for this file.
So by building it to say,
uploads slash the name off the file on the I'm preparing it to be moved by this function.
When I see,
move,
uploaded,
file and see dollar signs,
original file and then comma dollar sign destination.
So this function,
once it's called,
will look for the original file coming through our submit action on then create it at this
destination that we have specified come winter and a cursory test.
But obviously,
if I submit,
the form has been to attempt to do a database Inter,
which I don't necessarily want someone to show you.
A little d bullying trick where you can actually use a function called Exit that actually
stops the execution at that line.
So in other words,
when I submit the form it will get this far.
Once it hits the exit,
nothing else will happen.
So I don't want you to submit anything to the database just yet,
So I'm going to use this to pause the execution on just validates that the file is moved as
specified.
So I'm going to go back to my form,
refresh Philip totals,
and then I'm going to choose a file,
and I have to hear our student of stealing details someone to to students on.
Then I'm going to click submit and,
well,
nothing happened.
Hold.
I validate this.
I would have to go to my file system,
or I can just go back to visual studio cord on.
Look at the contents off the upload folder on Nothing happened on.
Nothing happened because I made a mistake here.
So the original file really should not have the name,
but rather the TMP name that's the attributes off the fire that we want,
so I'll explain what that means.
Name is what we see when I see student that PNG on the fire system that's the name over pH
.
B is not trucking it by the name off the file,
but it generated ah,
temporary name for transit between the post action.
So for us to be able to actually move the file or interact with the file itself in any
physical matter,
we have to reference it by the TMP on the score Name attributes.
So in the orig file variable that's I created here.
I want to say files of attire and instead of saying name with just a t m p underscore name
,
So move uploaded file will be moving.
Whatever file has that temporary name toe a more permanent destination on our fast system,
someone to see if these changes and then I went to just refresh.
So it actually just submits everything to the form again and click.
Continue on.
Then we're going to go back to our uploads folder on defy Look inside or close for you see
that a fire has been created by the name student that P and G.
No.
One thing we don't want is any tour registrants uploading the same image with the same name
on one over writing the other.
It's always good practice to rename your file to something that is unique on that.
When you're storing it in the database,
you are always sure that you're getting the CART picture for the courts person.
So in a situation where you have people creating user profiles with unique user names,
then you probably want to rename the image to the user name or to some unique I.
D.
That you're also starring in the database.
For this person.
In this situation,
the little really unique things about any registrants will probably be their email address
on maybe their contacts number.
And I think contact is probably more unique than email address in this situation.
So I'm goingto be renaming the files that they upload toe have the name that looks like
they're full number now.
In order to do this,
I'm going tohave toe change the way I set up the destination by setting whatever custom
name I need here.
But then I still have to add back the extension off the fire,
which I don't know what extension it is since I'm looking for images which can be PNG J
pick or G I f.
So instead of trying to force an extension,
I'm going to have to dynamically determine the extension.
But then I can on the fly determined the name because I'm collecting the full number from
this variable.
So what I'm going to do is create another variable under orig file and I want to call this
one txt short for extension.
And then I'm going to use a peace be function path in fourth into which I'm going to pass
the files.
Super variable,
sometimes stopping this.
But I'm passing in the name,
not the TMP name.
Because the TMP name is only known to PHP,
it only makes sense the PHP So I want the name which is going to be student dot PNG on.
Then I am going to use path in four extension as the next parameters,
so path inflows and to get certain information about any file that is given to it on the
information I want is the extension on then that will be stored in my txt variable.
Next.
I want to modify my destination toe instead off passing in the base.
Name off the file.
I want to pass in whatever value is inside contact as a variable coming back through from
my form on.
Then I'm also going to con Katyn,
eat whatever value comes back in my extension.
Variable after finding off the path info off whatever fire was uploaded.
So then the destination will have uploads slash whatever for number the person entered dot
Whatever extension that file hat on,
then the move uploaded Will store that file with that new name inside or uploads folder,
someone to run a test again with the same file and see the result.
So,
no,
we choose the file on.
I'm choosing student at PNG once again on Then I submit on Remember that we have the exit,
so nothing really happens,
But we can go back on,
then we see.
Okay,
so I messed up the quarter bit,
but at least we're seeing the phone number on the file extension.
But what we're not seeing is the dots,
because windows needs that dot in order to determine the file name.
So I'm just going toe modify the way I wrote this altogether on.
I'm just going to put in braces on day,
create one be contiguous string with interpolations.
So no,
my destination looks like the variable target directory,
which is upload slash than the value coming back from the contact docked.
Whatever value comes back from extension someone to see that change.
And I'm just going to re first re submits and re tries that operation and then when I go
back,
I am no seeing the full number docked.
PNG.
I'm just going to remove this file from the folder.
All right.
So,
no,
for each person who registers whatever full number they enter will be used.
The Brini more file on that file extension will always change based on what they put so
know that were successfully uploading fast our server?
No.
We need to modify the rest of the court so that the data bees knows about the uploaded fast
.
So the first thing I want to do is modify my database using Petri.
My admitted to add the new column.
So I'm going to my database into my attendee table.
And then I went to modify the structure by saying,
I want to add one column after specialty on the score i d.
So I'm setting off this column toe.
Have the name of a tire path be off Time of arch are 200 on dime sitting it to be no level
because once again the picture is optional and then we click Save on,
then that new column is no added.
No.
I need to modify my court to make sure that I'm passing in the file path off for uploaded
file to the database,
which would be in the column avatar path.
So we know the destination because we build the destination.
So we need to make sure that we're passing destination in tow.
Our insert attendees function on by extension.
We need to modify the function.
So I'm going to pass state destination,
and I'm going to add it as a parameter to the insert attend the function,
and then I'm going to go over toe my crowd file where no insert attendees is on.
I'm going to make sure that I have representation off that new parameter.
So it's expecting a new apartment.
They're called destination,
or I can call it Avatar Pa.
So remember that we don't need to call them the same thing as long as they're in the right
position.
So about our path will no be represented in my quarry when I come down here and I say comma
of attire path on,
then if I'm putting that there than I need to have my parameter,
which is being bone.
So that's colon of a tarp path on.
Then I just make another line here on,
but make sure represent avatar path as both a parameter in the quarry onda parameter.
In the function,
I'm going to execute the test where I fill out the form,
select the same student that PNG file on attempt to submit.
When I do all of that,
I get my success message on my take note of the contact number.
Of course,
I didn't change it,
so that just goes socially that it will not try to duplicate the finally will always
replace once it sees ah file with the same name.
So make sure that whatever nimir giving the file for each user is very unique.
However,
if I go to my database and I look at my attendee table and my data,
I see that the new column.
No has values.
On the path is uploads slash whatever the file name WAAS or has been changed toe now final
step Just to complete.
All of this would be to display this profile picture whenever the person submits
successfully,
as well as whenever one off the admin users views the profile for the user.
So that means we need to modify over success that PHP page as well as,
oh,
we're view dot PHP page to make sure that we're seeing the image as it is being referenced
on the persons database record.
So what I'm going to do in my success that PHP paid is go down to the section where the
information is being printed on.
I'm just number.
Listen to keep it simple,
I'm not really going to focus on getting it to aesthetically pleasing.
I'll leave you to experiment and do that.
I just want to show you how to display the image.
So since we're on the success that Ph.
B page we know the destination is going to be somewhere in our project on,
we just need to set up on image tohave an image tac toe have the value as whatever path is
being stored inside of this destination variable.
So I'm just going to go down to the sexual where I want to display the image on going to
see I m g SRC is equal to on.
Let me just leave that blank for no on.
Then.
Remember that whenever we want to put ph be content inside often.
Html tag.
We need to have our PHP tag on eco whatever variable it is that we want.
So I'm just going to see inside off these quotation marks a PHP tag and I disclose it at
the same time on.
Then I'm echoing my variable destination.
Remember,
destination is the path.
So this will say something like uploads slash file name Dr Extension on.
When this echoes that value,
it will be the image source value.
So if I do that and I refresh after submitting,
then I see where my file is.
This is the student found that I upload it once again.
I'm not too concerned right now about the placement.
You can go ahead and fix it how you need it.
But I'm going to just show you that whatever you do in the AMG tag affects that image.
So if I think it's too big,
I wanted to be,
maybe have a width off 200 by on the height off 200 I can say 200 on.
Well,
CSS is the best way to accomplish that,
so I would actually just a style style is equal to on then set the which so be maybe 50%
instead,
Andi height to be 50%.
So when I do with that and I refresh you see that the CSS would okay,
that's not much of our resize.
But you see my point.
Whatever you do on the ancient sites,
only sit this 20 on 20 and then you see a bigger resize happen on.
Then I have some bootstrap classes that can help me to make it look a bit cleaner.
So there is a bull shop class that sees rounded so that one gives it a little Rhone border
on.
If I do that,
then refers,
well,
the effects off road that aren't very visible,
someone to try another one and see rounded dash circles around.
It kind of takes the sharp edges off the corners,
but rounded.
That circle actually creates a circle circular representation off the image.
And there you go so you can actually go ahead and use bootstrap and whatever other tools on
make your image look nice representation.
Now,
this was a success,
but I need to repeat that feat on the view dot PHP p it's understand to call back on,
but actually just them to copy this scored because it will be doing something similar on on
the View page.
I'm going to Rio put my I'm g tug in my court.
But then you notice that on the view page we were referencing things by seeing results on
the subscript.
So that means I can't call destination on this side.
Instead,
I'm going to just reuse this bit off cord on.
Instead of echoing first name as image SRC,
I'm going to echo avatar underscore half,
because when we did our select query,
we selected star and star brings back all the columns.
So one of the columns that we get back is avatar path,
which is storing the path toe or image inside the beta bees.
So that's it.
So we can dynamically lord the image for the person who is logged in so I'm just going to
put this statist someone to go on on,
log in.
I know that I'm in.
I'm going to go ahead and view one of thes.
So if I view one from before,
then you see the images broken.
So we don't want that off course because this is broken.
Um,
well,
this is broken because this record existed before we started putting in images on There's
no image to display.
So we don't want that someone to go back.
And I want to find one that we just entered on.
There we go.
So the image is being loaded not because it's being stored in a database,
but the path to it is in the data.
Bees attached to the person's record on the file is present on our system.
So we know where to reference for what you know.
The last thing that I want to do is make sure that if nothing comes back for that person,
meaning they didn't upload an image or the register before the feature was available that
we displace something off a default avatar for them regardless.
So I'm going to adjust the court that is printing our of attire.
And I'm going to just put in so called Turner operator inside this string so that we can
determine if whatever is being returned from the data bases empty.
If it is,
then we want to print something.
If it is not,
then it's fine.
So there is a function in PHP that's is empty,
which takes ah parameter,
which is probably going to be a stringy can.
Binary can be anything but empty is basically I just seeing Is there any content inside off
this variable on?
Then it returns a bulletin which is a true or false.
So the Turner operator that we're going to put instead off a whole if else just to know
what to echo is we're going to see question Mark,
and then we see if it is empty.
So this is going to return Shore Falls.
What comes after?
The question mark is what will be done if it is true.
So if it is true that it is empty than what we want to do is put in the value up lords
slash on day,
I went and found some generic,
um,
image.
I'm calling a blank,
that being PNG So I want to reference that blank file if that If the string is indeed empty
,
so blank dot p and g So this will act as my default um of attire for anybody without an
image reference in the database.
So if it is empty,
then I want to echo this value on then we have a colon.
That is,
if this does not evaluate to true,
What do I want?
And what I want is to echo the actual path to the image.
So right here in our image SRC we're doing a quick if else are making a quick decision to
see echo this value based on the turn Eri operators old So the Turner operators seeing I
want something that is going to return to our falls in this case,
is the string empty or not?
If it is,
then I want to echo this or return this value so that we can be echoed if it is not,
then echo the actual avatar particles from the database.
So if I go back to my listing and this is one with it,
so I can refresh and I see that it's still keeps that image if I go back to the list and go
back to one of the first registrants who didn't get to upload an image.
Then we see that they get that default.
If I go to any other one that didn't upload an image on this person,
will this person is giving me.
Okay,
so I'm getting that default Archibald default.
Right?
But then this attendee with I d four is not giving me that someone to look into this.
All right?
So by looking in the database,
I can see what is happening.
So the attend you with the i d.
For those have content in the avatar path over.
The problem is that the file name is basically dot g pg,
whereas their own is that PNG?
So,
in testing,
I change the extension and change of fast around on dso.
The first fewer distress that we tested it with would have a dot PNG,
but the rest have the correct that JP.
So that is why you are seeing that broken image.
So it does work.
Um,
but then it's still a concern because then it's seeing that it can't find the file so well
,
we can We can determine if the file exists.
You can probably do some research,
but I'm not going to get into that.
I just want us to get over the hump off,
uploading a file on having it displayed.
So I'm going to just run through this with an entirely different person,
this time on a different full number so that the file is different.
So this is a different full number on I went to choose the file on.
I'm going to go on the Internet and find a different file.
So far.
I phoned a file off with a fox,
an image of a fox.
So that's the other tire that this registrant wants on.
Then when I click submit,
we're seeing the Fox.
And if I go and view attendees and I view that persons profile,
then I'm going to see the Fox as their avatar.
If I look in the data base by,
just refresh the database,
then Archibald Douglas was inserted with a different file with a different file name