Hey,
guys.
In our previous video,
we went through modifying our form submission toe.
Actually,
Goto another page once of data was submitted in the form on DTI to display the data being
submitted.
So just as a quick recap where distance of quickly,
Philo this form.
And I'm just going to use values that were there before to expedite that process.
And then when I click submit,
we go to the next page where everything that we just filled out is there on display.
Now we looked at using one and action and to the method get onda get method actually puts
all off the values being submitted in the form right there in the Ural in Plea Insect.
You don't want that if you're dealing with sensitive information,
you don't want that.
The earl will be a source for anybody who has malicious intentions to just come and get the
data.
It shouldn't be that simple.
So for certain applications,
yes,
it's fine.
But then when you're dealing with sensitive data,
you want to use another method which is called post,
and that is what we will be looking at today.
No,
get on post are very,
very very similar.
So the changes that we need to make toe or farm and tore action peach will be very,
very minimal now.
The first change that we would make is to change the method.
So we did say,
Get what we want to say this time is post Andi that is half off.
The work completes right there.
So just by changing the method from gets to post the form,
behavior will be entirely different.
And I'll show you.
No,
you notice that there is a difference.
So I'm getting an error here,
and it is seeing that I have undefined indexes on do other things.
So it's looking for the values that should be there,
and it's not finding it.
Also,
you notice that my girl does not spots over any values.
So then you're probably wondering,
OK,
where are the values?
So if we go back to our action page,
which was success that PHP,
we would have written quite a bit off course,
we we took this from bootstrap Society Does get that card on.
What we were doing was echoing get on each index off the get.
So what happens is that because we're not passing over the values in the get method anymore
.
The Super Vera before get is not getting any values.
That's that's pretty much what's happening here.
So that is why we're getting these errors.
That undefined index first name because they get Super Variable is looking for some value
with the index first name.
Same with the last name on every other one.
So this no is a way to introduce the other super variable,
which works with the post method on that one is post.
It's that simple.
So I'm going to leave this court and actually just going toe comment out this score,
or at least most off this court,
because after coming until the PHP manually.
So I'm just going to commented thoughts.
Andi,
I'm going to leave a notice above it.
So we all know what this code was for.
All right,
so I just throw this little guy to see that this spring Sol values our past toe the action
be using method equals get so that we know that that's what this section off court was for
.
However,
I'm going to duplicate this section of code.
I'm just going to make some modifications like I said Get on post are very,
very similar on the big difference is that instead off seeing get,
I'm going to see dollar sign on the score.
Post on that is half of the work on Peter's.
I'm just going to leave it with first name on.
Then I am going to go back now.
Another thing is that because the values are not here in the early,
it's kind of visiting the backgrounds.
It's like it has Tofik retransmission,
Ari submission.
If you try toe,
refresh the action,
Peter.
So when I continue notice,
know that Okay,
in the midst off the noise,
you see the word mirror,
and that's because the Post post super variable is actually seeing a value called first
name.
It's It works in the same way as against if you understand what the get works literally
just changing the method from get to post on where you would have said get you see Post.
That's the major difference.
But then I want toast.
I appreciate the fact that the behavior is also different because no,
we don't have that query string.
We don't have that question mark with all of the values like we saw with the gets.
All right,
so one where we post data,
it happens in the background.
So the sensitive data are potentially sensitive.
Data is not being passed in the URL as it was with the get.
However,
as much as it is obscured from the user's eyes,
we the developers know exactly what is happening because we know we're the ones pulling the
strings.
So I'm just going to go ahead and change all of these,
get references into post,
and then I'm going to refresh the page,
which is going to ask me if I want to.
You know,
it's going to say the page I'm looking for had some information.
Do I want to resubmit?
Right.
So that's what Crume is asking.
Understands?
It could continue on do that.
Then we snap right back to normal.
So all of the data that I just passed in the form is no.
There it is there no more errors,
but notice one.
No data is being passed in the URL.
However,
we are able to access it in the back in nonetheless,
someone to start from scratch.
I'm going to just go back to the form and then went to submit a brand new record.
So I'm going to make up a new person.
Agnes Walters Onda.
On a dead end of this exercise,
we're going to fix this date picker,
and then this person is a software developer.
Andi.
She's a Walter's at gmail dot com.
All right,
that's not the proper evening address on the number is one through night.
I know when we submits notes,
nothing in the world,
the early screen cleaners.
Also,
however,
all of her data is there for display.
So once again,
that is because we're no using the post method.
No,
I did see.
Just know that we're going to fix the date picker and let's do that together.
No.
So I'm going to go to the DJIA query You.
I references for the Deep eaker on going to see what options are available.
So I go to the website.
I find it picker on.
Then I'm going to see over here if they have any adjustments.
Are customer custom ways to display the date picker that is more conducive to my user base
?
All right.
And I found the one it's display month on dyear menus So you click on the example and you
see that it allows you to select the month,
select the year and then select the date on.
That's much better than the one we had previously,
which is the default on where if I was born in 1950 I would have to click.
That's not practical,
right?
So no want to modify it.
So I'm going to look at the example cord to see what it is that makes that one difference.
And then the major difference that I'm spotting here is in the function,
So we know we call date picker.
But what we did was call date picker and open and close varies.
What they're doing is passing in some values here.
So I'm just entity those values because that's all I really need,
cause I have the rest of the court.
So they want to copy all of this and replace what seniors are.
You just copy the relevant parts and replace.
I'm just stopping in the relevant part on.
Then I'll go back to my court,
where my date pickers defined which the function was being called in my footer file.
Onda,
I'm going to just modify it with the new values.
Alright,
Under Spend some time fixing my indentation.
Alright.
On DSO my date picker No has some parameters being passed in.
Okay,
so this is why you're court needs to look like if if you have the same concern that I So
when I go back and I refresh my page and I reload my date picker No,
it looks like a more user friendly.
We alot my users to select their deeds.
I can know comfortably Scroll on then you see,
it's limiting which year So that's another adjustment that will probably want to meet so
back to our court.
I'm going to add one more attributes on this one Will set the year range on the attributes
is literally here.
Range on then Colon Sanders following the same pattern as the previous ones on.
Then the value for this could be I think it's negative One on Dredd on call on plus zero.
All right,
I'm going to see that and see what it looks like.
And when I reload on take a look at the years available to me in this drop.
Don't I see?
I have up to 2019 on as far back as 100 years.
So let me just explain that when I set year inch and I said minus 100 colon plus zero,
it means I can see upto 100 years ago,
but nothing beyond this year.
All right,
so this will be a moving target off course,
because next year 100 years ago would be 1920 as opposed to 1919 as it is.
No,
on also close ear would be 2020.
So that is how you would go a boat sitting the range off yours that is available for
selection from your calendar control.
Ultimately,
the goal of this tutorial video was toe help us to understand whole weekend submit data
from a form to the other page using the post method.
So we already have the get and you still have the court reference scored above on.
No,
we know how to do it with post on comparably,
Each one has its own purpose.
Each one has its advantages.
I just use them wisely