Hey,
guys.
In all our previous videos,
up to this moment,
we have been looking at designing a form,
submitting the data on being able to view it after submission.
The next major step to take after doing all of this wonderful work is to actually store
this data that tomorrow we can view it the day after and essentially we are creating a
registration system for a 90 conference.
So at the end of the day,
we need to see a full list off everybody who has filled out this form.
The next major requirement for this to be accomplished is a database.
Our objective for this video is to start or database creation process.
And we will be using PHP my admin to design a database in Maria db slash my SQL No to get
started,
we first need to launch PHP my admin.
And to do that,
we just open a new tub in or browser and then we can rose toe our local host address.
But the application that we're going toward the folder is PHP my I mean art.
So that's a little the letters Ph b m y a d M i n aren't So if you type that in and it
doesn't work,
then you probably want to make sure that your my ESC UAL service is running sick and just
open zump and make sure that my SQL is up and running.
Andi,
It should work,
all right?
No,
something's the note.
I will say my SQL a lot because for the years that has been the default database engine
that comes packaged in Xam,
pour one for any off those server ph.
B environment applications.
More recently,
there has been another version off my school called Maria DB.
And so you see them.
You used very interchangeably quite often.
No.
If you have successfully Bro's two Petri,
my admin than your screen would look something like this.
If it does prompt you for lugging,
then you can use route with no password.
That usually works.
And if you still have difficulty,
you can let me know and I will assist you.
No PHP.
My admin is a database management system designed well,
really.
For my ask your slash Maria DD it's completely were based on,
and it would have been installed when you installed some.
So this is a Web based portal that allows you to manipulate the database as you need to,
without any additional overhead off,
opening another application and using up too many resources.
So it's really handy and quiet clean.
It's easy to use on,
so we will be using this to design our database that will be accepting data from this form
.
No,
based on the nature of this form,
I have scoped two tables in my design on It's Okay if you create wanted,
we could create one table to store everything.
So we just know that we're feeling wanted with all the information on day,
I'll explain why I have two tables when I am designing the tables.
So the tables that we're going tohave will be one attendee on to area off.
Expertise aren't on.
I'll explain why I'm making a table just for ear off expertise so we can go back to Peach
Member at men on then to create a new database.
We click on this new this new button over here,
that link and then that will bring up a dialog box or change appeared rather and ask us for
the name off the database so we'll just call this one attendance.
So I always name my databases.
Um,
clearly enough that I know exactly what application it is relating to so I can see
attendance underscore Bebe art,
and then we're going to go ahead and click,
create,
and then it's going to then move on to allowing us to start creating tables.
So the first table,
um,
went to create is a 10 B on the number of columns I want because I can do all of the
granted.
I can change that along the way,
but I can just counter and say I want 123456 columns,
seconds increases number 26 and then click Goal on.
Then the next screen is asking me toe actually fill out what I want so well,
actually should have gotten an extra column,
and I'll see why.
So the first column that I usually put in any database I'm designing is on auto
incriminating primary key.
So the 1st 1 would be an I d.
I'm going to call it a 10 d underscore I d.
On.
I leave the data type of int Andi,
I'm going to one say that it should be a eyeota increment Means is going to co owned by
itself.
So that means for every record that goes in this column,
the value in this column will always change.
And so that will always be unique.
And so this will be my primary key,
since every database properly designed it Abi's should be should comprise records that are
uniquely identified on having our primary key that is unique is step number one.
So the easiest way to make sure that you will always have a unique idea because based on
the data we're collecting,
there is nothing unique.
The only maybe the email address has to be unique each time and really and truly doesn't
because I'm not going to stop somebody from using the same email address twice.
So there's nothing here that really says old.
This person is definitely unique,
so I'm going to create my own unique value.
Call it attendee.
I d make it auto incremental ing Andi,
I'm also going to and then that promise the addition off on index,
where they're asking if I want to make it a primary index.
Others go on.
What that did was to create the index called Primary so That's how we get the primary key.
All right,
on auto increments.
Just by enabling auto increment,
it's just going to say,
Oh,
is this supposed to be the primary key on By enabling that,
then we know we have the primary key that is also implementing.
So then I'll go ahead and create a column that corresponds with each data point that I
intend to stores first name,
last name,
date of birth on DSO.
I'm just going to feel those old in Petri.
My admin.
So our first name and then the data type for first name can't be int it.
It has to be something that would be like a string.
So we databases they're not.
As for giving a speech,
be with BHP.
The data type didn't matter for the variable.
I could put text number everything inside off any type of variable.
But in the database you have to be very,
very special because what kindof data will be stored inside that column.
So the most popular ones that you see will use are at the top on.
We have our char,
which is one used for text a lot,
and then we also have text,
All right,
so you can use either one.
I'm going to stick to barter because Varta has been around for a while.
And that's what everybody has always been using.
And that's the more popular on.
You'll always see another database engines.
I'll just use var char onda.
I'll set this length toe 50.
So by setting Bartsch are,
which is a text on the 50.
I'm saying that I am allowing this column to store any block off text upto 50 characters
big.
All right,
I think I can set defaults and all sorts of things,
but I really don't need to sit anything else because I don't need a default.
Value should be getting it from the form on the other.
The other options don't really apply,
so I'm not going to put those in.
So I just move onto the next one,
which is last name and last name.
I'm sure you'll agree.
Kit can get the same treatment as first team,
and I also me that 50.
You can increase this if you wish.
Maybe 100 because sometimes you do have people coming with some very unique and long names
.
So what will happen is that if somebody feels old here,
form on their name is more than the number.
You sit here,
it will truncate it so it will only store as many characters as it can.
So sitting a bigger number is always a good idea in case you're anticipating that ah based
value is not practical.
All right,
so our first name last name next is did off birth.
so notes that this does not necessarily have to line up with the label or the name or the
idea that you give the control because mapping will be done in another way.
But you always want to make sure that you you have defined some space to store some value
on date off birth would not be a number.
It's more off a date.
So I'll use the date data type because I'll be storing at date inside off that column.
I don't need to set a length for the value.
So you know what is that?
Sometimes subtle.
And sometimes you don't.
It doesn't need a length.
They doesn't need a length.
The other two columns would be email address Onda contact number.
All right.
On both of these would be var char Onda,
said email address to 100 on the contact number.
I'm going to sit as Varta are also not int because people may come and they use their
dashes and their brackets when they're tapping in their numbers,
because some people type their numbers like that and then species right?
So you may end up with variations unless you're going to be very strict with your mosque,
and even then you don't want to use a number.
I my personal rule of thumb,
is don't use a number data type if you don't intend to do month on the column.
So we're not going to be doing any mathematics with the person's contact.
Numbers are leave that as Varta on the typical number is up to 11 or 13 characters.
Also said this the 15 so that anybody,
from any reason whether use 11 digits or 13 digits are you are one extra one.
There's no space for you.
All right,
on,
we left out a column,
which would be the era off expertise,
so I'm just going to add a new column.
So we ran out off columns because I asked for six But I used one off the six to do
something else.
So at the top here,
I can just see odd one columns are just let go.
And then that just gives me another column.
So I'm going to say special tea.
All right,
Onda,
I'm going to leave that as it on.
Do you see why?
So I'm going to say specialty.
I d All right on then I can choose to preview the SQL because really,
actually,
this is just going to execute some SQL in the background on If you are not sure about SQL
or the language itself,
you can trick or my other tutorials on my SQL development data database development and
mastery.
And you can also check out my other set of videos on Microsoft SQL Server for everyone.
So,
without previewing my the SQL that would be used to execute this,
I can district save which will actually involve the SQL in the background on give us our
table and then this is our table design and structure.
So we look and we see all off our or columns as they were defined.
So you see,
this little key indicates that this is the primary key,
all right.
And then they tell you that it's also incremental.
So that means for every value that goes in on,
uh,
value will be generated uniquely in this column.
No,
I did say that we would have to tables,
and I would explain why.
So you noticed that I use specialty I d.
Instead off specialty as a bar chart,
even though we're asking for Well,
we're showing words over here,
but we're not going to be storing words on.
The reason for that is I don't want to store words it to me.
It is useless tohave database add mean 20 times in my database.
Instead of doing that,
I'm just going to create another table for just the specialties.
Andi,
I went to reference the that table whenever somebody selects something from this drop known
.
So in other words,
if I had a new specialty to this list,
then this drop down list should automatically pull that from that table.
I shouldn't have to go into made into my html every time.
And if you remember the money or presents off adding the options and then I would have to
go on,
I don't know the option on then that that can be tedious.
So what I'm going to do is create a table that will have the sole purpose of storing the
list of specialties because we only have four on DWI.
No,
I tease our broader,
um carrier than just four specialty.
So we this will give us greater flexibility in managing our lists on wherever we have a
drop down list.
It's good if that dropped on the streets.
It's data from a table.
So I'm goingto go to new create the table called specialties.
All right,
on,
I need a specialty on the score I d.
So I always start off with my i d column on.
I'm going to make it also implementing,
which will prompt me to make it a primary key.
And I just go on interned.
Everything else is good on,
then.
I'm just going to have another column.
That's his name.
So this this would be the idea,
and this will be the name.
My name would be the name of the specialty.
So the text value that is associated with this idea will go in.
This column aren't on.
Then I'll just meet that one of our char on.
I can do this 1 50 on,
then I'll save.
And so I have two tables.
So I have specialty specialties and I have attendees so know that we have this new table on
the block and we need to establish that specialty I d from the specialties table is
somewhat related to an m Just going to click on the table here,
attendee.
Unethical.
Suppose with African structure on,
we want to establish that these two are related and literally the word related applies
because in databases you have what you call relationships.
So we need to establish that there is a relationship between the specialty i d in our
attendee table on the specialty I d in our specialties table aren't so I'm going to go back
to my attendee table Click on the structure on that I'm going to click relation view.
So have table structure were relation view on Then this will know asked us to set up what
we call foreign key constraints.
No,
In a nutshell,
our primary key is a unique value in in one table meaning attendee,
I d is the primary key in their 10 de table.
However,
we need to reference the primary key off the specialty table inside the attendee table,
and that's what makes it a foreign key.
So it's a primary key in the specialty stable.
But over here in that 10 detail is going to be,
ah,
foreign key.
Another thing with this constant is that if I have four specialties in the specialties
table,
I can't reference value in the attendee table.
That doesn't take this done.
That said so It's another level of protection to make sure that your data is going to be
clean and it's going to be solid.
So I'm just going to add this constraint name and number one to give it a name that tells
me what it is for so f k short for foreign key on.
It's a foreign key between attendee Onda Ah,
specialties.
All right,
so that's my naming convention.
You could name this puppies if you wanted to,
but if you name the puppies and took a sabbatical and came back,
I looked at your court.
It wouldn't make much sense.
So the point is,
you want to give this a name that is actually symbolic off what it is for so my knees
saying that this is a foreign key constraint between the attendee table on the specialty
stable on.
I can leave the restrict if you change this.
The cascading means that if you delete the primary key value from the primary table that it
would delete every related value.
So I'm going to leave these for no on.
I'm going to add the column from the attendee table,
which is specialty I d on.
Then I'm going to select the database that this is related to.
So we're still in that tendon,
Stevie on then the table inside off attendance.
Db is specialties on,
then the column is specialty idea,
so it's always going to default.
Whatever.
The primary key is off the next team that you say there's a relationship with because it
knows that clearly air trying to relate it to the primary key.
So if you don't see it up here like this,
that means you didn't set up your primary key properly.
Now,
once again,
if you want more in depth understanding off databases,
relationships,
SQL all of those wonderful technologies,
he can trick on my other videos.
My SQL database development and mastery or Microsoft SQL Server for everyone.
Now,
having done all of these things,
we can go ahead and click Save on,
then this would actually have executed this quarry on set up that const range between the
two tables.
If you need to quickly modify your table and make something the primary keys because you
may have missed it or you didn't quite understand it the first time,
you can always take the column and click primary.
All right,
And then,
if you want to make it off the increments,
you can go ahead and click.
Change on that will kind of bring it back to the design view where you could go ahead and
write all of what you may have missed the first time.
That is it.
For over database designed for this small application,
you will always have access to PHP,
my admin and for every application that you build and you might need a database for,
you can always go to local host slash PHP.
My admin.
Go ahead and create your new database on all of the tables that you require.
If you need further information or have any difficulties following the steps in this video
,
feel free to drop me a line and I'll be sure to follow up with you