Hey,
guys,
In this video,
we continue our task off,
hooking up our registration form toe our database.
You know,
previous video we went into Petri my admin and created our database.
With two tables on in this video,
we will look into how we actually connect to this database from our web application.
Now,
to get that process started,
we'll go back to our project in visual Studio Court on What we want to do is at a new file
to this entire project on this fire will be responsible for handling the connection to the
database.
Soto get this party started.
I'm going to click on the folder that we created from the beginning called DB.
It's empty right now when we went to select it and create a new file in there.
And I'm going to call this file,
hon,
that CEO and dot PHP And that's just a naming convention.
The other tutorials or other sources may have it as db conficker or something else.
It doesn't really matter what you call the file,
but once again,
you always wanted to be indicative off its purpose.
Now,
inside this file,
I'm going to start off with my Ph B thugs on.
We're going to see how we build what we call a connection string on.
We'll be using what we call a PDO object.
No,
there are multiple ways to connect a data base in PHP.
They're what you call Ap eyes that alot or facilitate the connection between your PHP code
on the database on the one that we will be using is PDO Now.
The reason I'm using PDO is that it offers some more protection than other libraries
immunity So literally the letters PD or that's there video,
aren't you?
See other drivers like my SQL on you'll see my SQL I Those are less secure than PDO,
and video is the one that people recommend you use to prevent things like SQL injection on
to prevent against other security concerns.
Also,
by using the PDO method,
you actually reduce the need to connect to the database every time you want to do something
against the database,
so connections can be expensive.
Andi,
the more your application is being used is the more connections will be there.
So off course,
you want to minimize how often somebody connects,
even if they have toe a lot of the times.
You don't want to multiply that.
So video offers quite a few benefits to the traditional my SQL In my school,
I,
um ap eyes on.
But it is what we will be using in this course.
Noto start modifying or file.
The first thing that I'm going to do is the clear on variable,
and I'm going to call it host on.
I'm going to give it a value.
Now,
the volume giving it is relative to the database server,
meaning my database server is sitting on local horse locals and Petri.
My admin is just a window into this database server.
All right,
but the database server is at local host,
so I have two ways I can read toast.
I can see the word loca host.
Or you may also see people refer Toho,
co host by I.
P has 1 to $7.0.0 not one.
All right.
And I just put this I p address in the context if I attack this into my browser,
All right,
So remember what happens when I type local host into the browser.
It automatically.
Brose is to the sump landing Peach look what happens in a type that I p address into the
browser.
It also Brose is to this landing page.
And that's because that I p address is what the word local host results toe.
All right,
so you can use them interchangeably or in any time you were a local hosting dinner at this
I p and vice versa.
So if you see the i p address in any other example,
that's really what's this is just another way of seeing local host all right,
someone to leave it with the i p address.
So we would learn something new today on going to declare another very bacall db onda db
that we're connecting toe B b is short for database.
So the databases that were looking for and looking to connect toe he's the one that we
created on understand,
to double check and make sure that I have the name quickly,
which is attendance on the score db someone to type attendance on this score.
Devi Next we have a user.
No,
my my PC.
My admin did not promise me to log in when I was loading it on.
I did mention that if years prompted.
You could use route with no password and you would get through.
So by default,
once you install my school or Maria DB here,
you're given a default user called route.
All right,
so I'm just going to see route as the user on wherever there's a user,
there's always a request for a password on.
Now,
just a pass is equal to Andi by default route does not have a password.
If you were using having the my SQL Community Edition,
then you would have been required to put a password on to the roots user at the time of
installation.
But once again,
if you're using zump one mom for any of these ph B environments all in one installation
packs,
then you would have a user called Roots with no password on that will grant you access to
your database.
This is not the more secure way,
but this is your machine,
so it's fine off course in production.
Then you want to take greater consideration with your user name and password on The last
thing we're going to sit is Ah charset on.
This is really just see what kind of symbols we expect to be working with.
And I'm actually just typing this because this is a standard charge sets.
They don't necessarily have to remember this.
Just appreciate that it goes there.
All right,
so after declaring these variables,
I'm going to declare another one that I'm going to call BSN.
No,
de Yasin is actually ah,
terminology used in the PDO connectivity.
So it's the way that it connects to the database is just another engine.
All right,
it's short for data source name.
So if you ever heard off jdb c r o d b c are stuff like that,
they they all ds in is related to that kind off connectivity are so we're going to do is
actually build a decent connection using these values on.
I'm going to type it out one by one and explain as I go along.
So the first thing that we do is the clear variable TSN.
It doesn't have to be called the assemble once again making variables useful in terms of
their naming on.
I'm going to use double quotation marks because I'm just going to take advantage of the
interpolation one some typing in the text.
So we have my SQL.
So,
firstly,
we declare the driver This is the type of database that we intend to connect.
Oh,
no.
PDO actually supports different databases,
different drivers.
You can use it for Oracle if you had a Microsoft SQL database working with.
So this driver is saying that I am about to connick toe a my SQL database and we see colon
and then we feed some some parameters in tow.
This connector.
So the first parameter is host,
and it was the host equals on die can actually just use my variable.
That I said,
is host.
All right,
so I declared host here.
So instead of typing,
it's old inside of this string.
I'm just going toe tap it here.
So the advantage of this is that I can always change this without having to modify this
entire string on Another advantage is that they were going to do this once.
So it's not something that you do every time you want to connect with it.
Every time you're about to build a site,
then you have to do this.
But for the purpose of this website,
we only do this activity one time.
And in this file All right,
so I'm connecting to the horse that I just referenced.
Variable.
Next parameter is DB name on.
We declare db off top on.
We give it the name.
All right,
So I'm just making reference all of these things,
and then the other thing is charged it on Once again,
we call in the char set,
So this would have constructed on O.
D.
B C like connector four or my SQL instance that's sitting on local host as a as the value
here suggests on we want the database called attendance TV on the chance that that we're
working with is this universal and standard one.
In the next line,
I'm going to do what we call a try,
catch statement.
So try Catches are used for what we call exception handling.
So I see try And then I opened the curly breeze on.
Then after the second appear to bring someone to see catch on.
Then we opened up two parents sees,
and then we have the curly braces again.
So let me just walking through the track.
It's what this block does.
Is it attempts to do something that will be defined in between the open and close for the
try on.
Then if that feels,
then it You can specify what you want to happen here,
where they want to throw an exception.
You want to stop execution or just want to show a nice,
friendly error message that sometimes things happen and you would see a im im aero pop up
unexpected error.
A lot of the times this is what is happening.
They have tried.
They tried operation that you requested.
You didn't work.
So they say unexpected error.
So what we want to do is to try to connect to the database someone to declare on objects or
another variable on.
I'm calling a p d o on in PDO and win today find or declare a new instance off a PD or
class.
So this class is built into PHP.
So we're looking at some object oriented stuff on the inside the parent This is for the PDO
function or class.
Sorry.
We'll be passing in the values D S n So we're passing in Whatever value is inside of that
variable d s n.
Then we'll be passing in the user that was defined So we didn't use user initially on,
then were passed in the password on Dwell.
There are other apartments is that could go in there,
but right know that that's all we need.
So we just need the DS in the user on the past.
Now you notice that there is,
Ah,
little Red Line under the capture nets because we need to put what kindof exception we
intend to cats so you can actually go with those apparently sees in a lot of languages,
and it's just a generic catch.
But in this one,
you need the parent disease,
and you need to specify what kind off error you're looking for.
So in this situation,
since we're trying to connect to the PDO,
they gave us an option for PDO exception.
So we're watching to see if there's going to be an arrow with the PDO object.
Andi,
I am going to assign its toe a variable called E.
All right,
so once there's a PDO arrow during this attempt,
then it will catch the arrow on,
then store all the details off the era inside off some variable called E,
and then in the next line you can decide what you want to do it.
So inside of this sketch block,
I'm actually just going to say something like throw new on once used the word through,
it means is going to stop all execution and just display an error.
All right,
So you may not want to do that all the time on your try catches,
but in this situation,
we actually want an error to see if our connection is working or not.
So I want to throw new,
and then I am going to see a PDO exception.
Andi,
I'm going to put in some cord that will get me the message.
So this e here presents an object,
and this object has quite a few functions in it.
So I have a phone sign that says,
get message on this get message function is going to actually print what the era is seeing
.
So whatever the area is,
sometimes you want actually read the arrow so that you can Deeble property.
Once you catch the exception.
You can always get the error here,
so I could just echo this without throwing on a new exception.
But once again,
I actually want to stop the execution for something as critical as the database
connectivity,
but you can do it more elegantly by just maybe echoing that old.
There's an error with this,
but the page would still load,
So that's up to you.
So I will leave with this cord on what's once again.
What's supposed to happen is that it's supposed to attempt a connection.
Toe A.
My SQL server phoned a dislocation with this database on supporting that.
Charset on it supposed to try that connection using a user name and a password as provided
here.
So if anything is wrong,
well,
if nothing is wrong,
then this will,
Lord are this will be okay.
And if something is wrong,
then all execution will stop and you see an error message someone to make it a bit more
clear when nothing is wrong.
Island See echo.
So if it tries the connection and nothing goes wrong,
I'm going to see Echo Hello theater basis.
All right,
so if we see these words appearing somewhere on our peace,
then we know that a connectivity or the connection attempt was successful.
So now that we've done up this con file and it is in this director under DB what we want to
do is actually include it in our page,
someone to go back to my form on Dougherty Road.
The line.
So what I did was see require once on dime,
requiring the file db slash conduct PHP.
So not because it's not in the includes full.
That means I can't include it.
I have to include it.
Everything that is not native on the page that I want on the page.
I'm going to have to use either require or the include to get it where it is the is,
though it's only a matter off finding where it is.
So in this situation is in the folder db on the finally Mishcon.
I just see require once when the db folder and get me that file.
All right,
So when I refresh my form,
the expectation is that I'm going to see Hello.
Database somewhere printed,
and I refreshed on.
There we go.
Hello?
Databases being echoed to our peach.
All right,
so that's great.
So that's some progress.
No.
What if I got some off my details wrong?
Like like maybe I missed upon the i P address.
I did once to 7.1 dot 0.1.
There's no address anywhere near here that goes by this.
So if I attempted this connection with the wrong data,
what would happen is,
well,
what should happen is that Hilo database would disappear.
So apparently 1 to $7 wonders series valid.
So I'm just going to take with one.
Let's try that experiment So I botched some detail in this case.
Well,
my attempt a budget feel the first time,
but let's I know for sure this won't work.
So let's go back and see what happens on when I refreshed.
Then we see that we caught this error on what we're seeing.
Being printed here is the result off us calling the gets message function inside off the
object aren't so.
That's what happens when you are at your core.
That way on,
you could insert once again instead off throwing the exception.
I could have let me just comment this oats Onda let me echo on elegant message on.
I'm actually going to say something like,
Well,
I went to print in each one on I'm going to see no database phoned.
All right,
close my H one tug and I wanted to stand out and show that it's dangerous.
Understand,
added the CSS class from bootstrap class equals art.
And then here is one of the dangers off.
Using single quotation on double quotation marks,
I'm going to use double quotation marks on the outside instead on single on the inside.
Someone just made that change quickly on I went to see a text dash Danger.
So let me just refresh and show you that the paid still loaded everything still executed.
But the message is being printed,
as expected because no data business phoned.
So that's what I'm saying.
There are multiple ways,
the 100 year errors.
He can do it where it's doomsday.
If something doesn't work for associate,
give a nice message that's user friendly,
and it doesn't cause too much disruption to the flow of your sides.
Off course.
You give that based on how important your task is,
all right,
So I'm going to put but my exception throwing right there,
because if I don't cut into the database there is no form,
there's no nothing else will happen.
Are should happen.
So that's it for facilitating a connection to the database using the PDO object in the next
video,
we'll look at Hall.
We actually store the values in the database