Hey guys, welcome back to the course. In this section,
we're going to spend time planning a strategy
for growth that fits your specific use case.
The strategy that works for a SAAS software company
that helps developers catch and record bugs is going
to be different than, say, the strategy for a business
that manufactures toasters that let you imprint
low resolution photos you made on
your iPhone onto your breakfast toast.
That last one in fact has no strategy.
No one is going to buy that, and if anyone
listening works for Toasteroid, please call me.
I would love to become your spokesman. Anyway,
such is the case that if we systematically chase growth
channels, well, some are going to work out better than others.
Which one works out depends largely on who you are
as a person and what your business naturally fits
into. Your Chowpatti stand is probably not going to crush it
in the viral marketing channel. And as I will say and
continue to say throughout the course, guess what?
You only need one traction channel to work for you
and then you could become very successful.
The vast majority out there get zero channels to work.
So if you get one, you are on a rocket ship to Planet Money.
OK, next lecture, we're going to talk about you.
So, yes, you can step away from the mirror and stop
admiring your cheekbones for a second, because, hey,
we're going to talk about you. And hey, you're also
probably not going to miss out a whole lot, unless
of course you are chiseled and not at all like me,
a potato face.
All right, guys.
See you in the next lecture.