Are you guys welcome back.
So in the past dozen or so lectures we've covered the basics of video production from our first steps
in pre-production where we figured out what we're going to do and then through production where we actually
went and made everything.
Now all that work with preparation lighting audio and video hopefully led to an easy and rewarding shoot
where you used all that equipment.
We talked about so much with perfect accuracy and where nothing ever went wrong.
Was he kidding there's always something that goes wrong.
Moore's Law is definitely something that applies to video production and well maybe you haven't shot
any video yet you want to do it all later.
That is perfectly fine as well.
Well either way that leads us to the next phase which is post-production.
Now it's time to assemble all those video pieces into an amazing finished product.
This might seem daunting if you haven't done it before but we've already got our script to guide us
right.
I certainly hope you wrote a script now whatever you got from a rough outline to a detailed script or
even that one in the middle we talked about the two sentence script.
Maybe you even have a storyboard if you went crazy with it.
It will help you put together all the pieces for editing now.
In fact when we say post-production most of the time we're really talking about editing which is the
process of assembling the raw video pieces you recorded in the right order cutting out the bad parts
and bad takes stitching everything together so it looks smooth sinking the audio.
Deciding which camera to show what time etc etc..
Then the job of editing is to add finishing touches.
Now these finishing touches could be anything like adding transitions or basically things like fades
or dissolves.
Really just different ways to go from one shot or scene to the next.
We can do things like titles which basically means adding words to your video which can be text on a
screen somewhere or full screen graphics you just slide in there to show.
I don't know logos taglines or separate sections of a video.
I do this all the time.
I usually sit at the bottom of what's called a lower third title and sometimes I put it over my shoulder.
You can also add sound in music where you add more audio beyond the stuff you recorded with your main
subjects during production.
Maybe you need some sound effects to make the video cooler or might you just want to add some background
music to make your talking head video a little bit less awkward.
Now there's more you can do and we'll talk more about that stuff when we jump into an editing program
in our next lecture.
But that brings up a great question.
What kind of video editing software should you need.
Now let me give you a quick rundown.
Regardless of whether or not you're actually going to do the editing yourself if you're on a budget
yeah you should do the editing yourself.
If you're hiring someone else I think you should still learn the basics of it so that when you do hire
someone and work with them you can actually communicate effectively and know what they're talking about.
Now there are really three different categories of editing software at the bottom you've got the amateur
level and these are the things that your moms and dads will want to use to edit photos taken in their
iPhones from placation or soccer games with their cats chasing laser pointers.
They're going to use like video editor apps on their phone or a free program like i movie on the Mac.
Those programs do basic editing.
And those people don't generally need more than that now.
But at the top of the spectrum you have professional level editing programs.
Now these are for people who cut videos for a living whether it's you know instructional lectures like
this one movie trailers commercials you name it they need full featured programs with lots of power
especially if they're into creating special effects or animation.
It's possible you might be on this level if you have lots of experience editing video but some of the
pro software choices here can be a bit pricey but then of course you have the in-betweens So if you're
not an amateur you're not a pro Well you're somewhere in the middle and that's if i guess that's where
most you guys are.
Now that's the content creator level.
You plan on producing videos regularly you want them to look and sound awesome.
You might be dipping into some features to make them look even cooler but at the end of the day making
videos is not your life and you're not doing anything that hasn't been done a million times somewhere
else.
You just want software that's got some power behind it in case you need to do something fancy and you
just want to make sure it has a decent array of features and templates that can save you time.
Oh yeah.
And you also generally want something that's not going to break the bank entirely.
So I'm going to talk about some of the video editing software choices out there with content creators
in mind but pros should also pay attention to because there's quite a bit of overlap here.
All right.
So first we have Adobe Premiere which has been around for a very long time and it's been updated and
fleshed out to include just an abnormal amount of features used by video editors of all skill levels
and Adobe Premiere you can import video and audio from pretty much anywhere.
And there are a lot of apps and plug ins that are being built just to work with premiere.
It's really a powerful piece of software and one great thing about it is it runs on PCs and Macs.
You have a PC and you would hire someone who has a Mac.
Well you can both use premiere and that will actually help you sync up the the work you do.
Generally speaking though Adobe going to charge you 20 bucks a month for it.
So do you guys already have subscriptions to the Adobe Creative Cloud so maybe you have Photoshop and
Illustrator as well.
But it's in that package.
And now if you would accidentally fall asleep on your keyboard and ending this lecture I'd be perfectly
fine because Adobe Premiere is kind of the Endal all four are our level of video editing.
People who don't know a lot about video editing can use Adobe Premiere.
People who wanted to really advance stuff like full feature films can use Adobe Premiere.
It's kind of the default thing that the vast majority of editors will use and that's why we're going
to focus on it in the next couple of lectures.
Now in some cases premiere might be overkill like it's too many features and it takes a little bit too
long to pick up and use and that's why often people will stick with all their choices.
Now another program that I do want to talk about is what's called Final Cut Pro now Final Cut Pro there's
Final Cut Pro and the Final Cut Pro X which is Final Cut Pro 10 but it's essentially Apple's version
of Adobe Premiere and only works on Macs with Final Cut Pro It's kind of I consider it kind of in the
middle between movie and premiere where you do almost anything and with movie you can you can't really
do that much but what you can do you can do very quickly and it's got a lot of prepackaged template
stuff by Dhokha prose kind of right in the middle.
And it's actually what I edit with because I'm not a professional editor.
I have a lot of experience editing but I don't want to do for a living I don't spend thousands of hours
making videos just for fun.
Vettel get Pro is a perfect in-between for me it's easy to use but it also has access to a lot of professional
features.
But then also at the same time it really does focus on using templates and using shortcuts that can
get you to the promised land sooner.
So if you have a Mac that's one I definitely think you should check out.
It looks a lot better than premiere.
It runs a lot better but it is just not as powerful.
Now the next two programs I want to mention are there's Cyberlink power director and then there's Coral's
video studio.
Now these are really just a set below premiere in terms of power and available features but they're
also quite a bit cheaper.
However if you're someone in the middle range or you just look at Premier and you think it's overwhelming.
Well this is something you probably check out now Power Director and video studio are very similar to
each other.
They're both under 100 bucks both PC based and they're both you know PC Magazine seems to love them.
Power to for instance can support up to a hundred different video tracks at a time which is absolutely
crazy.
But hey you never know you might need a hundred videos in the same timeline.
That's nuts.
Video Studio also has a pretty nice reputation especially with its features including some cool stuff
you can do like with motion tracking.
That's basically where you lock onto a subject on the screen and add some kind of effect directly to
it.
For example you might want to mask out a license plate of a car in a video or you could add text on
a screen that moves along with a person or an object that's motion tracking.
So really those are kind of the four that I would think about.
There's obviously ones like Sony Vegas.
Some people really like it but it's kind of on the level like Power Director.
It's kind of in the middle.
If you have a Mac I generally say use Final Cut Pro because unless you really really want to get into
your editing it has pretty much everything you would need.
But Dolby from here is pretty easy to actually suggest because there's nothing you really can't do in
it.
I mean it is it's really kind of the workhorse of almost all Video Productions.
Now aside from your experience level with editing choosing an editing program really comes down to a
few different questions.
First off how much video do you plan on producing and or in other words how serious is this video thing
for you if you're just dipping your toes in the water to see if you even want to make videos it doesn't
really make sense to spend a lot of money on equipment editing software but maybe you are ready to die
then you're really committed to this.
Well then you might need to find something it fits your plans or just pay for it.
Now if you have a lot of plans and a lot of videos you want to produce well and you probably should
go with something that's more versatile.
Now lower tier programs like Video Studio have pump the brakes on all the advanced features and things
you could do in a pro-level app like Final Cut Pro or Adobe Premiere but most likely they wouldn't really
need anyway.
So the video studio you're still getting a quality program it's highly recommended especially if you're
just starting out.
So if your community videos the next question is what type of videos do you plan on producing.
Not be playing on producing tutorials interviews and straightforward types of videos.
You can really use anything really to cut it together.
You need to shop around and look at the specific features you might want.
But generally most editing programs can do whatever you need.
Any point on doing a lot of screencast you might invest in a screencast recording software or editing
program like Cam Tasia or screenplay.
Or if you're cheap just use screencast romantic.
Those programs have screencast type features already built and like the ability to do picture and picture
mode screen highlighting or record for multiple audio sources and since you can edit your screencast
right in these programs it saves you time.
So in the end you could use an app like camp Tasia by itself or you could complement it with premiere
as well as Campton use campaign for the screencast take that video throw it into premiere or you edit
it in with your normal camera video.
Either way pretty legit.
So my advice is generally just to look in the mirror and see how serious you are about video.
If you're serious about it I'd probably go with Adobe Premiere and it's really only a monthly charge.
It's not that bad if you're on a Mac and you want to kind of work in a sweet spot where you want to
make good videos but there's nothing really off the top of your head that's really crazy and out there
that you want to do.
In Final Cut Pro is a pretty decent option.
Unfortunately you have to buy Final Cut Pro upfront and it's like $300 unless you pirate it.
But that's you know one thing is taken and 10 in mind is that you have to cough it up up front.
Then of course if you just want to stitch stuff together like an interview but you're not really going
to focus on editing like putting in graphics and illustrations and effects and things like that you
really don't think that's where you're going to make or break your videos.
Well then try looking into some of the other ones like video studio.
All right guys it's really what you need to know about editing software from an informational point
of view.
But we should definitely dive into a program and see what you can actually do with it.
That's going to be on our next lecture.
We're going to tackle Adobe Premiere and it's kind of important regardless of what software you use
because all of them have very similar elements.
All right guys.
Anyway I'll see you then.