All right guys welcome back.
Here we are with our grand finale the last lecture of our video marketing series Abdulla's point.
You've covered everything you need to know about the three phases of video production and most recently
how to get or fantastic the is hosted somewhere so you could put them on your site.
Now obviously we have taught every single thing you could possibly know because that would take roughly
nine to 10 years.
However we covered the crash course the basics of what you need to know to actually be effective.
The last piece of this whole puzzle is this question How can you tell if what you're doing is working
and video.
Great question and it's the subject of this lecture we got right here.
First of all you have to know where your analytics are where all the stats you'll be checking to see
what's working or not.
If you use a platform like YouTube to host your videos here's a hack.
Just go to YouTube dot com slash analytics and you'll see a very Google analytic view of your top videos
video views where people watch from and so on and so forth.
These are basic stats you get for the free service you're getting for free.
Pretty decent but paid services offer a lot more obviously.
Now we just just paid video hosting our last lecture.
Places like Vidyarthi wisdom sprout video etc..
So review that lecture if you need to.
Overall paid host will give a lot more detailed analytics about your videos but there can be a lot to
look at.
So really the question remains how can you tell if it's working.
The basic numbers like video views shares and likes help you see what people are reacting to and it's
a good first round type of indicator.
If a video really takes off and connects with people and those basic numbers will reflect that.
But the bigger question you have to keep in mind is are these videos helping you reach your business
goals.
Why did you start making these videos in the first place.
How was it to increase sales generate leads or make people more aware of you.
Chances are since we're trying to get our first 500 customers that's why you did video marketing proud
because you have 50 or 100 or whatever and you need something larger more consistent more long term.
But how you get to sales obviously doesn't really matter more brand awareness needs more people know
to buy from you more leads means more people you can potentially get to buy from you and more sales
just mean more sales.
So to get to the real impact of these videos I recommend checking out these stats.
Number one check out the percentage of video watched.
OK.
That means how long people stay tuned onto the video.
It's an interesting stat once you consider this industry trend.
Sixty five percent of video viewers watch more than three quarters of a video.
Now if you don't have sixty five percent of your viewers watching.
Seventy five percent of your video.
That means that you are below the baseline.
Maybe there's an issue but also keep in mind that the general statistics.
It really does depend on what type of video you're making and what industry are and bought but this
is a great place to start.
That stat can give you an idea whether or not your video is working.
Is it interesting or valuable.
Don't really be worried about people punching out right before the end.
When people have what they need and they anticipate the end they often will just click away before some
canned outros starts playing.
But if you haven't called the action plan for them maybe move that a little bit forward or tell people
about it before the end.
OK another thing check out is the ratio of page visits to video views.
That is if you embed the video on your page you want to know if anyone is actually watching it.
So for this you might require a little bit of math but you can do it I believe and you look at the percentage
of the people who visit a page where you have a video embedded you had a Google Analytics and you look
at how many people actually look at the page.
You can look at it in unique visitors or more realistically you should probably look at the page views
then what you do is you take that number and compare that to the number of views your video got in the
video analytics platform.
If less than say 50 percent of people are watching the video maybe the video looks interesting or it
might not make sense on that page or they actually don't see the video or there's no obvious reason
why they should play it.
But if the percentage is higher than well you probably got a good fit.
So are you taking advantage of that high view percentage to get people to take action afterwards.
A call to action at the end of the video like clicking a button or entering an e-mail address to get
more info to sign up for something or to download a demo.
Make sure you do that.
Can't say it enough.
Your video can support the goal you have especially the videos performing well.
So use analytics to improve your videos and to improve the ways you place and use your videos to support
your marketing.
Get in the habit where you check the numbers periodically.
Maybe once a week figure out a system so you don't go months without looking.
In the end don't get too hung up on absolute numbers.
There are many ways to gauge the success of individual videos and your video efforts as a whole.
Be sure to pay attention to all the information coming in from the dashboards on your video hosting
platforms to comments emails and more engagement in the form of shares and comments can lead to discussions
of viewers and customers better quality and placement.
Videos should lead to higher quality of people who complete the forums.
Not that you know there are higher quality people just that there are much better matches for the type
of customer or contacts you want.
So there you go.
Everything you need to know about video marketing how to create videos use them and measure them.
We've covered a lot of ground had some laughs but now it's your turn.
So get out there and create some videos.
If you're stuck just hit record.
Try to use some of the common formats we cover.
Try to fill in the gaps where you see problems in your marketing funnel and let the magic of video take
you forth.
Oh and also make sure to check your analytics make sure people are watching the video completing the
video and doing something at the end of it.
All right guys you got it.
Next we're moving on to the Get your thousand customers section.
We're going to start off with you.
So either.