All right guys, welcome back.
So in the last couple of lectures we went through the
basics of Snapchat, who uses the platform, what are
all the terms you need to know, how to
create an account, and where everything is.
Well, in this lecture, we'll discuss how to start
taking snaps and how to promote yourself.
You'll discover there's plenty
you can do to spread the word.
So snaps are the currency of
the land here in snappy chat land.
No blog posts or words need to apply.
Pictures and videos are the only thing that really works.
So you as a brand or a business need to think of ways
that you can use the visual format to communicate
and make some connections.
Like I've said before, this doesn't apply to everybody.
Some of you, it's going be harder to do visuals,
but I generally think it's worth trying
for most people. Now, taking a snap is simple enough,
you just go to the camera mode and then click the big circle.
You've probably taken thousands of photos in your
life, so you pretty much know how that works.
If you want to send a video through the camera mode,
it's a little bit different, you hold down the button
and then you see like a loading screen.
Now, you might ask, isn't this for my business?
Isn't this supposed to be professional?
Maybe I should get a professional camera crew, or lighting
setup, or something like that, where I start sending snaps.
Forget that, this is Snapchat. Just hold up your camera
and snap the picture, because everyone else, from
the Kardashian people to the guy down the street,
they're pretty much doing the same thing.
It's all about spontaneity, and if you aren't spontaneous,
then it kind of kills the vibe. Just like Snapchat
users embrace the idea that the picture is going to be gone
within either, you know, 10 seconds or 24 hours if it's a story,
they also know that everyone else is working with the same
toolset and the same structure, the same limitations
work for everybody.
Now, honestly, anybody making their pictures look too
good on Snapchat are going to actually look suspicious,
like they've got something to sell,
so that's something you want to avoid.
So that's how you take a snap, but to make an impression
with followers, that's just going to depend on what you snap.
And this is where you can make
a difference. Here on Snapchat,
you won't be writing blog posts or articles, obviously, and
you won't be posting long form e-books or producing videos.
Any of that content marketing stuff
is not really going to work.
So what exactly are we supposed to create here anyway?
This is the question that befuddles many marketers
and it's the reason why Snapchat is still an emerging
market. And I will warn you upfront, it is difficult.
It's very counter-intuitive,
and they didn't really make their platform
to make this easy on marketers.
But anyway, to answer that
question, what should you create,
you need to look at what's being done. Now, let's jump back
into Snapchat and look and see what other brands are doing.
Go to the camera mode and click on Search up at the top.
You should bring up a bunch of top stories, but also
a bunch of categories on the bottom. One of these
might relate to what you might do.
You've got "Around me" to see local Snapchatters,
then you also have music, sports, fashion, bars,
nightclubs, food, all kinds of stuff.
Scroll the category you like,
pick one that looks interesting, and then
tap it. Some of the snaps and videos you see might be exactly
the kind of thing you might do, and others just might suck.
In fact, most will probably suck,
but it's just a numbers game.
We're catching moments in time here for many people,
and they're not posed, they're not Photoshopped, and
they're not engineered.
Now, some snaps will have text and emojis, some won't.
My advice for you is just browse a bunch of these
Snapchatters, you'll see the kind of stuff that gets shared.
What do you like and what might
you want to try for yourself?
This is pretty much where you go for inspiration.
Now, asking yourself these questions might help as well.
What is my brand personality like?
If you could describe it, would it be,
I don't know, fun, playful, casual, serious, conservative?
Are you a rebel, are you a know-it-all?
Some mix of the above? And what Snapchat filters or
lenses would you use to then show off that personality?
Chances are, if you're trying to be professional and
serious, you're not going to be using the lens that
changes your face into a panda.
Also ask yourself "What would my followers
or customers like to see from my brand?"
Obviously, keeping it within the scope of Snapchat.
Is my target market the type of people that anxiously
awaits our next product or post?
Are they people that require constant care?
So they ask a lot of questions, or
they're not particularly on the ball at all.
What can I show them that will excite them, intrigue them,
amuse them, or inform them? Would they care about
how our product is made?
Would they care what our office looks like?
Do they care who the people behind the products are?
What can I show them here that I
can't show them anywhere else?
Do they really want to see selfies from our CEO?
Would they care about some of the things our team
does outside of work or charities we support?
So remember, you can answer any of these questions
with individual snaps, videos, or you can combine multiple
ones into Snapchat stories.
Pick some sort of topic and start snapping.
Let's look at an example, and this one is called Feet
Socks and it's a sock company that uses channels like
Snapchat along with Instagram and YouTube to post,
well, all kinds of different photos and videos.
But each channel is going to be different for them.
Shots from their professional photo shoots usually end
up on Instagram, but more random fun stuff, like special
promotions or even weird skits, or outtakes, or
behind the scenes, those generally go on Snapchat.
Now, one kind of snap that comes up a lot for brands
is that behind the scenes pictures I was talking about.
More than any other channel,
Snapchat really feels like the best place to share these
hidden moments just before or after events, during
the production process, when you're making your product,
or to catch up with people involved with your brand.
Show some of these moments that don't require you
to write an entire blog post or produce something
super fancy. Just take a snap and post it.
Related to this,
you could also offer sneak peeks of new products, upcoming
events, or promotions you plan on running in the future.
Let's look at another example.
Taco Bell, for instance, has done this a lot.
They'll create stories that are specifically about a
new product that's coming out and then tease out
details to its followers.
Watch out, here comes the
Quadruple Chalupa Queso whatever.
And yes, hey, you know, that works for them.
Taco Bell is a bit of a cultural icon
amongst people who like to get high.
But if you want to do something really unique and
exclusive to Snapchat, you could create what's called a
branded geofilter.
Now, branded filters are just like the regular filters
on Snapchat, except they're created by brands to
promote themselves and whatever else.
But a geofilter is tied to a location.
You have to be in a specific area, sometimes even
at a specific time, for the filter to become available.
For example, Starbucks created a branded geofilter
to promote their happy hour Frappuccino.
Snapchat users could take selfies with themselves
with this exclusive filter, and by sharing it, it would
help them essentially promote their
happy hour event and special pricing.
You obviously don't have to be a giant brand to do
this, but if you're someone who runs a meetup and
it's related to something, your business or
your product, you could do this if you wanted to.
And speaking of pricing, business
geofilters are actually pretty cheap,
it's something like $5 per 20,000 square feet.
So if you have a physical store or an
event where you might be appearing,
it's actually a tactic worth considering.
I did see one person do this once
when they were giving a talk.
They created a geofilter for the space of the talk
and then during the talk told people to do it. Now,
something else you might want to post is a shoutout.
Now, a shoutout is basically letting your followers
know about another Snapchatter out there that's
worth following, in the hopes that that account
will then give you a shoutout back.
For example, if there's a writer on Snapchat that covers
your industry and you developed an app they
might like, it'd be great if their followers
would follow you as well, right?
So you could snap a screenshot of their most recent
snap or story and then add text to it, like "Follow
this person on Snapchat" or "This person makes great stuff."
Now, in fact, this is so common that a lot of Snapchatters
will actually work out a trade in advance or they call it
a shoutout for a shoutout type promotion.
You just essentially ask the other Snapchatter to
give you one in exchange for one of your own.
You can actually do this through
the direct messaging feature.
Now, if the followers of both accounts are interested
in this, well, then it makes sense and it could
be a win-win and help you promote your stuff.
Now, speaking of promotion, Snapchat shouldn't be
your only channel, so don't treat it like your only child.
Cross-promote some of your Snapchat stuff on other
platforms. For example, create a story on Snapchat,
then download that story, post it on Facebook,
and then promote your presence on Snapchat.
You've got to make sure you recycle this stuff.
Post your Snapcode to your website along
in the other social media links and icons.
If you need your Snapcode,
go to your profile on Snapchat and click the
little Share icon under the Snapcode. It'll let
you download the image, so you
can put it wherever you want.
Now, if you have an email list,
and you might not yet at this point,
or maybe it's small,
you can put together a short announcement about your new
account, and that's generally a nice excuse to contact people.
Then you just write an email that's like, "Hey, some of you
guys have been asking if we're on Snapchat," and maybe
they've been asking you this, maybe they haven't,
doesn't really matter.
And then what you can say is,
you know, "The answer is now yes, we do have one," and
then you can put your Snapcode image and then just make
it easy for them to snap it and then encourage other
people on your list to download the app and follow
you as well. Plus, you can add what you'll be using the
account for, posting behind the scenes pics, sharing
discount codes is a great one,
say that like, "If you follow us on Snapchat, we share X
amount of discount codes a day, or per week, or whatever."
Give people a reason to care.
So sharing your Snapchat info across multiple channels can
drive people to your account and get you some followers.
Now, it's obviously not necessarily new followers,
but followers that follow you on multiple channels are
just in general more engaged,
more likely to buy your stuff.
Now, coming up in the next couple of lectures, I'm going
to share some ways to promote yourself on Snapchat
and expand your audience so that it's not just limited
to the people that came from your other
channels or your direct contact list.
All right guys, see you then.