Hey guys, welcome back. In this lecture,
we're going to follow up on the previous lecture,
where we identified how to get a list of topic based
forums for us to take advantage of and get in
touch with potential first 10 type customers.
Now that we have the forums listed out,
we need to reach out to the people that are in them,
and in this lecture we're going to cover two ways
of doing so that work at this stage of your business
development. There are, of course, other ways of taking
advantage of forums, but those are better suited
later when you have more time and
resources to dedicate to the effort.
The first strategy I suggest is,
number one, direct messaging them.
Now, the problem with online forums is that, well, people can
see what you're typing. Now, that's a good and a bad thing.
Good, because potentially more people will see it,
but bad, because you could find yourself up against
an angry mob of users hellbent on protecting
the community from corporate shills.
This obviously varies depending
on the culture of the forum,
and don't worry, we'll cover Reddit
in the next couple of lectures.
Oh, the notorious and mercurial Reddit.
Now, does every forum have direct message capabilities?
No, and that's why covering two different
ways is the way that we're going to do this.
Now, if it does have the ability to direct message, well, then
it would be relatively obvious to understand how this works.
First, find a thread that might be started
around your product area or industry topic.
There are really two different ways of finding this.
One is you can use that embedded
search function in the forum itself,
virtually all forums have this, and usually it'll have
an advanced option, and you can select whether
you only want to search things
like thread topics or full posts.
Really up to you.
Generally, full posts will get you more to look at, but that
also means you have more to actually weed through.
The second way you can do this, and this one is actually
my favorite, is to instead use the world's best
search engine, Google, to search through that forum.
Now, how do you do it exactly?
It's actually pretty simple.
Go to Google and type "site:" and then immediately
following that, no spaces, put the actual URL of the forum.
So if the thread you're looking at is like
"thisgreatforum.com/thread=blahblahblah",
then you just have to put "thisgreatforum.com."
If you only want to search a subdirectory, such as the
case where maybe you're using a forum where
only a subsection is relevant to you, then just type in
the subdirectory, "thisgreatforum.com/nameofsub."
The thing is that these embedded search engines
on these forums are usually just god awful,
which is really mind boggling, because it theoretically
has access to all of the pages on its site, so
shouldn't it have the biggest advantage?
I don't know.
I'd suggest you don't think about it.
It's kind of like having a stranger come into your house and find
your keys well before you even remember what room they're in.
Yes, Google came into your house and found you some keys.
Memorize that. Now, when you're searching,
don't forget to try key phrases that we
explored in the complainy people section.
Oftentimes, you'll have people say similar
things in these forums themselves.
Once you do some searching, you can narrow down on
what people are talking about, who is talking, and which
of the people in the conversation are potentially
someone with enough displayed interest that it might
be worth reaching out to them.
When you grab a handful of users, say, 5-10 or
10-20, depending on the quality, and you get ready
to write a message, what do you say?
Well, there are a million different ways to do this, but
I'll give you three different types of messages that
I have personally seen work best.
The best message you can send by far is going to
be based off something they specifically said in the
thread, followed by a reason for
why you are messaging them.
If they are, let's say, complaining about something,
tell them you think you can solve that problem that
they're complaining about.
If they don't know how to do
something, try explaining it to them.
Always round it off by telling them why you didn't post
in the general thread, because remember, it's kind
of weird that you didn't do it.
You can make something up or just explain that, you know,
you only wanted to message them and the thread
is so long anyway, you might not see it, blah blah blah.
So that is type one, respond to something
they said in the thread that you found them.
The second type I've seen work
pretty well is the feedback angle.
Now, you just message them with something
simple like "I saw you said such and such.
I'm working on something that is in that space,
I'm trying to figure out if people really want this.
What do you think?"
Or another way of doing this is to ask
"Can you give me your honest feedback?"
The key here though to make
this actually work is vulnerability.
People really don't like getting approached by strangers,
and specifically some of the more seasoned
users are actually hyper weary of people pitching
them and trying to actually sell them something.
So the way that you kind of get around that possibility
and diffuse the inherent tension is by being
as open and as vulnerable as you can.
Tell them the truth of where you are.
Tell them what you really think about your business.
Open yourself up.
It is much, much harder to shoot someone down
when they open themselves up to you like that.
And, worst case scenario, hey,
you've got some brutal advice.
So type one, continue the conversation
you saw them having, add some value,
point something out,
explain something, and then include your products
somewhere in the first message, or in the second one, or
just somewhere in there, as long as it's relevant.
Type two, just ask them as open as possible for feedback.
The point is it gets them on your
website, and if they're interested,
well, then there's a good chance they'll buy.
As always, don't get lazy and start
copying and pasting your message.
People can smell that really from like a mile away.
And if you plan on posting in here later on, people will
dogpile on you if they think that your spam messaging
people on the side.
Direct messaging is the best way to keep yourself
out of the fire and establish a direct conversation.
It might be a little tedious, but it will get you some
people looking at your stuff, and if you do it enough
times, people will start to buy or sign up,
whatever it is that you want.
Now, the second way of using this type of forum,
and 90% of the time you can actually do this,
is to just reply in the thread.
This is my second suggestion because its
quite a bit harder to pull off effectively.
However, if you do it right, you only need
to do it once or twice to get your 10.
Why?
Because not just one person sees it,
but many people could potentially see it.
Why exactly is this harder?
Well, because in general it's harder to please
a crowd than to please one person.
So you really have to tiptoe around
what you're going to say.
So read through the entire thread and
make sure you're not missing anything.
Don't get lazy, because if you repeat something someone else
has already brought up, you're going to get burned or ignored.
The number one thing that you want
to keep in mind here is value.
Am I adding value to this conversation or am I just
broadcasting something no one really cares about?
You can add value by sharing your experiences,
seconding opinions, sharing a resource you found, maybe
even doing some research to back up a comment
another person made, or just by asking a question.
Past that, there are three quick and dirty ways of
getting your product links in the actual thread post.
Number one, suggest it.
Someone mentions doing something and you suggest that
this product would make some aspect of their life better.
The key here is to not come off like you're trying to
convince them. Just say something like "Have you
tried this?" Or one thing I like to do is include
it with other similar or substitute products.
It's actually a lot harder to get called a shill when
you're just presenting options, and one of those
options happens to be yours.
You can, of course, present your option
as the best or the one in front.
I personally like to post and then insult
my own product, because, curve ball,
no one sees that coming.
The second way you can fit your product
into your post is to put a link in your footer.
Now, people read your comment, then they see this
little bio sentence at the bottom, and then they can
check out what you're doing.
It's pretty simple.
Most forums allow it and most people
will put something at the bottom.
Again, just make sure you're not
trying to convince them to go,
where you're saying like "It's 20% off at this website."
Just put it there.
This is what I work on. And last, but not least, you can
openly state that you own the product that you're
inserting in and just kind of own it.
You could say something like "I'm sorry,
but shameless plug, I made this."
People generally have an okay reaction to that.
After that though, it's best to then justify why you're
not just inserting it randomly into a conversation.
Again, relevancy is always going to be the key here.
OK, so now you're ready to go out and do this one.
Make your list of topic forums, do the digging to see
which ones you can use and are worth tackling.
If you can't find any,
well, you're just not trying hard enough.
Then do some lurking and gather some threads that
you think are on your topic or gather some individuals
you have seen that have displayed
interest in your category.
Direct message them if you can, and if not, try your luck
posting and participating in the forum, with of course
the link being slipped somewhere into the discussion
or into the footer.
Okay, children, go run free and
ruin forums for everyone for eternity.
See you next lecture.