Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
So we've talked about white papers e-books and email courses and our most recent lectures here on lead
magnet.
Next up we're going to cover one more type of weed magnet that many many marketers use and that is called
the Web and are now webinars are online seminars.
Generally you use an online presentation platform to give a presentation or conduct some kind of discussion
with other speakers.
People sign up for this webinars and attend virtually so you can have people from virtually anywhere
watching asking questions and hopefully participating in different ways.
Voters are usually 60 minutes long that's just kind of standard and they're usually free because many
of the businesses hold webinars to generate leads for its business.
Typically it's the case that they make a pitch at the very end of the 60 Minutes like there's other
lead magnet type white papers e-books and e courses and our ads are all about giving away value in exchange
for email addresses and other personal info so businesses can use them for marketing and promotion.
For example leave pages holds a weekly Web and promotes it with a video preview description and bullet
points you understand the value you'll get by attending.
Pretty common for a company to have one person in the company like the marketing person or something
do weekly webinars and you know the ideas you get to see it live.
Lots of interesting and someone in that company who knows what they're talking about so it's an expert.
So what are the benefits of creating and running a webinar.
Well showing off your expertise obviously is a big one.
If there is a topic your audience cares about holding Webinars on that topic and sharing helpful tips
and best practices proves your worth.
You've built a project management app it would make sense to hold the webinars about how to manage projects
better.
For example recordings of your revenuers could also be used to show off the breadth of your knowledge
especially if you do them consistently like once a month.
What Banaras are also an opportunity to reuse some of your best content.
You wrote a really good blog post about the steps to follow do know keyword research.
Google Adwords Well you could base a web on the same staps but use the format to go into deeper detail
and answer questions along the way.
Or you just use it as an opportunity to just do it as opposed to just give instructions.
Now what is an advantage over other lead magnets and that they're presented in a multimedia video type
format video webinars can't feature a shot of the presenter speaking over a full screen image of a presentation
slide or doing a walkthrough of an app or a platform.
One of my favorite benefits of these is that you only have to do them once writes a book.
You have to write the whole thing takes a lot of planning and creating the content.
Writing in and perfecting it with the webinars if you have an expert.
Not have to prep that much and you can kind of just put them on for an hour and there you go.
Collecting leads is certainly a benefit but with webinars you can also learn more about the attendees
by asking questions webinars are meant to be interactive so you could field questions from your audience.
But you could also plan times you asked them like poll questions have them jump in discussions and let's
say give them surveys after the webinars over webinars can also be a nice way to show off your personality
and make new connections the web in our format means you or another speaker will be in front be in front
and center.
Attendees will see and hear you and set of your blog posts or your web site being the voice of your
business.
You could be that voice.
Just remember unengaging web in speaker can convert a lot more attendees to paying customers than say
boring and unprepared one.
So what kind of businesses use webinars as lead magnets hold God a lot.
Any business that experts and expertise to share would be a good fit for webinars.
Secondly if you sell info products fantastic for web and are lot online courses will sell through webinars.
You're essentially giving a presentation on line so the more experience you have with different topics
the wider range you've got to pick from and thinking about webinars you can do business is offer some
kind of consulting or training services.
Also are natural fits Fitz's webinars and they can just offer a taste of what they do.
That also applies to product based businesses especially like software.
You can do a webinars showing how to use it or showing how awesome it is.
It's also something you commonly see in B2B.
So would be to be the business of business sometimes they won't even sell directly on their website.
Sometimes you will just want to do a demo and then sell because it's a higher contract value when you
actually do sell to a company.
These experts don't have to be people from your company necessarily.
Plenty of webinars are produced and hosted by one business but then feature outside experts.
Organizations like the wanto found the society of petroleum engineers know.
You know when they want to educate their members on topics like personal branding.
Outside experts probably probably going to be better for them.
Businesses that sell service platforms specially complex ones with lots of features are also a good
fit for webinars.
Being able to screencast and app talk people through steps and answer questions means the within our
format can be used for Q and A troubleshooting and potentially selling people on solutions you might
offer.
The platform is popular enough.
Think of something like I don't know Google Analytics you'll find a lot of people offer web in our training
including Google themselves.
However this leads me to the disadvantages of the Web and our format.
Things that you should probably keep in mind.
Well video recording itself might have a short shelf life after business.
The web aren't many of them will post their Web and are recording on their blog or an archive.
Or you put them on YouTube as well.
But if the subject of the web in our say is a platform it changes over time new features get added for
example the women are becoming out of date.
If you wrote a blog post on how to use something it's pretty easy to go in an edit.
What's changed with the web are you.
It's hard.
You might have to redo the whole thing even with other lead magnet formats like e-books.
It's pretty easy to just swap out swap out screenshots for example or change the tax when changes happen
with webinars.
Well odds are you might have to record entirely new version.
That sucks.
There's another issue to consider as well.
You need to have some presentation and public speaking skills.
You're not the kind of person who enjoys giving talks well webinars might not be your fit.
Or maybe you could find someone else to do them for you.
This forum generally requires somebody with enough confidence and experience with the topic to stand
in front of a virtual crowd or you know probably just sit with a microphone and a headset.
Either way you need to be able to speak well and think on your feet.
If you don't have the experience obviously just don't count out webinars.
It might just be the case that you need extra practice before you do one and I do recommend attending
at least a couple other ones to see what they're like.
Try your best to avoid the really really spammy ones though so all the really webinars have a lot of
potential value.
The promise of that value on landing pages and other promotional materials in ads is what can get people
to sign up but the quality of your webinars will keep the audience coming back and recommending you
to others.
So in our next lecture on how to plan and conduct the webinars of your own.
All right guys.
See you then.