Hey guys, welcome back.
So, in this lecture, we're going to briefly go over
how we can take the same principles of posting and
direct messaging, but now apply it
to an online community called Reddit.
Now, I know, yes,
yes, we already did a little bit of Reddit,
but you've got to get used to this system.
We're going to repeatedly dip back into the same groups and the
same broader strategies as we progress through the course.
And of course, as we go along, the
strategies are going to start to change.
They're going to be a bit longer, slightly more complicated, and
in general, will have a higher potential to get more customers.
And since we're keeping it simple and still only
looking for that first elusive first 10 customers, it
shouldn't be too difficult to get them to show up.
Just like your 14th birthday party, which consisted
of you, a Tivo, and some questionable tissues,
we're still just trying to get that first 10 to show up to
the party, and it really shouldn't be that hard, should it?
Reddit, not to sound like a broken record, is one of my
favorite places on the internet, and not coincidentally,
it's a great place to find a wide variety of people all over the
world that are making their preferences known publicly.
Ho-Ho, you suckers with your publicly
indexable displays of interest.
Time for us to take advantage.
Reddit, if you haven't figured this out, is divided into
what they call subreddits, which are basically subforums
dedicated to one particular topic, and
they can be as broad as technology,
interior design, and, say, productivity, and they could be
as obscure and hilariously random as "Where is the soda?"
which is a half a million person strong community
dedicated to finding clips of infomercials and then
cutting them to make them play out
of context and thus make no sense.
Or they can go as far as another sub called "Fish
screaming," which is a sub dedicated to high resolution
images of fish with their mouths open plus text interpretations
of what the community thinks they sound like.
Or, of course, the famous sub "Birds with arms," a sub
dedicated to, yes, people who like to Photoshop pictures
of birds and then put arms on them.
Reddit is a great example of everything that is right and
simultaneously everything that is wrong with freedom of speech.
So if you remember from the previous lectures, what tools
do we have in our toolbox? What do we load our spam
projectile gun with, if not 100% grade A Hawaiian spam?
True story.
No one actually knows how to spell Hawaiian.
Well, we have tool number one,
the direct message, which is as potent and as
effective as cornering someone in an elevator
until they buy your Herbalife lotion, and then we have
tool number two, which are the community conversation
tricks, which aren't really tricks so much as ways to
tweak regular behavior to drive traffic to your site.
So, in this case, in the land of
Reddit, can we direct message?
Oh yes, yes we can.
You can actually direct message anyone.
So first off, just go through some
of the subreddits, and if you forgot,
just remember to use the embedded search up at the
top right corner and it'll give you subreddit suggestions.
Or you can just Google in Google
"popular reddits" or "subreddits" + some
keyword that has to do with your industry.
After you do some trolling, just make a
shortlist of the people you want to message.
In this case, there's really no real
number that we're trying to shoot for.
You know, if they're relevant,
they've been talking about things that are relevant, and
you don't feel like a complete idiot reaching out to them,
well, then throw them onto your list.
You're probably, if I had to guess, across all the student
use cases are actual physical products, online SAAS
tools, whatever else you guys are doing,
you'll probably get open rates or reply
rates similar to cold email campaigns.
You might get a response 40% of the time.
Now, on Reddit, the best thing you can do if you want
to message someone is to first force an engagement
with them. Click their profile, and after you click their
profile, you can see where they've been posting.
Click through on one of those posts and then just respond.
You can do this to one or two or three.
Doesn't really matter.
The point is though that you want to get them to then
respond to you responding to their comment, and
then hopefully to start a dialogue. At that point,
now that they know who you are, they've at least seen your
username, then you can actually direct message them,
and if you do it that way, with a precursor, that will
dramatically increase the rate at which you get
responses, and it'll lower the chance they just yell at you.
It'll look like a continuation of a conversation, which is the
needed magic pixie dust of cold messaging, called context.
Now, as far as the second strategy of
community posting goes, it'll be very similar.
Try to stake out some of the threads where people are asking
for help on something - they're honestly everywhere.
Once you find a thread where someone is asking for help,
then just try to respond, and guess what?
Try to be as helpful as you can, while correctly inserting
your link without making it look too obvious.
In Reddit, there are no footers to abuse,
so make sure you are careful, and just try to very
seamlessly put it in there without raising suspicion.
With Reddit, people seem to be a little
more sensitive to the use of links,
so just make sure that you're not going over the top.
If you want to be really careful, try posting around a couple times
first with no actual active strategy for promoting your link.
That way, if you post a couple of times, when people
click through to your profile, which they will do,
they don't just see a wall of self-promotion,
you actually look like a normal user.
All right, guys, so try to take those two
techniques and apply them to Reddit.
Reddit is a little bit different, but we just covered
how it's different and how to change your strategy.
All right. Good luck.