OK guys we are back.
Thanks for being here.
So we've been running through some various steps now for getting PR coverage in the most recent lectures
we've covered how to find research and get the attention of some of your prospective contacts.
These reporters and bloggers and writers are on your list.
And if you've reached this point you've been getting ready to finally pitch them.
Just remember to go through these steps first and don't start your process here.
OK.
All right so once you're ready to reach out to a reporter or journalist you're going to need a simple
piece of information or e-mail address.
Now e-mail really is the best way to pitch people in general.
Reporters prefer it to social media messages or phone calls because well they can organize email keep
all those pitches and ideas in one place.
Also easier for them to ignore which is just being polite.
So pick their preferred method of communication.
Some might prefer Twitter but most of them are going to prefer email but this very simple piece of info
their email address isn't always simple to come by.
No not every journalist publicly lists their email address.
In fact very few do.
Why.
Because if they did they'd just get bombarded.
In order to get their email you need to do a process called email hunting and it's a process that every
would be marketer or just anyone who needs to do cold emailing in general absolutely has to know it's
a fantastic skill.
Trust me even if you have no interest in PR This will help you a hundred times over.
But the way it works is pretty simple.
What's your email address.
No seriously don't blurt it out at the screen.
I mean actually think about it.
I'm just going to take a weird gasp just to and out on a limb here and say that your username probably
has.
Oh I don't know your first name and or your last name in it.
Right.
Look at that.
I'm pretty much psychic.
I can even guess that your email provider is either going to be where you work or a generic provider
like Gmail or God save you Hotmail.
If everyone uses the same username and uses pretty much the same predictable email providers then hey
it's pretty easy to just guess their email.
Now you can do this manually if you for some reason wanted to do just that.
You would just take the person's first and last name and then permute it as we call it into 25 or so.
The most common combinations found in email addresses the top 25 permutations just printed is a fancy
word for different combinations of first and last name.
As a user name will cover easily 95 percent of all email usernames.
If you're trying to find my email address Well you can probably guess e Kimbrel or Evan K or Evan dot
Kimbrough.
There's a pretty good chance you get it.
You don't have to keep going to get the correct one but well that's your problem.
Well I personally hate doing this process manually so I use some tools now the first tool does the least
amount and will go through a couple more tools where they get progressively more complicated.
The first one is just called email permutations by Metric sparrow.
Put a link to it over in the resource is pretty simple.
All you do is you put in the first and last name of the person and the name of their domain and what
it does it just spits out the top 25 combinations.
You can try emailing.
Then what you do is you just copy and paste that and when you send an email to put it in the TO category
or if you want to be Slye put one in the two and then the 24 other ones in the BCSC so that when they
get the email it doesn't look like you sent it to 25 people.
That's kind of bad form.
Then what happens is you sent out the email and guess what.
24.
Most of the time will just bounce just won't go through and that last one will get through now.
I've had some people mention this before like doesn't this ruin my email provider's spam score.
No Know it all only matters if you're sending out thousands of emails if you're telling this to ten
or a hundred people.
It's just not going to make a difference.
Spammers get knocked down because they're sending hundreds of thousands of bad emails like this.
Anyway that's a pretty cool tool but it can get even better.
Now the next tool can go a little further with it's called email Hunter.
They install a browser plug in such that you can go to LinkedIn and then look at anyone's profile and
you click the hunter button on their profile uses their profile info to make their best guess at what
their email is.
Now I'd say it's right maybe 70 percent of the time.
Now you might get wrong emails but like we said before we're going to try to contact a lot of press.
So it really shouldn't matter if for some reason your emails are the same person are going through.
Well then you can keep trying try other domains or other combinations or I don't know just how to do
a little bit more research.
If email Hunter now is too much for you and let's say you already have all the info for the targets
compiled and you don't necessarily need to trawl through LinkedIn to find everyone.
Well there's another tool you can use and this is the most advanced but actually the simplest version
and it's called Law Norbert.
Yes I know it's a goofy name and it's incredibly hard to remember but they do have a tool that does
the same thing but simplified.
You just plug in the names you know and the domain you know and it just does its best to look up the
email and it gives you confidence rating and how sure they are that this email works now the way that
they work is they'll just automatically look up the names vs the domain and what they'll do is they'll
ping the e-mails server over and over again to see which e-mails actually exist on that server.
So it actually can save a lot of time by looking for what are called M-x records.
Then also it has a massive public database of all the other ones that have worked in the past.
A lot of times you types in again somebody else search that person's email Well it'll automatically
find it if they found it before.
All right so there's a few different ways you can hunt down someone's email address but if all else
fails if you've made contact with a reporter before you can always just politely ask if you haven't
engaged with them before then well I'd try one of the techniques I've just mentioned earlier.
Now once you have their e-mail address then you need to write something.
And that's what we'll start talking about in our next lecture.
See the.