All right guys welcome back.
OK now that we've talked to link structure and architecture in our last lecture there's a few more techie
kind of best practices you should use to optimize your site.
This lecture I'm going to go over the robot's text file and a few other things to prepare your site
for those creepy crawlers that Google uses.
So a robot stopped text file is a text file that you put on your Web site that tells webcrawler what
to access and what not to access.
On your Web site now Google sends out its web crawler its message is an algorithm that crawls through
Web sites looks for links.
The news there's links to go find other websites and just bounces around pretty much permanently making
their massive index of Web sites.
Anyway you were one of those crawlers hits a Web sites one of the first thing it does is look for a
robot's text file and the file gives you a chance to tell Google a few different things.
One tell Google which directories to index like where your great stuff is located.
Number two you can also tell Google which directories to skip.
Now these be the parts of your site with files that you don't want indexed or showing up on public search
results.
For example you have to skip directories where you developing new stuff or pages that aren't ready yet.
Like say your production server or you know use Wordpress you don't want it to constantly keep displaying
the log in page for your Administration panel.
So goes without saying you might want to add an internal use pages onto that text file and some people
also tell Google to skip directories of certain file types are stored like a directory full of say important
PDX or video files.
Especially if you're making lead pages where they have to sign up to get the file.
Well kind of defeats the purpose of ego and Google search and just find the file.
You can also use the robot's text file to tell Google where your sitemap is located.
In our last lecture where we talked about creating that SML site map for your site is really easy to
just use any free tool we use at SML Dasch sitemap dot com.
While listing that in your robot's text file will tell Google where that sitemap is before it crawls
and indexes anything.
Now truth is you don't have any parts of your site where you're worried about Google finding.
Well in the robot's text file really is not a big concern.
It might not really even be necessary.
My advice either way is to create one so you know it's there.
In fact do you right now know if you have one.
Well this is a good thing to check.
Go to your you r l and then just put Flash robots taxed after the euro and that's generally where it
should be located right in the main root directory of your website.
So if something shows up some lines of text should show up in your browser window you're good.
Very If you can do this for pretty much any Web site out there but some robot's text files are more
elaborate than others.
Here I'll show you an example of one even if you didn't ask for it.
If you go to pita pit you say dot com.
Easily a place I go to 10 times a day.
You'll see the home page for pita pit whatever that is.
They sell PITA's maybe out of the pit.
I'm just I'm just guessing here but if you type in pita pit slash robots are taxed after the address
bar.
Well you'll see a super simple three line text file and you also see where PITA pit hides all their
secrets.
Looks like kind of like this like user agent disallow WordPress blah blah blah blah blah allow WordPress
W admin admin.
OK you get the point.
Here's what the code means the user agent bit with the star after it basically says any crawler can
come in here to crawl and index these pages and you can an attribute tell certain callers not to call
the site or you know just do it in a different way.
Less Crawley disallowed tells the user agent the crawler above not to crawl a certain your Arel and
as you can see here it's a WordPress admin directory like I talked about before.
Internal pages.
They don't what their WordPress log in page for example to be indexed and listed on the search results.
Kind of weird.
Allow of course tells the user agent above definitely Crawl's specific you are Elen in this case it's
a PH P file inside that's in a disallowed directory.
So they've made an exception here for some reason.
Now they thing Peter pick could add if they had it was a u r l of a sitemap.
Now if they created and uploaded next XML sitemap Generally you'd add in a line of code to the bottom
of the robot's text file and look something like this.
Sitemap looks like PITA pit slash wherever sitemap is so pretty much an amateur move on the part of
it so you might wonder if this is the entire robot's text file.
Does that mean Google is only indexing one thing from the site that HP file.
No that's not actually not what it means.
All of the PITA pit people did was note a couple of exceptions.
Don't cross this but do Krull this one.
But aside from that Google will just crawl whatever I can find as it follows links throughout the site
as long as they aren't listed in the no follow section.
Now keep in mind if you don't have one of these robots textfiles at all.
Kernels are just going to assume that everything is fair game.
Now if you're in need of one of these magical text files for your site you also just use a free file
generator from the peep's that it's SBO books Dot com.
Just don't what you are or else you allow or disallow if you have any exceptions in mind and it'll put
it all together for you.
And only if do is just loaded onto the main director of your website.
Now you might be ready to set up a text file and perhaps you know for a fact you a section of your site
where personal information gets stored on pages.
People's ages.
I don't know names credit card numbers and I hope not.
You should really be careful with that stuff specifically.
Now send all that info to me.
I promise I'll take it seriously if you have parts of your site where sensitive information is located
you really do not want that index and then available through Google's ERP is imagine someone searching
for credit card numbers.
I can steal and your site comes up.
That would suck anyway.
In the case where you know pages of data like this that shouldn't be public it's recommended that use
a different kind of code.
Tell Google not to index it and it's called Big surprise.
The no index file instead of listing these pages in the robot's text you go right to the page itself
and go to the head section of your HMO code.
Remember we were doing this before really and it's the title of the page well right in the same exact
place you can add another line of code if you have a page that should not be indexed by adding this
line the robots like Googlebot for example might cross your page.
But when it sees this code it will not index it.
So this way you protect the page and add stuff.
So there you go.
Robots dot tax and no index.
Use them to prepare your site for the crawlers.
Help speed up the process of indexing and protect any parts of your site that shouldn't be made public.
Now one quick question which is should I make one of these even if I have nothing to provide as an exception
for the crawlers and in general.
No it doesn't really matter.
It's not you're not going to get any Seob value inherently from having this file.
It's just more so to help you get the most out of search engines and not to have some awkward situations
and optimizing what shows up in their search results regardless of where it ranks is half the battle.
So anyway that's it for now in the next lecture.