All right guys welcome back.
So spent last lecture talking about webinars what they are and why they're great for generating leads.
So we'll talk now about how to create one of your own.
The first step is to decide on the web on our topic.
Pick something that appeals to your audience so they'll be compelled to sign up.
Try to form the idea into a clear and interesting title.
Nurses and doctors might like this one.
Dealing with difficult patients and their families or how to position yourself for promotion might appeal
to people who want a shitty job that pays better.
Many of our topics end up sounding like blog post titles but ok since the idea is roughly the same thing
you want to attract people with the cool sounding topic that they're going to be interested in and if
they know it's 60 minutes long and they can't sound like it's really dry and boring.
However don't be afraid to use your product or platform as the topic for your webinars.
Doing a platform demo seminar for example is something plenty of businesses do you just want to make
sure the seminar is helpful and don't make it to sales.
For example user testing just two or three webinars a month and mixes up topics so some weeks that talk
about industry events and popular topics and other weeks they focus on how to use key features of their
platform during a series of webinars while you should consider how your women are fits in with your
full schedule.
Try not to repeat topics because you won't get the same people back.
Plan out a series of complimentary topics over multiple webinars So your attendees will have continued
interest in whatever you're doing.
So what might your topic be for a web.
Maybe you'd want to do a Webinars on current trends in your industry or a how to tutorial for people
who use your product or platform.
The only trouble coming up with ideas.
Give these tips a shot.
Number one look at your most popular blog posts or social content.
Whatever is getting the most engagement likes comments and shares is probably hitting a nerve for some
reason.
Adapt that idea for a seminar format and build on what you learned from the earlier posts.
For example someone might ask a question on Quora that could answer like how do I monetize YouTube videos
while you compose an answer on Quora.
But if your audience would be interested in your answer as well you can also create a web that are on
the same topic and then go into more detail.
Also you can post ancora and then say oh by the way I did a Webinars on it.
Click here to ask your audience.
You could put up a question in a forum send out an email or post a survey on your website ask people
what topics they'd be most interested in hearing more about.
You don't even have to say it's for a webinar user's responses to plan webinars and the other posts
that you want to create.
Number three research competitor webinars.
Who else is putting out webinars that your audience might like.
Research your competitors and see what they're doing.
Attend one you can see how they're webinars and figure out how to make yours even better.
So once you have a topic in mind you'll figure out who will be involved with planning and the execution
of said seminar.
Someone needs to repair slides and write up scripts and notes half a script but it's generally a good
idea.
Someone needs to be the main speaker.
You might even need a weapon or helper as Wallack someone to advanced slides and answer any tech questions
all the seminars going and if you plan on featuring a guest speaker Well you'll need to invite them
as well.
So who are all these people.
If you're the writer and speaker great you have less people to try and wrangle.
But if there are other people potentially involved you'll need to contact them obviously in advance.
Get them to commit and put it on their schedule and obviously you got to remind them about it coming
on and making sure they show up.
Was problem.
The next step is to create an outline work through your topic and decide how you can break it up and
easy to follow sections.
You might decide to work with a speaker to develop it or have them do it themselves.
It's actually a really easy thing to do if you have an audience.
You say to an expert.
I have an audience.
You have information.
Why don't you teach it to my audience.
And it gives you exposure and it's a great way of keep upping the attention and engagement and retention
of my audience.
And irregardless if you creates the outline be aware of how much material you are probably going to
need to be creating mini webinars are scheduled to last an hour.
They usually have some kind of intro telling people who the speaker is and what the topic is as well
as housekeeping announcements.
Things like this is being recorded.
Do you have any questions.
Do this and whatever you write decide designed to build in time at the end of the hour for questions.
Maybe five maybe 10 maybe even as high as 20 minutes.
Up people are there so in a lot of cases you'll be responsible for coming up with roughly 40 to 45 minutes
of actual presentation content for an hour of webinars.
This amount of time is what you need to keep in mind as you write your script so take your outline it
start fleshing it out.
One hour should be as interactive as live in-person presentations are.
So make sure you build in places for actual interactions.
Just because this is online doesn't mean you need to speak on a headset for 40 minutes straight playing
to ask questions.
Get people involved.
How they respond will depend on what Web platform you use.
But usually people can do like a text chat reply.
They might be able to answer a poll on screen and other times they might be able to speak on their microphone.
As you're writing up the script you might decide to do a fully written script.
You might write something out and want to present it word for word.
Now the big risk here is that if you deliver a script that way it'll sound like you're reading it off.
That might make people lose interest quickly.
Can it just depends.
Everyone has their own speaking style but here's what I suggest.
Outline the parts you know and script the parts you don't if you're the expert doing all the speaking
then you might not need any script at all just a bullet list type outline to fall.
So actually have you done this type of presentation before.
Just fill in the gaps of what you know and just kind of keep things moving.
If there's something you want to ensure gets across perfectly then type that out a word of advice to
just practice this more than once once you have your notes and scripts and whatever in place just go
through it.
It's only an hour and that way at least you're not freaking out when you actually did do it for real.
Make sure that you leave in delays for parts where you hope people might ask questions or get involved
practicing on the actual presentation platforms even better since you'll know where the controls and
their features are located and you really shouldn't.
You don't want to get lost during the actual live event.
None of his advice is to use time markers to stay on schedule.
What I mean is figure out where you need to be after like say 15 minutes and then put a note about it
in your script like type in 15 minutes and big bold letters or something like that so you know if you're
not there in 15 minutes oh crap speeded up if you're going to show slides in your seminar most women
our platforms are going to probably be PowerPoint friendly meaning you should be able to just create
the slides and PowerPoint then import the file right in.
You make them say in like Keynote.
Well you probably have to export your slides as a PowerPoint format believe you can do.
Here's a tip when designing your slides.
Just try to keep them as simple as possible.
Don't do not put in transitions animations and don't put an embedded video files inside the slides.
A video playing through a live stream video to someone watching that video is there's too many things
that go wrong.
Now while it would be great to include visual pop and your webinars slides most web and our platforms
really socket making those effects actually work so try to avoid any unnecessary bells and whistles.
Stick with a simple slide design and try to important tests or slides as early as possible so you know
what's actually going to work.
Now that brings us to the issue of choosing a web in our provider and.
Well you've got some free options if you want.
Now the first one surprisingly is actually just YouTube and YouTube.
You can do a livestream to do a live stream just go to YouTube dot slashed live or it's a live underscored
da app or something like that.
And then you can just click on the upload button at the top of YouTube and then select a live streaming
as the option YouTube requires that you set up streaming software.
But YouTube has some pretty helpful directions to get you through each step.
So it's a pretty good free options.
I mean considering it's free now with YouTube you can't add a PowerPoint presentation but you can add
these things called cards.
You can have up to five cards and each card is kind of like a full screen image that you can show on
the screen whenever you want.
You can use these cards to share links but what are the best uses with webinars.
Probably actually to just conduct something like a poll prep poll question in advance and show it at
the right time to have people answer.
They can even see the results.
No no other free option is google hangout.
You can conduct your own webinars with up to 100 people watching for free.
You can incorporate slides unfortunately but it does have screen sharing.
So you could instead do is just show the slides on your computer through Screen Sharing.
You might have to download install the hangouts plug in but it's generally pretty easy to go to hangouts
dot Google dot com.
Now if you want access to more features like e-mail invites which is pretty nice especially things like
the ability to include presentation slides or how people manage people log in and get information from
them things like that.
Well you're probably going to go the paid option.
Now one really popular option is go to a meeting and they really they have a specific product for this
is called go to webinars and you can do it free for seven days if you want.
Now there's a lot of other providers out there.
There's any meeting there's one called Zoom I think we mentioned this earlier.
So if you want to do something bigger try those out see what fits your needs best.
Honestly I just tried doing the trial and see how it goes.
And if you can't live without it do it but otherwise Google Hangouts the works pretty well.
Now once you've got your provider and slides and script and everything ready to go.
Make sure you promote your seminar using the usual channels.
Remember this is a lead magnet so the other half of the portion of this process is getting that page
out there to get people to see it to sign up.
You can run ads you can post it on Facebook and slacke groups or wherever.
Make sure when you are highlighting this and promoting it that you make sure people know that it's free.
People love free stuff.
Your web provider for instance has built in e-mail invitations and you can actually upload a list and
then send out invites to your audience.
Already do what you can do to get people there.
Now during your web weapon our rely on your preparation do you practice really have nothing to worry
about.
Answer questions be friendly and remember why you're putting on this webinar in the first place.
You're trying to get leads and get them interested in you and your business.
If any problems arise obviously just stay cool and be human about it.
People generally forgive you ultimately webinars help you make new connections with your audience so
encourage them stay connected let them know to contact you for more information to follow your channels
on social.
Sign up for your e-mail visit your web site.
All the things that can result in more leads and engagement across the board.
And you're keeping your eye openers going.
Tell them when your next webinars will happen before they sign up.
They're looking for inspiration.
Here's a few seminars we're checking out lead pages at weekly web in our series and does a great job
of promoting it with a pretty nice landing page when you where you sign up.
Pictures or video preview which I think is a pretty nice touch of the kind of hard to do if you have
done this before but it is your second time at it.
It's pretty easy.
HubSpot also does a series called broadcast and what's nice is that they provide some resources to download
as well like a to do list that you can apply what you've learned from the presentation and you can fill
it out as you go through.
The other one was training mag and they do a bunch of webinars on professional development topics usually
a feature a few speakers and each one they have a different style so we're checking them out.
You also just go to youtube and search for webinars on blank.
And then a topic you're interested in.
YouTube has tons of Web recordings.
You can check out and you certainly find whatever topic you want.
You want to learn about there being be hosting.
I did a seminar and it's on YouTube you can find it.
So before you design yours I recommend looking to see what other people have done.
So there's a lot to consider when planning and executing webinars but they can be a lot of fun because
of all the people that can get involved.
Try one out.
See how it works for you.
Make sure you prep and rehearse for you a lot.
Try a free solution like YouTube streaming and see if you can get it to work.
Otherwise upgrade and pay a little bit more for.
Go to webinars and don't forget to attend webinars of your own to get an idea of how these work.
Ok guys that is it.
Good luck.
I'll see you in the next lecture.