All right guys welcome back.
So we come to the point where we're finally going to write our pitch e-mail.
Up until that point we've talked in our lectures about many different ways to get to know these contacts
to read their work to understand their interest and to get their attention at different points in time.
All of those things help making this task the pitch much much easier.
And the first thing I remember about your pitch is that you've got limited time to make an impression.
Remember reporters are lazy but also busy.
They have no time to read through hundreds of words.
Discover your wonderful idea.
You need to grab their attention immediately and really really choose your words.
Sachs now that I have your attention now that needs to happen with a strong subject line here's a few
things you can do to improve your subject line for a pitch e-mail.
First up personalize it.
Remember all that work you did to get to know the writer Well it's time to use that knowledge.
Now you simply put their name in it.
Hey Steve Great post or call out some work.
They did that you'll eventually comment on in your e-mail.
Nice post on productivity apps.
Either strategy can get their attention and it doesn't immediately sound like you're about to pitch
them something.
The sad fact is that people like to hear about themselves and that is kind of the golden rule of cold
emailing you send an email.
You need to talk about them them them not you you.
If you want to take it a step further create some curiosity but don't make it a complete mystery.
Here's what I mean.
Let's say Johnny the reporter wrote a blog post about an app to find parking spaces in your city.
Now what you can do is reference that post of a subject like parking app question or parking app Post.
Thanks Johnny if I'm Johnny the reporter I know what the parking app reference is but yeah I might be
curious why exactly there's a question or why are you thinking about me specifically.
Now this curiosity could lead them to opening the e-mail.
Now here's another idea.
We know reporters want to be one of the first if not the first to report on something so getting a jump
on the competition can help.
If your subject line you create some type of a limited time offer type of fact that could be something
that's useful.
Now this one's a little bit debatable.
So one of the situations where if you ask reporters if using this tactic is a good idea they'll say
no it's super annoying and then you'll say well did you open the e-mail and they're like yes every time.
So it's kind of up to you.
But anyway if you add the word exclusive in the subject line a reporter might just give it a look because
they're just trained to be like oh sweet scoup it's exclusive.
I'd better check this out because I miss something.
Now the same thing does not go for using the word embargo.
That's one way to guarantee they won't open it usually with embargoes.
You want to say this later on in the sentence.
And don't imply that they have to follow it.
You basically just mention that this is this is how we're doing it anyway these are Grae's to grab their
attention or the promise of interesting information.
And if these contacts already have at least some baseline familiarity with you then these tactics shouldn't
actually seem desperate and annoying.
In fact they might seem like you're doing them a big favor by sending it their way.
There's a big difference between someone saying something and you don't know them and someone saying
the exact same thing and you actually know them.
OK so there are some tips on your subject line just personalize it create some curiosity and if none
of that works and try to use some limited time type exclusive something that kind of piques their curiosity
in that way type language.
But ultimately if all you can come up with is the simplest shortest way of getting your pitch across.
Honestly sometimes that's another way to do it.
New dog walking app now available for Bay Area residents.
You know if that's something that's interesting and that person covers the Bay Area or covers dogs in
the Bay Area well really hard to ignore.
Be on the subject line.
Consider those first two sentences in the body of your email very very carefully.
This is where you make a make or break your pitch.
You need to keep the attention of the reporter.
So follow through on the subject line immediately greet the reporter like you would anyone else.
Hi Steve.
And then quickly make a relevant statement though I completely understand that ties into whatever you
referenced in the subject line for example through an e-mail subject line it said no lightsaber article.
Thank you.
Maybe your e-mail will start off like this.
And forgive me for the Star Wars references.
Hey Luke.
Love the post you wrote on light savers dot com yesterday about fighting stances for using the force
out I'm just making it up or to use some of the tips in my training this morning.
The first part of this email now works on making a connection and establishing a relationship.
You show that you actually read their stuff that you appreciate what they do and you're not just someone
who's randomly master blasting out thousands of pitches at once.
Then after that you go on your pitch.
So basically become something like Thanks for this.
And now there's this other thing you might like.
As for the pitch itself clearly state the value for them and their readers.
If you've done your research you should know if this subject will be of interest to them or not.
But reporters always have to consider their audience too so they need to know why they should care about
this pitch.
Or of yours and try your best to make it crystal clear.
Remember that 99 pitches sitting on their inbox next to yours so if you don't make your point clear
and you don't make your point clear quickly Well it's going to go into the trash.
Now let's continue that last email.
Now I can say I just wanted to pass along some news that you might be interested.
And again you can be my startup makes custom lightsaber handles out of 100 percent Willkie hair or whatever.
In a recent survey of my customers 80 percent of them say they're willing to spend more to buy products
with authentic materials instead of the imitation materials made by the Empire.
If you're interested in the data I'd be happy to share it.
Let me know and best wishes Obi-Wan Kenobi.
OK so you've got some data to share about your customers in the industry and you want to know if this
reporter is interested in it.
You're not being overly dramatic like oh you'll never guess what my customers think of imitation lightsaber
handles.
Want to know.
E-mail me now.
The email example we've come up with here is a better cell.
This kind of information will be valuable to other companies out there and it's real data instead of
opinion.
You also established that you read their article you added some personalization into it and then you
connected that.
This is something you do.
It's important.
It's valuable and it's relevant to something that they've already written about or have had an opinion
about.
Now it will take some time to kind of perfect your pitch voice and style but in general be polite and
friendly but don't act like you're the best friend they've ever had.
Unless you are best friends of course them do that and be confident in your pitch but not obviously
arrogant you know believe in what you've got.
Don't sell it like it's the greatest thing in the world.
Be excited about it.
Whatever it is.
But sell it with the reporter and their audience in mind makes sense.
OK well we're going to practice a little bit more in our next lecture.
Just to be sure.
See you then.