All right guys we are back.
Here we go once again.
We've been discussing all these different ways to improve SEO over the section of the course and in
our last lecture we talked about link building and this lecture on expand upon why link building is
so important in terms of a concept called authority.
So what do we know about the SBO value of a page.
Well pages rank highly not only because they are awesome well put together pages but because many other
people agree they are awesome by visiting the page sharing the page and then linking to said Page.
And this is a big difference.
I want to highlight for all the work you do when pages get lots of attention and links from outside
sources.
It's hard to prove in the eyes of Google that the page really does have value.
And over time the page can build authority or real importance and influence.
Now this idea in mind Maw's reference and before Monster.com created a way to try and measure the authority
of a page and its Web site.
Now Mazas an NCO consulting group that's been around for over a decade and has established itself as
an influential source on that FCO knowledge and what maws did was create their own algorithm to measure
something called Page authority.
Now Page 30 is a measure on a scale of 1 to a hundred other pages ability to rank on a search engine
the result page.
The higher the score the better Maw's believes the pages chance are for being ranked highly on the SC
RPM search engine ranking pages.
In addition they also develop domain authority which as you might guess is the same measurement and
instead of a page it's for the Web site as a whole.
So with measurements like page authority and domain authority or P-A NDA if you're cool like breathe
everything you might have a few questions What's a good score you might ask what's the score I might
want to try and get.
How do I improve my score but also how relevant is the score.
Now first of all the reasons you don't want to pay attention to scores like page authorities to know
if your efforts are working from a non-Google standpoint as important as Google is it helps to get a
different perspective.
And this rating is another strong indicator of how good your SCA work has been.
So how do you get a good page authority score well.
Mazas worked on an algorithm that takes many things into account and includes many of the same basic
FCL lessons that we've already covered.
Make sure your page uses good code.
Make sure it has the links going from and leading to the page.
Make sure the content is complete and well written.
Always there is more to it but you should see that if you're doing what you're supposed to you know
following all the SEO best practices that you've already discussed while your page should have a high
authority score.
Now keep in mind though that the number of links leading to a page from outside sources definitely will
affect its score.
So don't expect a good P.A. page authority score as soon as you publish it.
In fact most pages start with a one until they actually start getting an downlinks.
If you're curious about these scores and you can install Mazas browser tool called the Maw's bar now
once you activate it it looks something like this.
When you visit different sites you to guess for example at a site like I don't know ESPN.
What kind of page authority would its home page have or domain authority.
Do you get something high.
Well you'd be right.
Because as you can see the ESPN home page has a page authority of ninety 95 Jesus and a domain authority
of 96 or even higher.
So if you're to somehow get a link from ESPN home page.
Well give a significant boost here as you know.
If someone important links to you they just assume you also are important like SBO And also mean girls.
But what does this mean for search results.
How does page authority and domain authority really affect search results and you've got the laws bar
installed.
Well look for yourself.
Check out a Google search like how to install a TV soundbar.
I don't know how it's a thing you can now see the page authority and domain it listed below.
Each result in a quick scan shows you that the top results generally come from sites with higher domain
authority but the pages themselves don't necessarily have high authority at all.
So does this mean page authority is meaningless.
No what it tells me is this pages with high page authority like ESPN.
Home Page could easily rank high for very competitive words words like sports news however pages with
low pages already don't really have a chance for the same terms but they do have a chance of ranking
for very specific longtail keyword phrases like How to install a TV soundbar.
None of this makes sense.
Authority is just another way to measure how you're doing with your efforts.
But again just a number of actual goals are trying to accomplish like reaching a thousand paying customers.
Cough cough.
The point of the course.
That's the kind of number you want to monitor.
Once you've implemented these SEO tactics now in fact we'll get into some of the numbers and metrics
you should look at in our next lecture to help you determine if your efforts are actually working.
All right guys I'll see you then.