All right, guys.
Welcome back to the course, the last lecture, I give you the lowdown on Instagram.
And for many of you out there, you're probably well versed already if you use Instagram and know all
the features and sections of it, please, for the love of God, skip this lecture.
I don't want to hear you complain about it later.
However, I'm going to go over the process of creating a business account for Instagram, which has
some advantages over the plain old regular account, just about as everyone else does.
So if you're an Instagram master, skip this.
If you're curious what the difference in business, Instagram and personal Instagram is, maybe you
increase the speed to two X and watch it.
And if you guys don't have Instagram account, well, I would suggest following along anyway.
So let's jump in for Instagram account.
You have those two options I mentioned that you can create and use a regular Instagram account or you
could create and use a business Instagram account.
Some of the additional features business accounts have are going to be contact buttons for your customers
that they can actually use.
And then it gives you access to insights, data with a capital.
Which gives you data about your post, your followers and really any promotions that you've run.
Now, Insight's is the same data that's used on Facebook.
So if you want a business account and access to this extra data on your followers as well, which is
generally a good idea, well, then you must have a Facebook page, unfortunately, to connect it to.
So if you want a business account, but you don't have a Facebook page yet, go set that up right now.
Really, really simple.
Takes two seconds.
No one actually sees the page.
So you have to do is fill it out.
You don't want to put a photo or anything.
Just go to Facebook dot com slash pages and then just follow those steps.
Again, you do have to customize it young to post.
Should honestly take it two minutes and I will wait.
OK.
Now let's get you hooked up with an Instagram account whether you want a business or a regular account.
Either way, you need to sign up for a regular account first.
Now, here are the first steps.
Now, guys, if you've done this before, please don't watch this lecture.
But otherwise, let's do it.
Number one, you got to download Instagram.
Got to do it on your iPhone or your Android.
Pretty sure they have an app for every platform.
Just download it.
You have to do it on your phone.
You can't do it on the web.
Number two, start it up and then tag right there on sign up.
Number three, then, as you know, since this is going to be your business.
Well, enter your business name and your business email address.
You'll get confirmation email.
Always make sure to verify that the number four is if you already have an Instagram account and you
want to turn it into a business account.
And it's generally a good idea, although, you know, if you use it for personal things has nothing
to do with your business plan.
I generally suggest keeping these separate, but kind of weird.
If all your friends are following you and you just turn into a business.
But if you wanted to do that.
Well, and just follow these next steps.
Now, if you want to just use a regular account and then not link to a Facebook page, you can actually
skip these steps.
Again, I don't generally suggest doing that, but if you want to save time, you could.
OK.
So if your regular account is set up, then just go to settings and then choose change to a business
account.
It's actually really that simple.
Pick the Facebook page you want to link to for this account.
That's kind of it.
You just then have to fill out a business profile your friend and put in contact info and at a minimum,
you put in a different email address.
But, you know, add your address if that actually applies to you.
Now, if you connect your Facebook page to your Instagram account, you should get a notification in
Facebook to connect your Facebook page to the new Instagram account.
Now, it's just another connection that should help you when you're doing stuff on your Facebook page.
So go ahead and just do that.
If you see it now, if your Instagram account is brand new, well, then you just have to add in the
basic info to your profile.
Short description, you are l a profile picture now in Instagram.
You can't actually just upload a logo and you know, if it's on your phone, well, and just go for
it.
But while you're here.
Be sure to include a specific call to action.
What are you hoping Instagram followers do when they come across your account?
The way that describes generally works is that it's just like any other content marketing.
You're going to make photos or videos that are interesting, attractive and somehow related to whatever
your topic is.
People see your account.
They follow it for updates.
And occasionally they'll see that you're going to try to link them back to your site or link them to
something that you want to sell.
A lot of business discovery happens on Instagram now.
So do you want them to go to a landing page to, say, sign up for an event or something like that?
Or are you trying to get them to say, subscribe to an email newsletter?
Maybe.
Do you want them to contact you directly through e-mail?
Or is there some other goal that you want to get out of this?
This call to action should be the last line of your profile.
Let's look an example.
Michelle Melchor as an artist who you can commission for art.
But on her Instagram account, the last line of her profile says for print purchases, visit her Web
site.
OK, well, her goals pretty clear here.
You like what she see?
You see?
Well, you can buy it from Irv's click that link.
So what's your goal?
Decide on your goal and included in your bio.
So this Instagram account can get you the results you want.
Really?
It's quite simple.
If you guys want to do really simple stuff, then I'd say make a quick landing page that they can then
go to and then give you your email address.
You can sell them later.
But if you're in like e-commerce and you're selling something from the front of your page, they just
put a link to that.
This called.
All you have to do is click on the edit profile from your profile screen to see a spot for you or you
are L.
So if you're driving people to a landing page or some other, you are l enter it right there, then
add a line at the end of your bio and use this trick at a colon at the end, something like use code
instead 20 to see that my store or contact me for a free quote here, didn't I?
It's pretty important that you give them some kind of an incentive to go right.
Otherwise, it's just a link and it's not enough for them to go from, like, browsing on their phone
to you.
I actually want to go purchase something.
Now, what's cool is here you are.
I will always show up right after the end of your bio.
So by adding that colon at the end, it actually makes it look like the two things are connected.
I mean, they obviously are.
But now there's a clear reason to click because you added that text in your bio.
Now, once you've got your account set, it's a good time to explore what you can do here.
Now, here's a quick rundown of Instagram's features.
Take a stroll left to right along the bottom icons with me now.
Home shows you your feed of people you follow and their pictures.
For some reason, Instagram doesn't show these in sequential order, which they used to.
And I'm not sure why they did it.
Now, for whatever reason, it's a feed run off of their own algorithm.
So it's in some kind of logical order.
And it does now include ads.
Still a great way to see what people are posting.
However, a lot of times don't even notice that the timeline is kind of screwed up.
Now, the next thing on the bottom bar is a search, and that allows you to search for people by their
name or handle.
And you can search for past tags as well as places.
It also shows pictures that are popular right now, usually influenced by your history.
For example, you might see a note at the bottom of the picture that says based on photos you liked.
Now, the third icon is to post and you can choose a picture or video from your phone or take one.
Now you have the option of choosing multiple pictures to make a gallery that can be swiped through.
Once you've taken or chosen a picture, you can apply filters to adjust the colors.
Do mild editing like cropping, changing the brightness and contrast.
And then you add the info, a caption, you know, you can try to tag people in it by linking to their
Instagram profile.
You can say tag it with location and then it shows up when people are searching for that location.
And if you want, you can cross posted on any linked profiles you have, like on Facebook or Twitter.
Now we'll get into what you should post and ideas for captions and tags later.
But for now, let's actually just continue on our tour so that we're not completely clueless about how
Instagram works.
Metaphors icon on the bottom is that heart, but it's basically your engagement activity.
Who started following you?
Who left your post, who commented on your posts and who liked your comments?
Now, if you click following up top, you can also see stuff like the people you follow.
It's a way discover new stuff that you might not have noticed because their usual feed is pretty mucked
up.
The last icon is your profile and it's important page, since people will be checking this out to see
who you are and what you've posted with a personal Instagram account.
You'll see a profile picture and name, bio link and all your posts, along with the number of followers
and people you follow on a business account.
You'll also see a category under their name like Target.
We'll show retail company or Domino's Pizza.
We'll show garbage company with a new account.
It makes sense at this point to start following people.
When you follow someone, they'll get a notification.
So it's a way to give people a heads up that you're now on the platform.
So this is hardly follow anyone.
But following people can only increase your chances of getting a follow back.
So I say go for it.
The basic premise behind Instagram bots, if you're curious, is that there are these programs that
will just follow people that have certain interests and then those people get ping that you follow them.
And a lot of times they'll then check out your profile and follow you back, or they might actually
just click through your your app.
Now, one important way is you get your first batch of followers is just to promote yourself to your
own audience through your other channels.
Generally, I say just get on Facebook, Twitter, email and your blog and let people know that, hey,
I now have an Instagram account.
Be sure to include what they can expect.
You to post tips, videos behind the scenes stuff, give them some kind of clue why they should care
and why they should go and take the five seconds to add you.
If you're not sure what to post, well, we'll cover some ideas in the next lecture.
So just stay tuned for a little bit longer.
Not work for new people you can follow right on Instagram, search by name if you know them, or search
by hashtag and see who's posting about things that are relevant to you.
And you sell custom design t shirts through your online store.
Maybe start by searching for hashtag t shirt and see what comes up.
Don't just look at the pictures, though.
Look for other related hashtags in the descriptions of these pictures.
Maybe hashtag streetwear is maybe your style or passion.
Funny t shirt could be a little bit closer.
Kind of depends what your angle is.
If you see people posting pictures that might relate to you or your product will follow their account,
maybe even like when their photos or maybe even leave a comment.
Don't obviously go for the hard sell and say, hey, check us out and buy our t shirts.
Just generally doesn't work.
Just generally compliment them, make sure that they are aware that you exist.
And then just move on.
Let the engagement you do marinate a bit and the result will eventually come.
It will take a little bit of time, though.
Now, if you wanna be sneaky about getting fallers, try this one out.
Search for your competitors on Instagram.
Click on their profile and then click their followers number and you can see who follows them.
Well, then go through and follow a whole bunch of those.
Usually Instagram limits you.
I think it's 200 followers a day and you don't generally want to get that close.
So maybe you do 50 or 100 a day.
What should happen is you'll get some followers back from some of those people, specially if they have
an interest in that competitor and they realize that, hey, you're a similar product.
Here's another thing you can do with competitors.
Look at their recent posts and then see who's left comments.
If you see a comment from someone who looks like they might be a possible follower for you, like their
comment or follow them.
Now, Shopify didn't experiment like this where they found competitor followers and followed them,
liked one of their pictures and they just commented on one of their picks.
In each case, it increased the chances of a follow back.
And if he did all three, well, there is something like a thirty three percent chance they'd follow
you back pretty much within 24 hours.
That's probably works better if you have pictures on your account.
So maybe keep this tactic in your back pocket for now.
No one likes to go and see an empty account because they're not going to follow that.
Not only does this get you followers who are interested in your type of product, but it's a way to
stick it to a competitor as well.
Instagram is for posting pictures and videos.
So in our next hour, we'll talk about taking pictures and then getting the promotions rolling with
those.
All right.
See you then.