Hey guys we are X and the last several years we've gone over a whole lot of information about video
production not just the fundamentals but also diving into some commonly used in popular production setups.
I want to wrap this section up on video production with a few extra tips that I have to recommend because
some of these are essential depending on the types of videos you want to create.
Now to talk about four different things from talking about teleprompters professional voice over artist
Dali's and slider's.
All right let's get in this.
If you anticipate recording a lot of scripted video especially longer videos Well you might consider
investing in a teleprompter.
Teleprompters allow you to read the words from your script off the screen while you record.
The big advantage here is that you don't have to memorize your script which is great if you have long
scripts or lots of them to record.
So potentially it could save you lots of time.
Now here is how it works.
Well the prompter uses a special see through screen that sits in front of the camera lens.
The camera won't see it but when you look at it you'll see the words from your script reflected on it.
Now in some cases you're just using reflective glass and then if you use an iPhone or iPad it just reflects
on the glass and you see that.
Or fancy ones will have a screen that's powered by a program that feeds the letters into it.
Those are very expensive and then generally in these more expensive setups as you say your words someone
probably controls it or scrolls the text down.
And the other cheaper versions you can either time it where it just goes at a certain pace.
There's some ones where they'll look for what you're saying and I'll match them up to the words and
then move along accordingly.
Or you can just use the remote in general.
Teleprompters are a great way to add polish to your videos if you're a professional and you care about
your brand well.
Then using a prompter is going to make you sound like you know what you're saying and you're more prepared
to deal with this a little bit in another video.
But the cheapest option you can do is what's called the parrot teleprompter and it just goes right on
the front of the Lindzi or camera they use like an iPhone to read the information onto it and you use
iPhone programs that can act like teleprompters.
It's really pretty simple.
I mean it doesn't work fantastically but it's only 50 bucks.
The alternative other fancy teleprompter programs which are God.
I mean they've I've never seen them lower than a thousand dollars.
Now one thing to keep in mind with teleprompters is that you will have to practice with them.
It's not as easy as it sounds like you're basically reading on camera.
But the hope is that you don't look or sound like you're reading.
You need to practice you come off as natural you're spouting off all this prepared material that's going
to do it for all of us here.
Channel 4 News.
You stay classy San Diego.
I'm Ron Burgundy not have you noticed this but newscasters they use teleprompters.
They're just really really good at it.
You might not notice that they're just literally reading something off with their eyes.
They just don't know.
I mean they've just gotten to a point where they can ad lib they can never really run into problems
they do it all live.
It's actually pretty impressive.
Here's the prompter one way you can tell if someone's using a teleprompter and this is one of those
things once you hear it you can never hear it.
Well there's two things.
One is what I call I lock.
So if someone's talking to a camera and they're just staring at the camera like this and they never
do long blinks and never look away like this.
That's a good sign that there is the teleprompter and the other thing is if you look at their pupils
generally speaking you can see them going like this because they're reading that teleprompters will
be too large based on the distance in the camera.
So a lot of times you'll be like this and that just looks really bizarre.
This is how people use help from the wrong where they put them on top of the camera below.
And that's oh I have to really hate that because imagine if I was talking to you like this like Does
this seem natural at all I'm just reading off a teleprompter.
I personally hate that stuff.
So weigh the pros and cons here and consider Will the extra expense hardware and practice and kind of
the high jinks you have to get through.
Is it going to be worth it to complete your recordings and get through them faster with more polished
and sounding more prepared.
Do I need to record long stretches of dialogue in front of a camera.
That would necessitate a prompter.
Is there a different way of recording these long scripts.
OK.
Well that's really enough about teleprompters because you might be thinking about this to yourself.
Yeah.
You know what I don't actually want to be in the video.
I don't want to talk in it.
I want someone else to do it.
And plenty of people will agree with you.
It's nothing about your voice but about their own.
A lot of video makers actually outsource the actual speaking being done in their videos and they get
professional voice over artist to do the work for them.
What I want from you is your full.
As it turns out not everyone has the most beautiful easy to understand and crisp accent.
People generally want to hear certain types of voices like for instance men for some reason think that
women's voices are more pleasing and more relaxing.
And I probably I don't know what women think about men's voices but in general if you're trying to get
across a feeling or some convey some emotion that you can't produce in your own voice while using a
voice artist is a pretty good option.
Now one popular voice you can check out if you really want to get into this and you have a little bit
of budget for it check out voices dot com.
They have thousands of people on there who freelance and do professional voice work.
And with all those people you have an immense amount of choices to choose from and say that five times
fast choices choices choices for choices anyway.
You've got men and women high voices deep voices people who sound professional people who sound young
and trendy people who can enunciate lots of detailed terms and then people who can do that cool in a
world like movie type trailer voice.
Now that's great if you have a very specific idea in mind of what you want but generally they're going
to charge you per word or per second.
And it can get kind of expensive depending on what you're using them for.
My preferred option is actually just go to five or dot.com five or it's five or with two Rs.
There's a lot of voice artists on there just type voice over voice artist and you'll just see an enormous
amount of them that's what I always use and I never really spend more than $20.
I mean you have people who are really good really in demand they have voices that sound like they're
from commercials.
Then you have people who are newer to it have perfectly fine voices just haven't built up a large portfolio
and therefore can be really cheap you go cheap is like a dollar a minute voiceovers.
Also keep in mind are great but only when you have to call this omnipotent narrator where you're narrating
a promo or an ad or whatever it is and there's a voice and that the viewer knows they're never going
to see the person who's talking this way called the OmniPod and it's like it's talking in the back of
your head that's perfectly fine.
But if you want to show the person talking well then you have to get a real person.
So anyway we talked about some ways to improve your delivery on camera and how to add a professional
voice to the mix if you don't want to do it yourself.
Now it's I got some equipment you can use to improve your camera work and make your videos look even
nicer.
Once you go down the camera equip it rabbit hole you may never emerge because there are so many kinds
of things you can buy to capture really nice footage.
There's lots of things to hold your cameras movie cameras when your cameras fly your cameras.
Drones are very popular right now because their costs have finally come down.
And if you need aerial footage or something like that for your marketing maybe it's a golf course or
a manufacturing plant or you want a sweet group shot of all your employees well a drone can be pretty
good.
In most cases you don't really need a drone but if you're doing it outdoors the stuff that I think it
might be worth buying otherwise just rent a drone for when you need it.
You've thrown a beach party and you know aerial shot will do that.
Great place find people or drone or owner operators.
You can Google it.
Also on Craigslist people posts on Craigslist all the time it's just some guy with a drone he's pretty
good at flying it.
They're usually pretty cheap it's not super cheap but they're decent but before you go buying a drone
fleet equipped with go pros and laser beams or However these things fly I want to take you back to a
couple of well-tested pieces of equipment the crews love.
Now Dali's and slider's Now Dolly is your very best friend.
Squishy be f.f you can dress and blow.
Now this auction I'm talking about a dolly is basically a train track that you build for your camera.
It's allow I call it a slider because I'm a simpleton.
But and it just makes it slide.
This is what we do in America we just call things exactly what they are.
It's not a roundabout there's a circle and you attach your camera to it and slide that bad boy forward
and backward or side to side to capture some really nice and smooth footage.
The idea with using a dolly is to create a factory make a scene more intimate bringing the viewer closer
to something or someone or farther away as you zoom out.
Now could be people product a place but being in as it's called focuses the attention on what's in view.
The flip side now if you Dalty out to expand the view that shows people a wider view or scope of the
location and situation.
In fact you could also Dehli sideways to follow someone as they walk from one side to another.
We actually call that one a tracking shot and you could even build a circular track around something
and then Dalty around it creating a cool mini kind of effect whatever direction you go.
These are great because they provide smooth video footage instead of doing the same thing while holding
the camera in both your hands.
Do not underestimate how much of a nice polished effect a dolly can.
And if you use a dolly correctly people won't even notice but they'll just know that this is way nicer
if you look at something like promo videos we almost always use Dali's and it's almost always on the
alternate camera.
So the first one static the never changes and Exide camera will always have a slight motion to it and
it really does help with this kind of feeling of a high production do not by any means try to do this
manually with your hands.
That's just just never works out.
The fact of Dolly the reason why it looks good is because it stays on a perfect track and it's perfectly
smooth when it's jerky or it goes up and down it kind of kills it for you.
Now of course there's other ways of doing this.
You can do it with some handheld cameras that are auto stabilizers like on a gimbal that's what they're
called but that requires an entirely new piece of equipment.
It's probably not worth doing.
There's also one thing that even goes one step further which is pretty ridiculous and if you look at
the become a product manager video we did we actually tried to use this.
It's called a parallax Dolley and what parallax is is it's a fact when you have something in the foreground
and then have something in the background.
And it's when the background is moving but the foreground is not.
Now that's a parallax effect.
It's pretty frickin sweet but it's kind of overkill for a lot of the stuff you do.
And there's specific dollies that you can use that allow you to do it and basically what it does is.
So is the camera moving like this never changing its lens.
It starts like this.
And then as it goes along it tilts the camera.
Right.
So whatever it's focused on doesn't move but the background does it.
I personally it's one of these things that when I see the footage I just kind of drool.
Anyway if you decide to go the dolly route it's going to cost you some money because you need to buy
a bunch of equipment to make it all work.
My general advice if you want to use a full blown Dolly is rent it because they're good or do you get
a good one they're really really expensive.
So I mean how often you use it like how annoying would it be if we are watching this for 10 hours and
you just have the camera keep sliding back and forth.
I say just rent it.
Now if you're really insistent on owning one well there's a much smaller and more affordable version
of Dolly that a lot of marketing video crews will use.
I actually called a slider and it's what I incorrectly mix up.
Now a slider is not a tiny hamburger.
Well it is but you know what I mean it's basically a miniature version of a doll that slides back and
forth along a super smooth track.
They can place it on a table or even mounted on a tripod.
They do is to create the same smooth motion we've been talking now with Dali's.
But in this case you don't need as much motion.
Typically a doll is going to be like Yeah if you're moving and you want it to track someone if they
walk or as a is just just get that nice little short motion at it even a little bit of motion in a video
shot really can look good.
Now you might be tempted to say well doesn't my camera zoom in and out.
Why can't I just dial in and out by zooming in and zooming out and just slap yourself because that's
just not the same if you actually look at the comparison of the two.
It's not actually the same thing zooming in and out kind of feels like you're pulling them towards the
image and then pushing them back outwards.
Dolly feels like they're just slowly moving towards it.
It's really just not the same effect if you did it with zooming and actually be pretty annoying.
It kind of has this binocular like a fact like you're looking into something really quickly and it's
really hard to get done well.
So like I said earlier you could go even further into camera equipment land and look things that will
help you get more advanced more elaborate kinds of shots you have a need.
Well there's pretty much always a piece of equipment that you can satisfy with.
For example there's a thing called gybe.
This is what it is is a long arm you attach to a camera so that you can capture a rising or falling
or even like a swooping kind of camera movement.
So for that reason they're also sometimes called Crain's because they look like Crain's gybes are pretty
nice and if you see footage from it they're pretty impressive.
But again a lot of work just to get a couple seconds of a swooping motion.
Now there's also things like shoulder mounts and you can use these with cameras of all sizes to help
the characters and hold the camera more easily providing a little more stability for your handheld camera
shots.
Steady cam mounts are another thing that you can mount on the camera so you can try and get smoother
footage when you know you're going be walking or even running while holding the camera.
You might also call this like a camera stabilizer.
And I've also mentioned go pros and drones at different points so really there's a whole bunch of ways
to get different and interesting video shots if you need them.
All these extra types of equipment can cost money especially those more elaborate setup so be sure you
really absolutely need them.
Honestly if you're just starting out personally I mean I'd grab a slider for yourself maybe and try
it out but again like I said rinde when you need it anyway.
So there you go.
We talked about teleprompters.
You know if those are voice over artist and additional equipment like Dali's slider's drones and a couple
of other things any one of these things can really add a nice professional touch to your marketing video
because after all anything it makes the video look better makes you look better.
Keep that in mind.
All right guys I'll see in the next lecture.