All right guys welcome back to the core.
So in our last lecture we set up an account and started looking for people to follow.
But the thing that's really going to encourage people to follow you is well what you post your pictures
and your videos.
So when you follow people you'll see a feed of recent posts show up when you launch Instagram for each
picture.
You could like it with you know that heart icon to show it some love double tapping the pick.
I think actually does the same thing if you just double tap it.
You can also comment or you can share the picture directly with a friend.
Now Instagram also lets you save pictures to your own collection using the little banner icon over on
the right for each picture.
You can see the first few comments and then if you click the View all comments link you'll see all of
them and have a chance to like them individually if you can post pics and videos and get any of these
reactions then you're doing it right.
So what should you take pictures and videos of much like Snapchat.
You want to post pictures and videos that help people understand you and what your brand is all about
based on what they see.
People make assumptions about you such as your overall personality.
Are you professional and conservative or are you fun and casual or are you stylish or are you helpful
maybe you're funny inspiring.
Matter of fact foul mouth or you know some mix of all of that whatever you are as a business as a brand
your Instagram posts are generally going to have to reflect that.
Now I ask these questions back in the Snapchat lectures and it's what would my followers our customers
like to see from my brand.
What can I show them that would excite them and them or amuse them or just help them learn.
What can I show them here that I can't show them anywhere else.
Now the same questions apply here but the answers could be different because the platform is different.
There are some common topics or pictures might include product pictures you know catalog type shots
or perhaps people using your product.
Retailers like Target and Old Navy upload images from professional photo shoots and then share them
with quirky little captions.
Obviously be careful you can't do this for every single photo because why would someone just follow
you just to see your product shots.
It's usually something you want to fit in with other things.
Then of course you could also do product videos show how it works.
Show someone using it show people reacting to it then you can do things like location pictures your
product being used somewhere notable pictures of your store you at an event or just a really nice landscape
or something like that.
People really love nature shots and Instagram.
You can also do things like behind the scenes pictures and videos.
What's happening in between these photos you're taking sometimes a behind the scenes pick is actually
more interesting than the posed and well manicured one.
Some teenagers are trying to take an artistic shot but it was their behind the scenes picture.
They got tons of likes because well how crazy it actually looks.
You girls use these stories feature and you use that feature to snap pictures and videos and then add
them to a daily collection people can watch.
Anyone who follows you will then see that you have a story up immediately at the top of their Instagram.
And that's one way of getting in front of them because not a lot of people use that feature especially
right now.
Now it makes sense for your brand and your kind of personality you could also consider a couple other
things you could consider try inspirational quotes or pictures.
When I do this for Instagram that's probably what I'm going to do since a lot of my people buy my courses
they're interested in starting businesses.
So it's probably to be something around that.
Well it's a good one.
The good quote is an Instagram account and only post inspirational quotes.
And while Here you go it's got 12 million followers.
I mean if that's not an inspiration right there to post some quotes of your own I don't know what is.
Do you want to do your own clothes.
Well a great app to try this is a thing called insta quote actually a free version where you just make
pictures with your own quotes pics and plenty of other options really just kind of systematized is the
process you know supposed random stuff that you came across.
That's fun or weird but obviously things are still of interest to your audience.
You can share posts from followers using an app like repost for Instagram.
Now this is a cool way to share a post from someone and give them credit.
This kind of move shows you value your followers and your fans and enough to give them credit for a
great picture as well.
When people post about the courses they take to me I usually repost them now giving other people credit
for their pictures.
Generally just good karma usually comes around back at you.
Obviously don't overdo this.
No one wants to watch.
Look at account that only reposts.
Now while you're at it share posts from bigger more popular accounts that you follow.
What are some of the Instagram accounts that inspire you share a great post from them and mentioned
them in the description.
You might be able to get some engagement from them.
And it's also a great way of kind of whittling down to posts you know will work well because of those
big counts posted them then re sharing them will probably also do well the bigger crowds usually have
teams of people that decide and test before they actually post.
So in the end engagement should be a goal each time getting likes comments and new followers from the
content you post helps grow your audience.
Every time someone interacts with your post Instagram's algorithm picks that up and then displays it
to more people more likes more repost more comments generally to them means a better post therefore
it's probably worth showing that to more people.
Now if you want to get the most out of your pictures there's a few things you can consider to optimize
them for Instagram specifically.
First of all a lot of brands post a well-designed nicely produced visuals instead.
Like I mentioned before Old Navy does this.
There's a picture of two little kids and their Old Navy summer clothes somewhere that has something
like 5000 likes so high quality visuals are appreciated on Instagram.
They look great in the app so consider how you can create the best looking pictures you can.
Your camera is obviously certainly an option especially you guys.
We're really going to get into video marketing as we talk about later but you can also just use your
own iPhone camera.
It's the easiest and most convenient way to do it and a lot of smart phones are capable of taking great
shot especially things like the Samsung Galaxies and the new iPhone which has a pretty over-the-top
camera but of course you could upload any picture you want to Instagram so long as it goes through your
phone first.
It's really not that difficult to share a picture to your phone anyway these days.
I personally use air drops his iPhone.
Also just use things like Dropbox.
That's usually pretty easy because they don't have a camera.
You're not really confident your skills.
Do you have any friends with the camera.
If you can find a photographer it's usually pretty easy.
You can even post on Craigslist and find someone who will give you a day rate to go take photos of things
that'll give you enough photos to work for months with visuals in mind.
Think about establishing a color theme for your post as well.
When you check out an Instagram profile you'll see a long visual list of previous pictures.
They have a color theme or style you consistently use or your pictures will look good together and then
make your profile that much more attractive.
For example look at Best Buy.
Well they posed a lot of product photos but the primary colors in most of them are blue and yellow which
are their logo colors as well eyeglass maker mirrored Warby Parker very hip very cool user.
There was a lot of bright colors some with their products in them but not all to be aware that Instagram
pics look best when they have a perfectly square sized ratio.
600 by 600 pixels twelve hundred by twelve hundred pixels whatever the size make it squares it shows
up perfectly in the Instagram feed and on profile pages.
That's my ratio is not a requirement but the fit is just better if you can do it that way.
If it doesn't fit then it gets crafted distorts your image and it just makes it look crappy.
My favorite way of doing this.
Making sure that my things are square is Canada.
Canada's a free tool.
You can literally select the template for Instagram post and it'll give you the options like small one
big one copy paste your image and then just kind of resize it using their tool.
You can also use Photoshop but not everybody knows that his photoshop so you can either their craft
and canvas Photoshop or you can also just do it in an Instagram.
So if you have a weirdly shaped shot then put it an Instagram and cropped on your phone.
Just let me keep in mind it's like a little bit harder to do it on your phone and you don't have a great
preview of what it's going to look like afterwards.
You just have a lot more control with some of these web apps.
Lindsey Graham also has its own filters that add color ization effects.
Now you could pick any one of them to apply to your picture or you can actually pick none of them.
Hashtag natural or I'm sorry it's hashtag no filter.
But if you do opt for Instagram filter while data tells us that some of them are more likeable than
others.
Overall people like pictures with what's called the Clarendon filter more than any other with gingham
and Juno coming in second and third.
But of course that's just in general on average actually depends on the industry you're in.
So for pictures tagged with fashion Kelvin is actually the most liked filter followed by Valencia and
Nashville.
What's also interesting is that pictures with no filter also perform well.
A lot of people who use Instagram a lot can just tell there's a filter and they generally support no
filters more often.
Plenty of people do all of their editing outside of Instagram and then post a polished picture with
no additional edits.
In the end a filter should make a picture look more interesting or more vibrant so try some out for
your own photos and then just generally see what works.
If his advice is just look at trends look what other people are doing when it's crime first came out
for the first three or four years people were pretty crazy about filters they would use filters to make
everything look better now it seems like the trend is moving towards less using filters less often.
In fact it's there's some accounts out there that don't use filters at all.
Just make sure that you're following the trends you don't want to be that company that comes off as
corporate and on like attached or you just don't understand your customers by doing the opposite of
what's cool right now.
And of course if you're looking for something different and fun you can also create a looping animated
picture by using Instagram's related app.
It's called Boomerang or probably any number of apps out there that do the same thing.
My favorite is cinema Graham cinema graph and what it allows you to do is take a video of something
and then freeze part of it while the rest of it moves so you can take a picture of a river or something
like that.
Freeze everything around it but make the river move in the photo.
I like that stuff.
I think it's cool.
Or of course you could create an image made up of multiple pictures.
Now there's a tool called dip tick a DIY P T I see that's an app that's been around forever but it helps
you actually do that or you go the multi photo route and do something like what.
Let's look at Caine's furniture did creating a picture out of pictures.
Now it's visible when you look at their feed from a glance.
See if you've got some ideas cooking in that brain of yours great while you're preparing visuals and
more ideas think about some of these best practices as you start to put together an Instagram strategy
of your own.
If you want to build a following.
Posting once a day is going to be essential.
The top brands on Instagram post daily and it helps to build your following.
If you can post consistently Instagram also notices they've got their own algorithm that looks for activity
from you and likes and comments and etc. They like people who have more activity but it doesn't mean
you are to be stuck on your phone.
Pretty much all day you can actually use tools like buffer I think as on called like Insta post to schedule
your posts so you could just make 30 of them and once a day you're done for the month.
Now the more popular your content is the more Instagram is going to feature you and your followers feed.
So it's actually worth investing in.
There's a paid scheduling app called gadget Graham.
It's very similar to what I was just talking about buffers free unless I think if you add multiple accounts.
Now since this is gonna be a business account you need a goal obviously in mind.
So every picture or comment should have some form of a call to action.
Now you don't want people just liking you for your photography skills.
What exactly do you want them to do after they like the photo.
Do you want them to double tap to like the photo.
Do you want to get likes and obviously who doesn't.
Research has shown if you ask people in your description to like if you agree or double tap.
If you love this picture can increase likes and engagement by something like two hundred and fifty percent
now of course the opposite is if you just say.
Like this photo or please comment below and you don't give any context or any reason for it actually
has the opposite effect.
Now if you what follows are shares well you can also just say follow for more of this or follow if you
agree or something like that.
There's also plenty of apps out there that will let you right on top of your photo if you want.
So you could ask people to like your pick.
Click your link or whatever.
Literally in the photo and you don't have to do it in the comment of course.
Keep in mind it's a little cluttered sometimes so people generally don't want to look at a photo that
smash full of text.
In general the point here is don't just post a picture and then hope for things to happen.
Make sure you ask them to do something and you give them some context and some reason why then what
you do is you use your profile you are all to drive traffic.
Now one big pain about Instagram is that you cannot put a clickable link in your description or comments.
There is actually only one spot where you can add you are L and that is your profile so use it to drive
people to product pages contest entry forums and other exclusives you promote on Instagram a lot of
brands just add click the link in our profile for more info or some variation of that.
That's kind of the baseline you get more creative with it but that also works.
Nothing you do is use location tags photo maps are a fun way to view photos show your customers what
your production warehouse and office spaces look like.
Show your products in their natural habitat or being used by current customers.
Use G.P.S. data in the photos and that'll let people see your pictures aren't just coming from you sitting
at a desk and said they're out being in the world engaging with the folks.
There's some good outdoor brands that do a great job of this like RPI and Patagonia do a great job of
tagging it in some really ridiculous locations.
So edit your photos if necessary.
Instagram has by default pretty good editing tools use them and promote your Instagram posts on other
channels.
Remember obviously link your Instagram account to your Facebook Twitter Tumblr whatever it is that you're
using.
Sure there's some overlap but you never know where and when your followers will read tweet share or
repost your content.
So don't take any chances.
It's literally just an extra click sometimes.
I know there's one more piece of advice for improving your post on Instagram and then using hashtags.
In fact there's a lot I can go over so we actually prolly get a break here and cover that topic and
our next lecture.
All right guys I'll see you then.