Hey guys welcome back.
So we covered a lot of Instagram Brown on our last lecture.
How do you post what do you post and ways to improve those posts.
Well the big ways to improve your post is the subject of this lecture here and that is hash tagging.
Now you may remember a lecture I did a while back.
We talked about using Twitter and hashtags to get your first bunch of customers.
If you do.
Well that's cool.
If you don't it's not really a biggie.
They're very similar.
The long and short of it is at hash tags are clickable ways to categorize your posts with topics and
other keywords so that other people can easily find them when they look at related stuff.
And those people don't necessarily follow you.
That's kind of the point.
That's how you get exposure to people who do not follow your stuff already.
Now while Twitter has a limit on characters Instagram actually has no such limit and you can hashtag
to your heart's content adding really as many as you want.
However the hashtags will not be visible past a certain point where then people have to hit the Like
view more to see it.
But you still will get added to these things.
And in fact data tells us that post with at least one hashtag get 12 percent more engagement on average.
Whew.
Some people recommend as many as 10 or more in fact I generally like to see something in a laugh.
I like to see at least a minimum of five five to ten I don't like seeing over ten because it just makes
it look ridiculously tacky or too corporate.
When you have 40 of them looks like a robot wrote the post.
So which hashtag should you use and how do you decide on them.
Well not really depends on the post.
If you post a product picture well then think of tags that actually describe the product.
Now Best Buy posted this video to promote a cool Sony speaker.
They don't just feel the beat.
See the beat hashtag Sony audio hashtag wireless speaker at hashtag light show.
You know if you're new to Instagram most of these should obviously make sense.
The hashtags describe the product.
And if you click any of them you'll see other posts from other people on the same topic.
Now obviously you have to think why would someone be typing this hashtag in to begin with.
Do a lot of people look for Sony speakers.
Maybe if someone's interested in buying Sony speakers they might type that in.
Would someone be searching for light show.
Possibly depends.
I don't know if that's something that a lot of people use and if I expect to see pretty pictures while
doing it.
So you have to make sure that people will be searching it and what they're looking for is going to be
somewhat relevant.
MAC Cosmetics another example has a huge following on Instagram over 15 million.
Now in fact fashion is a big industry on the platform because of how perfectly suited it is to the content
that you see.
It's a visual product being shown on a visual channel.
So what exactly can we learn from this account if you have a variety of products.
Make sure you include a tag to identify in the photo description.
This picture shows a specific color of lipstick with a hashtag Russian red meaning if you click it you'll
probably see more people wearing that lipstick.
If you have a product name or variety or even a feature that's unique well then tag it consider a hash
tag your future customers might do if they had a little product research in mind.
It's kind of similar to like running Google ads what are they going to be searching for when they could
potentially find your product.
Let's say that there are people out there who are looking for you.
They just don't know who you are yet.
If they have an interest in a type of product or service they might follow that hashtag.
Wedding planner for example in the hopes of finding someone who could satisfy a need for them maybe
they need wedding planning.
And one way to use the perfect hashtag might be to create your own.
Check out this picture for example it's from buffer we love buffer and now it's a pretty impressive
one.
Buffer posted this as part of their effort to build their own community even using a branded hashtag
called buffer community.
Now the pic comes from one of their followers who they credit in the description.
So one of the wonderful features of hashtags is that they're clickable meaning you can tap that tag
and and see who else has posted pictures with that hashtag and their description is branded hashtag
can be a way to gather people around a topic or an interest.
And also keep it relevant to you.
OK.
Here's some other hashtag ideas to think about.
If you post a picture from an event well and include the event hashtag like hashtag South by Southwest.
If you were at that and I guarantee you people are going to be using that hashtag host a picture from
behind the scenes well then you can use the abbreviation of that which is B.S. or either you can use
behind the scenes or both.
So we will look for that because those are just more interesting photos.
Also you can try to hook up with weekly trends on a Thursday as people post old pictures as part of
what's called throwback Thursday.
That's always a fun time to show a really old photo could be from the 90s could for when you could be
from when you started your company or you can show some love and share a picture of another account
as part of the hashtag Follow Friday.
Kind of like a Pay It Forward Friday get super general if you have to.
What season was this picture taken in hashtag summer.
Hashtag winter.
Now are you out of ideas.
Well check out the top hashtags on Instagram.
There's a lot of inspiration there.
Now should you immediately start tagging your pictures with hashtag love.
No but this list cloud over here is going to give you some ideas about the kinds of things people post
and what they're looking for.
So if you've got an app used to find empty parking spots on local streets.
Kind of like haystack.
Except maybe you didn't get sued into oblivion.
Let's obviously just say this is possible.
Let's call it parking brake.
Now what visuals come to mind if you're doing a parking spot app called parking brake.
You could put a parking spot kind of obvious you could put a street full of cars you put an angry driver
a happy driver.
I don't know.
You can also do that thing that people sometimes do and they want to save a spot like putting a lawn
chair in the middle of it or like a cone obviously as if that's going to stop someone from taking it.
Okay obviously it works most of the time but that is what I kind of imagined.
I think of empty parking spots.
So let's say I took a picture of a lawn chair in an empty spot on a street full of cars.
Well we could make it look cool and artistic matching our style of course.
So what.
In that case would we hashtag right.
Like it's something that it's kind of funny seeing someone do this and we can make it stylistic and
artsy.
We could even highlight the neighborhood it's in right.
If you could if you're in Brooklyn you could shoot it in a way that you see the buildings behind it.
So if the hashtags.
Maybe we could do the hashtag parking brake which is our brand name definitely doesn't stop us from
using it.
Girls just do things like parking brake app because a lot of times people don't know that it's an app
because they just do basic things like hashtag parking solid.
Okay you do hashtag parking nightmare something that's funny.
Maybe people are looking for funny things.
Hashtag Save my spot.
Accurate.
Maybe you could use hashtag launch here.
I don't know.
Not necessarily the right connection.
I want to make but again there's nothing stopping you from putting more hashtags have you come up with
ten off of the back.
Great.
If you can get less than just do some research jump into the Instagram search and then see what some
potential hashtags bring back for your results.
It's pretty easy to look at competitors and see what hashtags they're using and then or you go to their
competitors and look at their followers and see what their followers are responding to or using you
don't.
Most of the parking spot hashtag pictures are on Instagram while they're there.
Pictures posted by angry people of a shitty parking jobs by other people.
This is a very commonly shared thing unlike Reddit.
People love talking about showing off people who are awful at parking parking obviously on the line
or parking in the ways that people can't pull in next to them or get out of their car.
There's generally a lot of angst on that hashtag so parking spot could be a fun one to actually hook
into especially if your photo is equally humorous.
You can easily just do some searches and then see if you're onto the right vibe.
Then decide on a group and just post away.
Now one thing though.
Try not to park yourself.
Guess that's a pun on the same hashtags.
Every single post.
You really do need to mix it up by all means stick with the vital ones like your brand or your product
name for starters but vary it up so that the hashtags people see on any given day are different and
it gives you enough exposure ultimately adding hashtags.
Your post extends their life and their usefulness.
This will improve your discover ability if that's a real word.
People will be checking out your hashtags you use well the future and it could lead to new followers
right back to you.
So make sure you have a plan to include about 10 or so five to 10 tags each time.
Make them topical make them useful or try to make them fun hashtags can help show off your personality
as well.
See what works.
Change things up and you'll have a strategy in no time.
If you mess around with Instagram for a week or two and you're you obviously are following the what
I'm telling you now it's not exaggeration that you could get 100 hundred customers if you actually put
some effort into it.
All right.
Anyway.
Sounds good.
Well we are hashtag done with this lecture.
I'll see you the next one.