Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Okay, so we're just getting started
learning about press and PR.
And before we start learning about tactics, and pitching
yourself to the media, and all that, it's really
important to look at both sides of this whole PR situation.
Now, on one side, there's you, someone with a product
or service you're trying to sell, or some kind of business
venture you're trying to get off the ground. For you,
PR is an opportunity - getting more visibility through
press coverage can lead to traffic, customers, and
other related benefits.
Now, if press to you is basically free marketing,
that is absolutely not what it is to
the person covering you. To them,
they want interesting stories that
match what their audience cares about.
So it's kind of like a little bit of a Venn diagram, you're
going to have to find the middle between "free press"
and "this is actually an interesting story."
So on the flip side of PR,
well, you're going to have a writer or a reporter, or
a blog or industry site owner, someone whose job
it is to write stories.
Oftentimes, they have to write lots of them, and
those have to be interesting to their audience.
Reporters and other members of the media are the
people you're trying to reach through these PR efforts,
so it would help to understand who they are.
So in this lecture I want to step you through a day
in the life of a reporter and give you an idea about
who you'll be looking for,
trying to sell yourself and your ideas to,
and maybe creating a relationship with.
Not like that.
I mean like a work relationship. The better you know
them, the better prepared you will be to work with them.
So here we go.
This is a day in the life of a reporter.
And if you guys have actually been a writer or something
like that, please don't give me angry comments,
because everyone's day is a little bit different,
but there are some commonalities
that we're going to explore.
All right, so I'm an average reporter, it's 3:00 AM,
I'm going to wake up and it's all about
doing Pilates and eating quinoa.
All right, I'm just kidding, I'm not
that sarcastic about the press.
Reporters are just regular people, just like you and me.
That is really the first lesson here.
Think about what your day is like, once you get rolling after
your morning coffee, or your first Mountain Dew of the day.
More than likely, you'll be looking for
ways to accomplish your regular goals.
Create new content to promote your products to your
audience to attract more customers, and think up
new ideas to improve your business.
Well, reporters aren't much different.
They're creating new content to publish on their
outlet for their audience, they're looking to attract
more readers, and they're thinking up
new ideas and things to write about.
At the core, we're all pretty similar, but the way
reporters go about their jobs is much, much different.
While you're focusing on a product, like maybe an
app, their product is their writing, their posts, their
lists, their e-books,  their social media stuff, you name it.
Their job is to create written material, so writers
are always in search of something to publish.
That's the first thing to remember about them.
For example, some tech blog writers
don't actually get paid a salary.
Like, I don't know if it's necessarily true right
now, but it used to be the case at Mashable,
they would get paid by the page view.
Even today, people who contribute to Huffington Post,
like the regular contributors, they get paid per page view.
So either they have to write long pieces with lots of
pages, which usually doesn't fly on some of these
websites, or lots of pieces. Either way,
they need ideas to write about.
So the life of a reporter very much involves
writing and publishing. At any given moment,
they're probably thinking about their next
few posts while writing their current one.
They have a responsibility to keep producing material
for their outlet, whether that outlet is a news
site, blog, or another kind of content machine.
They need to keep feeding that machine. And these
ideas for new material need to be good ones.
Reporters are always looking for something interesting
to write about. With all of these pieces they
need to write about, well, their topics need to be
something of interest to the people who are going to
be coming onto their page.
And it would really help if they had a cool unique kind
of angle to it. Reporters won't succeed if they just
write the same stuff over and over,
and audiences get bored of it.
So what else are reporters doing every day?
They're doing a lot of research.
It involves reading other blogs and sites, googling topics
to see what's out there, and reaching out to people
they know for material.
Now, at this point, you might be thinking, "Hm, reporters
would probably appreciate it if I contacted them about
my awesome product, right?"
Well, you and lots of other people
have had the same idea.
So another part of a reporter's day is actually just spent
reviewing requests from random uninvited people
like you who want to get coverage, and to the busiest
reporters, they can often get hundreds and hundreds
of them in a single day.
Let's not overlook the fact too about reporters that
many of them work for editors whose job it is to make
sure the pieces being written match the outlets'
brand and have potential for popularity.
So reporters not only need to find great ideas and write
great stuff, but they need to have approval from an editor.
Basically, it's like another audience the reporter has to satisfy. So you might win over the writer or the reporter,
but that doesn't necessarily mean
it's going to make it up the chain.
Now, if this sounds like a lot of work,
that's because, well, it often is.
So another attribute of many reporters is that they
can actually be pretty lazy, that's one thing to keep
in mind. I don't mean lazy like they don't do their job,
you know, obviously, if they don't write
and publish stuff, then they get fired.
I mean lazy in that they're going to look for writing
ideas and topics that don't take a lot of energy
or time to develop.
They're always going to be looking
for low hanging fruit, if you will,
easy to pick and do something with. Basically, what that
amounts to for you, from your perspective, is that
oftentimes a reporter might be interested in two
different stories - one story requires a lot of research,
requires a lot of writing, polishing, fact
checking, and then the other one,
well, two thirds of the story is already written for them.
So 9 times out of 10 they're going to go for that one
that's already written for them. Later on we're going to
talk about that, how you can prepackage your
stories in a way that makes it easy for their laziness
to say "I'll do that."
All right, so let's recap.
Reporters are always in search of something to
publish, because, well, their jobs basically depend on it.
This obviously depends on the outlet.
Some have more of a "publish or die" kind of ethos and
then other ones are more like "you can publish one
thing a month or two things a month,"
but still, at the same time, they're
constantly looking for stuff.
Number two is they're always looking for something
interesting, but often deal with hundreds and hundreds
of uninteresting pitches.
And number three, they're often quite lazy, so they
need ideas that are easier to work with or are at
least more developed for them.
So if you're a reporter, what would make your job easier?
Someone researching and writing your stuff
for you would be a pretty nice start, wouldn't it?
Well, it's actually not as crazy as it sounds, and when it
comes to PR, you have a better chance of connecting
with them if you kind of fill in the
gaps in their daily challenges for them.
Now, if you do approach them with a good,
interesting story, then you are doing them a favor,
but if you just approach them with the 40th app
that does the same thing and it's not as nice as the
other ones, and it doesn't have any customers,
well, no, you're not actually doing them a favor.
Anyway, moving forward in the PR section of the course,
we'll discuss ways in which you can pitch ideas to reporters
and other members of the media, and then appeal
to their needs while also satisfying your own.
Alright guys, see you in the next lecture.