Hey guys, welcome back to the course. In this lecture,
we're going to get introduced to our first strategy,
strategy numero uno, the strategia (?) -
I don't speak Spanish.
So this strategy is going to be manual,
it's going to be direct, and it's going to be
pretty basic, but it does consistently work.
One of the wonderful things about
the Internet is that it is indexable.
Now, what do I mean by that?
Well, let's say I'm driving my
Toyota Prius down the highway,
and for whatever reason the accelerator gets stuck.
Maybe later, if I'm alive, I might go online and complain
about it saying that when I hit the accelerator,
it doesn't seem to un-accelerate. Well,
because of the way that the internet works,
anyone who is looking for people complaining about
that specific braking and acceleration problem will
probably be able to find what I said online, regardless
of whether or not they saw exactly where I posted
it, when I posted it, or if they organically stumbled upon it.
That indexable-ness - yes, I just made that term up -
is what we're going to exploit with this strategy. Now,
this strategy really only takes like 30 minutes to do,
and if it works for you, it is something that
you can replicate in a small scale fashion.
Now, in the last section, we had a lecture on
understanding your customers' pain point.
And if you haven't watched that lecture,
please pause this one, go back and watch it.
That one is crucial to understanding so much of what
we do later in this course, you're not really going
to be successful at getting customers if you don't
understand why they're buying your stuff.
What you should have gotten from that lecture is 1-2 general
ideas of what problem your product or service solves.
If you also remember from the lecture, we know that
all products and services, all business ideas spring
from solving problems, they all solve
problems, even if you don't think it's so.
Even products you wouldn't associate
with being problem solving still do.
Let's take an example.
You're playing an iPhone app, let's say you're playing
Flappy Bird or Angry Birds. What problem does that solve?
It solves boredom, more specifically, boredom when
you're riding in a car or boredom when you're waiting
for your doctor's appointment,
short periods of time in which you are bored. Now,
when you combine the fact that all ideas spring from
problems and that the internet is wonderfully
indexable, I think you see where I'm going with this.
We can find some customers that have our specific
pain point. And if they have an itch and our product
is the ointment for that itch, you'd better believe than if
we just connect the dots for them, they'll buy our stuff.
So what we're going to do is we're gonna get
into the mind of our potential customers,
figure out how they would verbalize their problems,
and then we're going to use that as a way to find
them and potentially get them to buy our products.
All right.
Now that you know the name of the game, next lecture, we're
going to cover how exactly we find these paying customers.
All right. See you then.