Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So far we've been discussing how to come up with ideas for videos.
That process includes defining what your goals will be for each video and then figuring out what type
of format and what type of video you want to make.
Well you go into your ideas goals and even potentially did some keyword research.
I'd say you're at the point where you can start developing your idea into an actual video project.
Now the first step in most video marketing projects is going to be writing a video script and that's
what we're going to cover right now.
Now the reason why I say most is that not every single video project absolutely require a script.
Sometimes when you're doing tutorial videos walk through F.A. cues you might not necessarily have a
script however a script almost always will make your video better.
And especially if you're trying to make something for your company I generally think that it's a good
idea.
The only exception where I would not script something necessarily is if you're trying to make a behind
the scenes video or something where it's supposed to be spontaneous and hand and leaning heavily on
its entertainment value.
Come on.
I don't know what to do or say
all of the situations.
I definitely think it's worth scripting.
So you probably know from watching movies and TV shows that the script is what people use to help make
all that Hollywood magic happen.
A script is a written document that includes all the elements of your videos.
It's going to have the words being said the people in it the actions they take and any other elements
that you need to describe to completely tell your story and maybe your story is about how some British
kid learns magic can takes down a dark wizard.
Or maybe your video is about how to navigate the many magical features of your new app.
You just launched pretty much the same thing.
Either way a script can help me prepare everything that needs to be in your video before you start making
it.
Now if you want to make a video about your app explain the concept of paper click advertising to your
audience or marketing professional.
You don't really need to write a 120 page script to prepare everything you need to write something much
shorter maybe just a few pages maybe even just a page.
But we can take a lot of lessons from those Hollywood movie scripts to help us prepare our own.
Now one of those concepts is how to write a scene.
Now you're not obviously going to be detailing scenes for every single script you write if you're doing
a walkthrough video you're not going to write out.
This happens in my living room up against a wall is narrowly.
There's no point to that.
But in other situations you're making an ad and you're doing something or there's dialogue or interaction
between multiple people or you just switch scenes which a lot of the is you'll do this that's where
you want to be able to write scenes now in the case that you use multiple shots or multiple locations.
Scripts can be broken down into scenes which are individual parts of the video.
A lot of our marketing videos are really just going to be one scene or essentially one section of content.
So if it's an expert standing in front of a camera explaining a concept for two or three minutes like
me except I never seem to keep it under three minutes and you don't really show or do anything different
than just stand there and talk well that's basically one scene if you have a longer video with multiple
sections of content like you showed your expert and then you showed him talking to people in an office
and then you showed a screen cast with the expert narrating something.
Well those are multiple scenes notifying those separate seems just makes it easier for you to plan your
video production out.
So each scene in a script has these elements that can help you set up and prepare now within each scene.
First you want to list off your setting.
Tell us very quickly when you write this out when and where your scene takes place for movies you might
write something like interior Deathstar day.
I mean that tells us everything we need to know.
We're inside.
Location is the Death Star.
It's day time although narrowish you know it's day or night in space.
There's probably a clock somewhere anyway for marketing videos you might write something like interior
White Room day if you wanted your expert to be standing in one of those blank white rooms again.
Settings help for planning purposes because you can see where your surroundings will need to be shot.
And if you have multiple scenes set in the same place you can shoot all of them at the same time.
Basically you can keep stacking your scenes together saves you a lot of time and hassle.
Now after you list off the set and you want to write up a description for your seat when the scene begins
what do we see.
What does our location look like.
Who and what are already there.
You're establishing the visual even if you just write our Speaker John Smith is standing in front of
a white background.
You're still telling us everything we need to know to start the scene detailing the stuff out.
Also can be incredibly helpful if you ever start turning this into a multiple person production.
If you hire help from someone to help you shoot these.
This is going to be a lifesaver because they don't know exactly what you want at every given moment.
Now the next thing you might write for a scene is then going to be the dialogue.
Now this is a dialogue between assuming two people talking with one person Well it's very similar.
This is the stuff people say.
And when you write dialogue you also make a note who's saying it Evan hey it's me.
Welcome back to the course.
I only said that ha probably 400 times each time someone says something you write that dialogue into
the script.
Now that helps the speakers or actors if you actually didn't fancy you know when they need to say something
and always say to memorize it if necessary if in the case that you're not memorizing it and you're using
say like a teleprompter well then you would take these scripts and nesses what you would put into the
teleprompter.
And that saves you a lot of time.
You also write some action into the scene.
When I say action I don't really mean a car crash or a shoot out although that would be pretty cool.
But this excitement is over from the circuits and my comes about here.
What I mean is after the scene begins what happens.
So it's talking if there's something specific you're planning.
Well you need to write it into the scene.
Evan reaches off screen to grab something when his arm returns into the frame we see he's holding a
cup of coffee.
So he slips it smacking his lips when he's done.
Let's have a cup of coffee.
Oh that's probably over descriptive you could easily just right Evan grab the coffee and takes a sip
movie scripts have plenty of descriptive detail but we're not making a movie we're not even Spielberg.
We're making marketing videos and you might only need to write things like we see a screenshot of the
Google Analytics main dashboard or something like that would save your editor down the line.
A lot of time now of course this all is going to depend on what your scene is about and what's happening
now what I think you might include for your scene in a script as a transition how you get from the end
of one scene to the start of the next one will you fade out to black.
Will you dissolve into the next scene or some other fancy transition.
A lot of times you might just say cut to the actual next scene and it just begins.
What are a transition you use it's good to know when you're editing the video and post-production.
You don't have a strong opinion about transitions.
Well there's an enormous amount of literature about how transitions make people feel and what emotions
you're trying to convey and really what's cutting edge and what's just kind of cheesy now don't really
worry too much about that one.
But you know in the future when watching YouTube videos see if you can actually notice the transitions
people use
it is over many videos created for content marketing purposes you won't need all of these elements.
But the more detail you can provide the easier it will be to create whatever you have a vision for hopefully
in the resources.
We've attached a template.
Right.
So you can just fill it out.
Speaking of detail and vision you might have heard of another kind of document related to a script called
a storyboard.
Now a story board is a document that takes your script and essentially add sketches or drawings of what
your video should look like.
Each time you record a new shot within a scene it can help you see what the writer or director has in
mind.
Like where people should be standing the angle of the camera and any other elements.
Now storyboards are essential for Hollywood movies and huge productions because there's a lot of people
who work the camera do the lighting and do the editing and need to know exactly what it's going to look
like before they even show up to set.
But for marketing videos storyboard is usually much less important of a requirement.
You know may be a good idea to make a couple of drawings of specific things you want or take screenshots
of things on your computer you want display like if you're you know doing a video explaining how a feature
works on your platform.
But for the most part you really shouldn't need a storyboard rebirth can save you enormous amount of
time if you start working with like videographer's though because you know you're kind of the director
there and they're the shooter as they call it in cool speak.
But having the actual sketches of what you've seen looks like it just kind of is a huge shortcut for
the two of you.
Now this leads me to a question I've gotten several times which is what about when I'm doing like a
live stream like Facebook Live or whatever like a webinars in those situations.
I want a storyboard and or write a script in those types of situations.
You don't always want to script everything because maybe you don't have enough time maybe it's too awkward
when you know of the equipment.
But my suggestion is to script as much as you can.
There are varying degrees of scripting so you could have something as minimal as to just writing out
a topic and then having you adlib it knowing that this is the topic and the next one and the next one.
In that case it's kind of like an outline right if you know the stuff up front and you know you're talking
out that's usually enough.
Now a step up from running these just vague outlines would be a technique that I used for the first
eight of my 16 courses and that's what I call kind of the two sit ins technique are the two sentence
technique is where you write a Simmie script.
However you only write in two sentences at a time.
So if I were recording something instead of reading off a teleprompter script or memorizing something
or just adlibbing it I kind of have something in the middle where I would write down two to three sentences
at a time.
I would look at it read it get the gist of it and look back at the camera and talk through it and would
never be word for word but I made sure that I always got the point from each two or three seconds chunk
then a step up from that is literally writing a script where every word you write down comes out of
your mouth.
So back to that question which was how do you do it in live video.
Well script as much as you can.
So if you can't do a full script try doing two sentence techniques where you just have to get the gist
of and spit it back and you can't do that then just do a rough outline.
Worst case scenario if you're doing it and you don't know what you're supposed to talk about next or
something unexpected happens you always have that safety net to fall back on to look at and go oh.
Now we're talking about the next topic for your marketing videos.
Your hope is to create something with lasting value to make sure you deliver that value.
Writing a script is a really really good idea.
That preparation can save your video from looking and sounding boring and weak.
It can also make the process of shooting and editing the video much easier because the script is your
guide for everything.
What are the worst things in the world to do is to set up have everything ready cameras on you and you
don't actually know what you're supposed to say.
That is the worst time to figure out what you have to say when you're being blinded by lights and everyone
staring at you.
Tell you a secret if you guys ever took my become a product manager course in our promo call and I did
not have a script and we kind of had to make it up as we went.
And it took four times as long as it should have.
So anyway when in doubt script it out and you can put that on a poster or a T-shirt.
Give me royalties.
OK so far we've talked about the parts of a script but you might still be wondering how do I know if
my script is good.
Well that's a good question if you're writing a video script for the first time.
Now the idea here is to create a document so that when you read it you can easily visualize everything
in your head.
You can read all these elements and then you know see the setting understand when and where people appear.
You see what they say what they do and how everything flows together from scene to scene.
In fact writing a video script is a lot like running a blog post or any other written piece of content.
But really what's the difference between the two.
Well it's kind of hard to define but in a video script you're going to be writing in a more conversational
manner whereas a blog post you can write more like you're doing an essay.
There are certain words that fly on blog posts and certain words that just simply will not work.
And a video script if I said you I've investigated a plethora of solutions you would think that I'm
a robot or someone putting words in my mouth because I don't speak like that.
If you haven't noticed if you are stuck in thinking that your writing is too robotic Well here's five
tips that I can share with you to give you some ideas of how to put a script together that works for
video number one.
And you know this might be tried at this point but marimba who's watching your video.
What do they already know.
Why did they decide to watch this video and what needs to be communicated here.
Make sure you keep your audience in mind when you write your dialogue or put different elements on the
screen that use a word you haven't established yet or they haven't heard of yet.
Usually it's a good idea to define that if whatever you and helps the audience wild and doing the right
thing and really helps.
Imagine watching the video as someone who's knows nothing about what you're talking about.
And just imagine that scene in the script you would have gotten confused at some point.
Number two is defying your scope.
How much detail do you really need to go into.
How long is the video going to be.
This is what an outline comes in handy because you could make note of all the things you want to cover
and as you write you can actually stay focused.
Or three is right in a natural voice.
Now this obviously you were saying before it sounds like a reasonable thing to do when you're running
a blog post because you want it to be more readable.
But is even more important when you're writing a video script because someone will actually be saying
the word.
So again in some situations maybe you want to write a loose script or an outline because then people
can interpret that into actual language and just habitually when we speak we will speak like we speak
not how we write.
One way to help you get closer to that is to do what's called a table read.
Right.
So when you write something before you actually go and perform it or film it try reading it out loud
either to yourself or to someone else reading something and in your head versus saying it out loud you
just will get a natural reaction when something is just unnatural.
The fourth tip I can give you is that in marketing videos especially really really need to focus on
the first 10 seconds you really need to focus on hooking your audience's attention really quickly.
The A in the idea.
Now you don't need a long and elaborate intro to your video.
No one really has time for that and in fact you'll lose a lot of viewers but you do want something at
the beginning that looks good and is easy to understand.
So this should help assuming the viewer will have arrived at your video with no idea what to expect
because sometimes that happens when things get shared online.
What you do in those first 5% seconds are crucial.
And if someone's trying to watch this in order to learn something figure out what you do figure out
how to do something it's really helpful to either establish credibility show your logo or to tell them
what exactly they're going to learn and what they can do with the end of the video.
And the last ever to give you is give them something to do at the end.
Make sure you went through all your effort for some kind of pay up.
Is there an actual called action when you write this out.
It's really easy to forget to do that.
Do you want to watch next video download this purchase that the clear.
Obviously don't be too pushy.
Hopefully everything you wrote and did in your video will lead naturally to whatever the call to action
at the end is.
So keep your goal in mind as you're writing hopefully that helps a little bit know your audience know
your scope.
Make sure you write in a natural voice and if you having trouble do a table read.
Start off with something that hooks their attention with credibility or letting them know what value
you should get by watching this video.
And then the last thing is just make sure you don't forget to write in a call to action at the end of
your script.
If you can do those things and your video scripts should come out well.
All right guys I'll see you next Lutter.