Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
So in the last lecture I showed you how to create canonical long form content really involved but for
what you actually provide it's generally worth the effort.
You checked it out.
Definitely do it in this lecture.
I've got another tactic you can use to create content.
Now these We're going to call controversial posts.
This is that thing or you pick a religion or a political figure of some kind and you just start laying
into them repeatedly personal attacks talking about their moms just horrible stuff.
Actually I'm kidding.
And that's not what I mean by controversial post.
You're not trying to anger someone in the world of content marketing you're always trying to be noticed.
Normally you let the value of your content do the talking for you but with a controversial post you're
just trying to spark a conversation or engagement with an aggressive title contrarian topic or both.
Now to be clear you don't really just want to jump into that religion or politics fool because you'll
drown honestly stay out of the deep end of things that are way too controversial and you can never win.
Avoid those at all costs.
It's just not worth it.
Now controversial posts are the ones where you're not going to bother being diplomatic.
We're polite and you're going to take a stand on something if you truly believe in something like Coke
is better than Pepsi.
Well then write a post and state that will you piss off Pepsi drinkers of the world.
Perhaps when they might comment on your post telling you that you're wrong or sharing it and telling
their followers how wrong you are.
Well that's actually kind of the point you want to generate reactions and sharing.
Other types of engagement.
Sometimes you need a strong piece of content like a controversial post to spur people to take action.
It's also worth noting that controversial pieces can show that you are not a sheep following the herd
but in fact you can think originally and you're not just arguing for the sake of it.
You might even be seen as a visionary or an influencer.
These benefits are nice but in the end you really want to generate those reactions we talked about.
So over avoiding religion politics the Nazis and black lives matter.
What topics should you talk about.
Well the answer is relatively easy.
Stick with the same topics you've been thinking about through all the lectures you've watched.
I'm talking about topics relevant to you and your audience.
There's no reason to change that now and go off running a post at the Syrian civil war and I can say
that's still a no go topic even though I have no idea when you're watching this video because well that
civil war has no end in sight.
Sad face emoji.
Instead with this tactic we're going to address the topics relevant to your specific needs and issues
related to that need.
And then we're going to give some people or brands or old fashioned ways of thinking and doing things
a good kick in the nuts.
I wish I had as many of them.
So there's three types of controversial posts I want to cover here.
Now the first type is the old right way vs. wrong way of doing things.
Post.
Maybe you've seen posts out there that list options for like web hosting or moving services or who knows
what but they write just to inform you and stopped short of actually choosing the best.
Well those are the distant Canadian cousin of the type we're currently talking about.
Why Canadian because they're ridiculous.
Polite.
In our case forget being diplomatic.
Call one out as the clear victor and then explain why say that strong man's moving service should be
called.
We'll see man moving service and another customer service is clearly inferior.
Another example if you know anything about project management for example you know that there are a
bunch of different approaches people use.
One of the older ways of managing projects with something called the waterfall approach.
But in recent years things like Agile frameworks and specifically things like the scrum framework have
become a lot more popular if you are for some reason fascinated by this stuff.
Waterfall is basically a let's do everything at once and figure out what we did wrong afterwards and
scram as a type of agile process.
That's basically more like let's just do a little bit here and then reconvene afterwards.
Anyway maybe you decide scrimmages better.
You highlight a bunch of reasons why and you title your post seven ways scrum is clearly better than
waterfall for project management.
You're not pulling any punches.
You have a clear vision angle and you're going all in on it.
People who agree with you will want to share it and people who don't will want to troll it
so that's one way to do it.
Now another type of controversial post would be to straight up declare that something is dead every
year or somewhere somebody in the entertainment media writes a post that says Saturday Night Live is
dead and in social media someone always writes Twitter is dead.
Ironically oftentimes on Twitter there's always someone who wants to drum up controversy in conversation
and that that's one way of actually doing it.
However repetitious that is.
For example remember how a bunch of designers some years ago adopted flat design.
You know that design that decided everything was too complex and advanced and then decided that icons
should now really look like basic doodles.
Yeah.
That one apple was using it.
So of course lots of people followed suit and of course just as flat design really reaches its peak.
People started anticipating its downfall.
If you Google that design is dead you'll see all kinds of posts from 2013 2014 and so on.
Now keep in mind these articles weren't all written just to be controversial.
2014 fast company wrote is flat design already passe.
Basically they truly wondered where the industry was going.
They could have gone with a safer more generic title like The future of flat design or even something
like evaluating the impact of flat design on mobile devices.
But these titles kind of read like academic reports asking if something is passe or declaring it dead
or useless or obsolete is really just another way to grab people's attention and make people notice.
People who agree will want something that reinforces their opinions of the read it.
People don't want their opinion challenged or that they just want to rage at the page.
That might be a really good time for you to get angry.
That's my secret.
I'm always
right.
Now the third type of controversial post worth covering is what I called the rebuttal when a blogger
media source or someone else declares something you respond with their own post and declare the opposite.
So when someone posts Twitter is dead you're right.
Twitter is not dead and here's ten reasons why it's basically that old playground argument of did not.
Did too but you know in content marketing form not only can you spur some responses with a strongly
worded post like this but you can also get the attention of the original poster and perhaps engage in
some online fisticuffs.
People might not pay for your product yet but they'll probably pay to watch you virtually fistfight
someone.
Now here is an example.
If you google rock n roll is dead you'll find a bunch of people whining about the current state of music
and Miley Cyrus and everything else.
But then if you search for a rock n roll is not dead you'll find plenty of people arguing the exact
opposite.
They don't like Miley Cyrus are either but they're happy with the current state of rock whether it's
an actual rebuttal to a written piece or just a kind of reaction to a general vibe you're getting from
customers.
Your post can state your support for a specific cause or angle.
All in the hopes of getting shares and reactions.
All right so here's another example.
Remember a while back there is that big public backlash against SeaWorld when a documentary called Blackfish
came out accusing them of animal abuse.
Well it accused them of animal abuse and you know not telling their trainers that one of their killer
whales what might be a little extra killer.
It cost them boycott's and a lot of online grumpiness.
Well a blog called Awesome ocean fired back and posted Blackfish is dead wrong and here's why.
The writer highlighted a few reasons they called the makers of the film selfish.
I personally would have called them shellfish but that's because I'm a little tone deaf ears.
Anyway the blog took a stand they believed in against the source they thought was wrong.
If there's a source you disagree with.
You can do the same thing now obviously don't go and write 10 reasons why Japanese whaling is great
unless one your business has something to do with whales.
Oceans are seafood too.
You actually believe that in theory you're a terrible person.
So there you've got three approaches worth considering.
We have the right way versus wrong way post.
The something is dead or obsolete post and then we have the rebuttal post.
Now of course in each case that we covered it's going to be really important that you get your headline
right for a controversial post to work.
Got to grab their attention like both hands grab it.
Use your robot hand if you have to shake it violently.
You know what I mean.
So how can you put together a great headline for your controversial piece.
I got three tips that I want to share.
First off stick with the fundamentals of good headline writing that we covered a couple years ago when
we talked about creating content for your audience.
Keep headlines to around 6 to 10 where it's long that keeps the headline fully readable in any format
or any screen and concise enough that it's easy to understand.
Second add controversial adjectives and or terms to the title.
Be confident and almost arrogant with your descriptions refer to things as the best or the worst and
use sharp adjectives like terrible crazy ridiculous mindblowing you know the terms that really only
exist in real life when you're goofing around with friends and trying to one up each other.
You know what I mean.
If you're with friends you might actually say crazy over-the-top stuff like this.
Pizza is the best ever.
Or where is the train.
It's the worst ever.
Or come on this Batman movie is worse than a minion's movie.
For example a site called Noble compiled a bunch of stories from people about terrible dining experiences
but the title doesn't try to sugarcoat anything it's just title horrified customers share their absolute
worst and Kappes dining experience.
Not only are the dining experiences the worst but the customers are horrified as well.
Too strong controversial as is for the price of one.
Personally I wouldn't say absolute worst because it's a headline not something you'd say to your best
girlfriend while driving down the highway in L.A. but whatever.
That's my preference.
Here's another example.
There's a sales strategist that wrote on their blog we'll throw it up on the screen about how a lot
of sales trainers share out of date information of the people they train.
But the blog post and the video within it are called Five Deadly Lies.
Every salesperson has been told by sales trainers not only do sales trainers lie but their lies are
deadly.
And apparently every salesperson has been told these deadly lies.
So really every sales person ever should just be dead.
OK maybe his title is a bit of an overreach.
Mr. Sales strategist or the spirit of these controversial posts.
Maybe Mr. Sales strategist you're just lying.
My advice here is that controversial doesn't mean overselling what you're delivering and your post your
title isn't accurate then it is therefore wrong.
Remember you still have to be credible at the end of the day.
That shouldn't hold you back from using more flamboyant adjectives.
Now here's a third tip for your headline.
Don't avoid conflict.
Highlight it again.
Forget diplomacy.
Don't be Canadian.
If you're going to attack something or someone name names.
Neil Patel recently wrote a piece called eight businesses that failed at content marketing and what
we can learn from them.
It was in his Forbes magazine and you could have called it lessons we can learn from failed content
marketing or something softer like that but he actually called out the companies included in the piece.
Now this technique is strong and it is effective.
Here's another example.
A piece called Why I hate Starbucks.
This is a personal lifestyle blog for The Huffington Post and yes the f bomb is censored in the title
but you kind of get the picture.
Strong opinions strong headline.
What's that.
The devil's words in your headline.
I will give you one of my clicks.
Good sir.
Well done.
So again without sounding too redundant headline is a key piece of making a controversial post work.
Now let's think about you.
What kind of controversal post could you write.
You want to stay within your topics and stay relevant to yourself and your audience.
But if you're looking for inspiration just go to Google and type in why I hate the term about your industry.
Graphic Designers can search for why I hate Photoshop.
For example while salespeople can search for why I hate sales trainers.
I don't know something like that.
Try some variations.
Photoshop is the worst photoshop sucks.
The results could show you post that either agree or disagree with the statement you looked for.
Either way it's great inspiration.
Here's another idea.
Go to read it and look for some controversial posts in some somberness for controversial posts are more
common like politics for example.
You can actually sort by controversial post that really polarize the reader with one click.
What a controversial post on Reddit means is that there's a big difference between lots of people of
voting but also lots of people down voting array as opposed to just top which means a pure mass of people
voting and not a lot of down votes.
Now Photoshop isn't quite as controversial though so what you can do is just go to like the photo shop
sub read it within that then search for the word hate and see what posts come up.
Here's a post that cuts right to the heart of the matter.
Photoshop prose.
What are some task that you hate.
The author asked what do you hate and what eases the pain.
Well you might find are people ranting and such but these rancid opinions could be the core of a controversial
post you're right based on that post about Photoshop.
Maybe you could write seven things artists hate about Photoshop.
Doesn't even necessarily have to be about you.
Now if you want to see how one site in particular creates controversial posts.
Check out that notable site that I mentioned earlier on their home page.
Actually you can sort by most controversial.
Not only can you learn from the articles listed there and see what they touch upon and how you can also
see what the titles look like and if there's a way you can use that to your advantage.
So what do you want to rant about or complain about.
What myth do you want to debunk or sacred brand or best practice.
Do you just want to rip apart write your controversial posts.
Give it a nice and Prickley headline and prepare for engagement.
All right guys that's it for now.
I'll see you in the next lecture.