All right guys welcome back to the course.
So the last couple of lectures we've been looking at editing programs like premier that you could use
to create your marketing videos.
Now you can see they're pretty powerful pieces of software.
But the sad news in all of this is that you still have to do most of the work yourself.
There's really no feature yet where you can say OK here is all my footage and please cut it together
for me.
Now if you for some reason don't want to do that basic level of work well then you've got to hire people
to do it for you.
And actually we're going to talk about outsourcing in a later lecture.
But let's assume that for now you do actually have to do that basic level of editing yourself.
Well first of all let me tell you it's really not that bad.
Put on a good podcast and kind of just space out as you do it.
The good news is that you can make a ton of progress with editing by creating a thing called a rough
cut or rough cut is a quick and dirty edited version of your video.
Not dirty as an adult dirty but dirty as in it won't be perfect and that is perfectly fine.
What a rough cut basically is is when you take all your footage you stick it together.
You get rid of all the bad takes all the retakes and then you sync the audio together and then you know
you pick which camera you want to use if you're doing multi-cam and you might think that I described
everything you do in editing but no not really after that fact and you have to do actual adding notes
and you put on your B-roll that's what you put in your time lapses as you put in your text titles of
facts transitions all that stuff.
A rough cut is basically just the bare basics.
Now you don't have to move anything on the timeline significantly.
And it should be ready for you to just kind of throw things on top and rough cuts usually also do some
corrections where like maybe the microphone accidentally came into the frame.
You might well crop it then or maybe one of the lights went out.
So he took out that section or maybe the colors are off.
So you did a little adjusting to the brightness.
The idea is this by creating a rough cut you can get to see an approximation of what your finished video
will look like you're good to see a rough idea of what it sounds like how long it is with the pacing
or rhythm of the whole video is like Rough Cuts are a great first step in the post-production process
because it can also let you know if you need to go back and reshoot anything.
Generally speaking the editing process will go filming right.
Then you have all the raw data you might do some processing to the videos if you want to like downsampling
talked about before on the camera and lecture and then you do the rough cut and the rough cut is the
quickest you stitch together gives you the best kind of overall look at your piece and then you go into
multiple rounds of editing or just one round.
So you go from rough cut to final cut.
In our case or videos we film it then we downsampled a video then rough cut goes to text and title cut
which is kind of like an intermediate cut where we add in text and titles and then it goes to people
who add graphics illustrations animations and all the other random stuff you've seen in here.
Now it's really going to be up to you what happens after the rough cut that's going to come down in
your process and what are you figure out works for you and also does depend on how many people you're
working with and if you're doing all of the process and also how many videos you're making.
So anyway how do we make a rough cut.
Well in general look for the best take in your video and then cut out the others.
Really the easiest way of doing that is to use what I call the scrubber but it's also called the play
head and you just scan through your video looking for each individual cut.
What it comes with the visual look for Takes where people look their best and aren't making weird faces
or movements when it comes to sound well listen for the best read of a line which time actually sounds
the best or most like the mood you're trying to create.
Also you notice any weird stuff like hums bumps cars people screaming outside in the window.
Don't use those takes if possible.
Really it's that simple.
You take all your videos you throw it in a timeline you sync up the audio and then you cut out the bad
takes.
Then you might do some light rearranging or picking which camera to use when you're done with that you're
done with the rough cut that is literally it but past that there are some ways that you can speed up
this process or at least do it more efficiently.
It's not going to go over six different steps that you can use to make this process work a little better.
So number one is always have your script or storyboard with you while you at it.
Really don't try to edit from memory.
Use your script or a shortlist as a reminder.
You'll stay on track knowing exactly what comes next.
Sometimes it's really hard to tell inside the editing what's going on.
Also with having the script you can see where people deviate from it so a lot of times you might have
four different takes one of them sounds the best but then you look at it and doesn't actually match
the script perfectly.
So you might end up choosing another one.
The second thing is it really helps to edit in a sequential order.
Start at the beginning of your script or storyboard and then edit there first then going straight through
to the end.
Editing an order can help you from being getting confused about what shots or pieces go where.
Don't try to jump back and forth because a lot of times ends up happening in the second half then you
do the first half and you'll just miss a chunk and then when you make your rough cut Oops there's a
whole bunch of stuff that wasn't supposed to be in there.
Number three is while you're editing use the audio wave form as a guide you can see in the actual timeline
when you have the audio it has a wave form where it goes up when people are speaking and it's loud and
goes down when it's quiet.
Then you can see exactly where people start and stop talking where they take long pauses smack their
lips cough whatever these noises make very distinctive shapes inside the wave form.
So if you see them you'll know oh they're about to mess up.
This is honestly one of the easiest ways of going through a rough cut is just when you first look at
it go and cut out sections where no one's talking.
That's an easy way to tell.
But you just look at the way form no one's talking.
Other thing you can do a lot of times is you'll notice filler words or things you're not supposed to
be saying like write well or um typically if you've done this enough and that happens with me I can
look at the waveform and actually spot those words because they make a very unique waveform repeatedly.
I don't even have to listen to the tape to figure it out.
Number four is when making your cuts make sure to leave actress face before and after each takes you
can shift things around if necessary.
Maybe it's an extra second or so whatever it's fine.
Remember you don't need to be precise in this cut yet.
Number five is don't add any transitions just do them later if you add them now.
Kind of going to get stuck in the order that you put the clips and set with the camera angles you might
want.
I generally with a rough cut you want to be able to easily move them around.
The reason this is add temporary titles.
If there are spots where they ought to go.
Don't worry about creating any nicely designed or animated titles.
Just create quick placeholders and then replace it later with the real thing.
Repeat this process until you're done and then when you're back when you are actually done give the
whole thing a watch.
GIGOT a nice sense of accomplishment from watching it all the way through and you should because you're
much closer to getting the whole thing done at the same time it might feel like you're watching a low
budget movie.
Well the edits are probably a little bit off the pacing to and that's perfectly fine.
A rough cut gives you a starting point where you can focus on fixing some of the finer issues.
Like I know is each cut sinked up with the audio.
Are all the effects in there correctly.
And obviously incorporating all of the titles you might want to do it don't take too much time with
your offcut again.
Do a quick and dirty run through your footage a simile or video and make your plans from there.
It's a big item to cross off your post-production checklist for sure.
Also we're talking about is that because the process is so simple and so repeatable.
This is often one of the things that people will outsource.
Can noise gets some of the cheapest people to do it because anybody with half a brain can do this.
They can just look through and go out.
Don't talk there don't talk there.
Occasionally you might some issues where they don't know which take to take what it take to choose but
what you can do is you can just watch the whole thing and put little markers for them so they know this
is the good one.
Sound good.
OK.
See the next lecture.