All right guys welcome back.
We begin our discussion of FCL and in our last lecture discussed how Google works and basically has
established many of the best practices and tools we use to understand SCEA today.
Well one of the things we learned over the years of studying search data is the value of what we call
longtail SBO.
Now let me talk about what that is.
Takes a little bit of explanation.
Now the simplest searches out there desk for example I don't know who search his desk but you know it's
a simple search are going to get more searches by users on Google than more complex searches like do
it yourself standing desk instructions.
Bamboo wood the simple search term is very broad so there are tons of pages out there that could be
potentially relevant to it.
Almost a billion in fact.
But of course who can do anything with a search result page like that.
Also known as you'll see as canceling drives me nuts but it's S-C RPE for short.
Now as DRP as search engine result page.
So if you want to be cool and hip with the lingo lingo you can say CERP or as I call it sir.
Now syrups or S-E are peas with that many results offer too much information too much ground.
So we as human beings have learned to get more specific with our search terms in order to find what
we need.
We're trying to figure out how to make my own standing desk for example I might actually search for
do it yourself standing desk instructions instead.
And then from there I'll find that there's over a million results but still far less than what we had
before and are just searching for desk right now.
Here is where the data comes in.
If you took a number of results from those simple terms just desk and the other more complex related
searches with desk in them and graft it all out well that looks something like this.
You got a huge spike of search results for the simplest terms.
And then as searches get more complex more words and them basically more keywords You're a sharp downward
slope of relevant search results or what people Nescio call the Long Tail it extends basically for ever
for the rest of relevant searches.
So we say longtail we're talking about that section of the graph where there are really really specific
searches not as many people doing them but there's almost like infinite combinations of them.
Those are the ones that are low competition and they're easiest to rank for.
But here's why this graph is important.
All those simple searches of a ton of relevant results.
You don't want to try and compete for the mirror what happens if you just search for desk Well you're
going to get all sorts of stuff and it's pretty much impossible to read through it to find what you
want.
People can only find what they need if they type in longer and more specific search terms.
It also kind of goes without saying that if you're going to search through a billion pages the ones
that are show up or something of that vague are going to be enormous companies with enormous SBO value
and and possibly tens of thousands of other pages.
So yeah good luck in trying to rank for that.
Now those longer search terms that people use and they know specifically what they want or what are
found in the long tail and those are the searches that you generally are going to want to try for.
It doesn't make sense.
Now don't worry about rank and ask if you are producing an article about how to get put together your
own standing Yes concentrate instead on the needs of people who are searching for your content.
What questions are they asking.
What needs do they have.
How can you satisfy those needs for information or data or products with your web pages or blog post.
These questions should drive your actions and help you think about what kinds of posts and articles
to write and publish.
By writing great focus content that addresses specific user needs your work will naturally more and
be more relevant to longer more specific keyword phrases.
Now going back to our example.
Well if you were actually making a guide about building a standing desk Well you wouldn't even want
to go for desk people aren't going to find you if they're searching for a desk.
But you have a better chance of finding your own article you search for.
Build your own standing desk or DIY Danding desk or even things like how to make a standing desk or
hundreds of others of slightly different variations on that question.
Now these keywords are located well down that long tail of that crap and people are looking for those
terms will find you because well it's not crowded and they're really looking for you to read.
Your strategy is going to be looking for these longtail as the opportunities and then writing posts
and articles or retailing the stuff we already have to target those because we know well there's a good
chance we'll be featured in them.
So this leads to a good question which is how do we figure out which keyword phrases and terms to focus
on.
Well lucky for you this is a topic we'll cover and our next lecture.
See the.