Hey guys, welcome back.
So what do I mean when I say raising your Reddit IQ?
I mean to say that if I just let all of you go and try
your best at making Reddit work for your business,
almost all of you would fail ingloriously.
Why?
Because if you haven't actually spent a lot of your
life living and breathing and scrolling through
online forums, you might not really fit in, so to speak.
Yes, it's true that Reddit's community
spans all types of people.
53% are male, the average age range is like 18 to 40,
there are 80-year-olds and quadriplegics and celebrities,
obviously separate people, not all in the same
person, but they're all on there.
But Reddit as a whole has their own way
of operating and their own way of speaking.
Sometimes if you just learn these rules of conduct and the
vernacular they use, it's actually enough for you to blend in.
So, generally, the first thing I suggest you do is go
to the first link in the resources called Reddiquette.
If you're one of those people that can't find the resources
section and are at risk of drowning in a bathtub,
then just google Reddit Reddiquette
or go to Reddit.com/wiki/reddiquette.
Now, here is where they lay out the
general global rules for the community.
Not every single one is set in stone, but checking your
behavior against this before you post can dramatically
increase your chance of success.
Now, the first thing you might notice scrolling
through that list is that most Redditors don't actually
follow all of these rules, especially in the category
of "don't accuse someone without proof" or "don't
downvote something just because you don't like it."
But c'est la vie, what can you do?
Just do your best to follow the rules the best you can.
Now, the main ones out of this list
I think that are worth pointing out,
there is a focus on being human.
Yes, I know, that sounds weird, as if you're like a robot
that's being asked to comprehend love, but what
they really mean is be conversational.
If you are talking to someone, how would you sound
versus if you were writing them an email or writing
an advertisement targeting them?
No, you would not say "There were a plethora of choices across
a myriad of options." Did I pronounce that right? I don't know.
Unless, of course, you are just irredeemably pretentious.
So just because you're behind a keyboard
doesn't mean you're any less of a human.
Other key takeaways,
stay away from words associated
with clickbait, like "breaking."
Make sure you announce every time you edit something,
don't pick fights.
There are almost like a hundred things on that list, so
just scan through them.
OK, now let's talk a little bit about
how people speak on Reddit.
Every country has its own dialect,
every neighborhood has its own slang,
and Reddit is really no different.
All right.
So here is the 80:20 of Reddit slang so you don't
accidentally just screw it up the first time you try.
OP, which you might have heard me
actually say before, means original poster.
So when you're commenting in threads, it can get really
confusing as to who is referring to who. The person
who posted the thread, made the original post,
will forever be the OP.
Subs, you know what those are.
Not submarines, not metro stations, or that
sandwich chain that Jared betrayed our trust with.
It means subreddits, subcommunities,
always displayed as /r/ and
then the actual name. What are upvotes and downvotes?
Well, in Reddit, if someone likes your post, they
will upvote it, if they don't, they will downvote it.
Upvotes will move your post and your comment to
the top of the list. When you post or are looking at a
post, you can see on the side the
ratio of upvotes to downvotes.
That's actually a fantastic gauge of whether or
not the community likes what's being posted.
Be aware, every single post will have downvotes.
It is just the way of Reddit.
Like the YouTube video of a paralyzed man learning
to walk again onto the beach into the sunset.
Yes, there are actually people who would downvote that
video. Karma is a fake currency that's used on Reddit
to show who posts and contributes
the best content and comments.
When you get upvoted you get one karma.
Your karma is then divided between your
post karma and your comment karma.
So keep this in mind.
Everyone can see your karma in both categories and
in which subs you received the karma in. Virtually
all users will use this as a barometer of how
seriously to take you when you post. More
karma means they're less likely to respond angrily or
negatively or call you out for something. Throwaway,
this means an account used for the sake of being
anonymous and it's something that we will definitely
use, and people for the most part are OK with.
Next up, Xpost. An Xpost, this is a posting
that has appeared in multiple subs.
Sometimes this is fine and sometimes it's not, we'll
actually talk about it later. Linkjacking, this refers to when
you share a blog that merely covers a news story.
It's a bad tactic and they consider it kind of like
a cheap shot way of getting people to
your blog as opposed to the news story.
Don't do it, it's not a good idea.
Other terms very specific to Reddit, AMA, an AMA is a
thread where someone offers to answer any questions,
it means "ask me anything."
Eli5 means a thread where someone asked a question
and wants you to explain it to them like they're
five years old, and not in the "you'll understand
when you're older" (you won't) way,
but in the "please make string
theory really simple for me" way.
OK, that's a good starter kit of vocabulary for you to use.
Keep in mind, generic internet lingo, like IMO,
IRL, AFK, are all used, so brush up on that if you're rusty.
If you want to, and I suggest you do, because it's honestly
interesting, go to the other link in the resources
that has an exhaustive list of Reddit terms.
There are a lot in there that we didn't cover,
but God, there's no way to cover all of those.
OK, next lecture, onto the step two, where
we start looking for our communities.
See you then.