Oh, and would you look at that, you stayed with me.
Let's get back on track with number six, email marketing.
I am sure you have subscribed to a couple newsletters,
Groupons, Udemies, or your favorite restaurants.
When you get ads routinely advertising discounts
or giving you news about the business,
that is what email marketing is. The gist here is
that you build up a subscription base of emails by
actively trying to get users to sign up.
Then you send emails regularly trying to sell your
products or services or just trying to endear yourself
to the person receiving the email.
True story, go to Udemy.com, create
a second account, wait 48 hours,
they will send you an email with a $10 coupon.
Don't tell them I was the one who told you.
Now, multi-billion dollar businesses have been built
off email marketing, so don't ignore this channel,
especially if you want to emulate Groupon,
that flaming ball of trash hurling itself
currently towards the earth.
Number seven, existing platforms. Now, depending on
what you're selling, there may or may not be established
platforms or businesses that you can
piggyback off of to sell your product.
No, I'm not talking about Twitter, which
actually falls into a different channel.
I'm talking about if you, say, sell $6,000 wooden desks,
mostly to people in Brooklyn, you have Etsy.
If you sell antiques, electronics, or something
you just stole, you have Ebay or possibly Amazon.
If you sell digital courses, you have something like Udemy.
If you're renting out a vacation home or a spare
space that you have, you have Airbnb. If you sell
graphic design, there are a whole bunch of places.
Now, it's not just platforms that can sell your stuff,
you can use the platforms for your promotional efforts.
Facebook, for instance, can be used to promote your
app or game, Spotify, you can create a playlist that
links back to your website, SlideShare lets you put
presentations up online and then link back to your
site, etc. Can you leverage the promotional and community
aspects of a different system to bring in traffic for your site?
Well, this strategy, which is often compared to being
a tick on a dog's collar (I think Gandhi said that),
there are still large businesses
that have been built this way.
Don't ignore it.
Number eight, affiliate programs. Affiliate programs
are sets of incentives that you make, publish, and
then manage to entice affiliates into
promoting your product on their own.
Affiliates are people that are
authorized to sell your product.
In this case, you might not have complete
control over how they promote it.
You end up giving the affiliate a cut of your sales profit,
often a high amount, and that further incentivizes
them to continue marketing your product.
That is, of course, until they find a better deal to sell
and they jump ship - usually to porn. Number nine,
business development. Business development, often
called B-Dev by the bros, is the process of establishing
partnerships and agreements with other companies
or startups to either promote each other's products
or services or to simply use the product.
You find a partner company, website, community, or blog,
and you establish a promotional partnership of some sort.
Maybe you agree to promote each other's products,
commonly referred to as a joint venture (JV).
Maybe you share ad space, since your groups are
complementary, or, in the extreme, maybe you combine your
products or offer a large discount to your partners
group, or you just sell them a big old contract to
your stuff. Number ten and the last one
we're going to cover, targeting blogs.
This could honestly be called PR, but in this
day and age, it actually needs its own channel.
This is when you go out and target
individual blogs in your niche.
You could get them to straight promote you with
an affiliate setup, but more likely, you'll ask them to
let you guest blog or something similar.
What is guest blogging? You might ask.
It's when you ask the blog if you can write some content
for them and either have a blurb about yourself
at the bottom or get to mention your
product, and then they post it on their blog,
the benefit being that they get content
from an expert and you get exposure.
Ok, wow, that was the whirlwind tour of the
10 channels we will cover in this course.
If you want to read about the other nine, I suggest you
read the attached resources, where we describe them.
This will help you out in the next section, where we
talk about building your strategy and which of the
19 fits you and your product specifically.
All right, I'll see you in the next lecture.