Hey guys welcome back.
So we started the section with a couple lectures about SVM what it is specifically why it's important
and a whole lot of detail about you know the terms that are involved with it.
PPC C-p MCP a is that we have quality score.
We have ADD rank you can reward that the previous lecture if you guys don't feel like you understood
the concepts thoroughly.
Now with all this info being thrown at you you might still be wondering is s.a.m right for me.
I get my toe into the paid search pool and try it out.
Is this something I should stay out of or should I jump right in with both feet cannonball style and
just like any other channel or tactic paid isn't the right move for everyone.
And it's certainly not a requirement.
Many web sites and business owners out there ignore it completely and just focus on Organic SEO efforts
to build traffic and their audience and some of them are doing great.
Just creating blog posts and articles sending out emails to people engaging on social networks etc..
Now there are a lot of channels you can use to grow your audience without the need for paid tools like
the ones we're going to discuss here.
However it's something that it's probably worth trying out just to see if it works for you should probably
try to explore the many avenues as you can.
As many traction channels as you can but just keeping in mind in general if you're not selling something
well then it can be hard to justify paid search.
Like if I'm selling something at $100 Well then it's pretty easy to say well I got to optimize this
ad and this landing page to get enough people to convert before I spend $100.
But if you're doing something else or you're selling to me it's five bucks you're selling something
that's just download like a freemium that it might be a little bit harder to justify.
And there are certain disadvantages that come with going the paid advertising route.
For one thing click through rates on search ads or just really low again or averaging around 2 percent.
Now for display ads it's actually even lower like less than a half of a percent.
I think it's like point three five of a percent.
Now the reason why display ads just don't know when clicks on them it just has to do with what we call
banter blindness and that's a concept that I think we covered in one of the earlier lectures of the
really long course some Never forget where we actually cover it.
But basically what happens is people get used to ads and especially getting used to ad formats and over
time as more and more people get used to it.
Your brain starts to just filter it out naturally.
So I don't know.
I can't even think the last time I saw a display ad but if I went through and looked at the last and
web sites I was at I guarantee there are some display ads I just don't notice them anymore.
It's also something referred to as the law of should he click through.
We won't get into it right now.
Also worth pointing out there's a general distrust amongst a big piece of the population out there when
it comes to any sort of paid advertising online study done a few years ago showed that between 40 and
50 percent of people trusted search ads social ads mobile ads and display ads 40 to 50 percent.
That's it.
The other half is really skeptical.
Now Trust has improved which is good.
But advertising still isn't as trustworthy as things like say advice for people you know or online reviews.
But at the same time there are some companies that not only use SVM they rely entirely on it.
Some good examples are e-commerce shops e-commerce shops oftentimes just really really heavily rely
on ads.
This is excellent and you see more and more now and it still blows my mind.
But a lot of kick starters are using search engine ads knowing that to back something at $400 or $300.
They can justify using search tools and especially if they're just using search ads for people searching
for really specific things or even just searching the name of the project they heard of.
Now are you still undecided about using SDM.
You probably are that's perfectly fine.
Let me offer some good reasons to use SVM.
Now some of these just might apply to your specific situation so you might want to use SVM to give something
new or timely a boost when you launch a new product page or web site.
You certainly want people to notice it but new content doesn't have any organic value by itself.
So you can use paid search to immediately get your ads in front of people who might be interested in
what you've got when they search for relevant terms.
For example right after the Pittsburgh Penguins won the Stanley Cup in hockey search ads pretty much
began immediately showing up on search results for Pittsburgh Penguins champion shirts and they were
from apparel companies selling championship shirts so that's a great example of you need to be shown
in front of people immediately.
So it obviously makes sense to strike the iron while it's hot and sell shirts to all the penguins and
other flightless birds living in Pittsburgh.
I don't remember if that new product happens to be an app you can specifically create an app ad which
will appear on phones and tablets and drive people directly to the mobile app store specifically for
that device.
That saves some steps if you're trying to get app downloads and new users from your paid efforts.
In general the fewer steps it takes for a customer to convert the more like they will convert say that
a thousand times.
They might also consider paid search to help you break through the competition.
If the search terms you want to rank for are dominated by competitors or your industry is just really
competitive in general using the paid search option might get you listed above others on the piece.
Some industries especially like service industries have dozens of companies that all offer very similar
things.
Think of tech right with like say web design agencies or even marketing agencies.
They're actually even pay per click agencies so that level of density actually makes it such the case
that you might be able to pull off running an ACM marketing campaign to seek out a little bit.
Finance is another industry that's pretty much the same way.
There's a lot of competition for services that are all very similar.
In fact tech finance and Consumer Services have historically had clicked through rates that are higher
than average probably because people are usually looking for help with building a web site or saving
money for retirement or whatever it is when they click the ad.
So if you offer a service and compete with a bunch of other places paid search might be an option for
you.
Other companies use paid search for some more specific reasons.
Now you might use SVM to keep traffic consistent like you trying to make your efforts work but maybe
not getting enough traffic or traffic is very inconsistent.
Paid ads might be a way to pick up some of the slack when you need to focus on specific conversions
paid search can also help.
Organic links might take visitors to your home page or some other page but you can set up your ads to
drive users to landing pages designed to drive users to take an action like buying something.
These ads could be based on mobile behavior as well.
Like if someone installed your app a while ago you can show them an ad inviting them to come back or
highlighting a new feature in the app.
They're not using it at times.
There's a specific kind of performance metric you're hoping to impact with advertising.
You usually wouldn't start running and paying for an ad just to see what happens.
You want to get more sales more users more awareness amongst your competitors or more use of your app
something that justifies spending the money to make that actually happen.
So if you find yourself in this position wanting to improve some part of your website or app performance
page search and other SVM options might be something you should try out.
And if you want to learn more about setting up ads and giving it a shot just keep watching because the
lectures to come will help you out.
All right guys I'll see you then.