Hey guys welcome back.
The last four lectures we've talked through tactics for creating content that can be controversial that
can be hyper topical.
And one other one.
Well now it's time to climb the mountain and discuss how to create a piece of content bigger and better
than anyone else's.
Bigger and better this kind of sounds like every strategy from every movie bad guy ever right.
Bigger and better guns bigger and better viruses bigger and better robots.
Well when it comes to content it's really not that dramatic.
So we're going to talk about the skyscraper technique now a skyscraper technique is basically looking
at a popular piece of content and saying hey I can do better than that.
And then actually doing it.
It's called like this because when you look at a city skyline What's the thing that catches your eye.
Most often it's probably going to be the tallest building right.
Well and content marketing of bigger can be better.
Especially in the eyes of people looking for that quality content they want so badly.
This is part of the reason we talked about long form content a few lectures back ultimate guides and
things like that attract attention because of the promise that it will be the ultimate The tallest skyscraper
ever.
Well for the skyscraper method of creating content we're going to look for ways to improve upon listicle.
Remember those top ten ways Redwine is better than water or 47 surprising reasons I love cheese.
Stuff like that.
Well bigger can be better and more.
Surely there are more items you could add to a listicle about a topic relevant to your audience.
This is the thinking behind the skyscraper method if you want to get your audience's attention.
Build a better skyscraper.
A longer guide or a longer listicle will obviously be better than the other ones.
Then what can happen is Google's CEO or Google's search will favor you because it's bigger and better
and what you can do very easily is go to the piece that you're beating and steal all their links.
Look at all the people that link to them using a tool like h Raf's a h r s.
Figure out who's linking to them and then contact them and say Hey I noticed you linked to this.
This piece of content on this person's web site I mean a much much better version.
Would you like to link to instead most of the time they say yes.
So the first step for the skyscraper method is to find the biggest most popular skyscrapers and town.
Well that means it's time to do some research.
Which list goes in your industry are getting the most shares and the most links from other sites to
figure that out.
We can use a tool like Buzz sumo which we've checked out before in the lecture where we used it to find
things to write about.
Or if you're looking for a buzzy alternative you could also try out the one I just read mentioned A.H.
refs which a lot of people really seem to like because it has a feature called content explore that
provides a little bit more detail than both sumo does.
So when you do these searches you want to look for the most shares and the most referrals were links
to the posts from other sites.
That means they've been shared a lot.
People really value the content.
The thinking here is that if people like that post then if you create one that's bigger they'll like
that too and hopefully you can get shares and engagement that's just as good if not better.
For now let's try a scenario news bus but summa.
Let's say you're a freelance digital artist and people always ask for your advice on how to use Illustrator.
You know there's a lot of tutorials out there so you've decided to put together the biggest list of
Illustrator tutorials that you possibly can.
Well you can start by just going out to buzz sumo the most free for the first three searches I think
per day.
So if you're cheap like me you need not to waste money on your searches.
So let's get right to the point just type in Illustrator tutorials or whatever your term would be.
Here's what we see for our search.
The top five search results are listed with 26 40 20 and 25 items each.
And if you click through on the second one it's actually got 27 tutorials in it.
So they're pretty much all lists now just how popular are these listicle.
Well you look at the stats on the page of colored circles over on the right you'll see the first two
articles.
Killed on Pinterest with over 2000 shares each.
The last you also did well on Pinterest and third one was a big hit on Facebook by the way if you take
a closer look you'll see that four of the articles here came from the same web site graphic design junction.
Clearly they know what they're doing when they comes in creating listicle.
OK fair enough.
All of them look like pretty popular list so we can use these articles for research and inspiration.
Help us build our own or listicle.
Well views in that skyscraper method that means we want to create a bigger list than anything we found
here.
So the biggest list here is 40.
Well technically we would have to create a list that's at least 41 to accomplish our goal.
Right.
Well as it turns out is not the price is right.
You don't just bid slightly higher than them to win your dream vacation in a minivan.
Let's do better than simply one upping the biggest list.
No other reason use a skyscraper technique is to intimidate the competition.
See how big you can make your new list so nobody else is tempted to try and skyscraper you.
If you do some quick math and add together the list numbers from the five list goes we found through
but somehow it comes out to just over turn 50.
Does this mean that by using all the items in those five lists we can put together a top a top 150 Illustrated
tutorials listicle.
Theoretically yes.
But here's why that wouldn't happen.
First off don't just copy and paste my friend that's lazy.
I said use them for research inspiration.
Don't just rip them off.
But does that mean we can't use any of the items on their list.
Well of course you can.
Otherwise how would you get 150 tutorials.
Probably not even that many out there but do it with some actual thought and originality.
They listen item and give a description and analysis and come up with your own description and analysis
put in the work.
The second reason your item can't be a hundred fifty items long is that well over 150 total items in
these lists.
There's bound to be duplicate these five lists all came out on the same time MiddleEast 2000 so they
might have listed the same items.
Maybe is only 100 unique items maybe more.
I don't know you have to see for yourself.
I don't know the reason of 150 items these other riders picked.
They're going to disagree with some of them.
You should review each one of these before you add them to your own list.
Again do the work.
Don't just post.
I found 150 tutorials give the ones that are worth actually linking to.
So in the end maybe you can cobble together a big list of 75 good solid unique items from these five
listicle.
Well you know what 75 is a way better than the other list.
That sounds like the making of a pretty nice skyscraper.
OK I the first step of the skyscraper technique is to find the biggest skyscrapers in town.
The second step is to start building your own.
Now that you've found your research articles fear inspiration whatever you want to call those pieces
you're going to blow out of the water.
Start creating your own draft.
Check each item in each list you found.
Start highlighting the ones you want to use and omit the ones you don't want.
After a while you'll probably have a long enough draft of what this new post should and will look like
at some point you may discover you don't have 75 items yet but more like I don't know 60.
Well that's fine because here's an opportunity and some important advice for you.
Make it a priority to add new content of your own.
For one thing you don't want to look like a jerk and just copy and paste items from other lists that
other people made.
You really need to put your own stamp on it.
But even more important.
You want this to be the latest up to date list of Illustrator tutorials or chocolate chip cookie recipes
or whatever it is that you're trying to skyscraper.
Specifically look for content from the last month or two so this thing really looks like it's brand
new.
In fact a search for recent content is something you can do in Bassoul help by changing the date filter
in the upper left corner of the search results.
Change the date filter rerun your search and you might find an even newer listicle than the others you've
been using.
Beyond both sumo and out to Google or YouTube or wherever else you'll find your own items and just start
adding new ones to your list.
Now once you have your list to the size that you want it and some shine to your skyscraper click through
on those graphic design junction articles.
You know the ones from the original five listicle were used for research but summa.
You'll see the list are all laid out presented the same way for each item there's a clear title description
a big graphic and a link to check out the tutorial.
The other article in the top 5 shows each item on a separate page so there there's this navigation element
on the top.
It's a little clunky so if I had to choose between the two I'd probably go with the layout graphic design
junction uses and list them all out at once.
But those really aren't our only choices of course.
I'm going to do a list of 75 illustrator tutorials That's pretty long.
Maybe some navigation and a long list would work together.
Maybe I group some of these tutorials by a common theme or subtopic like 10 illustrator or tutorials
for creating business logos and 12 tutorials for creating images of people or I don't know something
like that.
Basically just consider how you can improve upon those other lists you found in both quantity and quality
making lists easier to read and navigate well I'm sure more people will read through it and possibly
share it.
So finished building that skyscraper of yours write it up real nice create cool graphics for it add
some navigation or whatever you choose to do and whatever you think will make it obviously better once
you've got it done and ready for publishing is one more step you can take to help this become a success
and that is you guessed it to promote it.
In our scenario the original sources are those five listicle we've been focusing on since our original
post to my research.
Logic would suggest that whoever liked and shared those with the goals would have to like a bigger and
better and newer version of it right.
Well yeah.
And it's not too much of a stretch and this is why we're making this skyscraper.
We want to generate engagement results that are as good if not better than those original sources.
So is it possible to find the people who shared those original links.
Well you can but this is good it gets a little tricky especially if you're on a budget.
Now Buzzie even has a paid pro version and if you have that you got to just see exactly who shared the
list schools you found linked through social channels.
The same goes for a h.
Graphs and also has a paid services while but it will provide a list of linked shares or think in their
free version.
You have to pay to get more of them.
So if you want to pony up the money and figure out who shared those original listicle is the name of
a great list of people to tell about your new.
Then it's up to you to contact them via social media or email politely ask them to give your list a
look and to share you send them an email it might go something like this.
Hey I see you share this article while back Portie illustrator tutorials and you know include a link
to it so what the hell are you talking about.
That's a great purpose and inspired me to create my own.
My article has 75 items including recent ones from this year.
And now you see why I recommended you include recent content right so you can say this like oh no we
want to share stuff that's out of date.
I'd appreciate if you might consider sharing my posts as well.
Here's a link to it.
Thanks so much for your help.
Cheers.
Kanye West or whatever your name is.
You get the idea.
Don't be pushy though I understand you're asking for something but if they see you're delivering something
bigger and better than those other lists it saves them the time from looking for it.
Most likely they'll think you and share it.
Now if you don't have the money to pay for those services like a raft both soon what exactly can you
do.
Well just promote your skyscraper in the same way you pro any other piece of content.
Look for an interested audience and share the link with them.
Coming up in our series of lectures we're going to specifically cover how to promote your content and
then it will be especially relevant.
But until then you can return your bus.
You must search.
Pay close attention to the platform where your search results got the most shares and engagement.
Four of the five list goals we use for research got tons of shares on Pinterest.
So there's a place we can start for you.
It might be Facebook or elsewhere.
If those pieces did well on that platform then you are bigger and better.
Peace has a great chance there as well.
So search listicle by name on that platform and seeping find users or groups and you might find opportunities
that suggests your link to them personally.
Being on the platform might be able to direct message them or you might just comment on a post of theirs.
Either way don't be pushy.
Share your stuff and then thank people for your consideration.
Alternatively you can also just use google and try to search for that you are on the page that you're
trying to beat because it'll show you are ELB then it'll also show anybody else who included that link.
So a lot of times you'll find blogs that link to it anyway so those promotional steps can help you get
your skyscraper in of the view of people who have shared similar items before.
Remember you want to create something bigger and better and complementing items you find from popular
lists with your own original research and content will make yours as unique as possible.
Now Best of luck with those skyscrapers I'll see you guys in the next lecture.