Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
So the last dozen or so lectures have all focused on ways you could find ideas for writing content and
then we talked about certain kinds of goals you'd want to achieve with content like building awareness
increasing engagement or generating conversions.
But you know at some point you gotta start writing this stuff right.
Well the writing process is obviously important.
It's where a lot of these ideas and best practices all finally come together.
But no matter who your audience is or who you are you want to make sure your content delivers the value
you actually had in mind.
So in order to help you write something great.
I want to share a list of topics I've picked up from my own experience.
Now these are ideas you should keep in mind whenever you write anything because you want to make sure
your readers understand what you're trying to say.
Get value and that they feel compelled to share it with others.
So the first tip may sound weird considering you live on this planet but it's too bright like a human
being.
When people read pieces of content they read it in their head.
I know I do.
I'll look at a post I'll skim through it looking for the stuff I care about or if I'm really interested
I might actually go through it word by word.
But as I read it the words do sound like an actual human being is saying everything to me.
Basically what I'm saying is that the content should have a clear strong personal voice.
It should not be like a press release.
Maybe your voice is professional as if you're delivering a presentation at a conference or meeting with
executives.
Your voice might be casual as if the person reading it is a friend or a coworker or your voice could
be snarky or rebellious or inspiring or distracted whatever the voice is it just needs to match what
you've written so that when your audience reason they hear that voice that professionalism or snarky
ness loud and clear.
No it doesn't have a personality.
Faceless corporations and that's how you escape that.
For example look at Cards Against Humanity Cards Against Humanity as a party game where players are
challenged to come up with the most embarrassing and inappropriate match for a statement with a blank.
And it makes no sense.
But it'll will be like nobody's a bigger fan of blank than your mom and then you get to choose an answer
from an equally random or inappropriate set of cards like Crystal Pepsi or the Ebola virus.
The fun game and maybe you should check it out.
So other Web site.
The voice cards against humanity uses when writing their content is as embarrassing and inappropriate
as their game.
There are further questions asked by customers as your dumb questions and call their own game a party
game for horrible people.
You wouldn't catch the people behind monopoly are hungry hungry hippos running in a voice like this
but you know for cards against humanity it is actually very appropriate and it's consistent.
So what's your voice.
What's that personality that needs to shine through when you write your content.
Or let's put it another way if your company was a person what kind of person would they be.
A friend looking to help out as many people as possible.
Or maybe a nerd looking to show off everything they know it can really help to think of your company
with a persona in mind because it can make your voice that much clearer when people read what you're
writing.
Since your audience is most likely made up of customers or perspective one another important tip for
writing to them is to be helpful.
Everything you should write should help solve a problem for the reader whether it's a big problem or
just a little one at any given moment.
Your audience might be under a major deadline and need to troubleshoot a printer with a series of tutorials
or maybe they just need to know what time your store opened the next friday what ever they are of their
needs should guide your writing so provide information clearly and easy to digest.
Another tip writing for your audience is to try your best to be original.
I know it's hard to come up with completely original content these days.
Everything's a rip off of something but writing about a topic other people have written about is quite
common.
It's OK to do it.
Just make sure that there's some deviation.
So think of any type of fresh way that you can do this.
Come up with a new question about it or a new scenario involving that specific topic or a new angle
of looking at it.
In the end if you really don't have anything new to say about something maybe you just don't say anything.
Try something else.
The key here is just not to waste your audience's time with redundant or repetitive content.
So write like a human.
Try to be helpful and try to be original.
So far these should make sense right.
OK now here's a few more ideas on how you can write for your audience and be successful in it.
You really really really should use visuals and I know this sounds really stupid like put a photo on
it.
You'd be surprised how few people do it and they skip it because they think it's just too basic or obvious
or unnecessary.
You would be amazed at what a difference it makes.
Visuals engage people's senses and can help you communicate information better than text as you write.
Complement your text with visuals and try to appeal to what your audience likes best.
You don't know how to come up with visuals.
You can use work with someone to design it freelance gets them on fire for five blocks to make an image
or you can use something like Kanva and to put together your own images on the fly images make everything
look better.
Your audience might even like something like a walk through video that you create for the app you built.
Or they might like photo galleries of designs you've created in Photoshop.
Use visuals to break up big pieces of text and really make your content more interesting to look at.
It's like if you watched a lecture of me and we never put any visuals on the screen a while back.
The Huffington Post lifestyle blog to this person is called re-adjusted nine ways of brewing coffee
to find the very best method for many of us.
This is clearly some top shelf stuff.
Pulitzer level importance obviously is essential to know everything there is to know about coffee so
I applaud them for writing this.
I'm being sarcastic now.
They could have just proclaimed a winner with a written paragraph and just left it at that.
But instead they showed pictures of each of the nine coffee brewing methods.
A few.
I had never even heard of or seen before and it made for a more interesting post.
It's really just a simple thing that added visual interest as well as more context.
So remember that one please.
Love God put in images but also don't forget to show and tell.
Now the emphasis there is on the end show and tell.
For too many writers their goal is to get all the info about a topic out of their head and onto a post.
But just telling people about stuff is often only half the job.
You have to show them stuff too.
Don't be like a college lecturer just listing things out or spouting off information without showing
people how it's actually used in the real world or how the reader can use it for themselves.
Just joking.
What else would higher education be without any context.
In the spirit of showing and telling Well here's a listicle called sixty three generation strategies
and it's called from marketing wisdom.
Never heard of them.
Dizzy in wisdom I guess stands for God because you fall asleep.
That's how boring they are.
LOL It is a mess.
The first 21 of these strategies are accompanied by a block of text.
No images no videos no links.
And then the rest is just a list like they just ran out of energy or something and said like I only
just figure out the rest doesn't even add up to sixty three strategies.
My point here besides finish what you've started is that the content that is here is basically just
tell tell tell with no show there are no examples and very little effort was put into it.
Now if you can do some good showing and telling.
It might be easier to get your audience involved to something else to remember something that we covered
before trying to create reactions.
Some of the best content out there isn't necessarily like a big bold statement or a game changing declaration.
A lot of times though it's just a question that opens up possibilities for people.
Gets them thinking or it just gets them to chime in and represent themselves.
It's like lobbing who out there does this or a what if question into a crowd of passionate people and
standing back with popcorn to watch the sparks fly like hey app developers would have Android announce
their phones could now run all iOS apps or hey designers would have Adobe made all of their apps free.
Could even be as simple as hey where you're from if you want your audience to respond the best way to
do that is to ask them something.
Introduce a concept or an idea and dare people to rip it apart.
Writing for your audience isn't about making yourself look good.
It's about providing good material for your audience to enjoy and react to.
An interesting place to actually find reactions is from brand post on Instagram.
On the Go try to check it out you don't actually have to have him on your phone to do this.
You can do it through your web browser or just search Instagram and then search for a brand that you
can think of.
Now you could have a car company like Jeep asking where people drive their vehicles or in Airbnb case
asking people where they want to travel to next.
It really doesn't take much to give your audience a chance to join in.
Check out some of these accounts.
They're pretty good at it.
Right now there's one more tip law about you for writing content specifically for your audience.
Everybody just learn how to write.
Is that harsh.
Well sometimes you have to be a little bit harsh.
Sorry I'm not sorry.
I'm not about to teach you how to check for typos or use proper grammar or avoid run on sentences needs
to work on that stuff yourself.
Truth is if you don't write properly and your readers begin to spot errors they'll begin to distrust
what you say.
Les you're like one of those weird internet marketers that thinks by spelling every other word wrong
is more that makes your posts more personal and makes no sense.
Every mistake in your writing is generally like a crack in your iPhone screen.
No matter how small the crack is you know it's there and you can see it at the right angle.
If you have too many errors soon the whole thing just becomes unreadable and it's just painful when
it happens.
People generally go somewhere else.
So if you suck at writing much hey it's perfectly normal if you.
Just admitted to that you can improve.
Guess what.
Everybody learns how to speak English way back in like junior high and then I haven't got an English
class since I was 12 so it's it's not uncommon.
The best advice I can give you here is actually just to write more practice will help you improve and
over time you'll start to avoid silly mistakes and typos.
You just get better at it you'll get better at organizing your thoughts.
You write longer pieces you'll do it more quickly but until you're confident in your skills.
One tip is actually just to get an editor even if you spend five minutes helping you out with each piece
you create.
It could save you and your content from looking bad.
Or you can actually just go the app route and try something like early.
The has a free plugin that will check your writing for errors and other issues as you go through it
and it makes suggestions.
It's actually not a bad idea to just install this thing and get used to more red squiggly lines appearing
as you type and stuff so that you can start learning how to write more good or my suggestion is just
to spend an hour or two hours googling basic grammar or doing a basic UMT course on grammar.
You might think that it's beneath you or it's something that only children do but a refresher is incredibly
helpful.
I for the longest time had kind of forgotten what a preposition was until just like six months ago.
I just read some blog piece about proposition's how to use them correctly and now I actually remember
where to put commas.
So to recap these are the tips that will help you write write like a human.
Be helpful try to be original please.
Love of God use visuals.
Show and Tell.
Don't just show show show try your best.
Create reactions.
It's always free for you to do.
Pop a question at the end.
There's nothing stopping me from doing it.
And then try to learn how to write more good.
If you do adopt these things as part of your writing process your audience will appreciate it.
And honestly the one to read more of what you've got so go ahead and make it awesome.
All right that's enough tips.
My head's about to explode in the next lecture.