Hey guys welcome back.
So in our last lecture I gave you some really great tips on how to write better pat myself on the backs.
Great tips.
I mean you probably finished watching and wrote like 20 blog posts just right after you are done or
not.
Either way good for you.
But in this lecture I want to talk about an element that can really make or break your content and it's
surprisingly simple.
It's the part of your content that anyone who reads it will see first and you can guess what I'm talking
about.
Talking about the headline The title of your post or the headline is extremely important.
I'm going to say that right up front because honestly if you don't do a good job of creating a headline
you're really just doing your blog post before you even trying to promote it or your video or whatever
it is that you're creating that kind of freaks you out then good.
I want you to always remember this point your headline needs to be good but when I see your headline
needs to be good I don't mean it needs to be like the greatest bunch of words ever strung together by
a human being.
What I mean is that your headline needs to work.
Now the job of a headline is to grab the interest of your audience and to compel them to read your content.
That's it right.
Get your attention and make them want to read what you've got.
If your headline can do those two things and generally it's successful.
So the real creativity and strategy here comes from figuring out how to grab the audience's interest
and how to compel them to click through and read your work.
Those are the points I'm going to share with you right now.
First of all when you're creating a headline just get to the point.
There's this old saying that the simplest solution is often the best solution and that really does apply
here.
Think simple.
Figure out what's the main point of your content.
The simplest description of what your content is about is usually a great place to start.
When creating a headline of a size that you start there.
Don't.
Isn't there a really simple thing called.
This is an article about 10 things to do with your new apps.
No one's going to click that but use it as a baseline.
So if you wrote a post about lessons you learned from say attending an Android app development conference
and you wanted to tell a friend about it and the simplest way possible what would you tell them.
Probably.
It's a blog post about lessons I learned that the Android App Development Conference.
So guess what.
You should probably call the post.
Maybe lessons learned from the Android App Development Conference.
It's really not that hard is it just don't overthink it.
Getting to the point in your headline is the best way to get across of the value your content has to
offer.
Don't make them think too much when they read your headline.
Your decision to click on your headline needs to be instantaneous so be as clear as possible.
Part of getting to that point where there are headlines to let readers know what value your content
has to offer or promise value in your headline.
Let them know exactly what they'll get when they read it.
This is especially relevant for a post where you write about ways to do things or options for people
to consider.
In the end you could be providing details about how to install an app or might deliver an opinion that
helps your audience make a choice about that on a web hosting.
Any time you see a headline that starts with how to or best ways to.
Well you know exactly what kind of value you'll get if you click through.
So try your best to communicate the pieces value clearly in the headline.
In fact promise that value as early as possible.
Research has shown that when people see the value at the beginning of a headline they'll click More
often than when it's buried at the middle of the sentence or the end of the headline.
So for instance installing your sink in five minutes would be more effective than how to quickly install
your sync.
So state your offer or your value early and grab the reader's attention.
Now a great way to be clear with your headline is include any important or relevant details.
Another headline tip for you.
Specific detail is much more valuable than some kind of vague statement.
Numbers are great to include in headlines because for one thing they're not words.
Human eyes spots any differences so in the case of headlines numbers really jump out to you.
Yes I know there's some grammar nazis out there who don't like seeing numbers in headlines but the game
has changed.
I'm sorry for listicle numbers give that expectation of how long the piece will be so whether it's the
top ten ways to cook carrots or 68 prising uses for an eraser.
That's all weird on the reader knows how much time they'll take to read but numbers could also represent
data in the headline which is also a great way to communicate why you should care about this article.
For example how I reduced email bounce rates by 90 percent is way more powerful the headline than just
how I reduced email bounce rates that 90 percent provides a real number that helps the reader understand
the degree of value they can get from this piece.
All right so far I've mentioned temp's like get to the point promis value include any important relevant
details.
Those three basic ideas are the foundation of every good headline so make sure that you're following
them.
There's one other chap about headline that's entirely based on data and research and that tip is to
keep your headline between six and 10 words long.
Now I don't like to put limits on content.
I'm a big fan of taking as much time as you need to provide that value people are looking.
And since you're still watching these lectures I know you know what I'm talking about.
But when it comes deadlines restricting yourself to this range of six to 10 words is actually a good
idea.
And here is why there's been a ton of research done by different places on the effect emissive headlines
what works and what doesn't.
People have looked at thousands upon thousands of headlines and click through rates and shares and all
that stuff.
Most of the data tells us that headlines between six and 10 words get clicked on engage with more often
than others.
But wait there's more research also tells us that when people evaluate headlines you know that fraction
of a second when they look at the search result or a title that pops up in their Facebook feed they
usually look at the first three words of a headline and the last three words kind of like the way you
read sentences apparently don't read the letters in the middle of the words read the beginning and the
end of the words you drop the middles you can actually read them fine.
That kind of a fun experiment but it actually works.
Now if we assume it's true that you only read the first three and the last three in headline then you
know what that means for headlines that are six words long.
People read the entire thing for headlines that are ten words long and they might skim more miss some
of the middle few words.
Someone interesting right.
So if you read a headline that's like 16 words long say the Top Ten Ways to Use Google Analytics find
customers in other parts of the world.
Well a lot of people might just see the top 10 ways and maybe parts of the world.
But everything in between that is a blur and therefore the meaning of the article is completely lost.
Remember we all make these decisions really fast if something takes more time than something else we
usually opt for the quicker shorter route.
It's human nature.
I'm sorry.
So do what you can do to stick to this recommendation six to 10 words to create your headline.
That's it.
Now about that research we talked about before.
You know where people evaluate thousands of headlines looking for trends and such.
Well there's a few other insights that I can share with you and we can pull from that data.
Research has shown that headlines with positive adjectives attract more clicks than headlines without
them.
What's a positive adjective.
Things like bestor biggest or even great.
Those words are positive in nature.
The opposites of course are things like worst or smallest or terrible.
Those are negative adjectives.
Part of the human nature we talked about is to seek out positive content and data shows people click
headlines and positive actions more than others.
So in your case add some positive and interesting touches to your headlines.
If you're writing about a client's success story the subject is already positive in nature.
But if you're writing about like five mistakes you've made with clients and lessons you've learned.
Highlight the positive angle here.
Something like five surprising lessons learned from my client.
Now here's another idea that you can try out a few onto your post.
Answer an important question.
Try making your headline the question by asking a question in your headline you're offering something
different so you actually cast some attention.
Just make sure whatever question you ask actually gets answered in the post.
Here's an example.
What is our title said.
What does Google's algorithm change mean for marketers.
Well this tells you what the content is about.
It's a recent change Google's algorithm it tells you it's for marketers.
It also tells you that we're answering an important question in it you'll find the answer inside without
being said.
Another good idea for your headlines is try to make them somewhat of a teaser.
Now not only is he not a fan of people who make headlines that seem mysterious for no reason.
But sometimes it can be interesting if you twist it slightly.
So for example if you write a headline like how one changed my writing process saved my blog people
might wonder what changed.
All they know is it's about writing for a blog if they have a blog they want to save or keep running.
Well perhaps we'll check it out and click the title.
Word of warning please do not do this repeatedly because then when people look at your page for all
your posts it just looks like a ton of crap that's just tons of click and do all these things that are
best used in moderation.
If you keep using it it loses its magic.
Now be careful and not get too mysterious or try to be too clever with your headlines.
If you're not sure.
Show the title to someone and just ask them to tell you what they think it is and if they are in their
perfect world would click on it or they hate people.
You can try to coast schedule headline analyzed or put it the resources will throw it up here.
It's a page where you can just go and plug in your title and they'll evaluate it for things like length
clarity in other ways.
Us human beings look at these headlines.
It works pretty well.
Either way a different perspective sometimes helps to show you're not as clever as you think you are.
But don't worry none of us really are.
So when in doubt default back to those original three tips I gave you for writing headlines.
Get to the point.
Promise your value and include any important relevant details.
You follow those three tips and maybe sprinkle in some of the other strategies from time to time the
optional ones like including positive adjectives and trying some questions in your title you might have
some really interesting headlines that are in the worst case scenario they're still effective.
All right that's it.
Go away.
I'll see you in the next lecture.