Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
So we've covered a lot of different ways to generate ideas and build content for your audience.
And our focus has been to put it all on your website or your blog.
It makes sense because your site is where conversions happen sales sign ups client inquiries all that
good stuff putting great content in your site means people will come there from searches social shares
and email.
Well there's another way to get people to come visit your site and that's through what we call guest
posting.
If you don't know a guest posting is.
Let me introduce you to it.
So guess posting just means that you write a post for someone else's blog or someone else's web site.
You're a guest and you contribute with a post.
So this sounds a little backwards to you.
I get it but actually think about it.
Do you have a blog.
You probably have a certain amount of writing you need to get done each week that can take a lot of
time and effort so why not get someone else to write something you approve it and then you post on your
site as an extra or an exotic way to fill in the gaps between your post and the perspective of the writer
it works because you get exposure on someone else's web site and can drive traffic from their site back
to yours.
Kind of like co-mingling your audience's guess posting also known as guest blogging.
Sometimes works because it can help you build an audience beyond where you've already posted.
Now remember we're still trying to build up our first 500 customers here and if you want to reach more
people at some point you have to go outside your usual web sites and social platforms like Mad Max venturing
into the desert in search of water.
Sometimes you just gotta hit the road and find some peeps to help you with your mission.
Now the exposure factor is not the only reason.
Guest blogging is considered a great traction channel.
I'd say there are probably three big reasons.
Number one like I said before it gets seen by someone else's audience and gets some new exposure to
that new audience can directly lead to more traffic for your web site.
And number three if you get close enough you could be seen as an authority or an expert.
People Google your name they're going to see you on a lot of different Web sites generally a good thing
that then can snowball into more exposure building activities like getting interviewed or speaking at
events.
So this sounds like the kind of adventure you want to sign up for.
Great because I'm a whole bunch of letters coming up telling you how to do it.
First you'll need to figure out where you can post.
That involves some research but it ties into a bunch of activities you're probably already doing like
following blogs you like and being aware of what's going on in your industry.
After you find some sites or blogs where you might be able to guess post you to approach them pitch
them your idea and then if they accept to write something that fits their style or format if you pay
attention you'll find that the next handful lectures are pure pure gold if I may say so myself.
Absolutely perfect.
Alid didn't.
Content.
So if you're interested in this guest posting thing keep watching.
Otherwise see in the next lecture.