Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So in the last several lectures we talked about a whole lot of different ways that you can come up with
ideas for your blog or whatever online content you want to stick into your content marketing plan.
So maybe you've looked through the list of supposedly great ideas you have so far and you're working
on them right now or maybe you've got something written and it's ready to be published.
Great.
Well when you publish your content what essentially that means is it's now available for people to see
online.
It exists somewhere and really kind of stating the obvious point here because many people publish their
content and then they think yes I did it.
I'm done.
I don't have to do anything more.
And then they just move on to writing the next thing or they go play Call of Duty or something I don't
know what you do after that.
Here's the problem.
Just because you publish something doesn't mean people know it exists.
That whole building.
And they will come slogan from Field of Dreams doesn't exactly apply well to content marketing.
Somebody that's you have to tell your audience about what you've got.
Kind of it's kind of like feeding cats.
Cats don't really care about anything but themselves.
They're just a bunch of self-centered goals that do really whatever they want whenever they want.
Much like your audience.
You have zero control over them.
Now if you walk in the same room as a cat holding a big can of tuna.
Yeah.
They'll continue to ignore you but the moment the sound of that canned opening hits the air those cats
will come running
terrible metaphor.
Yeah I know.
My point is if you publish something you need to make some noise about it.
Part of your content strategy must include promoting your content as well.
Just like Toona.
So in this lecture I'm going to run through this steps on how to promote your content will cover some
things that do when you promote on social media and also talk about how you can approach and even work
with industry experts or influencers or whatever you ought to call them.
Those are the people who can help you promote when the time comes right to share your stuff promoting
your content is a necessary step.
So my hope here is to help you create a process.
You can repeat.
Every time you publish something in general it's a good idea to have a set playbook.
Every time you publish something because you don't want to be reinventing the wheel every time you hit
publish on a new blog does not address the fact that are a million different ways you can promote your
content online than what has gone to growth hackers dot com.
Literally every single day there's probably 10 different ways or new ways that you can promote what
you've written.
We're going to cover are some of the more classic more everyday ways of promoting it.
And these are kind of the bedrock of your promotional strategy feel free to add in more of those accessories
or more of those eccentric styles of promoting your stuff later on when you get a better grafs of the
basics.
Zounds good.
All right.
Let's discuss.
So just to be clear when I say promote your content what I mean is you tell people about your new piece
of content people who might be interested in it and potentially in a bunch of different places and perhaps
you might actually end up doing it by making a whole lot of smaller pieces of content that are chunked
up from the larger piece that you wrote.
I'll explain later.
So this could mean tweeting about it.
You could write up Facebook posts you can post on LinkedIn.
You can do Instagram or you can even retrofit it for youtube.
Maybe you could use something on Reddit or any other half dozen platforms.
It also means sending updates out in an email newsletter but each time you promote your piece that's
a little new piece of content you're creating.
Now could be 140 characters or something more.
But each one does take time and effort to complete.
Unfortunately you cannot just write the one promotional line that works for Twitter or Facebook that
works for a medium that works for your email that works for everything.
The world is much harder than that.
This is why promoting content to me feels like more work than it really is and you might agree.
You might have to go to all these different Web sites or apps just to get the word out about your new
stuff while you feel the same way you want to check out some most social media scheduling tools to help
you save time and effort.
Now you could use a scheduling platform to plan tweets Facebook posts and more.
And while you can also Prioleau those platforms with tweets about your company and your products or
whatever.
To me the real value here comes when it comes time to promote your new stuff.
You only have so much time in your day or your social media intern only has so much time in their day
so you dont want that to be taken up by are remembering that it's three o'clock now I need to post for
the third time on Facebook and at 3 dippie 3 I need to post again on Twitter.
No other reason why I really liked the social media scheduling applications like a buffer or like a
meet.
Edgar is that in general if you want to be successful when you promote your content well you need to
promote it multiple times in similar places and not just once.
Now if you tweet about your new blog posts one time say he did it on Tuesday at 10 a.m. Eastern Time.
Well there is a chance that anyone on Twitter at that time that is also following you will see it but
those people are not generally enough.
You just put 2 percent effort into promoting it compared to the 98 percent you already spent on writing
it.
You're not doing it justice.
Now the same idea applies for all social platforms so it's become an accepted best practice schedule
a series of social posts beforehand.
Now you might do two posts on the day you publish and then one day for the next five to seven days.
Now this would ensure your audience whenever and wherever they get on line has a much better chance
at seeing your promotional message with a scheduling platform this task becomes way easier for you to
handle.
Now there are two really good platforms that I think you should probably check out and I just mentioned
them briefly before the first phone call buffer.
You FFE are on the second one is called Meet Edgar.
So if a scheduling platform can help you address the problem of getting seen by your audience it doesn't
guarantee that they'll click or share what you put out there.
Now you need to create a promotional message that's somewhat eye catching.
Now a helpful tip for making that happen is to use custom images by custom image.
I'm talking about graphics that you can create specifically for this one piece of content.
Now it could be a picture you take with your phone something you put together with a free tool like
Kanva.
Or you could even use like a paid tool like Photoshop or Illustrator if you have any idea how to use
those.
They're really complicated here.
Up on the screen is a custom image the content marketing insitu made about this topic.
Nine brilliant ways to promote your blog on Facebook.
How Mehta why would they put an owl right here.
Well because owls as everyone knows are brilliant.
You can see has glasses come on you know that Al is extra smart.
Als are just those guys in class that always set the curve anyway.
Now compare this to a stock photo image of an owl or what.
Do a lot of places use when they share a listicle.
Probably a close up shot of a checklist or somebody writing some really really boring like stock photo.
So obviously a stock photo at a glance when a custom image like this one with the owl catches your eye
and you can quickly see what it's all about.
And there is science behind the use of images to support this.
Probably a research done by a very smart owl.
Probably really if there's anything I can.
My research tells us that posts with images get something like two to three times more engagement than
posed without images.
That's why I've anyone follows my Twitter.
I always attach images to my tweet even if they have nothing to do with what I'm talking about.
So try to find something relevant and try to find something eye catching.
It will dramatically increase your reach.
So so far I've mentioned a social media scheduling tool so you can promote multiple times and I just
mentioned the use of custom images.
These are both important steps you should take for promoting your content.
But there's one more thing you can do that will help.
If you've mentioned any web sites or people in your content contact them and let them know about it.
Any time anyone gets mentioned in a piece of content they didn't create themselves.
Well that's pretty cool.
People love to hear about that and a lot of them would gladly share a link to it to show how cool they
are.
So if you cite any sources link to any outside content or quote some expert make sure that the source
knows about it when you publish to put it another way.
While you're writing your piece think about ways you can link out and mention other people in your industry
especially those with bigger followings than you.
Presumably everyone knows actually leads into another kind of strategy for promoting your content and
that is to work with influencers.
Now I'm going to cover that in the next lecture.
So we get into it.
I'll see you then.