OK guys, welcome back.
In our last lecture, we talked about ways to get the
attention of a reporter by considering certain angles.
We focused on three of them actually, offering
something special and unique, or at least one thing in
your product offering that's special and unique, tying it
into a trending topic, or taking an opposing position,
or just piggybacking on some general, something that's
happening, and you have data to support or go against
it. As part of your PR efforts, you should try and come
up with something relevant, timely, and with an
angle that's interesting to a writer and their audience.
Well, your angle can also be more effective if you
consider the person you're pitching your story to
and the place they write for.
Now, some writers operate a one person blog, but
many of the writers you might be after will write for
bigger outlets, news sites, magazines,
industry blogs, and more things like that.
Each of these outlets has its own style and
this gets to what our lecture is about.
I want to discuss how you can base your angle on
the outlet or individual you're pitching to and how
to make it as effective as possible. As you go through
the section and you start doing your research
into reporters, bloggers, and writers, which
we'll jump into in our next lecture,
part of the work you'll need to do is
to get to know them and their outlets.
Knowing the types of stories they publish, the formats
they use, and the subjects they usually cover will
give you a clear idea about which places and
people would be interested in what you offer.
It also will give you some idea on how to angle it to them.
I mean, you wouldn't necessarily walk into a vegan
restaurant offering a kick ass steak recipe.
So I don't think you can just walk up to any reporter
or magazine and then just get your pitch approved.
You need to understand them first.
So part of gaining this understanding
is reading what they publish.
Now, for any writer you identify as a lead, you'll want
to read their works to see if their style and
opinions are a good match with what you want them to
write about. The same needs to be done for the place
they write for.
Does the magazine, the blog, or the media site they
write for publish anything like what you have in mind?
Certainly, if you have an app or some kind of tech
product, maybe you've considered approaching an outlet
like, let's say, Wired or Engadget, which
feature tech subject matter all the time.
If you're trying to pitch a story about great recipes
for cats with dementia, maybe Wired is probably not
your thing. While you're reading their work,
make note of the format and
subject matter of each piece.
Does the site you want to get in feature long form
pieces or do they concentrate on shorter posts?
Consider a magazine like The Atlantic, for example.
While they cover different topics, like politics, human
interest stories, and culture, they're very much
known for their long form pieces they publish.
If you have an idea they might like, make sure it
fits in a long form format and there's a lot to say
on it, or it fits into a rather long form story.
When you're reading works from a specific
writer, make note of their writing style.
Does the reporter write in an unbiased or biased way?
Are they offering nothing but facts
or sharing lots of their own opinions?
Do they inject controversial ideas into their work
or do they keep things conservative and safe?
If you're interested in being featured in Vice, for
example, you should be aware that their articles
are often opinionated and they always try to go for edge.
Now, would your subject fit their vibe?
They're always counterculture.
They're always going to be contrarian.
They always want to have things that no one else is
covering and things that are kind of grungy or edgy.
If you fit somewhere in there, you can
make a pitch that fits somewhere in there.
Consider a pitch that takes advantage of that style and
then emphasize how rough and kind of cutting edge
and hip this is. As you do your research into the writers
and outlets you want to potentially reach out to,
remember that they have just as
many angles as your story does.
Writers don't just want relevant, timely, and interesting.
They want something they can easily plug into their
blog or magazine and something that fits well with
their style and for their audience.
If a writer gets a pitch that really fits with their interest,
it has a much better chance of being heard
than one that only fits your interests.
Now, obviously keep this in mind going forward.
So really it comes down to two things.
Are you matching the person
and are you matching the outlet?
The outlet is going to have a brand personality.
They're going to cover certain types of things.
Forbes, Business Insider, and Entrepreneur.com, they're
all going to cover very similar things, they're going
to be above water,
they're very rarely opinionated,
they like to cover things that happen in businesses,
and they love startup stories or some juicy gossip
about the finance sector.
On the other hand, like a Wired or an Engadget, we were
talking about, or The Verge, they're going to cover
technology and they only want things that are
cutting edge or things that seem futuristic.
They also do like to insert opinions and they do
like to cover things that are kind of in the blind
spot of the cultural eye, so to speak.
They like to cover things that you were not aware of,
things they love covering, like spying stories.
So the first thing you have to do is make sure that
your pitch and your angle matches the brand of the
overall kind of umbrella site.
And the second thing you need to do is make sure it
matches the interests of the individual. You're going
to pitch to a writer, not the brand.
So when you pitch to the writer, read what they've
written before and you'll notice, hey, they like covering
certain topics. They'll even write in their bio sometimes,
"This is what I cover."
So if you can match in one of those realms, one
of those topics, and then match it to the angle and
the brand of their outlet,
you have a very good chance of getting picked up. Okay,
I think we've covered all the angles on angles on angles.
I'll see you guys in the next lecture.