Hey guys, welcome back to the course,
so in this lecture we're going to demo it.
Last lecture, we talked about finding
potential complaint customers.
So for those of you out there that are still a little
confused how this would look or how you would
do it, let's just do it with an example idea.
OK.
So I'm going to make something up,
this was part of a startup competition
I was just in yesterday, I was a judge for it. Someone
pitched an idea for something, I'm going to say exactly
what it was, but it helped people transfer money to India.
OK.
So let's pretend that was our service.
That's not exactly what they're doing.
We have some servers that transfers money to India.
So typically that's going to solve the
problem that people can't transfer it,
probably, they're probably having trouble finding a way
to transfer it, or they just can't find a way to send back
wages or pay people in India.
I'm not sure.
So probably what I would do is focus on someone
complaining about transferring to India or "can't send
money to India" and I'll probably
see where that takes me. Okay.
So the first thing, remember, we just go to Twitter,
and right here in the bar we're just going to try a couple
of things. So I'm going to say "transfer to India."
I could say "can't transfer to India," let's see
what it says. Can't transfer to India.
But the reason why I might shy away from these is
because on Twitter you can only put 180 characters, so
long sentences like that might actually be broken
up because people have to save time, so
they might not say "two," they might
put the number, they might abbreviate
"can't" to CNT or something like that.
So we'll see.
OK, so off of that, we can scan through these,
and I can see two people right off the bat.
So one person is saying, "Can someone
volunteer to spare something something
transfer to India? Need to order something and I can't
make a payment from PK," I'm guessing it's Pakistan.
Whatever.
OK, so that was one, we would mark that one
down and we could reach out to that person.
It looks like we have another one. "Trying to
transfer money to India for urgent need.
What the, you know, you guys can't fix your
[...] online services for more than 48 hours."
Ah, that guy is complaining about another service.
Maybe you could swoop them up, talk to that person.
This guy's complaining again, "Both MG and PP
can transfer to India online, but WU can't?"
Western Union can't transfer to India.
I didn't know that actually.
So that's another person we could actually talk to.
Great. OK, three people right there
we could reach out to, those are some great leads.
Let's go back to the search bar.
Let's just try more broadly.
"Transfer to India."
See what that gives us.
OK, so let's see. We have one person advertising
a service that does that. Looks like a lot of people
are complaining about something
topical, something in the news.
So let's try something a little more broad. We'll just
try "transfer money to India" instead of "can't
transfer money," see what we get.
OK.
If one person looks like they're pitching their service,
we don't really want to go to those people.
Another person pitching. Here's one person
that is happy about their rate.
And you could potentially reach out
to the person, not necessarily a complaint.
And here we go, here's a complaint.
"Hello, @TransFastWorld,
how long do you take to transfer
money to India from Canada?
It's already 50 hours. Kindly respond." That person
is having trouble transferring money to India.
There you go.
There's another one. And it looks like another person
is roughly complaining, he's saying he could transfer
money between bank accounts in US
and India, but not true for all accounts.
You could maybe reach out to the person whether
or not they have an issue with one specific account.
OK, we can try again, and we can try something, now we have
I think five people. We could say "can't send," we'll just
say "send money to India" and see if that's broad enough.
OK, and this one is broad, but we can still pick out
some people. Looks like people are complaining about
Pakistan, can't ever search for India
without complaints about Pakistan.
This person says "We are facing a lot of trouble
sending money through the Maldives to India."
Still counts with sending money to India, that person
is complaining that he has a problem with it.
Here is another one.
"30 minutes on the phone to send money to India and
now I have to go into a branch to sign papers.
This process is broken." Very dramatic, but that guy
is a very good potential customer for our service.
We just grab 7 right there, and
I don't know how long that took me.
They only took me about five minutes
to do and we got seven people.
Great.
All right.
Now let's try the Reddit technique.
So remember it's site:reddit.com,
and then we'll use the same search
terms, "can't transfer money to India."
All right.
And looks like right off the bat someone started
a discussion about how they can send money.
This person wants to know the best
option, easiest, cheapest, best ways.
I mean, anywhere in here you could pitch them.
I mean, they probably are having
trouble, that's why they're asking.
Looks like someone here is asking "Why did it take 100
days to transfer money to India versus other countries?"
That guy probably has a problem.
Here's a person complaining they have PayPal restrictions,
probably trying to send money through PayPal.
Here's another person complaining about transferring
funds without any fees back and through India.
That's another person who probably has a problem with it.
What you would want to do is just hop in here and read them
and see whether or not they do exactly fit your problem.
OK, this person is trying to send
$50 every month to his grandparents.
He's trying to figure out the best way
to do it is, he's concerned about fees.
OK, so that's a legitimate one, what you
could actually then do is reach out to them.
We cover that in the next lecture,
so stay tuned for that.
OK, and then the last one was just Google.
You know, I can just go back to here
and just drop this, and just go through that.
OK, and then just see what happens.
OK.
Here we go.
I mean, looks like on digitalpoint.com, some random
forum, someone is straight up complaining about
how you can't transfer money.
It says "from" India, but you could
probably find someone who is "to."
We have some people asking it on Quora.
Remember, Quora was one of the ones we mentioned
that's usually pretty good for this technique. "I can't
transfer funds." Look at all these people.
Tons of people just complaining, complaining, complaining.
We have quite a lot to work with.
It's only been like 8 minutes, and
look at all the possible leads
I have found. You could do this all day long.
All right, guys. Hopefully that demo helps
you kind of wrap your head around it.
See you in the next lecture.