All right guys welcome back to the Corps.
We're going to talk about influencers so I just started about promoting your content using basically
social media.
You all have social media platforms whether there's not a lot of followers of a lot of followers.
It's basically free advertisement.
And if you don't post on there and you don't do it correctly with a post scheduling tool well then you're
basically a noob and you're screwing this up.
And social media is probably the first thing a lot of people think when they think of promoting blog
pieces or videos.
Oh I'm just going to throw a link out there on Twitter and see if people share it.
That's pretty much the baseline amount of work you should do.
Well the thing with sharing and promotion is this.
The bigger you are in the industry the more established your reputation is the better your chances are
that your tweets or post or other promotional stuff gets shared.
So if you are in quote unquote influencer or you can get it influence or to share your content.
It can be very helpful.
Now what exactly is an influencer.
Basically it's just someone with real sway in the industry.
They're popular because they have thousands or even millions of followers.
There's stuff get shared a lot.
And they themselves get mentioned or quoted frequently.
Influencers now are usually thought of as high profile people.
We could be authors speakers executives members of the media and celebrities but they can be really
anyone who just has a large following.
Some niggas don't have influencers with millions of followers sometimes an influence there only has
5000 Twitter followers or 10000 or something like that.
So it could really be anyone take this all in the context when you're looking at your industry but in
general they have similar behavior patterns.
They're usually very active online.
Usually people know their name.
And usually people care somewhat about what their opinion is.
Now towards the larger end of the spectrum and you get people who are really well known in the millions
of followers you often see them sharing promotional content for brands and that just in the form of
advertising.
That's how a lot of influences make money.
So I mean honestly just go to Instagram and look at half of the models that are on there posting pictures
with diet products or teeth whitening services.
Those people are professionally pretty and that's what they do for a living.
They just go on Instagram and say I eat this bucket of stuff and look how fit I am.
They go to Twitter and you'll find mommy bloggers who are posting hashtags sponsored tweets about skin
care and coffee and whatever new health food scam is out there.
But what if you're not necessarily within that definition of an influencer.
Well that's perfectly fine.
You can find one or more to help you share your stuff.
Influencers have to cure eight and 10 to their audience.
And honestly it's very hard for one person to do that constantly.
So they're looking for stuff to share all the time.
So you just need to get in contact with them and let me tell you how my friend.
Now the first step in an influencer outreach campaign yes that's a buzz word.
You'll hear it later.
Now you can use it.
Reaching out to people with followers.
That's all that means.
The first step is merely identifying the influencers in any industry who could potentially help you.
So really you're just going to platforms like Twitter Facebook and others and searching for your topic.
If you're going to search for Django it's framework web development or that are no extreme babysitting
whatever it is that you're in and see who comes up with the most followers.
If the people that show up look at all promising then you're just up to you to read their bio.
Look at their post and see how they interact with people.
Now you'll get a basic idea of who they are and if they're someone you might want to reach out to.
That's really the basics of identifying them.
They're low hanging fruit.
They're popular therefore they're easy to find to be up to you to list them out and cure rate the ones
you think are worth the effort.
Keep in mind also you can outsource this.
You can hire someone for $20 an hour.
Twenty five dollars an hour whatever to do this research just looking for people in your niche making
a list and then just using some basic criteria to kind of drill down on that list.
There's something else you could do is use a tool similar like a more dot coms fall or walk.
And then what you can do is search for Twitter BIOS that are related to your topic.
For instance you could search for Photoshop expert or craft beer.
AUSTIN.
In fact let's do that real quick so let's go to follow along and we'll do a search of the BIOS for that
second one craft beer Austin you guys can't find the site.
You can probably see that you are at the top if not.
Oh my god Google it.
Now the first bunch of Biles that appear here all have tens of thousands of followers.
And you can clearly see some relevance.
They're all in Austin.
And craft beer is in their bio.
What's also cool here is you can look at the column on the right and see what they call social authority
which is followers of Wongs measurement of that Twitter accounts influence.
It's kind of similar to like a Klout score if you guys remember that company.
K L O T basically what they look at is how many followers do you have.
How much engagement you have now when you post something or other kind of a ripple effects that move
through the market some people lots of influencers but don't have a lot of engagement because no one
really cares.
And then a lot of people have smaller ones that have a very engaged following it kind of tries to take
that into account.
Really any of these top five could be good leads for any influencer outreach campaign that I wanted
to run.
So now you might think OK if I can find some influencers I'll just reach out to them as soon as my post
goes up.
Await the results.
And yes net some fancy profit well pump your brakes young one because before you actually do any kind
of asking you need to actually connect with an influencer and show you're not in this just for the shares.
It's kind of similar to our PR Saxa and remember where it's about building the relationships so you
can use it later.
Somewhat like a CIA operative who likes to build their assets and then later convince them that you
know you're going to assassinate the prime minister.
So you need to convince them that you're not just in this for shares and for self promotion and really
you shouldn't only be in this for that anyway and especially if you want to actually grow your audience
or be effective at your promotion.
Hash tag authenticity.
So the first couple of steps for promoting your content through influencers are to first fall the influencer
and engage with them either.
You know you share their content or their or you comment on their stuff or you comment on their blog.
Just find some way of making them notice you.
Now you can link to them or mention them in your blog posts or your social media posts.
Now what you're doing with these first two steps is essentially establishing a kind of relationship
you want to be noticed by an influencer which can be difficult but by connecting and engaging with them
in these ways it can make it happen more quickly.
For example if this influencer writes a blog post like three vital lessons learned from my craft beer
taste test you could comment and give your perspective or float an idea or ask them a question.
Remember the PR thing just just be helpful.
Maybe you can go out and do some primary research and return to them and say Hey look.
Turns out people hate this crap year that you selected.
In other words show that you are actually interested in them.
If they then engage with you well then that's a great foot in the door to starting this relationship.
Now connecting with an influencer makes this next step so much easier and that's the actual ask.
So Step 3 in this process is to contact the influencer and then ask for a share.
Now this is assuming of course they haven't already shared your content before.
If they have already shared it well then you should immediately thank them send them a personal email
shout out on Twitter or whatever but then keep connecting with your influencer in different ways and
be ready for the next time you want something shared.
The first time.
Share your stuff is going to be the hardest and then after that it's much much easier because he essentially
passed their sharable test.
Well they haven't yet shared your content it could be because one they didn't see it when you shared
it on social media your email or whatever online community you use or to.
They did see it and decided not to share it.
Well life is too short to wonder why they wouldn't share your wonderful content.
99 percent of the time it's because what you made is probably just not that good.
Like always keep in mind this is a process you're not going to get it out of the park the first time
you do this first piece of content you make is probably going to be ok.
Maybe the fifth or sixth isn't good enough to get shared.
Just push forward and assume that you can get them to do it.
But at the same time consider these questions that they might ask you.
They could ask you Will sharing this content get me extra engagement will make me look better or smarter.
Will this new connection with you the writer the something good in the future.
For me the influencer notice a pattern here.
It's all about me.
If you guys have taken my other courses go over cold email you know that the biggest cardinal sin of
a cold email is to just talk about yourself.
When people read email and when they read tweets and when they look at content to share they're always
going to be filtering it to their head.
Does this somehow benefit me.
Now you have to think of this from their perspective.
They become an influence there because people trust them their content and their opinion on things.
Would your content help contribute to that.
If it's called quality work and it's relevant to them then there's no reason they shouldn't share it.
So reach out to them.
Now personal e-mail I think is a nice touch.
And if they know you already it's a big help.
Ask them politely for a share of your post on the social media of your choice and give them a link to
check it out.
Or alternatively what I personally prefer to do as opposed to saying Hi my name is this.
Please share this is to ask their opinion of it instead.
Hey I made this.
It's based off what you said before I think could be relevant to you.
What do you think.
And if it really is thoughtful and you really did connect some dots between what they care about and
what you wrote about most of the time they will gratify you by sharing it.
It's really easy to just say hey I'd love to know what you think of it though.
Understand that this message is kind of covert ask but it's a way more polite and thoughtful way of
going about this.
Now go to remember the end of the day.
These are people too.
They like noticed and included on things so don't just ask them to do to share this or promote your
work because you know you want free promotion.
That's a one way ticket to no one ever working with you.
Now what could you expect out of this.
A social share could be great influence or retuning your link or sharing your post on LinkedIn for example
would be great.
It's a whole new audience and you can be exposed to.
And it could lead to more followers and more engagement.
And who knows what else.
A social share was some kind of comment would also be cool instead of just a straight read tweet.
Maybe an influence or tweets.
Great insight from at your username within the link to your post.
Now that's even better.
An endorsement can speak way more volumes than just clicking or each tweet.
Now can you expect anything more than this.
No.
So don't push it.
Share of some kind is your goal here.
Anything else is pretty much gravy.
And if when you do share your stuff send them thanks.
Yeah maybe all they had to do is click a button on their end.
But it should mean a lot to you that they took the time to help you out.
Show some respect and email them personally or just reach out to them through the same platform they
shared on.
But after all of this is said and done Yeah you got someone to share it.
Good job well just continue to connect with your influencers.
Step one and step two are kind of never ending process that if you really want to use this as a channel
for promotion you need to constantly be looking for influencers who are the new ones who are the ones
that have dropped out our favor.
And you constantly need to keep up this process of connecting with them and building relationships.
While we are in that get your 500 section it's probably good at this point to be thinking about how
scalable this process is.
One important thing to share once that's great depends how big they are could get you your 500 customers
but you put a lot of time into developing this relationship finding them and all that jazz so probably
makes sense that you need to keep this up and think of this more as a system.
I got one share this time next time can I shoot for two 2 next time I shoot for three.
That's why it's crucial to keep reading these influencers stuff commenting and engaging especially when
it's not necessary.
That's the basic gist of how you can work with influencers to promote your content.
There's actually one more strategy you could consider and that's to get your content linked to from
blogs and other Web sites.
So get to wrap up this lecture and I'll cover all of the detail of getting back links in the next lecture.
See the.