Hey guys welcome back.
So in the last few lectures we talked about creating your own posts creating them for others as a guest.
And then finally how to promote all that stuff that you made.
Well I know that's a lot of work.
And if you're like me you're looking for some way to organize all of these efforts lists and spreadsheets
will help you organize things up to a point but once you start publishing content and taking this really
seriously it becomes a bit like a machine.
You've got to maintain that progress or it's going to break down.
So the content marketers out there that are serious about keeping that machine going usually create
what we call a content calendar.
If you haven't heard of a content calendar before.
Guess what pretty much any large blog any large publication or even people who just take their blogs
seriously will have one of these.
It is industry standard in the simplest terms a content calendar is a system you can use to help you
keep on schedule with creating and publishing content.
It also helps for coordination especially when you start bringing in researchers collaborators other
writers graphic design artists.
There's a lot of different other people who could participate.
Generally speaking you plug each blog post and other items into deeds in a calendar depending on when
you want them to go live or when you plan on starting the process and then publishing what you have
and now you can do this any number of ways there are actually softwares out there that are solely dedicated
to this.
And usually it's a literal calendar like in a Google calendar for example.
Now I might also be in some cases a spreadsheet like in one column you plug in the dates when you think
you'll be publishing in the next column you put the title of each post.
Or if you want and you want to get serious about this you could use one of those apps dedicated to it.
Like I just mentioned before probably the best well known on and one that I've used before is called
Code schedule which basically lets you and your team certainly if you have a team manager blogs manage
your social media and manage a lot of other different content within your calendar like task lists and
other integrations with apps it tries its best to kind of put an umbrella over everything you would
need in writing researching collaborating putting it together scheduling and then publishing and promoting
your content.
Now however you create this calendar based on how serious you are.
You do need to have some kind of system especially if you're to take content marketing seriously.
Let's be honest here all of us get a little too busy and get interrupted by things to be of any use
to anybody unless we have a system to help us do it.
How many of you don't have a calendar at all and can remember every single thing you always have to
do.
Basically no one if you want to wake up in the morning use an alarm clock if you want to keep track
of your money.
Use a banking app accounting calendar is that system and helps you focus on creating a post and getting
it done within a certain amount of time.
And the reason I keep harping on using a system like content calendars is because content marketing
works best when it's consistently published.
People see a cool blog post or video from you.
They'll probably look for more.
If you only publish when you feel like it there's no guarantee they'll find enough stuff that will make
them think you're worth following.
But also you'll lose their attention.
People who want to follow a brand have an affinity for them and want to and what you publish into their
consumption diet will look for a steady stream of things.
Just in general like if you have an email list if you keep e-mailing people to they'll stay more engaged.
So when you ask for something you want more people will react.
It's really the same thing with blogs.
No not saying you need to post every five minutes but I want you to do is make sure you have a steady
stream of posts and other content.
There's a concept called a publishing cadence meaning how often you publish so it doesn't matter if
your cane says I post twice a day.
I post once a day.
I post once a week.
The point is you're consistent.
People get used to it.
Now this is a bit of a side note but have you ever heard a concept of the 12 touch rule.
Well in sales basically what they say is that you have to touch.
Not like that you prospect at least 12 times either through email calls them reading about you hearing
about you or some interaction before they on average convert.
You can actually look at the conversion stats on like email for instance you'll get after one email.
2 percent conveyer after 3 emails 5 percent after 7 emails you have another 5 percent and for some reason
around 12 you start noticing a large uptick in people converting.
The point here is that in sales one touch isn't good enough.
So in content marketing very similarly one post isn't good enough.
Another benefit to a Condon calendar worth mentioning is that it does also help you kind of keep a mental
check on how much content you have in the pipeline coming very easily look at a content calendar and
go oh wow we have nothing to publish.
We need to think of stuff quickly.
Or look at it and say hey we need to stop spending time brainstorming we have way too much stuff to
write right now because of the benefits of the content count right it's a helpful system helps you schedule
your content helps you publish content on a consistent basis.
And it can serve as a reminder to restock your ideas for your blog post fridge or other content because
he might be wondering now when you say publish content on a consistent basis.
Now what exactly do I mean.
How often should I be publishing what should my publishing cadence be and how that's really going to
be up to you.
Larger companies that have more people reading them are going to publish more often.
But then also you can look at places that publish longer form content and their cadence is going to
be a lot slower.
Well it really is probably going to happen is that your publishing frequency you're publishing Canaan's
is most likely to be tied to how many resources you've got.
You don't have to consider how much time you'll be spending on creating content versus all the other
pieces of your business.
Remember this is only one channel and that's why generally guys mind when I say we're going to look
at traction channels.
I generally say pursue one or two at a time because it's impossible to pursue all you know 15 at once
then what you can say is you know if it works out then I can spend a lot more time towards it.
But you're really going out to be conscious that this is going to take 100 percent of your time.
How much time can you give it now.
If for instance you already have multiple people on your team that are going to be helping you while
you can produce more.
But let's assume it's just you.
Because most operations are generally going to start out that way.
So really if it's just you it's going to come down to how much time you have how productive you are
and in general what how often you think your audience wants to hear from you.
I'm not going to lie and say that there's some formula that says if it's just you and your X-amount
of age old and you have this much time in the day you should publish three times a week or whatever
it is.
What I'm going to say is just first start off with something that's kind of moderate Sarraf with something
that's like let's say twice a week.
OK.
You want to go short posts or maybe once a week if you want to go with a long post and then adjust accordingly.
You can very easily quick to figure out that hey this is way too hard.
Or hey I have a lot of extra time this is a lot easier.
My audience wants more and I can do more.
Also around that time you'll you'll be figuring out whether or not content marketing is going to work
for you.
So how can you get started with this whole content calendar scheduling thing.
Well there's a great model that makes a lot of sense for people creating a calendar for the first time
for the purposes of this example let's just open up an Excel or a Google sheet and do it in a spreadsheet.
Now first off let's just create a basic calendar.
No seven days in the week.
Sunday through Saturday or however we like to set up your week whatever.
Then when you can do is you can set up your month by labeling each week.
We can do week one week to three and four.
That's really all we need for right now we don't need to make some multi year thing right now.
We don't know if Content Marketing is going to be a channel for us.
So even month one let's just start off by publishing one poster to post a week that is totally doable.
It means you need to save for good post ideas to get started for that month.
That then gives you time to prep and create each one month one is a good month to experiment with publishing
on different days of the week as well.
Keep in mind one day the week might work better than others and it's just going to depend on your industry
and your audience.
So try to test it out here because they're all post in let's say Week 1 let's put it on a Tuesday and
then a week to put the Post on Thursday and then Monday and then Wednesday and weeks three and four
after this month you should have a decent idea of which one roughly did better than the other.
And the reason for different days is so you can essentially look at the results of each post and see
which one performed best.
But you know the Analects we set up a while back.
I hope you did.
You can track the number of views and see the number of comments and social shares.
Now how do we know if we posted something and it did well because of the day of the week or because
of the content was better.
Well you just have to kind of tease this out in the analytics generally is pretty easy to tell.
Right.
If when you post it on you or you're promoting on Twitter or Facebook or whatever and you posted and
you look at the page views or how many people came to the page.
That's generally an indication of how many people are paying attention that day when we send an e-mail
how many people click through.
Generally an indication of how many people read it but then you need to look at the goal of the post.
How many people then went to sign up how many people stayed for long periods of time on the page.
Those type of metrics that's going to tell you if the post itself was good or because it anyway after
month one is over let's just go back and look at your results.
How many views of each one get.
Maybe it's a case that on Monday you got the most views whereas you know the content you posted the
next week has the best ratio of views to sign ups or whatever your goal was.
OK that's great.
Well that gives us some ideas for experiments that we could do theoretically in month two and then maybe
next month we could publish each week on a specific day and then see if that performance we predicted
actually plays out.
So in month two let's just say we stay with the once a week frequency but now we'll post each week on
Monday.
You know whatever day you you figure out you think is best.
Now here in our spreadsheet will just duplicate our sheet pretty easy change of names here from month
one month to and now will move all of our publishing days to Monday.
So still for post this month's now on a Monday the idea here is that month after month you can basically
take the learnings from the first month and then roll them forward.
You can throttle up your cadence or throttle down your publishing cadence you can settle on a day of
the week you can settle on which types of content seem to do the best whatever it is and then take that
learning from month 1 into month three if you obviously continue to pursue content marketing.
By the end of the second month you should have a pretty good system in place for creating the post.
Now it should be more natural now to prep and to draft and to edit and in general know how long it takes
you to produce something you're probably looking for ways to make this whole writing process easier
for yourself because at some point we're going to increase the load potentially a little bit.
So let's say in month three we decided to uptick our publishing canes.
So in month three we could you know keep our weekly posts on Monday or whatever day but somewhere in
there will.
And one more post in the month.
So here on the schedule we can easily just duplicate her sheet again change the name to month 3 and
we'll add an extra post let's say in week three of Wednesday.
You know I'm just picking out obviously randomly so obviously you could have like a total of five post
that month.
It could be whatever day you want.
This is just one way of representing it.
So you know you would see how that goes not just from a performance standpoint like did that extra post
get views and engagement but also could you actually handle it.
Was that extra post a pain or you know was it worth the pain.
And is it possible you could handle the extra work if this is the case that you think that content marketing
worked works for you but you're just maxed out in terms of your time.
Be the case.
We start looking at working with freelancers or working with pretty much anyone who can help you unburden
some of the load scripted dot.com.
They're kind of like a marketplace looking for freelance writers that can fit your needs are experts
in different areas.
That one is definitely worth checking out and get a wide range of people some are really cheap and some
are not free and then you know theoretically in this content counter if you're doing all right that
in month four we could add another post.
You know maybe you're already out of the post and retirees and we got an extra one in week one year
you're still doing well for that.
And yet another post and month five and another one month six busier what you'll end up with and you
can see this here in our spreadsheet is to post a week in month six.
So if you follow that plan you'll have gone from publishing zero post amount to eight and in six months
you'll have published a total of 34 posts.
I don't know if you've noticed this but all we did was slowly uptick something that you previously established
as doable and we slowly just increased it as your efficiency increased and there you go now you're 34
34 posts which really is not nothing.
All right so if you like this approach Well then I think Coast Gadgil is a great resource for additional
information at putting together a calendar and scheduling content especially with the app they have.
You really have to use their app but their blog is really focused on how to make the best content calendar
you can if you're starting off at the very beginning and want to keep this simple I suggest just keep
it simple and use an ax spreadsheet.
And then if you decide to get serious about it then I think you can justify paying the like $30 a month
they cost because that is an example of a content calendar.
You don't need to pay for it.
You can just make it in a spreadsheet very very quickly.
But more important than the structure in the system is the process of learning that kind of goes along
with it.
Make sure you use something to schedule your posts to predict it.
People generally expect publishing consistency or publishing cadences if you don't do that well and
you kind of lose the attention of your audience and therefore anything you do in the future will be
less effective.
So commit to a very liberal a very easy schedule at first try to roll the learning onto each successive
month and really after four or five months if you keep at a very low burn schedule you should have a
lot of posts 34 blog posts.
That's you know that's a full blog.
All right guys hopefully that adds a little bit of structure to the process for you to do that.
Guys who found this promising and want to go down that path.
The next we're going to talk about how you can figure out whether or not everything you've been doing
until this point is actually working that is actually a tricky question to answer.
So I'll see the.