Hey guys welcome back.
So we finally reached the homestretch of this content of your journey.
Yes I know see obscenely long on the one recording it but I figured content strategy is incredibly important
because while content strategy is easy for everyone to do and his fingers on a keyboard it's free and
if you put some actual effort into it it's one of the most promising channels I think to go from 100
customers to a thousand.
They aren't really buying ads and are only risking much and risking is your time and at this point your
time probably isn't super valuable in all of our previous lectures here.
We spent a lot of time talking about ways to identify your audience come up with the content ideas ways
to create the content and then most recently how to promote yourself and the content.
And then obviously I don't make a system for managing it all now with all this effort you put in.
At some point you'll want to know is this working or not.
Well in this lecture we're going to cover ways to figure out if your content strategy is working for
you.
We'll talk about the metrics you can measure tools you can use and what to do next.
All right let's get started.
Now if all of our content strategy efforts paid off perfectly than everything we created would have
been seen by everybody in the world and we'd sell all the things to all the people now we'd be rolling
in cash.
Probably Scrooge McDuck ing into a giant pool of gold coins and probably all be floating on hoverboard
by now.
Unfortunately nobody no piece of content is ever perfect.
Everyone is still fighting and struggling to get their blog posts and videos seen in the hope it will
accomplish some goals like selling stuff or connecting with more people you know keeping your business
afloat.
Well I'm just going to say it now.
Measurement is the only way to know for sure if you're succeeding.
If you don't check to see if things are working you'll never know.
Did you get 10000 people to read your blog post.
I don't know if you're not measuring it.
Did you sell enough products this month to pay your rent.
Maybe I he's probably figure that out with all the work you put in.
Or will put in after you're done with the course.
You owe it to yourself to measure results and know for sure.
If you measure the results of your content and also if you figure out ways to improve your future stuff
specially if you can see what worked and what didn't.
So the two important questions we have to ask when it comes to figuring out whether or not we did this
correctly is one what should we measured honor to come to that conclusion and to how do we actually
do the measuring.
First let me address the how because there is a common to everybody and their mom uses to measure content.
The pages and the websites and more.
And that's oh yeah that thing we set up and like Section 4 called Google Analytics.
Once you grow your business into the thousands of customers perhaps you can look into more advanced
tools like a mix panel or a Kismat tracks but for individuals and small businesses that are sub thousand
customers.
Nothing really beats Google Analytics.
It's free and it has pretty much everything you need.
So what should we measure about our content.
Well there are a lot of things Google Analytics and you know the other platforms can measure.
This is our focus and content marketing now is going to be three key metrics that we have to focus on.
So the first key metric has page views now page views are going to tell us how many times a piece of
content was viewed by someone that clicked on your link and viewed your content.
OK whatever.
It's a basic stat for sure but it can help you get an idea as to what people are looking at in general
which topics are being viewed more which formats of content are viewed more like for instance did you
write a listicle and suddenly get twice as many views.
Are there any exceptions worth noting like a post you publish on a holiday the got less views than normal
is used generally is going to inform the decisions you make going forward about which content to make
when to publish it and what promotional techniques you use that work versus others but also give me
some indication about your headlines more page use means more people clicked through.
Again it's a very basic start but it's one of the ones that gives you a baseline that you can work with
through essentially establish the top line.
OK now the next metric you need to make sure that you're paying attention to is average time on page.
Now this data tells you how long the average reader stayed on the page and it's measured in minutes
and seconds.
Now as you might imagine longer content usually has a longer time on page shorter content has less.
Either way though a higher average time on page is better for you more time on pages generally means
the reader hasn't left yet.
They're reading longer and we can assume that means your content is more valuable.
Or you know fallen asleep.
That really happens more time and is also good though because it means that there are more chances for
the reader to see other things on your page.
Like any offers or calls to actions or links to more pieces of content.
So unlike your in-laws the longer these people stay the better.
Now there's always a delicate balance you have to be aware of if you publish a lot of short form content.
You're probably going to see lower time on page and that makes sense right because even the most engaged
people are going to read it but it's going to be over pretty quickly.
And then if you publish the guides while it's generally on average going to be longer where you want
to be aware of is the percentage of people that make it longer than say a minute.
How fast you can read but in a minute that means that they're sufficiently into it.
And if they go past that minute mark that generally means that they're satisfied with what they're reading
or at least interested enough to go farther.
It's kind of similar with video and video we know that there's a 90 second rule.
Usually people drop off around 90 seconds so they make it past 90 seconds.
That means well you hit a winner.
My general advice is to actually just time yourself.
Try pulling up your iPhone or whatever you use and using the timer app and trying to just read it you
know what to do that there's actually a website called word count and it's word count.
Now one of those plug the text into it and I'll tell you the average reading speed for just an average
person reading it.
Then just take that number compare it to what you see and that's a general idea of people finishing
it or not.
So if total page views tells you things like whether you're using the right promotional channel or people
find the topic interesting or the headlines are written well.
TIME On page then I tell you once they came to it.
Are there expectations being met.
Are you getting the right people and is what you're writing something that's worth someone's time.
Now besides those two there's one more stat that I think you should probably pay attention to and this
is the dreaded bounce rate the bounce rate was created by Sir Mix a Lot back in the 1990s during that
music video I think is called Baby Got Back.
My is kidding.
Burns right measures the percentage of readers who bounce from your site without visiting any other
pages on your site.
They read your content and immediately leave.
That's basically it.
Now there is seriously a debate out there as to what bounce rate necessarily means.
Google Analytics actually measures this slightly differently however the difference in definitions is
not large enough to really matter.
The point is if someone bounces.
That means they saw that they click through.
They saw what you had and decided that they were not interested or it didn't match what they thought
it was.
If you have an abnormally high bounce rate it could be a lot of different things.
It could be your site is just ugly.
Could be that you're advertising your stuff or promoting it incorrectly.
Or it could be that what you write is just low quality.
So with that being said what's a good bounce rate.
Well it's kind of hard to say and it's really it's really about interpretation.
Again a good bouncer it's going to depend on what you're writing and who you're going after if you're
writing long form content while you're naturally going to have a group of people that see how long it
is and just naturally leave.
However if it's really thoughtful long stuff that's supposed to be really about people then you probably
shouldn't see something that's too high or the hand you're running short form stuff you can generally
see Ballantrae be a little bit higher and still consider that healthy it's worth keeping in mind.
What were your goals with this post right so a lot of like news sites out there for instance only want
page views on their page.
So if they publish something got a lot of people to click through and 90 percent of the people bounced
it still doesn't matter right because they just want to people see the advertisements.
Now compare that kind of mentality to another kind of site lets say they like a retail website that
sells products 80 to 90 percent of the people arrive on your product page and left.
That's really bad.
That's ads very bad in fact and according to research most retail sites for instance should see a bounce
rate between 20 and 40 percent.
Meaning most visitors will at least look through a few pages before deciding that's not what they're
looking for.
Now there are two reasons why your bounce rate might vary and it's worth kind of keeping this in mind.
Number one it might be the case that there's just not enough for the person to consume me that you wrote
a one page piece.
They read it really quickly or scanned through it and that's it.
OK in that case oftentimes it's because you didn't give them enough internal links or links to other
things to read.
That's why it's important to always have suggested articles that pop up later for them to read more
or some way to push them towards a call to action.
Now another reason you might see a high bounce rate is that your content on the page doesn't match the
way that you're advertising it.
Remember we talked about how to write a good effective headline.
Well sometimes if you take that a little too seriously or too far you can end up running a title that
is just to click Batey or it's a mismatch between what you're actually trying to deliver sometimes the
right content and it's great and there's really you can't really think of a way to sex up the headlines
so you write something that's just inaccurate.
Remember titles create a first impression and users see them on search results or on social platforms.
Someone clicks through starts reading and sees the content and it doesn't really match the title as
they probably end up leaving that's totally natural.
So naturally if you for some reason thought your bounce rate was too high I'd recommend you try to add
more internal linking ways to keep them on your page or at least keep them in your site.
And the other thing is to make sure that your title matches the content of your post.
An easy way to tease that second one out is just to ask someone.
Show them the headline and ask them what they think it is.
Again you can use tools like five second post to do something like that.
You can run a basic survey on Facebook as the survey you Mechanical the survey whatever you can send
out an email.
The point is you just want to see people that say Oh I think this this article will tell me this.
Now I've mentioned page views we talked about time on Page and we talked about balance rate.
Those are the three metrics that are very common ones used by content marketers to measure the success
of posted pages.
But when you see all of these numbers you might still wonder.
I don't know if I'm doing OK.
I don't feel bad because again obviously these numbers are downright confusing and a lot of times it
feels like you're interpreting tea leaves.
Now there's a lot more metrics and Google Analytics as well.
You can get lost in there for Taizz But if you can focus on some key metrics say once a month you get
a much better handle on how to interpret what the numbers mean.
It's also important that you understand basic attribution.
So for instance if you have a page that sells something and a page as a blog you should be able to use
Google Analytics to tell how many people came to this page and then started buying.
That's generally pretty easy to do on Google Analytics just by sorting by origin.
That doesn't necessarily work for you.
There's some other things you can try that are more easy to tell.
For instance there is a site called Jayco or full story.
What it does is it literally records what users do on your Web site so you can watch the people that
come to your blog and watch them and see are they actually going from the page to where I want them
to go.
Anyway back to the point about comparison with content marketing the first time you post something I'm
going to be honest with you.
It's really hard to tell if it's actually working for you.
This is really kind of a long term thing.
So after a month then you might be able to look at it and say yes or no or two months but after one
post it's really hard to say.
Let's say like after four weeks or six weeks or whatever you have a really high time on page and a low
bounce rate.
OK.
This means that they're reading your content and looking around your site for more.
This is probably your best case scenario.
Now if you've a high time on page and a high bounce rate this could mean a lot of different things that
could mean that the people that come and stay really like your stuff and the people that don't kind
of leave.
I consider this kind of middle of the road.
It also kind of depends on how you define balance right.
Some people define bounce right as people who leave immediately and sometimes Google says that people
who bounce or someone who looks at one page only and then leaves.
If that's the case well then your browser doesn't mean anything it just means that they didn't necessarily
convert or go to other pages in your site.
So I consider it something that's kind of in the middle of the road.
You probably want to work on keeping them on the page or promoting in different areas.
Now conversely Let's say you had a low time on page and a low bounce rate.
While that means that people are probably finding what they need quickly and looking around your site
for more.
Again that's kind of middle of the road it kind of depends on what you're publishing.
But if you have a low time on page and a high bounce rate well then people aren't spending a lot of
time looking at your stuff and while they're leaving.
And that's most likely a signal that you didn't make some changes to your content.
But let's not devote all of our attention to Google Analytics because there are other places to look
for data to help us measure success.
Social media content will generate likes and engagement and shares and you can gather that data using
platforms like buffer hoot suite is another one.
And meet Edgar.
There's obviously a lot more each social platform has its own metrics even within that that they can
give you an idea as to what works.
Facebook pages for instance give you detailed stats but the total number of likes and followers you've
got as well as specific post views reach and engagement showing you which content work best.
These web pages also feature insights tab where you can dig into your audience and see demographic data.
Now Twitter on the other hand provides an analytics page you can see your top tweets as well as basic
metrics like followers shares and mentions how many people click through to your profile or click through
to your link when you post something.
Twitter also has a followers dashboard that lets you see information about your followers like demographics
lifestyle info consumer behavior.
Little creepy.
Now depending on how seriously you use these social platforms you have a chance to get more detailed
info on how your content promotional efforts are going with access to this data in different places
so the success of your content obviously is important.
And using these metrics and ways to interpret numbers will help you figure it out but ultimately your
success hinges on the original goals you've set for yourself.
Why are you creating content in the first place.
What did you hope people would do.
Do you want them to buy stuff.
Register for something or simply read it and then remember you.
Your success here will be measured by a number of conversions that you can generate.
Google Analytics does allow you to track conversions meaning it can record every time a Web site visitor
performs a specific action like making a purchase or signing up for a newsletter for example.
So setting up conversions that relate to your content strategy goals all of you understand if you're
achieving any measure of success you might see that some pieces of content lead to more conversions
while others don't.
Eventually you'll get to a point where you realize have a big overarching content strategy goal.
Things that benefit your business as a whole and you also have individual content goals like jittering
page views and longer time on page.
You'll see that the success of those smaller pieces then drive the success of the bigger goals.
So don't worry if it seems like things are taking way too long a time.
Now this is an ongoing strategy.
You need to keep feeding kind of like a fire or wild unicorn.
Don't feed it and it will die.
So once you've got your measurement platform like your Google Analytics and you know how to do the basic
tracking that we covered before and you've got the numbers look at then you might see some opportunities
for improvement.
In general there are some tips that can help you get better numbers regardless of the kind of industry
or business you're N..
Number one is try to focus on writing better content.
I know it sounds all simple but make better stuff.
It's really that simple.
Spend more time on it research it more polish it more get more outside information.
Think through it more.
Number two is maybe if you don't like your metrics instead of going back and editing what you have or
are trying to do more try to change your process.
You've got to just focus more on consistency.
Don't stop producing content.
Remember like a fire or a unicorn or a cat you don't feed it it will die.
So keep going.
Sometimes the problems will iron themselves out.
Number three is try your best to look for clear successes and then duplicate them.
A lot of times are published 10 things and one will do way better than the others.
It should be obvious when you look at the metrics in the metrics you might see that the blog post called
top 10 ways and app developers like getting a root canal is your best one and it's got a lot more attention
so maybe you make some more listicle.
Or you create more stuff with the funny titles or you focus more on trolling the dentistry profession.
But if something works try to exploit it in the end measurement will go a long way towards helping you
understand what's working and why.
But it's not everything.
Keep experimenting and figuring out new ways to create content and the results you want should come.
Keep in mind this is more of a long term strategy.
So at first you might not succeed.
That does not mean you won't succeed in the next round or the next round.
Over time you also get better at interpreting your metrics.
Right now I can't give you an absolute answer as to what your bounce rate should be but you can figure
it out over time.
If you notice that as you make subtle changes you get better at your process.
It goes down well then generally you know you're moving towards the promised land.
You could also just use common sense.
Are you getting more sales.
Are you getting more conversions.
And then look at how much time you spend on the content strategy yourself.
Is it worth it.
I think it's a fantastic way to get to your 500 customers.
I don't think it takes longer than a month to use it to get to that point.
If you're smart and you're diligent about it anyway that's enough of what I think.
I'll see you guys the next lecture.