Now in order to get the most out of your mykes and capture the best audio you can remember the second
point I mentioned at the beginning of this lecture.
Great audio making means making sure we don't hear anything else but the subjects on screen.
Now what do I mean.
Well let's do a cooking experiment.
Wherever you are I want you to actually stop.
Don't make any noise.
Pause the video and listen.
Now you might be in a living room office or bedroom.
Take a listen and make a note of what you hear besides me obviously.
Maybe there's the slightest hum of an air conditioner.
Perhaps you're in the kitchen and you can hear your refrigerator buzzing away.
Maybe someone's outside right now mowing the lawn.
Some kids are probably skateboarding on your sidewalk god dammit.
Maybe a large truck rambling body there might be birds if they have opposable thumbs they might be tweeting
right now.
Coral is full of sounds.
No matter where you are we get used to it so you don't really notice it.
But as soon as you set up for a shoot you might all of a sudden notice hey I let my neighbors are actually
quite loud.
So part of the challenge of capturing great audio for your marketing video is going to be eliminating
as many of those worldly sounds as possible.
Now that really just comes down to choosing a location.
Well try to choose a location that says isolators possible US few extra people machines and noises as
possible.
Then when you're in your chosen location you want to do something that's what I consider more important
which is called an acoustic treatment.
Now this means optimizing your room to deaden any noises in it and reduce any echo you might get.
In case you're in a room that's empty or the room might just be big or it might be big and empty.
Now you might ask What do you mean by Echo.
What do you like filling in a cathedral so every time you make a noise I can hear.
After three seconds your voice comes back like a boomerang.
No what I'm talking about and I was as I say Echo because Echo is what you might recognize it as.
But technically it's called reverb.
Now what reverb is is when I talk and the camera picks it up it's also going to pick up the sound waves
from my voice that hit the wall and then bounce back to it.
Now comes the absolute millisecond after it captures the original sound.
The time between it coming back distorts the sound but also the refraction off of something will change
the sound.
So in dead rooms what that basically means is when I talk.
That's all you hear.
You don't hear any secondary voice bouncing back with like a tinny or a hollow sound to us if you're
really bored actually just turn off all the sound right now in your room and clap.
And when you clap just listen to it does it just go.
Or do you actually hear it reverberate on the walls.
That's a really good way of testing a room to see if it's worthy of shooting.
If you clap and you go Oh wow yeah I can hear the ceilings of the walls.
Well yeah then it's probably a bad place.
Usually a dead room when you clap.
It's barely sounds like anything they might say well what's it matter if there's a little bit of reverb.
What really matters if you have bad reverb it's really really hard to understand you and you add in
music.
Oh man it just becomes a muddled mess.
It's actually one of my promo videos I had to redo entirely.
I can probably link it in the non-technical person's guide to building products and apps.
The Echo was so bad it's it's really hard to tell what I'm saying and unfortunately is because I was
in a room had too much empty space and the walls were metal sorry the walls were like cement whatever.
It's a really bad material for sound bouncing off of it.
All right so really there's three steps in general for doing what we call an acoustic treatment to make
the room not sound terrible.
Now the first thing obviously is like I said before get as quiet as you can clap your hands see how
it sounds.
Then also just listen for hommes buzzes other noises from machines and any other sources use your microphone
and headphones and just tell everybody to shut up for a second.
So usually if you want to be polite you kind of stay quiet on the set you know probably not on a set
right now but people think you're cool for saying it did you will have things like refrigerators conditioners
microwaves and fans and things like that and you're going to have to turn those off a lot of times you
have a window open you're going to have to close it.
Unfortunately the temperature in the room is probably going to be the least of your concerns.
Do your best to turn off what you can and eliminate all the outside sources.
Next step would be to focus on reducing the reverb that we talked about before.
Now have you done the klap test.
And you said wow I can hear the walls or if you couldn't tell what you can do is just record Samaniego
just saying talk talk talk or writing off a fake sentence or whatever and then put it into a computer
listen on your headphones.
That's the best way to tell because that's what people are going to hear at the end of the day.
So a lot of times you listen to it oh go oh wow that's really what this room sounds like in this case.
The best tip I can give you is use blankets if you've ever moved from one apartment or house to another
you probably seeing these heavy quilted blankets they use and they wrap and cover your furniture and
they're thick because you know if you bump into something that ought to damage whatever they're carrying
you know if you buy them without moving and they're really cheap you get each one for like two bucks
or something.
Well you can do with those is a lot of things you can use some clamps and you can hang them on if you
use a couple light stands.
Sometimes the molding in the room you are in you can use hooks in and hang them up like that.
Worst case scenario I've done this before you leave a big exposed wall that's really hard metallic material
like a cement or something.
What you can do is duct tape it.
I've duct tape these to the wall and it works pretty well.
Do your best to cover as many expose large spaces that could be reverberating sound and then keep testing
it as you go.
There are things you can do if there's options available to you it's just fill the room with more stuff.
If you're in a living room that's empty and you might have emptied it because you think oh that's better
for filming.
Well that actually might have worse reverb than if you put the couches and the tables and the stuff
back in larger rooms means that the sound has to travel farther before it comes back.
And so that actually can create a lot of problems.
So what you can do if you're limited on supplies is you can take one of those blankets I was talking
about and try to hang it up kind of like you'd hang up clothing after the wash and turn up if you're
in a large room.
Try to put in the middle of the room and what that does it essentially cuts the room in half so that
the sound doesn't go all the way to the end and then back it only goes halfway back and then actually
that can actually help quite a bit.
But as you do about reverb and this just really comes down to choosing a location is.
I know hardwood floors look great but carpeted is just going to be so much better.
You can only cover so much the floor with blankets.
Just pick some place that has carpet or throw down a rug that will make an enormous difference.
The third thing you can do and this is kind of optional it's kind of out of the way but you can invest
in if you're using the same location.
Often you can invest in foam pads and there's a lot of them out there and they're not really cheap.
You can get these half inch foam pads they could look like egg shell basically or a lot of times they're
like these triangles spikes and they usually come in like one and a half foot by one and a half foot
squares.
You can buy things like 10 of them for $30 or something like that checked on Amazon but you can cover
all your walls with that and that will deaden up the noise quite a bit.
The only problem with that is like if you're using a space like a rental space or are you going somewhere
you shoot out all the time.
Well you have to put those foam pads up and you know if you're renting your apartment even when you're
shooting your apartment you know that's always something you have to take in consideration make sure
that when you put them up you use a light adhesive because otherwise you take them off they'll rip the
paint off and other other foam options you can use.
They all get way more expensive from there you can do what are called acoustic panels which are kind
of two foot by four foot panels and you hang up against your wall.
You can see them in some of my courses I use to put them on the doors but they look kind of like something
you'd see in someone's home.
That's the best part about them is that they look normal.
However they do cover a big section of a wall and they're pretty good at absorbing sound.
You also invest in things like bass traps which are foam pads that go up on your ceiling in the corners.
Right now you might think that will cover the whole walls of foam when Also I need all foam actually
only will stop certain frequencies of sound.
You actually need these things called bass traps to help with the lower frequencies of sound so that
your voice sounds low or unmanly or whatever.
If you're really an audio file or if you really have a space you are doing a lot of recording in that
symphony something to look into.
The last thing we need to talk about really quickly are audio recorders.
Now those are those things that you use kind of in the field that record the sound of the microphone
to the recorder.
They're better than going right into your camera because they don't have as much static noise incorporated
with them.
They're also pretty portable which means that you can have more flexibility of what you're shooting
where you're walking to.
Really they're all just kind of small boxes I just showed you mine before they record.
They have a lot different settings you can use them for a lot of them actually can record on themselves
alone without using an external microphone which is pretty cool.
At least good when your mikes break and you're in a Penge.
So the most common brands you'll see are like Tass cam or zoom and they both make really popular recorders
that are usually around like $200.
Now the only consideration pass that I would say with these recorders is if you start getting really
fancy really they're getting professional audio and you might start getting something that's way more
fancy you start mixing audio professional audio people though record one thing for each person on the
set and will even have recorders around the room just to pick up and be noise and they can feed that
in later into the video.
Yeah.
You don't need to go that far by it.
You do need to consider how many Mikes you need.
Ninety nine percent of the time you'll be fine with any zoom more tabs cam recorder because they allow
you to put in at least two microphones.
The last thing I'll say about audio is that unlike lighting you don't just set it up and then you're
done with it till the end of the shoot.
With audio you do have to do what we were mentioned before called Audio monitoring which means that
occasionally you have to check to make sure that it is working as it should.
This is especially the case with lava liers but occasionally you run into situations where a car drives
by and wrecks the sound or just something happens and if you're not paying attention to the audio you
might miss it.
Now the best thing you can do is if you're working with someone have them monitor it as they monitor
the camera on the lights and other things.
But if just you well this thing to do is just occasionally take breaks and then listen to the audio
to make sure nothing went wrong.
OK.
Later on in the lectures of this section we're going to talk about different production setups and we'll
again discuss audio but we'll discuss it in more detail about where to position them what types.
I prefer to buy or what's best for your budget.
Until then I'll see you in the next election.
We talk about video.