All right.
Welcome back to the course.
We're still talking about defining our audience and well for good reason.
We discussed all the different ways in the previous lecture we can collect data and the more we know
about our audience the better.
It helps us plan and helps us create content and it helps us understand our audience better.
Those are all good things.
But every time we have an idea for a blog post or a video we don't want to dive into the mountain of
data or dozens of Google Docs or lists or whatever we've collected.
You might be familiar with that saying that a picture is worth a thousand words.
Well rather than consult with those thousands of words every time we have an idea let's instead consult
with a picture to help us get that picture of our audience.
We're going to create what we call a user persona.
Now if you guys are in some of my other classes we cover user personas so you can skip this if you want
to use because you're a new user persona is basically a character we create that represents our ideal
customer or client.
It's an approximation or an average or representative.
However you want to describe it of our audience but for the purposes of coming up with content ideas
and creating those pieces a user persona is like a gatekeeper.
If an idea works for them then it should work for our target audience.
So how do we put together a user persona.
Basically if our target audience could be represented by one person we would want a profile or a bio
of person.
We'd like to know their name their job role their goals professionally and in some cases personally
and would be great to know their daily challenges what they have to accomplish each day.
What often gets in the way of meeting those goals.
Oddly enough the weirdest part of that bio might be the name because if we're supposed to create a profile
that represents an entire group of people we can't exactly call it Carl or Gloria or something like
that right.
Oh actually we can.
Let me help paint this picture here and really we can just do this in a Google doc.
It's really nothing fancy.
If my target audience was let's say new business owners perhaps I named my persona new business Bob
or not I know startups Steve or people out there who do X will recommend a new user persona when you
pick a name for your persona.
They'll suggest you use alliteration because it helps make those names easier to remember.
That point is really up to you.
I personally think it's a little goofy but I will stick with that pattern.
After you decide on a name for use a persona then we can add in other details that we've mentioned before.
Their job role while job role does not necessarily equal job title.
Our business owner might be credited as the CEO or owner or president or founder something like that
but in reality our audience members have multiple roles.
Are the CEO as well as the chief product officer.
Maybe the CTO as well.
Maybe they're the head of business development maybe even sales and support.
Certainly if that business employs one person well for our persona we can select the roles most common
for our audience and expand upon them in the section where we talk about goals and daily challenges.
When we lose goals in this persona we'll probably list common new business struggles grow our user base
scale the business and define a business strategy.
So our challenges will reflect those goals.
Limited resources to grow user base limited finances to hire new people.
Limited knowledge of industry.
We can continue to flesh out this persona more data that we've collected like the demographics we found.
Let's put in an age for our persona.
Somewhere in that range that we identified for 25 to 30 for any number in there can work.
Where does this guy live.
Well our audience is from all over.
But they are most likely city dwellers.
We can leave it as that actually helps us understand what they have access to on the day to day basis.
We don't want to be overly specific and put in an example like Austin Texas unless we were actually
targeting just that one city.
Let's put an annual income and let's just put something in a range that we identify let's say a range
is thirty five thousand to ten thousand dollars.
We can put in whatever we want there then for education level let's say bachelor's degree.
It's kind of hard to guess that one but based on your research we ran a survey you might be able to
kind of figure that one out.
Also if you just look on Facebook at some of your users you'll notice a pattern pretty quickly if you
notice that they have universities listed one more piece we can add here.
Favorite Web sites and brands.
Now when we research Serious Eats in our last video we found information about users on Quantcast and
it showed us some of the brands and Web sites their users liked here and your persona.
We can list these names and you or else to give us more of an idea of where they go and what they think
about during each day.
So is sort of Steve here starting to take shape.
Well a little bit.
You could even add a picture if you wanted to and find you know just some guy on google image search
wearing a hoodie or something that looks like he or she might be in your target audience.
Again hardcore people and you x will suggest that you do put a photo because the photo will allow you
to connect to that persona on more of a human level.
This pic is of an actor who is on Mad Men a few times.
I don't know.
He just kind of looks like what I'd imagined sort of Steve looks like it's just really I don't know
another way to make him more memorable.
Another detail.
And here is a biography or a persona story and really all you'd be doing here is playing a little bit
of make believe if this persona had more history to it more motivation behind it what would it all be.
Why did startups Steve start his company what's driving him to achieve those goals of his.
Is he a hard worker or is this more of a side job like.
I'll put more effort into this if it takes off kind of approach.
Are there causes he believes in all this can help us speak to some of the values of our audience.
And honestly if you don't know this information that's fine but do it last and take your best guess
at it again try to read people's Facebook posts try to actually talk to some of your customers and try
to kind of create an approximation of a story that you might think is believable if you figured out
that they believe in hard work well then so should our persona.
So our guy Steve.
He learned how to create apps in college.
And his first job was as a developer.
He did that for a few years and on the sides started developing this app idea.
He had six months later after you launched it he realized he needed to make a decision.
Either stick with his day job or quit and devote his time to the app.
So he took a chance and now he's trying to build a business around this app.
There you go.
That's a story.
And one more detail you can add here is a quote almost like a personal mantra or a mission statement
totally optional for you guys out there.
But some people have found that doing this can also help their understanding.
It's another way to quickly sum up your persona and make it again more memorable.
Perhaps it's something like I can't wait to retire at 35 which clearly means or this guy wants to make
lots of money.
Or maybe it's if I can help just one person a day I'm happy.
Which could mean he's not as interested in growth as he is and say like user satisfaction or making
some kind of personal or social difference whatever that is.
Sort of Steve would most likely say I want to help as many customers as I can to achieve their dreams.
So he believes in growing his company and doing good at the same time.
Good for Steve.
And there you go.
We've got a Google doc page here that's less than a page long.
Somewhere you can find a lot of detail.
Just a glance.
This is the picture we're talking about now and we've created a user persona we can use that to help
us come up with content ideas or at the very least validate the ones we've already thought of.
Let's say we've got some ideas for blog posts squirreled away.
The question becomes would startups be interested in these.
So say idea number one.
It's a blog post titled Five Easy Steps to grow your user base through targeted Facebook ads.
Let's say idea Number two we can do a series on how to articles demonstrating how to use different apps
and platforms.
Do payroll accounting and finance funds stuff let's say idea Number three is an interview with a startup
founder we know personally asking him how he managed to become profitable within a year.
Which of the three ideas would make the most sense for our persona.
Well we know sort of Steve wants to grow his user base and it's one of the goals we mentioned and it's
in that quote We came up with so idea one probably seems like a winner right now.
Idea number two is interesting there's plenty of new business owners who could use the help of platforms
and apps to organize and automate different tasks.
But it is finance and accounting.
One of the tasks that Steve would be interested in is payroll specifically something Steve would care
about.
I'm not entirely sure because there's no indication of that in the user persona we put together a lot
of these startups Steeves might be the only employees at the moment so maybe it's less of a concern.
For now I might say let's pass on it but don't dismiss it completely you can just kind of store it off
to the side.
Maybe there could be demand for it later or maybe might change your mind.
Now that idea Number three or three is this interview of the founder a friend of ours.
He's willing to give us advice on how to become profitable and this could speak to some of startup Steve's
goals some of his psychographic It's like scaling the business into finding a strategy.
I'd say this is one we could definitely consider.
So there you go.
You had three good ideas but thanks to the help of our persona we know that two of them would be more
appropriate for our audience user personas can help focus our efforts this way not just with creating
the content but of validating our ideas before we've even one word of it saves us a lot of time and
a lot of trouble.
So now it's your turn.
Do you have a startup Steve or someone else that would serve as their user persona opened up a Google
Docs or just some easy place you can jot down information like this give them a name give them a job
role or multiple job roles.
Remember don't give them a job title because they're just not as accurate.
Give them some professional and personal goals.
Give them some challenges you think they might deal with on a day to day basis and then give them some
demographics like age location education level and income and maybe if you want favorite brands and
Web sites that they use then you can kind of wrap it up with some optional things that I like to add.
You can tell their story you can add a quote and you can add a picture boom.
There you go.
You've got a persona.
And through this process you might realize you know we've got startups Steve for sure.
But beyond new business owners I know that we also get a lot of people who invest in their businesses
as well.
So maybe then you add a second persona like let's call it investor Irwin or something like that.
Now keep in mind no company is only going to have one user persona.
It's good to get a good handful as long as you think there is a good serious chunk or contingent of
your audience that fits each one.
A lot of businesses can easily define one or two or even three personas.
But if you go beyond three then I think you might be spreading yourself too thin.
And it's hard to kind of make content that bridges the gaps between too many personas find the ones
you absolutely want to focus on and make this persona as your primary ones.
So once you have your personas print them out and put them on your wall or post them internally with
other people who write for you your personas can be your virtual customers the people you keep in mind
as you work through ideas write content prepare other marketing materials.
Don't forget about them.
OK that's it you guys know what goes into a percent on how to kind of rationalize your way through them.
You have any questions.
Make sure to post in the slack.
Otherwise I'll see in the next lecture.