All right, and we are back. Last lecture, we got real
acquainted with this lovely graph that growth marketers
dream about at night, and I've heard
stitch into their bed pillows.
It's just a rumor, and like most rumors, it's 100% true.
OK, so we get it.
New businesses need short term manual strategies
to start feeding the gears of feedback that will allow
you to progressively expand your
growth efforts with more confidence.
But there's one more thing we need to talk about,
lest you've finished the rest of the course with exploded
brain syndrome. In all growth strategies,
there are two components that make it work.
Number one component, you have something that attracts
attention, and number two component, you have something
that converts that attention into sales or conversions.
You have the honey that attracts the bees or the
milkshakes that bring the boys to the yard, and then
you have whatever the bees drown in, because from
how I understand it, that's how beekeeping works,
and then you have whatever convinces the boys to drink
the milkshake - which is a metaphor we are no longer
going to explore.
Basically, it is the world's simplest jigsaw puzzle.
Everything we cover in this course and everything you
do in an attempt to buy some customers will need
both components to work effectively.
Presumably, you sell something on your website or
through some web property you control, or even through
a platform where you host your
business. If you want to sell something,
first we need to get people to our page, and then we
need to make our page in a way that actually then
gives them what they want.
If we say we're pursuing a content strategy, we would
need to make something and then promote it.
The promotion could be community posting, it could be
borrowing traffic from platforms, buying ads, targeting blogs,
there's a million other ways you can get eyeballs on it.
Once the user sees the post, and it's the post's job
as the second part of this formula to convince the
user to either buy something you're selling, do
something, like give you their email address, or follow
your brand in the future.
Oftentimes, this piece is the end point
and it tries to convert the user.
Sometimes it's just a link in the chain and it's
used in tandem with, say, email marketing.
So get used to thinking about growth strategies
as always two distinct actions. Throughout the course,
this is also how we're going to be explaining these.
In the next couple of lectures, we'll go over how to
check that your site is ready for sales,
and if it is, then that dramatically simplifies
that second process. I will see you later.