Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
OK Sue we just covered making a system for tracking your content ideas pretty important to list them
out and to have something that you can easily input them.
When the idea actually comes to you in in lecture what we did I think we used Google sheets to just
list them out.
Right.
And then I gave some criteria that you could use to sort them or at least label them so that later on
you can find whatever you're looking for.
It's really important that you do label these out because later on when you have 60 70 ideas and let's
say you only have enough time to do a short post or how you can determine which of those are theoretically
short posts you know spending hours just going through all of them to pick the one that you wanted.
It also helps if you can give them readings so you can prioritize and focus on the ideas you think are
the most obviously valuable and the ones that you think are more easy to promote Really.
You know the day content is all about promotion.
So your resume is great but it just doesn't make any sense for how to promote it you know idea.
OK let's not nearly as good as something that's half OK but it's really obvious how to get distribution
how to get people looking at this.
Anyway so this is what I use and it's a bit old and outdated.
If anybody's been following my blog I don't blog a lot.
I tried doing it but it's just not something that I Wike doing.
And I'm not consistent enough.
Right.
So this was a channel I explored put some work and effort into it and then just kind of realized it's
not really worth it anyway so I use air table and now is something you mentioned before.
This is the way I've set it up.
So this is my content pipeline over here.
I list the names of all of my content ideas.
There were a lot more in here but I guess I actually finished a lot of them.
This is where I put the status so I could sort by editing it and my writing it.
Am I just planning it where am I at.
And then the date would be the launch date and rate so I could list these out.
I want this in this month or on this specific date.
So if I were just looking at what I need to get done now I would sort by this I put summary notes right
here because its really helpful because a lot of times you'll put down an idea and then later on you'll
come back to it and you're like what does that mean.
I have no idea what I'm talking about like this introvert OK wat is that me.
So I put some notes as an opportunity to do that.
I put an approval column.
The reason I did this is because I was working with other people and so they were doing research and
editing and things like that so I would have to prove it to say yes I want I think this is good enough
to go on my blog or go to the next stage and the next thing I did is a format.
Now the format I think is really important to tag them like this.
And if you guys use our table to really easy to tag I literally can just go in here and add whatever
I want.
Not logged into this I got it but so what I did was e-mail I guess like guest posting.
Cora for making long court posts they then copy to my blog.
Now they have things like a public publish on medium or some of these are actually mini sites.
So this one's a mini site.
And so I did end up actually launching this one.
This is what it ended up looking like.
If you guys saw it on product thought or not so I would have checked this one off.
But anyway so what I can do is like I a lot of time and already something big I get sort by this and
look for my mini site ideas if I had something I was really short I could just look for blogs or core
posts or something small then what it is I put them in the category thats obviously really important
that you know which categories your audience wants.
And so I had entrepreneurship business and strategy and then I had kind of a catch all for everything
else which is like technology but all my stuff probably kind of falls in that category.
This was how it relates to each course I make use of you know to do that and then I put kind of a sub
where I explained how I thought at least what I thought the angle of this post was going to be so I
put.
Op Ed if I was going to write a post and its not like a research article its something that I was going
to just give my opinion and wax on about op eds you see these all the time in like newspapers.
This would be like a how to guide so would be more instructional.
Do this this this this and this and then this And so that also would mean and probably need more graphics
and videos and other kind of supporting information innovation.
I think it is more of like a series I was thinking about doing focusing on innovations.
Case studies.
Okay so then I get to read a case study this way and it probably me a lot longer it's probably going
to involve a lot of research and involve doing interviews and talking to people trend analysis.
You know I thought that was another common one might do and then list like good all this tickles and
then other than that I put things like targets goals you know you don't do all this stuff.
CTA is.
So what was my goal.
Well you know if I'm making something for a read it that's my my target.
Well then karma or it might be my goal or my goal might be click or it might just be building my where
my brand on that platform so that later on I can use it click through.
So by CD-R's are usually kind of the same thing.
I hadn't really narrowed down what exactly I wanted them to do and this is actually one of the problems
with this was I just made this for fun and I wasn't really trying to drive people to sign up here but
had I done that had I focused on it then I would have gotten a lot more e-mails.
I think this only got like 4000 emails and how I focused on it I probably would convert it a lot more
people.
So for me I call actions are usually like joined my slack if I'm promoting it go to my blog Good on
you and the pages.
I don't really have that much else going on and repurpose these are just plans that I had for repurpose
Right right.
We'll talk about this later on but if you write a blog repurpose thing is pretty important.
Where can I chalk this up and put it out.
And then over here is this is these are the things I put for ranking them.
So how easy is it to promote.
How well does this fit with my brand and how original is it.
I'd rank them and then give them a ranking that made it easy to sort.
Well take a cruise real fast from the other things going on here.
Those are my dream Raf's This is my actual pipeline.
So these were more of the post that I was actually kind of focusing on with more notes on what they're
about.
All filled out pretty much the same.
They rank them all so I could filter by this if I wanted to and then see.
Those are the worst ones the best one is the non-technical stack.
Ok so I had a idea for a post where I would kind of propose a stack of technologies for people who are
non-technical founders and then orated it based on like what I'd seen how original It is my brand.
Absolutely.
How easy is it to promote.
Pretty easy.
Oh and I just said other times this just kind of sorted everything by the month.
So this is what I'm shooting for for the month.
This is what I wanted and that was just a good way to look at a broader view of how I'm handling this
or what's coming up in the month like month whatever laundry was just a place where I put a bunch of
notes were put a bunch of notes on how to promote it are things to look into what do you think I think
is really important.
Was I set this up so that I could have different views and what I meant by views was that this is my
main view this is internal.
Anybody working with me can see this and we can collaborate on it.
However I need something for idea capture.
So I have an idea I need to write this down really quickly.
So what we had was an actual input page.
Now we can actually see this right now.
But it's a good read only mode is actually disabled.
But the idea was I created a form so what I could do is just go here and write in all that information
as I want it.
And it was all optionals like you put in the information like the title notes some kind of a subtitle.
I could even categorize it then I could rate it at the time.
But the point was it was really important to have just a sheet or a page that I can repeatedly go to
just input it and be done with it.
OK guys so you don't have to be as crazy as I was with this but if you're really serious about content
marketing then and making something like this to handle the information especially you start working
with other people can be pretty crucial.
I like using air table because it just has a lot of features and it's kind of like Google sheets or
Excel but they just made it a lot easier to use a lot more user friendly.
And there's just a lot more features.
You know it can be a little overwhelming.
It does take a couple of hours to figure out how to use it.
But once you do that it's pretty awesome.
OK guys.
Well this is my content pipeline.
I might publish this in the resources if you guys want to look at it since I'm not really doing much
with it but otherwise in the next lecture.