All right guys welcome back.
So in the last lecture I gave a rundown of one kind of editing style we looked into a bunch of techniques
from a man named Casey Neistat and we looked at how he uses and puts together his videos.
Now in this round I want to give you more ideas for how to edit your videos by looking at techniques
used by the team over a YouTube channel called Crash Course.
Now a crash course produces a series of educational videos on all kinds of topics Gooding science history
economics and more.
And you can imagine if you're in the business of creating videos for educational purposes like what
school kids or college students or whoever might watch.
You really need to create stuff that's not only accurate and communicates all the facts people need
but they also have to be interesting educational videos in general need to capture attention and keep
it so if you're running down lots of facts well you might consider doing what Crash Course does and
using a couple of their editing techniques to make your visuals more interesting and well fun to watch
crash course by the way came from a YouTube channel called The Villon brothers where two brothers would
ask them each other questions one would ask question on video and then the other one would respond.
And it got really popular.
Millions and millions of followers.
Largely because of the styles they used in it.
They use a lot of jump cuts.
They created a lot of techniques that you see all across YouTube now.
Crash course of their hand is like their first attempt at being more straight faced more educational
less just goofy.
Q and A and casual.
All right first of all it's just if you have the time go and just watch a quick launch go to YouTube
and type in Crash Course if you go and look at them and watch one of their videos.
This will help you understand this quite a bit but generally it's just it's John Green who is also a
famous author now sitting at a desk with a bunch of goofy things around him and constantly cutting to
images or animation and then they have a couple kind of narrative mechanisms that they use over and
over that are either funny or goofy or gives them an opportunity to have some back and forth.
So let's actually get down to their editing style.
First off they do this thing that well I'm going to call the three for one at it.
They shoot their lecturer in a medium wide shot.
Basically it's like a waist up shot from them in the center of the frame.
Now this is a nice shot and it's kind of similar to what I'm doing now.
Little bit of this is a little more narrow than that and it's totally fine to use this throughout the
entire video however you run the risk of being a little stale.
Now what I mean is that no matter how interesting the stuff was that the speaker was saying if we sat
on the same shot here for 10 seconds 20 seconds and 30 seconds.
Well it would become tiring.
Yes we're learning.
But us human beings need to be stimulated at the same time.
So crash editors take that medium shot and then they crop that frame just a little bit like this.
And you know I'm looking at it feels like we're just slightly zoomed in.
And now the speaker is on the right side of the frame.
It also looks like a different shot with a different camera.
But no it's just the same footage cropped a little closer using editing software or in Premiere.
They probably selected the shot and increased the scale after you by making the image bigger.
It seems like we're about zoomed in either way it's a pretty basic technique and with HD quality especially
with four k this very slight crop wouldn't actually degrade the quality of the video really that much
still looks great.
And if you can crop the image in this direction well we can crop towards the other side too.
So 10 seconds later in this video the next line the speaker delivers has him now on the left side of
the screen all the Crash Course editors did was shift that crop from one side to the other.
Now I see what I mean.
Three for one you have the normal shot but then within that shot they just zoom in on either side.
And now they have three shots out of one.
The way you do this in your actual editing software.
Pretty simple.
You just take your time line image.
Then you look at the little preview window and you're caught at the point where you'd want to zoom in.
So you cut your clip in half then you take that section where you want to be zoomed and go to the preview
window.
And there should be control.
Will do this but there should be a button that allows you to drag a corner of the image.
So then all you do is grab the corner pull it so it zooms in but only on that second part of the clip.
Now why would you do this Croppy kind of editing.
Well there's probably another take in there somewhere on the speaker recorded this.
Maybe he messed up a word or maybe he just wanted to say things a different way.
But either way they wanted to make an edit it without leaving a jump cut.
There's an edit where there's a gap of some time between two identical shots.
The fact that some footage is missing is notable but by cropping the original image in a different direction
you can make the edit without creating the jump could affect and make it look like you actually shot
with multiple cameras whereas in this case they actually use one camera.
So there you go three different shots created from one a three for one special.
Now you can certainly crop and zoom a shot in other ways too but Crash Course uses this technique a
lot to keep the video looking energetic and clean.
It's a pretty economical way to use one camera angle.
The next technique we're going to look at that crash course he uses is an editing incorporating animation
now animation can take a few different forms but for marketing purposes I'm not really talking about
the Disney Pixar type stuff.
Animation can be used to make tiles move and pop like a lot of those ads you see where as you're saying
the words they show up on screen they rotate and they shift the globe and they slide around etc..
Crash course these is an animated tidal effect that's even more subtle than that.
In this video the use of animation emphasized the word for word sections the speaker says it all verbatim
but on certain words or phrases they animate the word and an emphasis just a little touch like they
can help the viewer stay more connected with what's being said.
Now Crash Course also uses animation by creating characters that appear and then move around on the
screen all the speakers talking.
Check this part out.
It's not even necessary that the character be there.
But again it's a little touch that adds some visual appeal and keeps you interested for longer sequences
like when they need to provide long examples or in this case tell a story.
Crash Course uses a full screen animated sequence to explain everything when they need the viewer to
take in a bunch of details or steps full screen visual can really capture their attention.
Now the way that they do their animation is actually partnered with a Taiwanese firm to make these and
you know they have a lot of audience so I think the Taiwanese firm gives them a pretty good deal on
making these for each one.
However you know you're only making a couple of videos it's actually pretty easy to go on fire and say
hey I want to make a video that looks an animation that looks like this.
There's a bunch of people sitting around a table and in one of them laughs and the other one slaps someone.
It's not super expensive.
However if you get to make hundreds of videos then well and yeah that might get pretty price.
So it all sounds great you might say but I'm just getting started with the editing.
I don't know how animation even works yet.
How can I get animated titles and characters added to my videos.
Well I can give you a couple of oftens that you can use on your own to create some animated sequences.
Number one is check out power tuner and a moto if you get a power tune for example.
They've got templates and ideas you can use to start creating animated sequences of your own.
It's really just like a software where they set it up to make it brainless and non-technical or you
just grab animations or images and illustration and throw it on canvas and then you just set it up to
make them move in a certain way probably can learn how to use it in a couple of hours just like Crash
Course you might be thinking about emphasizing points and specific part of your script or maybe you
want to create an animated sequence to act out a story like you're telling.
So try two or and a moto there just softwares that allow you to imitate and quickly make a lot of these
animations.
And also if you don't want to do these you actually pay someone else to use in a moto.
And if you do that well that's really cheap.
Maybe if you already know you want animated titles and sequences as part of your video you have written
it into your script already by knowing what you need.
Earlier on in the process you'll know what skills you need to hire for when you look for a video editor
or some other freelancer.
If they can do all the things you need then you only need to hire one person instead of many.
So that's what I wanted to cover about Crash Course and their editing style.
They've got a pretty slick way of turning one camera shot into mini.
By using a crop or scale effect really quite easy to do.
It's a great option for editing when you don't have alternate angles or multiple cameras.
Are Of course these animations to inject some more visual flair are all the titles little characters
and full screen sequences.
Look for parts of your script that you want to emphasize what you really need the attention of your
viewer.
Or maybe you're hitting on a pretty well-known quote.
Those parts could be good candidates for these types of editing techniques.
So take a second watch on their videos if you want or 10.
Sometimes I go down the rabbit hole because they're pretty good and see if there's anything else you
can pick up on.
They have a lot of goofy high jinks of repeatable gags and inside jokes that are actually pretty good.
All right guys.
Anyway I'll see you in the next video.