All right guys welcome back to the course.
Our last lecture me got all set up in Facebook's ad manager.
So now we can get to the fun part of actually creating a campaign.
That's what I'm going to walk through in this lecture.
So we want to head back to the ads manager go to business dot Facebook dot com then click on the hamburger
menu in the upper left.
Yeah it's actually called a hamburger menu.
Now mouse over all tools and under the Create plus manage section.
You should see Button says ads manager.
Now if you haven't created an ad or a campaign before Facebook might drop you right into the new campaign
creation page you'll know that because it's a campaign choose your objective.
If you're following along and you're not on this page then you're probably on the ads manager dashboard
where you can see four times shown horizontally account overview campaigns ad sets and ads.
That's perfectly fine.
Facebook likes to cut to the chase sometimes and gets you into that ad creation screen sooner so that's
fine let's just go up to the green button in the upper right that says Create and and then click that.
Now everyone should be on the same page and you can actually see the steps for setting up a campaign
on the left.
Now you'll see this structured campaign ad account ad set and an ad campaign is where we're going to
tell Facebook what our goal is for the campaign.
But choosing a specific goal Facebook will give us customized options.
For example if you want to drive traffic to our website the last time you are out.
But if we want to generate more likes of our Facebook page for instance then they'll give us different
fields to fill that out out a cow is our business the info where we tell Facebook which account this
is for now you shouldn't actually have to touch any of that.
And that is where we define our audience for this.
And by selecting all kinds of different attributes based on all that juicy Facebook data we also choose
some of the settings for the campaign including how much will spend and how long we want to run it for
now it is where we create our ads and figure out where they're going to go.
But each of these steps has different choices.
Kind of like a Choose Your Own Adventure book that all hinges on which campaign objective you choose.
So let's start there.
Now you'll see a group of 10 or so objectives to choose from.
They're listed under three different types awareness consideration and conversion.
These might sound familiar because they're the three stages of what's called the customer journey awareness
objectives are focused on introducing yourself to a new audience.
Getting on the map so to speak.
Consideration objectives can help customers learn more as they're weighing options for a purchase for
instance.
And then lastly conversion objectives match up with the with customer decisions like when sales are
made.
If you click on each of the 10 objectives you'll see the information on the left and below the changes.
You choose brand awareness while you simply give your campaign a name and then you just begin.
You choose traffic then you'll have the option of doing a split test.
And if you choose engagement Well you actually choose another option of what kind of content you want
to get engagement for.
So could be post pages or events.
For example I want to create here my goal is to drive traffic to my website.
I've got a service on trying to form and I want people to learn about it.
I'll create a landing page and drive people to that specifically.
So if that's my goal I'm going to pick traffic.
But since we're doing this for the first time let's just add another wrinkle to it.
Let's just do a split test.
This way we can test out our first efforts here with two versions of the same at so check off the split
test box and go down and then name this thing.
Call it whatever you want and click the set up an count below that we probably want to do a split test
upfront because chances are this is the first ad you've written for Facebook for your product and chances
are you're not going to get the best ad on the first attempt.
Usually you come up with two ideas and it really can make a big difference when you're testing and you
least do one other version.
Now this you really just need to confirm the settings you see are correct.
Got the account country currency time zone.
That's obviously all be correct.
You shouldn't have to touch anything.
And also just continue what comes next is the asset which I'll leave for the next lecture because it
includes setting up your audience.
Now that will be a cool part I promise.
But it might take a little bit of time.
So let's break and we'll just come back together in the next lecture.
See you later.