OK guys welcome back to the cause.
Now we're in the homestretch here a video marketing and we've spent all this time talking about making
videos editing them.
Eventually you'll have some great videos ready for people to see and then what.
Well that's what this lecture is going to be all about.
It's about integrating your videos into your marketing plans.
There's a couple of important questions you'd answer when it comes to your videos.
Number one where are you going to host them.
The video files you export from premiere or whatever program you use need to go somewhere right.
We talked about YouTube way back in the preproduction section of US course.
And yeah that is an option.
You to use things like wisteria or quick sprout or actually you can host them on your own server.
However we're not going to get into that.
We'll talk a little bit more in detail about the first couple options here in this lecture and then
number two where will you be using these videos.
Now you've got your videos done.
This means you can start adding them to Web site pages social media blog post landing pages all kinds
of places.
Well I've got some recommendations on how to add your videos so they have a better chance of being found
by search engines.
And to help you accomplish whatever goals you've set for yourself.
So first things first.
Let's talk about video hosting.
Now once your video files get exported from your editing program they need to get posted somewhere and
really there are two ways to go about it.
Free and paid free solutions include places like YouTube and Vimeo and really that's about it.
With regards of these two you might choose Vimeo because their player looks a lot nicer it looks pretty
classy if you're trying to make a video that looks fancy or looks hip or you might use YouTube.
Because while Youtube is owned by Google and you better believe that Google is pretty biased towards
youtube search results YouTube really has no limits on how much video you can upload to them.
They don't track how much bandwidth you're using.
If you put it on YouTube you can get these videos can get seen throughout their community but then you
can also embed them wherever you want.
I think between the two I usually would go with YouTube.
So as far as the free hosting platforms go there are generally pluses and minuses both Vimeo and YouTube
are community.
So if you post something on there then oftentimes it's gonna be seen by people in their community.
They can be a plus or a minus.
And a lot of situations where people might say find your video on YouTube.
Well it creates kind of a barrier between your YouTube video and where you want them to go which is
your Web site.
So a lot of times you really have to make your videos specifically for the YouTube audience and in a
specific way to get them to go from there to the page that you want.
So usually those two options are fine unless for some reason you have some concerns about it being opened
up to large communities or if you don't like the video player or something like that or maybe you don't
even like the analytics that you get from the free versions if that's the case well then you have paid
options.
Now we briefly discussed these back.
I don't care what lecture I think when we're talking about YouTube or I mentioned places like Whist
Yeah video card sprout video and I think one other one.
Anyway these paid video hosting services offer some pretty nice features.
They provide a reliable hosting for your videos and can offer better performance than YouTube.
Each service has its own unique features as well.
Did your ad has some nice features if you doing interesting thing in live streams.
The Tsar often offers bulk video uploads which yes supports things like 360 video and also allows you
to customize their video player if that's something you need.
But the three most important features with these third party hosts in my opinion are under the number
one is the ability to ad calls and actions and forms right inside your video.
You don't do that with YouTube and Vimeo but usually those clicks lead them back to YouTube and then
you need to direct them to another place.
Also YouTube kind of limits what kind of calls actions and cards as they call them you can put in them
whereas whiskey like sprout video there's a lot more you can do.
Number two is you have access to a much wider range of expanded analytics about the performance of your
videos.
And then number three you have more advanced ways to embed the videos on your own site.
So about those called actions you're talking about.
Now remember the goals you want accomplish with these videos.
Did you want to generate leads or sign ups for something.
If so then the ability to add a sign up form right at the end of your video saves you a bunch of steps
and it removes a lot of friction for your user rather than ask them to go somewhere else or to look
around the page for the form you're talking about.
It's right there you can put the form at the beginning and require an e-mail to watch the video.
I think it's kind of a dick move or you put it in the middle.
The promise of more or input at the end knowing that the person that makes it the end is probably a
satisfied viewer.
So let's call that action in your video are a nice feature the analytics you can get from these third
party hosts can be pretty insightful as well.
Some of them offer visuals where you can see how long people watched a video and where people dropped
off by looking at it.
You can see which parts of your video interest them and which ones don't.
Now YouTube and Vimeo have these basic analytics but they just don't go into as much detail as for instance
wisteria or sprout video.
Now some of these paid hosting services will also offer integrations with Google analytics so that way
you can actually see all of your information on one place.
That's actually pretty helpful especially if you have a page that's Google Analytics stats and has a
video in it.
And then you have to go to waste.
You have to look at your stats for that specific and then like have two tabs open but the other important
feature that all of these other paid hosts are really helpful with is making sure your videos work where
you want them to.
And this is the next thing you have to think about where will these videos go once they're hosted.
I mean what pages or platforms do you put them on while sharing on social is pretty straightforward.
You just go to Facebook and upload the video and then hit post or Twitter you go to tweet at it post
putting videos on your actual custom Web site requires an understanding of embedding.
Now if you want to embed videos on your site basically you need to add some code from a third party
host that allows this video to show up.
Now don't freak out because I said code well this is probably the easiest thing you could ever do with
code.
It's also important for the video to appear in a way that match the design experience of your site.
Thus third party hosts are pretty helpful usually with these paid hosts you can customize the look of
your video player you can change the border the color make your own custom thumbnails things like that
if you put a youtube video I mean you could almost always spot a YouTube video being embedded in someone's
site and it's largely what YouTube wants.
They want you to constantly be reminded of their platform.
Now in the case of almost all of these they'll just give you the code and it's usually just an embed
button somewhere in their analytics platform and it's just something you copy and paste.
But for example you can have a video appear right on the page or in line or you could have the video
up here above the page in its own window or what some people call pop over.
So while embedding is pretty straightforward there's a lot of options you can actually try when you
embed a video on your site.
Ideally you'd like search engines to be able to see it and drive people to your site.
However this is where embedding from YouTube might become a problem when Google sees a YouTube video
embedded on your site.
It basically gives the NCO value back to the youtube page with a video lives.
Now that doesn't do you any favors when you're trying to drive traffic to your site and get people to
buy stuff in a lot of cases will end up happening is since YouTube has a higher page rank in your SCA.
We have got to go yet but just listen.
What will happen is you'll search for something and the YouTube version of your video will outrank your
page that has your YouTube video embedded in it.
So in that case many third party hosts use code to ensure that the page you embed a video on gets all
of the SVOD benefits and not being directed back to say like a VCR.
They might also help you create a video site map.
You can add to your site so search engines know about all the video content you have to offer much faster.
So review your goals and figure out what's important to you.
Video Views and shares well maybe YouTube is probably your best bet because hosting on there also gives
you access to their community.
And since Google favors YouTube well you'll get that YouTube link much much higher up.
But if you trying to drive traffic to your site.
Well then probably I paid third party video host is gonna be better.
Or maybe you want people to sign up for newsletters or buy things based on your videos.
Well I'd absolutely push for a paid solution in those cases.
You could really have a lot more flexibility with the call to action.
Now compare the hosts out there and find the one that makes most sense for you.
OK that's it for this luxury.
We've got more to go.
See you then.