Hello.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting Tools of the Trade in the course,
The Technical Business Analyst.
Here's a great quote.
"A good tool improves the way you work.
A great tool improves the way you think.
" I really like this quote.
I think analysis tools should improve the way you work,
but more importantly the way you think.
Just the act and process of using a tool can elicit so many new questions,
leading to new insights, or lead to even cooler ideas and innovations.
Now when I use the word tool, it is more than just a hammer.
A tool can be a process, a methodology or a way in which to go about your work,
or maybe a combination of all those.
So please keep that in mind in this module.
Eighty-nine percent of analysts use visual diagramming techniques,
and I bet this percent is growing.
I strongly recommend that for any tools you use,
either automated or manual, reports, spreadsheets or whatever,
you be as visual as possible.
Visual depictions greatly enhance understanding and comprehension
and the ability to communicate with your business and technical
teams more rapidly and with greater quality.
If you have the opportunity to actually pick the tools you can use,
please keep in mind,
those with visual interfaces or expressions of information will
likely be the most productive and revealing.
Here's the overview of this module.
First, we will start with a technical BA's skill areas.
We touched on these in the module The Technical Business Analyst,
and in this module, I'll be going into more detail with each one.
I made the point as well in that module that knowledge and skills
in these areas will also greatly help you bridge the gap between
the business and the technical teams.
Most of this module will be covering those tools.
At the end of the module, I will cover the technical BA's basic tools.
We don't want to lose sight of the basic tools all analysts use every day, technical or otherwise.