User interface and user experience design.
Do you know the difference?
Intrigued?
Well, let's explore further.
Now let's define user interface and user experience.
Something that looks great,
but is difficult to use is an example of a great user
interface and a poor user experience,
while something very usable that looks terrible is an
example of a great user experience, but a poor user interface.
So what is UI/UX design?
UI design stands for user interface design.
UX design stands for user experience design.
Both elements are fundamental to a system's design, and they work hand in hand.
UI design is closer to what we refer to as graphic design,
though the responsibilities are somewhat more complex,
where UX design is a more analytical and technical design.
Here's an example, skin versus mind and heart.
If you envision a product as the human body,
the bones signify the code which gives it structure.
The organs signify the UX design's supporting life functions.
And UI design represents the skin, the clothes,
the exterior presentation of the body.
Now everyone has heard of looks are only skin deep,
so in essence,
the UX design is much more important and critical
to a system than the UI design.
So here's a tip.
A great product outcome begins with designing the user experience,
and then it's followed by the user interface design.
Hence, ease of use has a greater emphasis.
Why use UI/UX design tools in the first place?
Well, they help elicit requirements and people can relate to visual artifacts,
such as screen or page layouts, rather than words on paper.
Help users know what they want, sort of.
UI/UX design is not the end all, but greatly helps you get there.
Usually UI/UX design artifacts are a major portion of the prototype outputs.
We will talk more about prototyping later in this module.
Since systems are really just a bunch of 1s and 0s,
product owners and customers love to see visual samples of what they might get.
UI/UX design is a process of visually guiding the user
through incremental and iterative experiences,
arriving at the worthiest design.
When to use UI/UX tools.
Whenever there is a visual or experience requirement, anywhere and anytime.
Usually this means web pages, desktop applications,
phone applications, numerical control applications.
So anything that a human will visually see and experience to get their job done.
Need I say more?
So you must always have some tools in your toolbelt to
perform UI and UX design experiences.
Here are some example of some UI/UX tools you may want to consider.
Whiteboard.
Yes, it's old school,
but it's quick and easy and can get the basic UI/UX roughly
laid out for those ad hoc discussions.
Visio, or tools like it, allow easy workflow and screen mockups.
PowerPoint, again, quick and easy, low cost,
everyone typically has all these tools at their
disposal with no extra expenditures.
Now, here's a starting point of some of the more popular tools to check out.
But tools are constantly changing, so do some research online as well.
As you can see, InVision, Adobe, Origami,
Sketch, Axure, Webflow, Framer, Atomic, Principle,
Justinmind, Balsamiq Mockups, just to name a few.
This is just a representative list to get you started in the right direction.
Ultimately,
it all comes down to choosing the one or two that works best
for you and it's affordable for your company.
So you can get a quick visualization of what I'm talking about,
here's a screen mockup built in Balsamiq.
This and other tools do far more than just lay out a screen.
Check out the website of the tools I listed to get a good sense of their power and benefits.