Now, here are a few ideas regarding certification and training.
IIBA, the International Institute of Business Analysis,
has a few certifications that might interest you: Entry
Certificate in Business Analysis,
ECBA; Certification of Competency in Business Analysis,
CCBA; Certified Business Analyst Professional,
CBAP; and Agile Analysis Certification, AAC.
Also,
IQBBA has a Certified Foundation Level Analyst Certification; IREB has
Certified Professional for Requirements Engineering; and the PMI,
Professional in Business Analysis, PBA.
Now,
all of these are more generic analyst certifications and are
not just targeted for the technical BA.
Unlike certifications, which are designed to prove the skills you already have,
bootcamps are designed to teach you new skills or improve your current skillset.
Bootcamps can be anything from traditional workshops held over
the course of a few days or full-fledged,
instructor-led courses that run much longer. Here are a few bootcamps for business analysts for your future reference.