Let's discuss the good traits of a user story.
These are known as INVEST,
since each of the words I will discuss spell out the word invest.
Independent.
Now, independence means that a story can be coded,
tested, and even delivered all on its own.
That is, it is not waiting for another story to be completed.
And what also makes independence important is that
it can be independently valued.
Negotiable.
A user story is a placeholder for requirements to be discussed
and potentially accepted for development.
In the traditional waterfall approach,
requirements were basically contracted to implement.
So a process of negotiation is conducted between the
product owner and the development team.
And very important here,
each respects and jointly collaborates to arrive at
the best approach and solution,
aware of each other's potential limitations and strengths.
Valuable.
The full team's most important goal is to deliver the most value
given their available resources and time certainly.
Therefore, I will suggest to you that is one of the most important INVEST traits.
Remember, the backlog is prioritized by value and value alone,
hence the importance of this trait.
Estimable, a good and well-written and discussed user story is estimable.
Backlog items can be any size really.
But let's face it,
more decompose user stories are much more likely to be
estimated with more accuracy in the event that you are facing a
challenge of coming up with an estimate,
then it may be likely that you need to decompose or break
down the user story into smaller stories.
Small.
So how big is small?
Well, small.
That is a user story you can finish in one iteration.
Most iterations that I have observed are two to three weeks.
That gives you an order of magnitude from the lapsed time perspective.
Smaller stories in your sprints are more likely to come out faster.
Testable.
In the agile world, all code is tested code.
But if you think that the user story cannot be
tested in the sprint or iteration,
then it is quite likely that the story is not well-written,
or maybe linked to other user stories, or just too complex.
Vague and fuzzy words in user stories will usually come to
light when discussing if something is testable.
Okay,
don't worry if not all six attributes apply to every one of your user stories.
This is a guideline,
so use the INVEST convention as a checklist against every
user story you write and it will greatly improve your
team's ability to write them.
Now, better stories result in better outcomes,
yielding value to the business much quicker.
SMART, like INVEST,
is a checklist of traits or characteristics to follow
and order the right quality tasks.
SMART is not for user stories,
but for the technical tasks required to develop and complete a user story.
These are written by the dev team and not by the technical BA normally.
But for completeness, I felt it is important to include these.
Please note the sample task at the bottom of the slide.
Okay, the first is for S, specific.
A task needs to be specific enough so that everyone can understand it.
It helps to keep other tasks from overlapping and also helps people to
understand either the tasks add up to the full story or not.
In this example it seems quite specific enough, so check.
The next is M for measurable.
The key of measure is can we mark it as done?
The development team needs to agree on what that means,
but it should also include what is it intended to do,
are tests included, is the code refactored,
and things like that.
So in this example, it seems specific enough, so check.
A for achievable.
The task owner must be able to achieve, that is complete the task.
It may be achievable, but is it achievable within the time box of the sprint?
If so, check, if not hmm,
maybe then it's possible to decompose into more subtasks.
Next, R for relevant.
Every task must be relevant and contribute directly to the story.
User stories are broken into tasks for the developer's benefit certainly,
but the product owner should still be able to presume that
each task can be justified and explained.
Once again, check.
Next, T for time-boxed.
A task should be limited to a specific duration, and usually in hours.
This doesn't need to be a formal estimate in hours or days,
but there must be an expectation, so people know when they should seek help.
If a task is harder than the expectation,
then the team needs to split the task, change players,
or do something to help the task, and therefore the story,
get done.
Also,
in any part of your technical BA job if you are enumerating the list of tasks,
well, why not follow this model?
It can be applied on more than just tasks for user stories.
If you'd like to know more about the SMART characteristics, check out the writings by Bill Wakes.