You may not be able to ever completely close the gap.
That's a natural circumstance of any organization.
But you can certainly narrow the gap.
Let's see how.
I strongly recommend that you need three key skill areas and
expertise to becoming the most successful at bridging the gap
as a technical business analyst.
The first, leadership and communication skills.
Next, business knowledge and alignment.
And lastly, the technical business analyst skillset.
Now let's touch on each one of those.
Remember we defined bridging the gap as creating a connection
between two disconnected or disparate things.
How do you think you create that connection?
Well, not just with 1s and 0s.
Before I go over this list,
I want you to think about each item and rate yourself on each item,
say 1, for not that much, 2 medium, and three for,
well, pretty good.
For those items you rate low,
that only means that that's an area to think about and improve on.
Okay, for the first one, embrace and champion change.
Leaders drive change and are change agents.
Do you like change?
Change is typically not a natural attribute of most people.
Earn credibility across an organization.
In order for you to be successful, work hard to earn credibility.
That is, you are honest, have integrity,
and always follow through with what you say and do.
This will enable you to be more productive in your organization and
enable broader career opportunities within your company.
Ability to build trust.
This is a critical leadership quality that you must master.
Strong negotiation skills.
Most business interactions entail discussions in arriving at consensus.
Therefore,
you must have the ability to communicate clearly and effectively to others
during the discussions and negotiations as a technical BA.
Strategic planning skills.
This is important as people want to know where are we
going and how are we going to get there?
Project and team management skills.
Yes, leadership is paramount and essential,
but you will still need basic and practical project and team management
skills in performing your duties as a technical BA.
Strong communications and marketing skills.
Certainly verbal and written skills are essential,
but what I mean by marketing is that you will need to ensure that the
business and IT know what you are doing clearly and succinctly,
and this typically means getting out PowerPoint and putting together
regular presentations to communicate effectively.
This will result in you receiving better projects to work on,
maybe even more resources, and better career opportunities.
Strong interpersonal skills.
You want coworkers to feel that they can approach you,
talk to you, and share important information.
The use of these skills with your business and technical IT teams will
greatly enhance your ability to bridge the gap by helping you elicit
and capture business requirements and then bring forward and
communicate those requirements to IT.
Required business knowledge and alignment.
Aligning the IT outcomes to the business.
It's the activities of formulating, integrating,
and implementing decisions between the business and IT.
You will need to rely on your soft skills heavily such as speaking,
writing, presenting, and leadership that we talked about in the previous slide.
Working on the right priorities.
You want to ensure that IT is staying the course,
working on the right work at the right time and not chasing the shiniest,
new object.
Using IT to achieve business objectives.
It is when a business organization is able to use information
technology effectively to achieve its business objectives.
That is your job.
Resulting in improved business outcomes such as improved financial performance,
better products and services or marketplace competitiveness.
The bottom line is the ability of IT to produce business value.
Do not forget that.
Your value to the organization will be measured by
your capabilities to do just that.
The technical business analyst skillset.
Remember all those technical skills we discussed in the last module?
Well collectively, their use will help you bridge the gap.
They are user interface and user experience,
prototyping, data modeling, business data analytics,
interface analysis, quality assurance test plan and test cases,
off-the-shelf solutions, cloud services,
and other building blocks.
Again, I won't go into all the detail because we already did that before,
as well as, in the modules, Tools of the Trade,
I will drill into each one of these in detail.
Here is what I found to be a secret weapon to my success.
By becoming a trusted advisor, you will be more successful at bridging the gap.
Here are a few guidelines to think about so you can plan and implement
building trust with your business and IT colleagues.
As you begin each engagement or encounter with your customers and IT,
have clear and consistent goals.
Always know where you are going, the big vision,
the projects, and the daily tasks.
This will help your coworkers have a better understanding of what you are
proposing or aiming for and what the end game may look like and how the teams
will know when they arrive at a conclusion or a solution.
Be open and listen.
This builds trust and shows compassion.
Your business and IT coworkers will come to believe that they are
understood and feel they are being listened to.
Not only is this respectful in all encounters,
you will actually get more honest input to do your job better.
Be decisive.
Wishy-washy is a weak quality in your position.
Would you want to see the CEO of your company in a various situation say,
gee, I don't know what we should do?
This does not mean that you will have all the answers,
but it does mean if you don't know something,
you will take action to find out.
The world and you are not perfect, so admit mistakes.
This shows that you are human, and even if it's not you,
per se,
who made the mistake take one on the chin and show that you're responsible.
This will also build trust.
Respect the opinions of others, always listen.
Now, it does not mean you have to agree,
but you do have to listen,
then be decisive and make appropriate recommendations or
decisions and explain your reasons.
Manage expectations.
This is a biggie to me.
You will likely spend more time managing the business
side than the IT side of the house.
Every single customer interaction is an opportunity to
manage expectations such as meetings, emails,
phone calls, status reports, presentations,
and more.
Never pass up this opportunity to further connect and
communicate with your business customers.
Now, you can't just be robotic and stiff to go through this checklist. You need to be sincere and it should come naturally.