What I mean by the missing piece is that the technical BA is a role that
must be both business oriented and technically oriented.
Very challenging, indeed.
So the technical business analyst is the professional who is
generally associated with the following: Business requirements
gathering and analysis on IT projects,
using more complex technical processes and tools,
and solving problems with technical solutions.
One of those problems may be, as examples,
Software as a Service, SaaS,
which a third-party provider hosts applications on the internet,
such as Salesforce, for example, plus thousands more.
Infrastructure as a Service, IaaS, and Platform as a Service,
PaaS, are also key cloud computing, off-the-shelf offerings.
Custom development.
The technical business analyst needs to understand the custom
development processes and common tools used today.
This includes the lifecycle models of waterfall and agile,
plus the accompanying technical tools to support the processes.
And, complex integrations.
So much work today is all about integrating systems.
About every service and product has APIs,
known as Application Programmer Interfaces,
which allows access to the features or data of an application or
other service to be easily accessible and shareable.
For example, when you post to LinkedIn, you could also have it push to Twitter.
In this case, LinkedIn is leveraging Twitter's APIs to do this.
Next,
collaborating with information technology experts in
determining the desired solutions,
so working with your IT professionals in your company,
or consultants, or other IT vendors is a common daily activity.
This is a crucial role in the bridge between business and IT.
I will get into more detail in the technical skills needed by the
technical business analyst later in this module.
A Day in the Life of a Technical Business Analyst slide is a broad view of
what a typical day may look like for a technical BA.
Organizationally positioned in IT or PMO.
They are usually not employed in the business side of the organization,
but instead in the IT department.
If the organization has a PMO, a project management office,
they may be staffed there as well.
By the way, a PMO is charted with selecting and executing IT projects,
hence the technical BA will work on both the selection
and execution aspects of the project, if connected or positioned in the PMO.
From the business side, they are the ones eliciting broader,
mode complex requirements from stakeholders and analyzing those requirements,
then documenting those requirements,
likely using more complex requirements management tools.
These documents are known as business requirements documents,
or BRDs, from which they will create functional specifications,
also known as FRDs, functional requirements documents.
These documents contain the application's functional requirements,
they define things such as data models, data manipulation,
processing, workflows, screen layouts,
user interface and interaction with the application.
These are technical documents.
Lastly, the technical BA interacts directly with the technical teams,
such as developers, creatives, architects,
data engineers,
and quality assurance professionals to ensure they understand the requirements,
answer questions, take issues back to the business,
and ensure that the technical implementations ultimately meet the
business requirements and objectives of the project.
Since the technical BA typically has a role squarely in
the IT organization of a company, they need to know a few more things.
This first list is centered more around process.
They must have a good understanding and appreciation of the
myriad of processes around software development.
Gathering and managing requirements,
this skill should be second nature and leverage best tools to capture,
track, and manage those requirements.
Understanding and use of waterfall.
With the waterfall project development approach,
a technical BA working in a classic development environment
is more heavily involved at the beginning,
gathering, analyzing, and prioritizing these requirements,
and later in the project lifecycle,
handing those off to developers and then moving on to
another software development project.
Understanding the use of agile.
Agile has changed the timing of the BA's involvement
with the given development project.
With agile, they are involved throughout the entire agile project lifecycle.
I like this much better.
So they generally stay with the project through multiple
releases to a project's completion,
designing and planning test plans and test cases.
This is a likely role as well since you will be intimately
involved in the requirements side of the house,
you will know exactly what to expect from the system,
as well as have a relationship with the business side.
Now this makes you a great candidate to design and plan the system's testing.
And again, these are centered more around process,
whereas this list is focused more on technology.
Technology stacks is a list of all the technology services
used to build and run one single application.
The social site Facebook, for example,
is composed of a combination of coding frameworks and languages,
including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, and React JS,
plus many others.
All these make up the stack.
DevOps.
Now, DevOps is a combination of cultural philosophies,
practices,
and tools that increases an organization's ability to deliver
applications and services at a high velocity.
Sometimes we refer to this process as Continuous Integration.
You should be aware of this process and how it can affect delivering software.
Now there are many Continuous Integration tools such as Bamboo, for example.
Skilled at software testing.
Software testing is a process to evaluate the functionality of a
software application with the intent to find whether the developed
software met the requirements or not and to identify any defects to
ensure that the product is defect-free.
This will potentially include automated testing tools
such as Selenium and Katalon Studio, for example.
Experiencing appreciation for managing user acceptance.
User acceptance testing, UAT,
is typically the last phase of a software testing process.
During UAT,
the users test a software to make sure it can handle the required tasks in
a real-world scenario according to the specifications.
You should be involved in that process as well.
Awareness of system usage trends.
Well, after all that hard work, is the software being used?
How is it being used?
Is it really helping the business?
Will the company achieve a return on investment?
You should be prepared to answer those questions,
and especially the ROI, or the return on investment,
is it substantiated?
I would like to make a key point.
Organizations that recognize the importance of the critical
contributions technical business analysts provide will flourish.
The bottom line is that the goal or outcome of business analysts conducted by
technical business analysts is to ensure that the growth of the organization is
in alignment with the goals and objectives set by its management and is focused
on improving an organization's long-term success by selecting and implementing the appropriate technologies.