Unquestionably, technical BAs add value to the agile dev team.
Position the technical BA as close to the end product as possible.
You would like a BA to be responsible for delivering a
working product and that they directly work on validation
and implementation of the product.
Since the technical BA is deeply involved with the product owner
or customers and developing the user stories,
it enables the dev team to quickly get answers or details without
having to circle back to the product owner.
Plus,
the team can adjust rapidly if some ideas do not work since the
technical BA is embedded in the dev team.
This saves time, not just the dev team's time,
but the very busy product owner's time as well.
Therefore,
you would like to have a technical BA as one of the development team
members just like a developer or quality analysts are too.
Now,
the technical BA can use his or her expertise and domain knowledge
to optimize the product development process,
keeping focused on the end result.
The techies on the team are great, of course.
But I have seen where they can get carried away with the
technology and may lose sight of the end result.
The technical BA is there to provide the continued focus.
Lastly, the technical BA adds an organizational or political overlay on the team,
which can be beneficial on how best to handle troubling
team or departmental productivity issues.
So if you want to optimize for speed, agility,
and learning,
it is probably better to have a technical BA be part of your agile team.
Here are a few more examples of how technical BAs
add value to the development team.
Remember the technical BA's skill areas from the previous module?
Well, they all apply here.
User interface and user experience, prototyping,
data modeling, business data analytics, interface analysis,
quality assurance and testing, off-the-shelf solutions and building blocks.
Lastly,
the technical BA focuses on ensuring that real business value is identified
and revealed by working closely with the product owner.
And then, helping to convey the requirements,
priorities, and business value to the agile team to make their work easier,
more productive, and more enjoyable.
As a technical BA,
be aware of your organizational surroundings and what
I'm calling organizational awareness.
Typically, management is matrixed.
That is where the members of the agile/Scrum team is a collection of people,
generally self-directed, but still report to managers.
In fact, everyone on the team may report to different managers,
therefore their points of view of agile,
Scrum, and technology may flow from different organizational biases.
Each of their managers will have different viewpoints about agile,
some good, and maybe some not so good.
These managers at times may push for their own deadlines,
which would usurp the agile process flows.
By the way,
this includes the manager of the product owner who might
apply the greatest pressure on the team.
Be prepared to deal with those challenges.
Lastly, executives and senior leaders,
they are the most removed from the action and will be
more inclined to see schedules, milestones,
and the supporting financials.
This is where you come in.
As the technical BA,
you not only have the knowledge and appreciation of the project itself,
but will be the best candidate to relate and report this type of
information to the executives and managers.
Consider partnering up with the product owner as well,
since they will have a direct connection to the business.
And, of course,
partner with the management of the agile IT team members to educate
them that there is more to life than just agile.
Hence, be aware of the organizational issues,
personalities, politics, broader budgets,
and things like that, since it may be you,
the technical BA,
who's the most qualified to bridge the gap between the business
and possibly a new way of developing software,
which may be quite different from the traditional way senior leaders are used to doing business.