Now let's look at the level of technical skills
required to be a successful technical BA.
While the knowledge of IT is not a prerequisite for
all business analyst positions,
sufficient understanding of the latest technology trends
would definitely add value to the technical business analyst
capabilities and contributions.
Therefore, what level of IT knowledge is enough?
Or, how technical should a technical BA be?
Well, it depends.
You were probably hoping I had the perfect answer for the $100,
000 question, but I don't.
It truly depends.
You just need to be technical enough to bridge the gap.
And every gap is different,
and every company based on the abilities of the business
side and the technical side as well.
For example, the pure business analyst, that is a non-technical analyst,
talking to a highly technical developer may have
many challenges in communicating.
That might be too big a communications gap to cross effectively.
Know the basics of IT.
You don't have to know enough to do what the developers do,
of course,
but enough to understand what they do and to be able to impart
empathy in order to better bridge the gap.
The technical business analyst is a key role that can facilitate and optimize
the system design process by simplifying the work of designers and system
implementers further down the development process through the identification
of quality requirements which are correct,
complete, and doable; therefore, by applying and leveraging technical tools,
you'll be able to better convey business requirements
and features clearly and succinctly,
and hence the IT team will be more able to comprehend and develop
technical solutions more quickly and with better quality.
Now let's talk about the technical skill areas you need to master.
Here are the technical BA skill areas where you can best focus your energies.
Design the user interface and user experience.
You know the requirements and the users very well,
so you can provide valuable insights here by utilizing the tools,
develop the user interface, and user experience mockups.
The method or technique known as prototyping is used to elicit and
validate stakeholders or user's requirements.
Again, you can apply some great tools to reform this function as well.
Data modeling.
Today, data is everywhere, and you better know where it is and how to get to it,
and how to reshape or model it to meet the customer's requirements.
Business data analytics is the skill of analyzing raw data in
order to make decisions about that information.
This would include things like data mining, SQL, S-Q-L, and visualization.
Here's a couple more to focus your time on.
Interface analysis is a connection between two entities,
people, systems, applications, etc.
No person, system or application is an island.
Everything is connecting to everything.
Quality assurance, test plan, and test cases.
Since you understand the requirements,
you're well positioned to write the test cases and the test plans,
very important.
Off-the-shelf solutions, cloud services and other building blocks.
Not every problem should be solved by custom solutions.
If you can find the perfect off-the-shelf prebuilt solution, well, use it.
Typically though,
you may need to integrate a couple of off-the-shelf
solutions to meet your requirements.
Where you should likely not venture is deciding which program languages,
frameworks or technology stacks to use,
let the application developers and architects do that.
Now,
knowledge and skills in these areas will greatly help you bridge the
gap between the business and the technology teams.
Now,
we will get into much more detail in all these areas
in the module Tools of the Trade.
Here's my point of view.
Varied opinions exist on why and to what extent
business analysts should be technical.
There is much discourse on this topic.
In my opinion,
it is the confluence of the business analyst role and the systems
analyst role that were more typical many years ago.
Since organizations are much leaner today,
it seems that these two roles may have merged into one role or one person.
First and foremost,
technical BAs need to be a very strong business analyst in my view,
period.
Over time,
continue to improve your technical capabilities in order to enhance
your communication with IT and provide the added value to the
solutions designed and to the business.
If a technical analyst is too technical,
they may focus on the solution at the expense of the requirements.
I think this is a recipe for failure, so be careful about this.
The right amount of technical knowledge and understanding ensures that
unrealistic requirements can be discussed with the stakeholders much
earlier in the requirements gathering process.
This is not to say that the stakeholder's business ideas are wrong,
it will just place them in the right context for
developing priorities and budgets.
What is the right amount of technology to know?
I hope and trust this course will help guide you,
but you will likely have to figure it out based on the type of
organization you are in and the various skill levels of your teammates
and who you are and what you are capable of.
You still need quality business requirements.
No matter how great or cool the technology,
without high-quality business requirements that align to the
business and meet the needs of the stakeholders,
technology, well, to me, can be irrelevant.
Lastly, if you do in fact love development languages and tech stacks,
and the like,
then extend your career path by transitioning from a technical
business analyst to a developer or software engineer.
People with a technical BA background would make a
superb developer in my opinion. So, go for it!