Here is my point of view.
Now those technologies on the previous slide are hot now,
and may remain so for a while, but this list will continually evolve,
so I recommend staying abreast of the latest technology trends.
With the internet you can learn a lot about what's hot
and what's not very hot very quickly.
Learn new technology capabilities.
You can take a few Pluralsight courses and get a deeper understanding of
those technologies and how they may help the business.
Involve and seek support from IT.
So run your technology ideas past your IT team to see what
they think of it and how it might work.
With those ideas and technologies and opportunities,
be proactive and present to the business with business cases
and how your technical recommendations are in alignment with
the organization's business goals.
Don't ever forget that.
Just because a new technology is trending,
it doesn't mean to go out and deploy it,
but it may mean to read about it, understand the business implications,
maybe develop a proof of concept with your IT colleagues,
and then present your ideas and recommendations to management.
Okay, let's summarize this module.
We learned that the role of a technical BA is to serve as or
create a connection between the business and IT.
Therefore,
the key job of the technical BA is to ensure the technology
successfully meets the business needs.
We discussed that all business activities can fall into one of three categories,
operations, projects, and initiatives, and in each of these categories,
the gap is different.
We learned that the level of effort to bridge the gap is smaller in operations,
about medium with projects, and quite large with initiatives.
We also learned that the business and technical
knowledge required is smaller in operations,
about medium with projects, and quite large again with initiatives.
We discussed the required skills to bridge the gap,
which are leadership and communication, which is critical to your success,
ensuring that you are always aligning the IT outcomes to the business,
and that you have a good grasp on the tool areas we discussed
that comprise the technical BA's skillset.
Lastly, the technical BA's priority, business or IT.
I generally lean towards the technical BA's priority is the business,
yet be proactive and recommend new and exciting technologies that
can potentially change and reshape your company.
In the next module,
we will dive into some of these analysis tools you will need to
help you become the best technical BA you can be. See you there.