[Autogenerated] When you first start your deployments with terra form in a W s,
you're probably not walking into a green field type situation.
There's probably existing deployments,
or at least existing practices that are happening in your organization,
and you need to integrate terra form with those
existing practices and resources.
That's what we're going to be dealing with in this module.
Hey, everyone,
this is Ned Bellavance and let's get into using data
sources and CloudFormation templates.
All right, what are we gonna cover in this module?
Well,
the first thing I want to do is take a step back and we are going to
talk about infrastructure is code and how you should layer your
configurations when you're building out.
This infrastructure is code.
It's not specific to terra form.
It's more oven architectural discussion,
but I think it's important in the context of how you're going to
integrate terra form with your existing AWS environment.
Then we'll talk about an important aspect of that
which is consuming data sources.
You're going to have existing data sources in a W S.
How do you consume the information in those data sources
to use them in your tariff arm configuration It's
something that we've already seen,
but we're going to delve a little bit more into it.
And then finally, the sounds a little counterintuitive,
but we're gonna look at how you can use CloudFormation
templates in your ______ form configuration and,
like, mind blown.
Why would you even do that?
We'll dive into why you might actually want to do that
a little bit later in this module. But first, let's talk about the concept of layering configurations.