[Autogenerated] alright at Globomantics.
If you'll recall.
We had a software developer, Joshua Magee,
and he has some applications that he wants to deploy into the
Dev VPC that we created in a previous module.
Now,
in order to get information about that Dev vpc he could query a W s directly,
but there's actually an easier route for him.
He can query the network state data because we're storing that network
state data in an S3 bucket in a W s so he can connect to that and
query for information about our deployment.
He's going to do exactly that now.
What is he planning to deploy?
Well,
the application he wants to deploy is going to be an auto
scale group across the two public sub nets,
as well as an application load bouncer that's public facing.
He also wants to deploy a my SQL rds instantiate the database sub nets.
Now, in this graphic I have to database servers.
One would be a master and the other would be a replica in the actual deployment.
I've only deployed one because I'm trying to save money and I
don't need a bunch of extra database instances eating up cost Now
where is he going to store his state.
While he's not going to store it in the same S3 bucket
that we're using for a network state,
he's going to store that in a separate S3 bucket for application state,
and we will deploy that as part of our configuration Before
we take a look at that configuration.
I do want to quickly reference how you can use terra form remote state as a
data source in order to use ______ form remote state.
As a data source, you're going to create a data source configuration block.
It starts with the keyword data,
and then the data source type is terra form remote state.
And then we have to give it a name label.
Now, just like when you're setting up remote state for a configuration,
you have to specify a back end.
We have to specify a back end argument here telling terra form,
where can it find this remote state data source?
In our case,
we're using S3 to get information about that networking remote state.
And then, just like when you configure a back end,
you have to specify config data for accessing this back end And in our case,
since it's an S3, we have to give the name of the bucket,
the name of the key and the region.
You note the Dynamo DB is not in here because we're not
trying to lock the state and change anything.
We're simply reading information out of it.
There's also no authentication information in here,
so it will use the authentication information that was supplied with the A.
W s provider. All right, let's go over to visual studio code and get things set up.