[Autogenerated] Let's go ahead and open up the commands dot txt file and will
run through the process of deploying this configuration.
Now, just like any terra form configuration,
our first thing to do is run terra form in it.
But first I've got to get in The right directory.
Wouldn't work too well if I wasn't All right.
Let's go ahead and run Terra form in it,
and this will download the module and provider executable.
That should happen fairly quickly.
The next thing we're going to do is run ______ form plan.
Dash out vpc dot t f plan and so we'll just create an execution
plan for the creation of these two VP CSS.
Let's go ahead and let that run.
It's going to be creating a lot of resources because it's
too full VP CSS into separate regions.
Wow, that's a lot of stuff.
It's going to add 30 new resources.
So 15 in US East one and 15 in US West one.
All right, let's go ahead and run the Terra form apply.
Go ahead and copy that and paste it down here and now it's
going to go ahead and create those resources.
We don't have to wait for it to create all those resources.
We can, go over to the console and see those resources created in real time.
Okay, here we are in the AWS console, and I'm going to go into VPC s here.
And as you can see in the North Virginia, which is the U.
S.
East one region for AWS, we now have a prod dash V P C Dash East VPC created.
Now if we go ahead and hit the drop-down here and go to us West one,
which is Northern California we can see the at Prod
Dash v P C Dash West has been created.
So we've successfully used two different instances of the AWS
provider to create resources in two different regions.
That's one way of doing it.
Let's look at a different scenario where we're going to use to different AWS accounts.