[Autogenerated] all right.
Here we are in visual studio code,
and I have the exercise files open on the left.
In this case, we are going to be working with the directory five dash,
remote Dash State dash set up.
Let's go ahead and expand that out.
And let's start by opening up the commands dot txt because there's a
little bit of set up that's going to go on here.
We are going to use the environment variable A.
W s profile for our authentication if you'll remember back to the first module.
When I talked about authentication for the A.
W s provider,
you can use environment variables to tell the provider which
profile you want to use in your credentials file.
That environment variable is called A W s underscore profile.
So we're going to set that here and in my case, I'm using windows.
So I just opened up the terminal below,
and I'm gonna go ahead and copy this instruction here
Environment colon AWS profile equals infra.
And now that stored in the environment variable.
If you're running Linux or Mac,
you can use the export function to do the same thing.
All right, Now that we have that set up.
Let's go ahead and take a look at the main dot t f configuration and I'm
gonna hide the terminal to give us a little more room here.
So first, we're going to set up some variables.
No surprise there.
We need to set the region where we're going to be creating our bucket.
We are going to give a bucket prefix.
So this is the naming prefix for our bucket.
And by default, it's gonna be Globo.
You can change that to whatever you'd like for the Dynamo DB table.
We are going with the default of Globo Dash TF State lock,
which will alter a little bit in a moment.
And then we have two variables to define the users.
In the two permissions groups,
one is the full access users and the other one is read only users by default.
We're not putting anyone in those groups.
So if we do want someone in that group,
we have to specify a different value for that variable.
And I have done that in the terra form .NET TIFF bars, files.
Let's go ahead and open that and we can.
See, we've got two entries here for full access users.
We've got Elsie Vasquez.
All right, that's good.
And then for read only users.
We've got our software developer, Joshua Magee,
and he's gonna be ready to go to use this state data as a data source.
When we get to his configuration component, go ahead and close that.
And now let's scroll down to our provider.
We're using the provider AWS.
We've specified the version and region,
and you'll see we're not providing any authentication information.
But since we've set the environment variable A W s underscore profile,
it's going to use that as our authentication method.
And we do want to create this in the infra account,
which is why we used the infra profile.
Okay, let's go down to resources now.
The first resources,
a random integer and the reason we're creating a random integer is
because the name of the bucket needs to be globally unique.
So we're going to create a random integer between 10,000
and 99,999 and upend that to our dynamo to Docker Hub
table name and our bucket name.
So our bucket name will be globally universal and or dynamo
db table name will be locally universal,
and the way that we do that is by defining to local values
dynamo db table name and bucket name.
And like I said,
we're taking the name that we already have and simply a
pending the random integer result.
And that will be the name for our table and bucket.
So we're all set with that.
Now we can create our table and bucket.
Let's look at the table first so we're creating a
Dynamo Devi table called Terra Form.
Underscore State Lock.
You'll note that we're setting the hash key equal to Lock IDE,
and that's actually a requirement of using S3 as a back end
with the Dynamo DB table for locking.
We have to have the hash key set to lock IDE and then configure an
attribute with name equal to lock ID and type SQL to S,
which is for string.
That has to be in the table.
And that's all the table needs.
It's not gonna be getting a lot of reads and writes,
but it does need that hash key and attributes set.
All right,
let's scroll down to the S3 bucket and we're simply creating an S3 bucket,
and we're setting it to be private.
I've also set forced destroy equal to true,
and that just makes it easier to clean this up.
When forced destroy is set to true,
it means that it will delete the S3 bucket even if it's not empty.
So in a production environment, you might set that to falsy.
All right,
now let's get into our group configurations and we've got two groups here.
One is bucket full access, and for the name of this group,
I'm using the name of the bucket dash full access.
So it's pretty obvious what this group is for.
And then for the read only group,
I am naming it the bucket name Dash read only so again,
very obvious what this group is for.
Now that we have our two groups set up, we scroll down a little bit.
We are going to add members to each of those groups using the resources AWS.
I am group membership.
In this case, we're specifying the users for full access.
So I'm using the variable Full Access users, which is a list of users.
I want to grant access,
and then I'm specifying the group to add these members
to which is the full access group.
Below that I'm specifying the read only group membership and
getting that from the variable read only users.
And we know that we put Joshua Magee in that.
So he's going to get added to that group.
Now that we have our group membership filled out,
we need to create a policy granting them the proper
level of access to the S3 bucket.
So let's scroll down a little bit more,
and we have our first policy for full access.
So the name is going to be the bucket name dash full dash access for the policy.
So it's pretty obvious what the policy does,
and we're assigning it to the full access group that we just created.
Looking inside the policy, we basically have to allow statements here.
One is for S3, so you can see that the action for that, says S3.
Any action you can do whatever you want in S3,
and the resource that you can do whatever you want on is the local
bucket and any objects inside that local bucket,
so those to resource lines defined the bucket and
objects inside that bucket awesome.
So we're all set with our permissions to the bucket,
Then below that, we have an allow effect for Dynamo db Colin Star,
which means any action in dynamodb.
What resources are we doing that on why we're doing it on the dynamo
db table that we're creating this configuration,
which we references using the ARN property of that resource.
All right, so that's our full access policy.
Scrolling down.
We get to are read only policy, and this one only has one effect in it.
Because you'll remember the read only group doesn't
need access to the dynamodb table.
They only need access to the bucket.
And what access do they need?
What we're granting to actions here.
We're granting anything that is get and anything that is list on S3 against
the bucket and any objects in the bucket so they'll be able to list out the
objects in the bucket and get those objects.
But they won't be able to manipulate those objects
or write anything to the bucket.
So that's read only access that we've granted them.
So that's everything that's in the configuration.
If we get down to the output,
we're gonna grab the name of the S3 bucket and the name of the dynamo
DB table because we're going to need that information as we prepare
to migrate our state from local to S3. All right, so we're all set with that.