[Autogenerated] Alright,
so I've opened up main dot t f and we've got some variables in here.
The first thing is the region were using us East one,
which is where the dead VPC is.
And then we are referencing the network state bucket,
the network state key and the network state region.
The only one that doesn't have a default value is the network state bucket,
because that's going to depend on your deployment.
But the network state key and region were coded
into how we deployed the Dev Vpc.
Now, if you changed those settings,
then you could just submit different values for the variable.
But if we look in terra form dot t f bars,
I have set the network state bucket to the name of the bucket that
we created for the remote state of our Dev Vpc.
It's Globo!
12251 Excellent.
Now let's go ahead and close that terra form dot t f vars scrolling
down we get into our providers and the only thing to point out here
is that the profile is equal to app.
So once again,
we're using Joshua McGee's credentials to deploy all of this infrastructure.
Now we get into data sources and in data sources.
The first thing is this terra form remote state for the networking information.
This is exactly like the example that we saw in the presentation,
So I'm not going to go into too much detail.
You might wonder how Joshua Magee has permissions to read
information out of the network state.
And if you'll remember back to when we deployed the S3 bucket for remote state,
we created a read only users group and added Joshua Magee to that.
So he has read only access to the contents of that bucket.
Scrolling down a little bit more.
We get into the data source for R A W s,
am I So since we're deploying ec2 instances,
we needed, am I to do that?
We could hard code the AM IDE, but that doesn't work very well,
especially if you move to a different region.
The am I IDE is totally different.
So instead we're using this data source.
We're setting the argument most recent equal to truth,
so it's going to give us the most recent version of the Am I that's available.
We're setting the owners number to the Amazon owners IDE.
So that's a unique IDE that corresponds to images managed by Amazon.
Then we have two filters.
If you've ever used the AWS CLI to filter am I images,
this will seem very familiar.
The first one is the name,
and we know that the name for the Amazon Linux type that
we want has the value am zn am I H p m.
And then and then some strength.
We have the star in there, and then it ends in that x 86 64 dash GP two.
So that should retrieve a single image ID.
We're also adding a filter where the owner alias is Amazon.
It should already only the Amazon because we're specifying owners but
no harm in specifying it twice so that will give us our am I that
we're going to use for the two instances.
Now let's scroll down into resources.
We're building a random into jury that could be used wherever we
need a globally unique ID and then for RDS.
We need to create a security group.
So we're going to create an RDS security group And where
is that security group going to live?
Because security groups need to be associated with the VPC.
We want to associate this with networking VPC and here's where we
use our terra form remote state data source.
You'll note the PATH is data dot terra form remote ST
dot network dot outputs dot vpc.
The outputs refers to any outputs that we created with the
configuration that's being stored by this remote state.
The important thing to understand is that the only attributes
that are available when you reference remote state are those
that were exposed via and output, and in this case we're referencing vpc IDE.
But first,
let me expand the Dev VPC configuration and we'll look at main real quick.
Here's the outputs that we defined for the Dev VPC.
We defined three outputs vpc, IDE,
the D B Sub Net group and public sub nets when we
reference the remote state as a data source,
these are the only outputs available to us if we want to
references other attributes Within this configuration,
those also need to be exposed as outputs,
so that's very important to understand getting back to our configuration.
Once we create that RDS security group will create a
security group rule that allows 3306 and then an egress
rule that allows all traffic out.
That all seems fine.
Let's scroll down a little bit more in order to deploy our my SQL environment.
We're going to use the RDS module that's available on the Terra form registry.
I mean, why not?
I don't want to code all this myself.
The main thing to call out here is under instantiate class.
We're sending it to D B t too large.
So this is gonna be a T two large instantiate ploy ID in your vpc.
Obviously, that costs some money, so I just want to call that out.
It's probably a good idea to clean up after yourself when you're
done deploying this so it doesn't keep charging you money for
having this rds instance running.
Now let's scroll down a little bit more and we see under DB Sub Net Group,
we are again referencing our terra form remote state data source
and we're pulling the output db sub net group.
That's pretty much everything for our my SQL deployment.
So we can scroll past all of that and get into our launch
configuration and auto scale group for R E C two instances to the
all scale group needs a security group.
So we're going to create a security group and put it in that same VPC.
And then we're gonna add some rules to that security group.
We're gonna add one that allows Port 80 and then we're gonna add
an egress rule that allows all traffic out.
So now we have our security groups for our auto scale group.
The next thing we need to do is create a launch configuration and a target
group for our Web servers in the launch configuration.
That's where you set the AM I IDE that you want to use So under image IDE
were referencing our data source data dot a w s a m i dot amazon Linux dot
i dy perfect The instance type is t to micro.
So I tried to keep this pretty small.
The micro could be in the free tier, but again,
probably a good idea to clean up after yourself when
you're done and then under user data,
we are specifying some user data by using the file function to pull
in information from these user data dot txt file That's in the same
directory Let's take a look at what's in there real quick in the
user data down to the bottom.
After all the comments, all we're doing is running.
Yum update installing engine NICs starting the engine X
service and then setting it to auto start.
So we're gonna get the default engine X page when we visit this website,
and that's fine.
This is purely for demonstration purposes.
You can put whatever configuration you need in here to load a config for this.
Easy to instantiate.
I'll go ahead and close out user data.
The next thing we need to do is create a target group that will associate
with the load balancer and that is our Web servers.
And we're referencing port 80.
So that's where traffic should come in to hit our target group
using the HTTP protocol and what vpc IDE should this target
group be associated with why the same dead VPC we've been using
for all our other resources?
Now we get into the auto scale group for the Web.
Servers for the auto scale group were setting the max
size 24 and the desired capacity to two,
so it should spend up to instances by default.
If we look under vpc zone,
identify are This is where we tell it what sub nets should it spin up?
The instances in and we want it in the public sub nets.
So we're using the public sub nets output from our Dev VPC
configuration Scrolling down a little bit more.
We get into the application load balancer side of things,
the application load bouncer.
We also need to set up a security group.
So we create the security group.
We have an ingress rule that allows port 80 in and we have an egress rule
that allows all traffic out and then scrolling down.
We get into the actual load balancer itself.
In our case, we are deploying an application load balancer.
So if you look under load balancer type, we have it set to application.
We refer to the security group that we just created, and then for sub nets.
What sub nets are covered by this load bouncer.
Well,
it's the same public sub nets that we referenced for our
auto scale group because those are the easy to instances
that we want to connect to.
It's going down a little bit more once we have our load balancer created.
We need a listener.
Needs to know to listen for requests on the front end.
We want to listen on Port 80 for http protocol.
And when we get a request on that port 80 we want afford that request to
the target group of web servers that we have created.
So that's everything in the configuration. Let's go ahead and get it deployed.