[Autogenerated] if you'll remember from our previous module.
The security team at Globomantics is a little bit concerned
about being able to inspect and use their security
applications within the context of A W S.
And the person that's responsible for security is JSON Gibson.
Now, what is he planning to do to accomplish their goals?
Well,
the first thing he wants to do is create a separate security
account in A W s specifically for security services and then limit
everyone else's access to that account.
That's smart thinking, Josh.
Now, within that security account,
he is going to create a security VPC where he deploys
all his mysterious security tools.
And we don't need to know what those are.
We just need to know they exist now.
His plan is to Pierre that security vpc with all of
the other vpc s that are out there.
So when a new VPC is created,
he wants that vpc to be peered with the security vpc so his
security tools can get their hooks in.
That's the plan, and he wants our help to make it a reality.
How is Elsie Vasquez going to help out with that?
Let's take a look all right.
As Elsie Vasquez,
we now need to take our dev account where we've created our Dev vpc and
Pierre that up with the security VPC in the security count.
Except Elsie doesn't have access to the security account.
How is she going to get permissions to accept the
peering connection over on that security?
VPC Good question.
There is a way to do this.
And the way to create that peering connection is through creating a peering
role and giving her account access to that peering role.
How do we do that?
If you've worked with I am before,
you'll know we can do this by creating a policy and
a role in the security account.
First will create that peering policy,
which basically says you're allowed to describe the peering connections and
then accept a pending peering connection from another VPC.
And then we'll create a role and assign that policy to the role.
So if someone assumes that peering role,
they will get the permissions defined in the peering
policy over in the development account.
We're going to create a policy that allows users in the Dev account to
assume the peering role in the security account,
and then we're going to assign that policy to a peering group.
So we can basically add individuals to that peering group,
and they will get the permissions to create that peering connection.
So that's the overall goal of what we're trying to accomplish this.
So first we're going to have to create all these
different roles and groups and policies.
And then we're going to create the security vpc and then
finally create these actual peering connection.
So let's go ahead and get started by creating all these groups,
policies and roles.
And we're going to do that.
You guessed it. Using terra form, let's go over to visual studio code.