[Autogenerated] So as you can see in the slide,
we've created our group, our policies and our role.
Now we need to create that security vpc that we're going to do the peering with.
So let's go back to the S code.
Go ahead and hide the command window and we'll close out these files
just to remove some of the clutter and the folder were interested in
now is four dash sec cache VPC go and open the main on that All this is
doing is creating a security VPC So it's almost the same exact
configuration as the Dev VPC,
except we're going to submit different variables for it.
So if we open up the dot t f bars we can see that we're setting a different
VPC cider range and a different range for the public.
Sub nets were also creating some private sub nets and some interest sub nets.
Those are different sub net types that are available in the VPC module.
So we're using 172.16 address space for all of these
different sub nets going back to the main.
We're gonna go ahead and scroll down here to providers and
here we can see that for the provider.
We're specifying the profile SEC.
So now we know that we're dealing with the security account.
This VPC will be created in that security account and the
rest of it is the same as the Dev VPC.
We get our availability zones,
we create the security VPC with all of those settings and then finally,
at the bottom,
we output that bpc IDE because we're going to need that
to set up the peering relationship.
So let's open up our commands.
Txt!
And this is basically the same as before.
We'll run Terra form in it plan and apply.
So let's go ahead and run through that very quickly,
and I better get in the right directory or this is not gonna work out very well.
There we do.
Okay, Terra form in it and go ahead and copy Terra form plan.
While it's doing that.
Now we do.
We'll go ahead and run that and finally we'll run terra form apply
once the plan has been generated successfully.
All right, go ahead and run terra form apply,
and that's going to create that security VPC in the separate
security account and boom that's done already.
Let's go ahead and grab that vpc IDE because we're going to need
that for the last portion of this process.
And this is where we're going to peer.
Are Dev vpc with this security?
Vpc How are we going to do that? Let's take a look.