[Autogenerated] all right,
we have successfully created the groups and rolls to allow for appearing.
We've successfully created our security vpc that Joshua
can do use for all of his security tools.
Now it's time to get this bad boy peered up with our Dev Vpc
So let's go ahead and go back to one dash,
Dev Dash vpc And within there you'll see there's a peering TF dot rename file.
Let's go ahead and open up our commands dot txt file and I'm gonna hide the
terminal for a second just to give us a little more room.
All right,
in the commands dot txt I have a section here called
multiple provider module commands.
So you know where we're coming from and the first thing we're gonna do is
rename that peering dot t f dot rename to just peering dot t f.
And by doing that, rename,
what's in that file will now be part of this ______ form configuration.
So let's go ahead and run that to rename the file,
we'll go up a directory and go into our Dev VPC Directory Run that rename.
Now that file is renamed, and since it's renamed,
let's go Ahead and take a look at what's in that file.
Okay, Hide the terminal to give ourselves some room.
And we've got two variables in here.
We have the destination.
Vpc IDE.
That would be the vpc idea of the security.
Vpc and we have the pier role ARN,
which we had as output from when we created the roles and policies.
Alright, awesome.
We already have the values for those variables scrolling down to the provider.
This is a little bit different.
You might notice a different section in here.
We're giving it the alias Pierre to distinguish it from the other provider.
That's part of this dead VPC configuration for the profile we're using infra.
So we're using the infrastructure account and we
specified and assume role setting.
And this says we want to assume a role that's in a
different account for this provider.
And that's why we need that peer role,
aren't This is where we assume that peering role in the security
accounts So we can except the peering connection.
Tricky.
Pretty cool, though.
All right, down in data sources,
we're going to need the caller identity for that AWS pure provider
because we're gonna need that account IDE again scrolling down some
more We get into creating the peering connection we need the VPC IDE
off the source vpc That would be our Deb vpc It's reaching out to make
that peering connection.
We need the vpc IDE of the VPC it wants to peer with.
That would be the security VPC which we have stored in
our variable destination vpc IDE.
We need the owner ID of that peering vpc which would be
the account IDE of the security account.
And we got that from the AWS Caller identity data source.
We need the region where that peering vpc lives which we have
stored in var region and finally auto except says,
don't try to automatically accept this connection
because it's in a different account.
We're going to do that in a separate step.
That separate step is directly below.
We're creating a resource AWS vpc peering connection.
Except er it's a very special type of resource and it does
exactly what it says on the label for the provider.
We're using a W s peer and you'll notice for the peering connection.
We didn't specify a provider.
We're using the default provider for the Dev VPC that's in the infrastructure
account so that peering connection above uses the infrastructure account this
connection except they're below is using the assumed role in the security
account by referencing a w s dot pierre.
And then we have to specify the peering connection we're going to
try to accept which we can get as a property of the peering
connection resources we created above.
And we'll set auto except the true,
because now we're ready to accept that connection using the assumed role.
So that's everything that's in this configuration.
Let's go ahead and go back to the commands and we'll note
that we want to run terra form plan.
We've already initialized this configuration from when we created the Dev VPC.
But now we need that peering role.
ARN and the destination vpc IDE.
So I'm going ahead and grab that peering role ARN from
my Notepad and paste it in here.
Okay, there we go.
We'll scroll over and now I'm gonna grab that vpc IDE of
the security vpc and paste it in here.
Great!
And now I'm going to copy this entire command,
Bring the terminal back up and we'll go ahead and paste it
in here and it's going to run an execution plan that
includes this peering connection.
All right, so it's creating two new resources,
just like we asked it to ones that peering connection.
And the second one is that, except er of the peering connection looks good to me.
Let's go ahead and run terra form, apply and paste it in here and there we go.
It has successfully created that peering connection.
Let's go head over to the AWS console and just confirm visually.
All right, we're in the AWS console.
We can See, we've got our Dev vpc here.
Let's go ahead and go down to peering connections.
Here is our peering connection we can see the the requester VPC
which is our Dev vpc and the except er VPC,
which is our security vpc in the other account Scroll Scooch this up a
little bit and take a look at the requester owner.
That's the account IDE for our infrastructure account and the except er
VPC owner is the account IDE for the security account on we can see the
at the except er vpc cider is 172.16.
So we definitely got everything set up correctly. JSON Gibson is going to be super happy