[Autogenerated] Now that we have successfully used code
commit code building code pipeline to get our development
environment deployed automatically, we want to expand it a little bit.
Let's see how we're going to do that.
So we still have our source control and that's using
CodeBuild to deploy our resources.
We have our pipeline,
and we have our environment variables that are being pushed
into CodeBuild as part of each build process.
In that pipeline,
we first had our development environment and we successfully were
able to build out our development environment.
That stage is working great.
Now we're gonna add to more stages to the process.
We're going to add a u A.
T.
Stage where we'll build out a you 80 workspace and environment,
and then we're going to build out a production stage,
and within that production stage, we're going to do something interesting.
We're gonna have it run through the plan process,
but we're gonna put a manual approval stage in there that prevents
production from being applied until we give it the thumbs up.
So we're gonna go back to the S code and uncommon TsUM
code in our code pipeline configuration.
To add these components.
Add these additional stages and then we'll kick off
another release for the code pipeline.
So let's go back to visual studio code and take care of that.
All right, we're back in visual studio code,
and we need to update our code pipeline.
So we're gonna open up main TF.
All right, here's our configuration in maine dot t f.
And we're looking at the code pipeline resource.
If we scroll down a bit here, here's our first stage where we set up source.
We scroll down a little bit more.
Here's our second stage, where we set up development with the two actions.
And then if we scroll down a little bit more,
you'll note that I have commented out any additional stages in this pipeline.
We have to more stages were adding.
One is UI tea and the other one is production,
and they are remarkably similar to the information
That's in the e development stage.
So I'm simply going to delete these characters here too uncommon
this you 80 stage as well as the production stage and if we
scroll all the way down to the bottom,
we're gonna have to delete the other side of that comment block.
So now this whole thing is uncommon.
Tid We'll go ahead and save it and we'll pop open the terminal.
Let's go back into the proper directory.
So go up.
One will go into implementing Terra Form A W s and into this directory and
now we can runtime reform plan out code dot t f plan.
So we'll plan out our update that will add those two
additional stages to our code pipeline.
There we go.
So you can see is planning to change one resource by
adding those additional stages.
Sounds good to me.
Will simply run terra form Apply code TF plan.
And since we're just modifying an existing resource that runs pretty darn fast, let's go back to the AWS console and see the update in code pipeline.