[Autogenerated] alright in summary.
Just to give you a few key takeaways from this module,
The first thing I'll say is that Generally speaking,
if you are going to be using your configuration for
anything approaching production, use remote state.
Just do it by default.
Make that part of your practice.
Yeah, If it's a dev throwaway environment, you can use local state.
But generally speaking, you want to use that remote state whenever you can.
Another key take away is that S3 and Dynamodb support locking in workspaces,
so they support both of those extended features that you might
want to use in a collaborative environment that's going to have
multiple deployment environments.
The last thing is that migration is super simple.
I mean, you saw how easy it was.
We ran one command.
After adding the configuration,
it seamlessly moved our data up to S3 and we were done.
Of course.
Like I said before, I take that back up just in case.
But migration itself is super simple.
Now, coming up in the next module,
we are going to get into the world of automation and we're
gonna automate the deployments of our VPC.
How are we going to do that,
we're going to use the native AWS code tools like code
commit CodeBuild and code pipelines.
So that's all coming up in the next module. Stay tuned.