[Autogenerated] all right, I know that was an action packed module.
We learned a lot.
So let's just quickly review what we went over here.
We talked about multiple A W s providers,
and the reason why you would need more than won a WS
provider in your configuration,
it would either have to do with a different region or a different account,
or we kind of saw how you can use an assume role setting
to use a different account if you have access to assume a
role in a separate account,
we also saw how you used the aliases you create for those
providers in resources modules and data sources.
That was pretty useful coming up in the next module,
we are going to look into remote state.
How do we move all this local state,
which we know is not really best practice to use a W s native
constructs for storing that remote state.
So we're gonna use S3 for that storage,
and then we're gonna migrate these existing state of our Deb vpc to use a
back end configuration that's using S3 and dynamodb. So that's all coming up in the next module