[Autogenerated] a typical A W s provider.
Configuration block starts with the keyword provider.
That's how you know you're defining a provider.
And then the name label tells terra form what type of provider you're creating.
In this case, it's an A W s provider.
Within this configuration block are a number of arguments and values.
A common one is version.
And I mentioned this earlier that you might want to
set the version for your provider.
So when a new major version release comes out,
it doesn't break your configuration.
Another common argument is Alias.
If you're going to have multiple instances,
oven A W s provider in your configuration using
aliases is how you differentiate them.
The A W s provider is also region specific.
So you have to tell it which region it's going to be working with.
And then for authentication.
You could explicitly state the access key and secret key
and submit them through variables.
So that's one way that you could use this provider.
We'll see other examples as we get into the demos.
Now I mentioned environment variables, so let's see how those work.
There are a bunch of different environment variables
that you can use with the AWS provider.
Two of the obvious ones are AWS access key IDE and A W s Secret access key.
And that's basically your access key and secret key.
If you set these environment variables,
terra form will find them and then you don't have to
explicitly set them in your configuration.
Another one is the AWS shared credentials file,
and this is simply the location of the credentials file,
which is useful if you're storing it in a non default location.
You can also specify which a W s profile you want to use
in that credentials file by setting the AWS underscore
profile environment variable.
If you have a default region you like to use, you can set a W s default region.
And if you don't specify the region,
terra form will use whatever value is in there.
If you have m f A set up and you're using session tokens for authentication,
you can set the session token through an environment variable as well.
So those are a bunch of different environment variables you can use
as part of your authentication process with the A.
W s provider. Now let's take a look at what's going on at Globomantics