So if we look back on what we've got so far everything seems to be working.
When we canceled out log logged in when we click on sign up and something goes wrong we get these error
messages that just a bad request an encore promise undefined.
So if we click on this right here and head over to the Network tab and look at are in our Ajax requests
we can see the response from the server.
Is this nice error object.
So sorry the user name or email is taken.
What we want to do now is display this message to the user to do that.
We're going to dispatch another action.
If something goes incorrectly.
So inside of our office we're going to add a little bit of functionality to handle errors.
Let's go to our actions and we're going to have some actions for errors.
So we want to be able to dispatch an action to add or remove an error.
So let's start by importing our action types.
Let's get an error and another and that comes from I-Slash action types.
So we're going to go back to folder and go to action Tex
and here we're getting right to very small action creators functions that return actions.
So make a function called an error which accepts a parameter we'll call that error and it's going to
return an object.
So I want to make sure we have those parentheses around that that's really important.
That type of add error and that error as whatever the second parameter is and here we'll call this from.
We'll let's make another function we'll call that remove error which doesn't accept any parameters.
It's still going to return an object.
So let's make sure we also change the type to remove error and online and delete that parameter.
So these are just some action creators for adding and removing errors.
We're going to need these inside of our office.
We're going to need these because inside of you yes we want to either show the error or remove any existing
errors.
So let's import and error and remove error from slash errors.
And we're going to use these inside of our DOT then or our DOT catch if there any previous errors let's
dispatch remove our and if there are any errors that get created let's dispatch add error with an error
message number that message property is coming from the server in our error object.
So I mean yes let's go send those errors to these forms.
So we've got to go to a relaxed day and we're going to grab those errors so we can keep errors and get
that from state that errors.
Let's see this.
We should be able to now pass these as props to our forms.
So inside of our off form let's add a prop. we'll call that errors and we'll get that value of errors.
Let's do the same thing in our other form as well.
So this and inside of our form how do we display these errors.
Let's write a little bit of conditional logic to see if there are any errors.
So if there are any errors you want to display them.
Otherwise don't do anything so right after our wedding what's.
A little bit of conditional logic which ESX will say if there are if there is a message property inside
of errors let's go display some information so will display a div with the class name of alert color
danger.
Pretty standard bootstrap I don't have an inside of your whatever that error messages.
Let's go make sure because I did make sure that our syntax is proper.
That looks good.
So are there any specific errors here will display them.
Otherwise we will.
So let's go to the browser and it says errors is not defined.
So that's because we're trying to use something called errors but where did it come from.
It came from prox.
So if to make sure that we pass that from this start process what's the first page and how errors is
not defined as well inside of major US.
And that's because inside a manger.
Yes.
I also do structure errors from props as well.
You'll make this mistake quite a few times.
It's great to see me make it because you will as well and that's totally fine.
So we're going to pass these as props to our main component and then we'll pass them down as props to
the form.
So if you have a page and click sign up we should now see that error.
And that looks good.
Let's get going again and this error is still here.
And that's not really applicable to the log in form.
So anytime that we switch on these routes let's clear those error messages that we've seen previously
to do that.
We're going to use the re-act rather.
So what we'll do is if there's any change between sign up in loggin we're just going to clear any previous
error messages in order to do that.
We're going to send our remove error action creator to our form.
So let's ignore it remove our from Dr. I-Slash store slash actions slash hairs.
And we're then going to pass in Ramoo.
We can only pass a prompt if we sent it in though as an app dispatched.
So let's make sure that we pass that in as well.
So that's Kassandra with error.
And inside of each of our all forms we pass and a cousin of Ruah will also call this room of error to
keep it consistent and we'll pass in that same prop to the other form as well.
So each of our forms have the ability to remove an error.
So back in our off form we're going to structure something else from props.
We're going to structure an object called history and we get this from the Riak router as this not perhaps
that history will also structure the remove error function.
What we'll do here is simply Before we return we'll call history lesson.
We're just do a listen for any change in the route.
And if there is a change in the route we're going to call her a move error function.
So let's say this let's go back to our application and if we try to sign in with something we'll see
invalid e-mail or password.
Notice the error messages on and on line the blurring there isn't sensitive information we want to make
sure that no one sees here.
So it looks like I have that right here.
That looks good.
Let's try to sign up and here was that nice error message that says user name or e-mail is ready taken.
And the next section we're going to start redirecting.
When we successfully log in we'll talk about how to display all those messages and keep working in our
application.