The next instructor I'd like you to meet in L.A. she'll pick Oh boy where do we start early.
We've been teaching together for a couple of years now.
First at General Assembly and then we both went to galvanize and work together as well.
He is without a doubt one of the best instructors ever had the privilege of working with.
We're actually very evenly matched and ping pong as well.
And we have pretty similar backgrounds as to how we arrived at teaching moment.
What's your story.
Sure.
So I actually studied finance.
I worked as a consultant for a couple of years and I was working on a startup and was the only person
who was not technical there.
So I actually kind of had to learn the hard way to build websites and build applications and always
had the dream of being a teacher but never thought I'd be lucky enough to do it.
When I did and I'm really passionate about seeing people learn how to code in doing some similar things
that both you and I have done so I'm asking ever on this what's your thing.
They're quick to him.
I mean you teach it all you do everything.
But what's your sweet spot.
Yeah I really like teaching some more the advanced concepts in javascript I think it's pretty easy to
learn some of the fundamentals on your own but when you really start diving into those more advanced
topics it's really hard to do it just by yourself.
So I really enjoy teaching those.
I struggle to learn it myself and I've just gotten better and better at teaching it.
So it's a real passion of mine to impart that knowledge on people who are just getting started with
more advanced parts in the language and we're really lucky to have Ellie to teach that stuff because
personally I struggle with it but it's always been a master at breaking down those tough parts of Javascript.
So you see him a bunch in this course of pop up pretty much all javascript stuff.
Testing.
Yes 20:15 much more hardcore stuff.
All right.
So now that you've met all the instructors and whiskey I wish you.
Let's take a little bit of time to talk about what the Course covers and what you can expect.