Hagen this course is a bit different and that we have four instructors you've already met me.
Now it's time to meet our next instructor.
MATALIN Hey I was going this is WiFi of course mascot.
Every course I've done so far it had an animal.
Whiskey is our mascot this time.
That's been a teacher for over 10 years teaching budding engineers at UCLA and devolve into camps like
galvanize.
And he has a Ph.D. in mathematics and he just published his first book Power up unlocking the hidden
mathematics of videogames in stores now.
That's him right there.
According to his personal bio on his website Matt loves to eagerly go off on nerdy math tangents at
every possible opportunity.
So you have that to look forward to.
Joking aside I've known Matt for three years.
We used to teach together galvanize.
He's just an incredible instructor and super smart guy all around just great person.
So you'll see a lot more of him and Matthew later on in the D-3 and data visualization sections of the
course.
So I've done a lot of talking all that Matt take over and chat a bit about his background so met.
How did you end up running your own boot camp.
Ah well I've always loved teaching when I was in grad school I taught students for a number of years
and after that I worked at math education start up and that's sort of where I picked up my my technical
chops.
And after a few years doing that I miss being in the classroom so I started teaching at galvanize and
after doing that for about a year I started rhythm with Ellington.
So I'm going to ask everyone this question.
You know we have this giant curriculum in bootcamp you've taught or three months or six months long.
All of that stuff.
What's your thing.
What's your favorite topic to teach.
I really love teaching D-3.
Let me sort of teach some some of the more math concepts which I always think is fun.
And Students also get to build things that are really cool to look at.
So you get a lot of wows when you're when you're given those kinds of talks.
Isn't that convenient.
Yes teaching I do three sections.
So you'll see a lot more of that later on in the course will pop up a couple of times.
Talk about some CSSA stuff.
But the main focus of his lessons are going to be on D-3 and building a really cool dashboard that is
going to be fun.
All right.
So I was.