It's time to meet our next instructor Tim Garcia Tim doesn't really like talking about himself so I
mean to do it for him.
Tim is the most experienced developer on our team.
He was building web sites before I was in kindergarten and it's now because he's old.
It's because basically he's a point genius.
He started building websites when he was in middle school.
And it's gone on since then.
He spent five years at Amazon.
And what were we doing there.
I was working on a lot of different Kindle products.
And then you have Amazon to teach.
Yeah I found my way into teaching to general assembly.
That's how we met.
We got together there four years ago.
Yeah.
Four years.
And then we left went to galvanize there together.
And then Tim left to do what.
Yeah.
About a year ago we started rhythm school which is where we are right now.
On top of being a really talented developer Tim it's just a really great guy.
Tim you're obviously super skilled developer.
What drew you to teaching.
I think the biggest thing was just helping people.
I love seeing people learn and growing and then also teaching the material I'm really interested in
teaching software development to people.
So speaking of the material in the book captured we talk together at rhythm here.
There's a lot of stuff they teach.
I mean what three to six months of content.
What's your what's your thing.
What do you prefer to teach and what are you going to teach in this course.
My favorite is definitely reacts.
I've grown to really love re-act over the past couple years I've given a lot of conference talks about
it and I think it's just a joy to cope with so I hope you enjoy it as well as being humble.
Tim is just a beast with react and you'll see him.
That's going to be kind of a specialty in this course but you'll see him before then as well talking
about some javascript stuff.