Okay we're back to the recipes app and now it's your turn to finish up the app.
Everything we've learned in this section you'll incorporate into the recipe app that we saw earlier.
So let's get started.
Earlier we made a component that looks like this.
It's got our title our ingredients our instructions and image.
There's one thing I wanted to clean up here I don't know if any of you noticed but I left this recipe
string in there and I didn't mean to.
So let's take that out.
So in here in my title I will remove that recipe string.
We go and I'll say that.
And now we don't have the recipe there anymore.
And that matches up pretty well but it looks like over here.
OK so your goal is to get the app looking like this.
And first of all this talk about breaking it down.
So we've already broken it down to one component the recipe component.
But now we want to have other components in this application not just a single recipe.
So the first thing you might think about doing is making a component for this Nav..
So I would make a nav bar component and then the next component you probably would need is a list of
recipes.
So I would probably put all of these recipes inside a thing like a recipe list and then finally at the
highest level you would still have your recipe app and your recipe app would probably just be one nav
bar component that you render and then one recipe list that you render.
And remember I expect all the things to be used here that we just learned so you would definitely want
default prop's that's how you're going to load this data.
And you're also going to want to use Propp types where appropriate.
One last thing.
Try to make sure you get at least three different recipes in here if you like.
You can copy mine.
These are my original recipes so please treat them well.
Anyways after this we'll talk about a solution.
So good luck.