Welcome back.
In this video we'll learn about the basics of building forced directed graphs with D-3.
Before we look at any code let's unpack some of the terminology a force directed graph is a way to visualize
relationships between nodes in a graph.
It can be helpful for trying to gain insights into a network.
It's called the force directed graph because you can simulate forces acting on the nodes so so they
move around in response to one another.
Indeed three the four simulation works by calculating velocities and positions for each node based on
the forces that you configure.
If you look through the examples page on the D-3 website you can find many examples of force directed
graphs.
The first one is a visualization of the characters from the book Lynda's or up.
Each node represents a character and the edges tied together characters that appear in the same chapter.
As with so many of the visualizations we've seen D-3 is doing a lot of the work for us in terms of positioning
these nodes and moving them in relation to one another.
But in order to harness the tools the D-3 provides There are a few underlying concepts we need to understand.
In order to build some force directed graphs from the ground up let's start with a basic example.
Here's a link to some code will be working with during this video.
I've already created some starter code for this project.
I've got to assemble a DML file along with a minimal amount of C S S in my app J s.
I've taken care of some of the basics.
I've set a width and height for my SPG created an array of no data join there's no data to an empty
D-3 selection appended some circles and added some styles based on the no data.
In general when you're working with a force directed graph a node will typically just correspond to
some data point but it's the relationships between the nodes as visualized by links.
That makes a force directed graph interesting to look at.
For now though let's just focus on the nose when we open this page in Chrome.
There's not much going on.
This shouldn't be too surprised.
We didn't even set X or C-y attributes on these circles.
So everything is crammed up into the upper left corner of the SVGA.
Let's fix this by creating our first for simulation to create a simulation in D-3 we use the 3.4 simulation
method.
D-3 that for simulation accepts an array of nodes and begins to simulate forces acting on those notes.
You can also update the array of nodes you want to attach to the simulation at any time by calling the
nodes method on a simulation.
Let's create our first simulation passing in our nodes and storing the result in a variable called simulation
Well that was anti-climactic.
It may look like nothing has changed but in fact there's an important difference.
If we select one of our circles with D-3 and look at the data attached to it we have a bunch of new
properties index the X the y x and y these properties have been provided to us by the simulation.
The x and B Y record the velocity of the node based on the forces acting on an x and y record the position
based on the nodes current position and its velocity.
Still though there isn't much happening in this situation.
But that's because by default simulations have no forces on in order to get our nodes moving on the
page.
We need to add some forces to our simulation.
There are a few different types of forces you can add.
The first one we'll look at is a center force which tugs on the nodes so that their average position
lies in the designated center create a center for us you can use the D-3 dot force center method which
takes in the coordinates of wayed like this force to pull the nodes by default for center will pomos
towards 0 0.
The origin of the SVGA to this force we need to use the force method on the simulation.
The force method takes two arguments.
The first is the name you'd like to give the force and the second is a description of that force using
the theory you can name the force whatever you want.
This is just how you can refer to the force later on if you need to access it.
I'll call this force center and set it equal to a new center force passing in the middle point of the
SVGA.
Now we should be good to go right well not quite.
It turns out there's one more thing we need to do to get this simulation working.
We need to write our own functions specifying how the positions of our nodes should update based on
the velocities and positions calculated by the simulation.
Then we'll need to pass our function in as a callback to the method for the simulation similar to date
pre-selections and transitions D-3 force layouts simulations have an on method.
However there are only two types of events to listen for.
One is a tick method which gets called after every tick of the simulations internal timer.
The second is and which is called the simulations timer stops.
We'll listen for that ticket after every tick of the timer we'll grab our selection of nodes and update
to see X and see y properties based on the x and y properties assigned by the simulation.
Finally our noses have moved to the center of the SPG.
They're still pretty motionless though.
It turns out that the center force isn't terribly compelling visually even though it's really helpful
in making sure our visualization stays centered.
Before adding Lintz to this visualization Let's take a look at one more force D-3 dot for anybody.
This method adds interaction between all nodes in the simulation by making them attract or repel one
another by default the many body force is a repulsive force meaning that it causes the nodes to push
away from one another.
But you can change this by calling the strength method on the force and passing in a different value.
Negative strengths correspond to repulsive forces while positive values correspond to attractive forces.
The default strength is negative 30 out of many body force and give it a name of nodes.
Finally something a little more interesting.
The nodes are pulled into the middle by the center force but pushed apart by the many body force.
Notice that if I set the strength to a positive value then the nodes get pulled even more tightly together
into the center of the SVGA this covers the basics of nodes and forces with force and mutations in the
next video will add some links to this graph.
See there.