It it's time to start working on our actions.
This is the missing piece of redux that we haven't spent a lot of time on.
So what we need to do inside of our actions is create a file for us.
We're also going to make one for our errors as well.
We'll call that errors.
Yes.
These are going to be actions that we're going to dispatch we'll use our action types that we have before.
So in our Oggi we need to make an Ajax request to our backyard.
So each of these actions we can bring in actually those.
But what I'd like to do is abstract all that logic to a file called API Dutchie as inside services.
This file is going to be a little bit tricky at first but this is going to be really helpful to build
a generic way to make an Ajax request.
So we're going to import exodus from access.
So if we remember earlier actuals is a really friendly way to make each of your requests similar in
terms of jaggery.
But a much smaller library.
So what I want to do here is export that function and we'll call that API call.
It's going to accept some kind of method some path and some kind of data.
It's a very generic function.
And what it's going to do is return a new promise so we're going to do is resolve that promise when
our actions are resolved.
So we're going to use the promise constructor.
If you remember.
Yes 2015.
This accepts a function
with two parameters we can call those whatever we want but we'll call those resolve and reject
inside here.
We're going to return our Actually US request with whatever method you pass.
We can't do that because we need to evaluate whatever the value of methodis
this is going to return to us function so we'll invoke that function with the path and data when that's
done will run a function with some response
and inside of this response will return resolve and we'll pass in resident data.
If it doesn't go well we'll catch with some kind of error and we'll simply return or reject with error
response that data error.
So you might be wondering where rest that data comes from.
And response that data comes from
the idea here is that when we get back information from ASIO's it always comes in in a certain object.
In this case it's going to come in in an object called response and a subobject called data when something
goes wrong inside of data.
There's a sub object called error which is what we're sending from our server as the error handler that
we built with the successful request we always get back some object of data.
So we're taking the data that we get back from X-ers I'm turning it into an object that we can easily
work with.
So we're going to be using this make API call inside of our off J S So we first want to import API call
from that I-Slash data slash services slashy API.
Let's also import our set current user action type from data I-Slash action types same thing is action
type slash index We're also going make a function that's going to be an action creator.
We'll call this function Sacranie user and all that's going to do is accept a user will return some
object with a type of that current user and the entire user.
This is what we're going to dispatch and send to our redox reducer.
So what's the function that we're actually going to run to log in or sign up successfully.
This one's a little trickier.
We'll call this off user.
It's going to accept the type is going to sign up or sign in and some user data is going to come in
from the request or return a function with dispatch.
We're going to use redux thunked to do this and this is where it gets a little trickier.
We still have to wait for our API call to finish before we dispatched this action.
And since we're not using any kind of lifecycle method we need another promise to make sure that we
wait until the API call has finished before we dispatch anything.
So we going to return a new promise.
And once again we have those two parameters resolve and reject.
And this is a function and inside of this function we're going to return API call and here will pass
in a post to slash HDI slash slash whatever the type is that's passed then sign up sign in.
We don't know yet here we'll pass that user data as well.
When that's done we're going to run a function with some data
and if it returns successfully we're simply going to set some information in local storage.
This is how market user has logged in.
So we'll that a key or GWG token and a value.
Now we get back Deodato.
So if you remember our response from the server we get back an object with the token profile image the
user name the ID.
So we're going to the structure what we get back from the response with the token.
And then the rest of the information will call that user sensitive data our token.
We can just type in token and I think we're going to do is dispatch our action creator called Send current
user and that's going to pass in our user.
This is where we're going to go and create that current user in a redux or we'll then resolve.
We're going to save this and we'll see what happens when we test this.
Let's go back to our component to make sure that we can use this off user function so back in our manger
Yes we're going to have to bring in this off user function.
So at the very top We're going to import all the user from that last store slash actions slash off and
off user is going to be passed in as a prop to or.
We can call this product on off a value of off user will also passes down as well to our other offer
no matter what.
We're still going to be using that user inside of our form.
We want to handle that summiting of the form.
So let's write a function called handle submit.
That will be run when the form is submitted.
And this is going to be a function we use the same functions and X we saw for and here will prevent
the default actions of the page just fresh.
We're going to figure out what the off tape is.
So I'll say it does not prop's that seiner then cyano.
Otherwise seinen.
And this is going to be useful for determining the type of requests that we're going to make.
We'll then call this our props on off and pass in the off tape.
And whatever our state is that will be our data.
So this is a promise to us.
So when that promise is done we'll run a function and inside of here we'll eventually redirect the user
to another page.
Right now it's going to cancel out log logged in let's see if this works
would see this and test it out in the browser.
Let's make sure that things are running properly.
So if your refresh the page and seinen looks like we don't even have a button to sign up what's good
make sure that we first have a button would be tragic if we read all this code and couldn't even submit
them for.
So the very bottom of them make sure that I have a button inside we'll pass in a class name of BGN BGN
and primary pretty standard bootstrap button styling with BT and block as well.
NBT and LG also give us a type of cement.
Let's close those quotes right there and here will passen our prop button text.
Let's see if that can match the browser and we see a sign up on.
Great.
So will hasn't the US has to clean this up for now.
That's OK.
We'll see if this works.
So if it's a crime to have tools getting a couple warnings we'll clear those up a little bit.
But we're not getting anything really on the air front yet.
So let's try Tristana we'll sign up with some information when we go through this.
It's good to see this the proper start ON-OFF is not a function.
So why are we getting this error.
Well we want to make sure that we actually pass on off as MAP dispatch to process.
So we need to pass that in right here for map dispatch to profs.
We also need to make sure that we pass that down as a prop inside of our main component.
So in our main component will change the syntax here so that we can structure a little bit of information
from prop's
So let's go fix that syntax and inside of here let's make sure that we structure all the user from prop's.
So now that we're correctly getting the right product we can pass that down to our components.
So it's try to sign up first.
So the image you are now.
And now we're actually signing up.
So we were getting at that request because we actually haven't created a user by that.
So there's a lot that we've really done here and what we'll do in the next section is review the Kodaly
Britain so far because we've done quite a bit to get everything to communicate.