All right let's get going.
So let's start off with the ugly ex-aide char syntax.
So we're going to start by selecting the button and we might as well just knock all four of these out.
So I'm just going to call this one ex-aide char PTEN equals document query selector.
And then you said ID.
You could also use a document that get element by id and then I'm going to fast forward as I select
all four buttons.
OK I have the four button selected using those ideas.
Now I'm just going to use Exige our button and set up a quick listener then and here will make our new
ex-aide char.
And that's going to be new text.
Each TTP request my favorite phrase then we'll do our ex-aide char send and also are open.
And before we go any further we should add that you are all that we need.
So we'll make a variable for you r l equals u r l here.
Perfect.
And then we're going to open a get request to that you are just like that.
So this should send the request but then we need to actually process that we need to do something afterward.
So we'll add in our ex-aide chart on ready state change.
And then in here if statement if they are not ready state with a capital S equals four and ex-aide chart
status equals 200 then let's do a cost that log ex-aide Charcot response text.
Let's see.
Does it work.
I open up the console.
I click on exit char button and nothing's happening.
So let's see if I click listner works I'll just do an alert here.
And now if I click that still not working.
Silly mistake I'm missing what I'm listening for.
There you go.
Hopefully you saw that for me.
So now I click SH Are we get high and we get our data perfect So our data is in an array.
But remember it's Jaison even though it looks basically like only a string it's inside of an array.
So we need to parse it first.
So we're going to do.
Jason parce Charcot response text.
Let's save that to a variable called the VAR quote perfect.
Now let's just print out quote
We should get rid of that alert.
But that looks good.
So we want quote zero.
So let's save the quote.
Add the zero on the end here and now and we click should just get the raw quote.
Perfect OK.
So we have that let's get rid of our annoying alert and now we just need to do the part to actually
update this paragraph here.
So I'm going to select it var let's call it display equals document queries selector with the ID of
quotes and then all we have to do is set display dot in inner text because the quote that comes back
that we just got to make sure it works.
Perfect OK.
So that's our version using SH are.
Now let's move on to fetch.
So we have this fetch button.
We need to add our listeners for that and we're sending our fetch get request to you or else we have
right here.
So fetch you Arel and then our DOT then
our function and then we'll also add a dime catch
OK.
So let's just do an alert here.
Error.
Good enough.
Then let's do a constant log request.
Make sure it works.
Open up the console click the fetch button and we're getting our data back.
So this is now where we need to do our Jason.
So will do request that Jason just like that.
Then
and will cancel that log our data.
You don't have to nest then.
But I'm going to do that for now.
That's quick.
Perfect.
And we just to that log data zero there we go.
So the last thing will do is just steal our logic up here where we're just setting the displays in our
text equal to data zero.
Let's see if it works looks good.
H.R. still works and fetch works.
OK.
Now we're moving on to our Jay query button.
And in order to go any further we need to include J query.
So open up the queried page.
I'm going to include the minute script.
You can also the easier way for using code Peniche just include it over here but I'll just include this
save.
Now I can reference a query and why not let's do this one the query way.
So rather than selecting the button like this.
Let's actually do a dollar sign and the button is called the query.
Is that right.
Yes.
Click.
And then in here we're going to send our Ajax request I'm going to use get Jaison and that you are all
we want.
It's just called you Arel.
Well then
and remember that our response in this case actually it's better if we make this up done.
So Jake Weary Way and will do a cost that log response.
So let's see what happens.
I clicked the J.Crew button and look at that.
We don't even have to parse our data or anything because we're using get Jason so we can just call it
let's just name this data instead of response because it's not the entire response it's just the data
from the response and we just want data zero.
There we go.
So to actually update this paragraph down here we're just going to select the ID which is quote and
then set text to be data zero which is what is coming back from the API.
There we go so fast.
SH R and J Cory are working great.
Finally we have access.
So we need to include it.
I'm on the ex-CEO skit page.
Copy this script here and just include that with a query.
So now I'm going to use this X years button.
I've already selected come down here and do an event listener.
Technically you know I could mix J query with this as well but I'm kind of making the point that you
may not need a query all the time so I'm not going to do that.
And let me make sure I don't forget to say this one is quick that we're looking for perfect and in here
we're going to do our X-post dot get what's the URL appear safe to variable already.
And then we add in our then
we'll just you come to that log.
And let's at our catch we don't really have to handle errors on this one but just good to get in the
practice of that.
OK.
So let's see what happens when really quick it.
Great.
So we're getting our data back but it's actually inside the response itself so we want response data
which gives us this.
And then we just want to access zero again.
And finally we want to take this and actually update this paragraph.
So just a matter of display in our text just like we did earlier equals that and there we go.
So let's compare them.
We have these four different ways of writing it.
Start at the top.
The longest bulkiest is the X H.R. syntax.
Then we've got fetch which is not too bad.
I like fetch and texture pretty good.
The only problem of course is that it doesn't work in Internet Explorer.
So that's kind of a big issue.
Then we've got a query really nice beautiful.
So I would say that people don't like this but it's really easy and short but it comes at the expense
of having to include a bunch of other stuff you may or may not need.
And then finally we had ex-U.S. which actually is not really fair to compare the syntax to this because
we're not handling any errors in here so we could add the dot fail and that would make this seem a little
longer.
Anyway the point is that these are very similar in syntax.
They work across all browsers.
There's no compatibility issues.
But this comes with a bunch of extra stuff.
You may not need and if you don't want it and you just care about making your requests then use x yes
or use fetch and just don't care about Internet Explorer users.
OK.
Kind of a long exercise there.