Welcome back I hope you are able to successfully add some features to this.
Notes using the three in this video.
I'll write out my solutions for this exercise before I write any javascript.
Let me first take care of some small updates to the T.M. and CSSA files.
First to handle the preview functionality.
Let me add a new tag above the form where I put the preview.
I'll give it a classic preview along with a class of hide.
Since I want the element to start out hidde eventually I'll toggle this high class to determine whether
or not this element should be visible.
I also need to add a couple of more buttons when to remove all notes and one for when I'm feeling lucky.
I'll give these buttons their own classes so that they're easy to target with CFS.
I'll also modify the type attribute of each button since only the first button should trigger a form
submission.
I'll give it a type of submit for the other two buttons.
I'll set the type to button.
This ensures that clicking on these buttons won't trigger a form submit and that submitting the form
by pressing Enter will have the same behavior as clicking on the add note button.
Great.
Next I'll hop into my CSSA file and modify my styles a bit.
First let me tackle the previous class.
It should share some styling with the notes.
Namely the width should be 75 percent and the margins should be the same.
There will need to modify these original margins of it.
It should also have some scows in common with each individual note namely the border radius and the
padding on need to adjust the margin of each note a bit so that the preview will be the same size.
Lastly I need a few brand new styles.
I need to put a couple of colors for my preview one for the background one for the border.
I'll also need to change the box sizing property from its default value to border box so that the preview
has the proper width next only to define the style rule for my height class.
Namely that the display should be none finally.
I need to set some colors for my new buttons logo with red for the Remove button and green for the I'm
Feeling Lucky button for both of them.
Also add a slightly darker color on hover
OK now it's time to get to the fun part.
What's happened to our javascript file and implement some features.
I'll take care of the more straightforward features first began.
Let me handle the remove functionality first.
I'll grab the Remove button with D-3 and attach an event listener for clicks inside of the callback.
All I need to do is grab every element with a class of note and then call remove.
On this D-3 selection let's make sure this works out a note then try to remove all of the notes.
Great.
Next let's implement the feeling lucky feature as you may recall.
Do you want to do here is totally up to you.
I decided to randomly update the font size for each note so similar to the last feature.
I'll first grab the button with D-3 then inside of the callback I'll create a selection from all of
the known elements.
However this time rather than removing the notes I'll call the style method and update the font size
inside of a callback style overturn a random pixel value from 0 to 100 remember.
Since I'm passing in a callback it will get involved for each matching element in this D-3 selection.
This means I'll get a different random font size for each note rather than a single random font size
for each note to share.
If I refresh the page again it looks like this is now working too great.
Last but not least let's tackle the preview functionality.
Previously I grabbed the input inside of a callback to the form's image but now I want to reference
that input element in a couple of different places so I'll first move this variable declaration into
the outer scope while I'm at it.
I'll also use D-3 to select that preview element that we created earlier in each D.M. out.
Next I want to attach a listener on the input for input events when there's a new event I first try
to grab the current value in the input to do this.
I can use the input itself or the event target.
Once I have the input value I want to use that value to set the entire text of the preview.
I can also use the value to determine whether the preview should be shown or if the input is empty.
Then I should probably hide the preview.
Otherwise I can show it.
Put another way using the classmates in the class of hide should be present if and only if the value
in the input is the empty string.
Cool.
This seems to be working well almost.
Notice that there's a small bug if I submit a new.
Note the preview screen doesn't clear I need to duplicate some of the logic inside of my callback for
input events.
Once the formis admitted to avoid that application let me write a small helper function called Set preview
which takes an hour value and updates the previous selection based on the value passed in.
I can now use this helper function in two places once in the input callback where I pass and the value
input and again the Submit callback where I pass an empty string to force the preview to hide.
But to refresh the page again.
Cool that bug is.
I hope this solution makes sense and is similar to the approach you took when you're ready.
Head over to the next section.
I'll see you there.