Now we're going to add a little bit of complexity to what we've done so far.
So everything we've talked about up until now has just been one single reac component but in practice
you're right many components and you use those components to create other components.
And this video will have two objectives.
First will render an array of jazz acts.
And then after that we'll refactor it a bit to use a react component inside of another component.
So let's get to some code.
Here's our component from last time.
Remember it's a pet component.
It's got a div our name Moxey here a picture of Moxey and then a list of her hobbies.
So if we take a look it looks like this.
So you've got some styling and some classes to make it look a little nicer than before.
But let's do another refactor now.
Let's see if we have a variable number of hobbies down here.
We don't want to have to list them out by hand.
So one thing we can do is we can create a javascript array
and now we've got three things in that array instead of two.
Now we can use curly brackets inside of our GSX to render this array into GSX Elyse.
So let's change this.
To be hobby's dot map in our map callback will transform these strings into GSX elements.
So I'll start out with H.
That'll be the string for my hobby and then I want to return an ally that renders H.
And I also don't want to forget about my style so my style here as well.
All right so if I move these.
Now I have three hobbies instead of two sleeping eating and curling.
But if we look in the consul will see that we have a warning here that tells us that we need a unique
key prop for each child an array iterator.
This is happening because of the map that we're using mapper turns an array.
Anytime you render an array and react you need to give each element a unique key which is important
for reacts rendering.
So let's add in that key and the key should be a unique number that has something to do with the data
that we're displaying.
Unfortunately we don't have a great unique number right now.
So I'm just going to use the index in the array and that's not really a great unique key because if
the array ever changes and we lose an element or add element that ID that index could change.
But in this case our arrays never changing so the index will be OK.
Now as you can see the air goes away and we still have our list here.
Now we've successfully rendered a list of GSX components for our next task.
We're going to refactor this to use two components instead of one.
So will simplify the pet component and add a new component that the pet component uses will start by
creating our new component up above and I'll call it a hobby list.
It's going to extend re-act component
and just like other component will need a render method.
Now I want this component to take care of the rendering of that hobby list.
So first grab this array from the pet and put it here.
And next I'll take this code and use that as our render.
And I want to return that GSX
just format that a little nicer.
OK so now we have two components are hobby list and our pet.
But so far the pet doesn't actually render the hobby list.
So how do we get that Javie list to be rendered inside of our pet again.
Well we just use the GSX component so it's called Javie list up here.
I can just put a hobby list right inside this component and this is really the power of reacts.
We are composing more complicated component.
In this case the component out of a simple component the simple component being the Havi list.
So this is what we'll do throughout the course we'll use multiple components to build up something larger
and larger.
And let's take a look at this in action one more time.
It looks like I've got an error here so let's debug.
Ah ok so style is not defined.
I made a mistake so inside this else we were still using the style but it's not defined in this component.
So I also need to grab style out of here.
And use that one in here.
Also So now with that change.
Yep my components working and the errors are gone.
That's all we've rendered a list of GSX elements and we've used two different components to compose
our app.
Next up we'll be looking into something called prop's which makes our components more customizable.