Welcome back in the previous video we learned about the basics of force directed graphs using SVGA.
Now that we've got a handle on the basics it's time to add some links to our graphs.
Here are some links to our code where we left it off.
I've added a few lines of code compared to the end of the last video.
Here you can see I have an array of objects stored in a variable called links.
Each link object has a source and a target D-3 requires links to have both these keys.
In order to incorporate them into a force directed graph.
When we created our for simulation in the last video we only passed in our nodes not our links.
So how do links fit into the picture.
It turns out that if you want to add links to your nodes and have them influence the behavior of the
nodes you need to add another force D-3 provides a way to add link forces with the slinky method.
You can pass an array of links into the method directly or pass them in later by calling the links method
on the forest and passing in your links.
Let's try this out.
I allowed a third force to my simulation code lengths and passing my links to the source link method
while that seemed to make things worse.
If I happened to the con..
I can see there's an error missing read in case it's not clear what this error is referring to.
In order for the simulation to apply the proper force between the two connected nodes D-3 needs to be
able to translate between the link in the source and target nodes.
By default it assumes that the values for source and target are indices in the nodes array.
But in our current example our values aren't indices.
Are the colors of each node.
One way to fix this is to change our lengths array so that the values for each object are indices.
But another approach is to use the ID method on the force which lets you specify how D-3 should find
nodes based on the source and target values.
In this case we could use the ID method and specify the D-3 should find nodes based on the color property.
The strength of the forth between links is determined by two values.
Distance and strength distance determines how long the link was.
Interactions with other forces however can cause the links actual distance to vary from its ideal length.
In this case the strength attribute is proportional to the difference between the lengths actual distance
and its desired distance.
This is similar to a spring.
The more you stretch or compress the link the more it's going to want to return to its original length.
Both of these parameters have default values.
For now let's change the default distance to 300 as you can see.
Now the nodes are much more spread out.
The link forces are present now but it would be nice if we could also see the links in our visualization
to do this.
We'll need to add some line segments for each of our links.
I'll create a selection very similar to our node selection and I'll put it above my notes selections
of the links get drawn first.
After appending my lines I'll set the stroke to black in the stroke with one.
When I refresh the page though everything looks the same as before.
My lines are there but I need to use the simulation to set the X-1 why 1 x 2 and why 2 attributes dynamically.
How can I do this.
Well if I grab one of the lines and look at the data join to it.
D-3 has done something helpful to replace the original string values of source and target with all of
the know data including the data added by the simulation.
This means that I can use the positions of the source and target nodes to tell my link where it should
go to do this.
I'll hop into the callback from my tick handler and for each line in the link selection update the X1
y one X to Y two properties.
I'll map x 1 and y one to the coordinates of the source and x to and y to the coordinates of the target.
One last trick before we move on.
Since we see now that links have access to the properties on the source and the target node we can use
these properties when setting up the linked force.
For example in the distance method I could pass in a callback where the distance between two nodes should
be based on their sizes with this expression.
Large nodes have a greater repulsive force when connected by links and smaller nodes do OK.
That's all for now in the next video.
We'll throw another wrench into these simulations by making the nodes interactive so that we can drag
them around the SPG area.
I'll see you in the next video.