Welcome back in the previous video we discussed the third rule for determining the value of the key
word this the explicit binding.
We learned that using call apply or bind can change the value of the key word this.
Now let's see how we can fix our previous issue with call the first code block is identical to what
we saw before.
But let's see what's happening in the second section.
Previously we were calling person dog that say hello which was returning.
Hello undefine.
This happened because the value of the key word this inside of the say hello function referred to the
dog object which does not have a first name property since we are using call we can now change what
we want the value of the key word this to be.
So let's change it to be the person object.
Now that we've done that we can see that the function returns hello cold and our issue is fixed.
We can also use the term in context function inside of the dog object and change the value of the key
word this to make the function return true.
One important thing to notice is that we are not invoking the say hello or determine context method
we just attach call onto it.
So there are no parentheses after say hello and determine Pontiac's when we use call very commonly calls
used to help avoid code duplication like this example below.
Here we have two objects cold and L.E. which both have a first name property and a say hi method.
All this code works totally fine.
We're repeating ourselves quite a bit inside of the highly object to say hi method inside of the elhi
object is identical to the same high method inside of the code object.
How can we refactor our code and get rid of the Say hi method inside of the object what we'd like to
do is use the say hi method from the cult object.
But instead of the keyword this referring to the cult object we want to explicitly set it to be the
only object CAUSLEY video now and see if you can figure out how to do this using Paul.
All right let's take a look at a solution.
We remove the say hi method from the alii object and we are using the call method to set the value of
the keyword this to be only when the say hide method is invoked.
The first parameter to call is what we want the value of the keyword this to refer to.
We call that the list arke.
Once again this stuff is quite challenging.
So if you're feeling a bit confused look at the previous slide and make sure you take these examples
to see exactly what's going on.
Now let's take our example one step further and create a say high function that anyone can use instead
of attaching the same high function onto the cult object.
Let's make it a standalone function.
Here's what that might look like.
Now how can we use the say hi method and have the value of the keyword this be called or L-E we can
use call to do it.
We now have created a standalone function that can be used in many different cases.
Awesome.
So what else might we use call.
Let's imagine we want to select all the divs on some page.
We might do that using the Get elements by CAGNY method and that would return a list of dead elements
to us.
But what if we want to find all the divs that have the text Hello and return an array of them.
Filter would be wonderful.
But the device variable is not an array.
So filter does not exist on it.
The issue here is that Argives variable is an array like object.
So it would be really nice if we could convert our array like object into an array and we can do that
using the array that slice method but with a slight modification instead of the target of slice the
key word this being that array.
Let's set the target of the key word this to be our diverse array like object.
Here's what that might look like.
We are setting the target of the slice function to be the array like object.
And after we do that we can use the filter method.
What we're doing is trying to slice something that is not actually an array in javascript slice will
not work with all data types but it works very well on array like objects in the next video.
We'll take a look at apply and how that can be quite useful as well.
See there.