Welcome back in the section we're going to talk about another array method some.
So far we've seen four each which iterates over an array and runs a callback function on each value
in the array and returns undefined.
We've also seen map which is very similar to for each except it returns a new array to us with the same
one epts we saw filter which returns an array of the same or different month depending on if those values
in the array have returned true.
From the callback function.
Now let's take a look at the SUM function.
This function is called on arrays and iterates through each value in the array.
It runs a function on each value in the array.
And if the callback returns true for at least one value the entire function returns true.
Otherwise it returns false.
The idea here is that if some of the values passed of the callback return true the entire function returns
true just like filter.
The result of the callback will always be evaluated to a boolean.
Let's see an example here we have a variable called R.
And it is assigned to an array with the numbers 1 2 and 3 on the next line we are invoking the sum function
on the array and passing a callback the value index an array.
We do not need all of these parameters.
This is just to show you that you can access them if you need inside of the callback function where
returning an expression which evaluates to a boolean.
We are checking to see if the value is less than 2 as long as there is at least one value in this array
that is less than 2.
The entire function will return true.
So if you run this code some will return true.
This is the first time that we're seeing an array method that doesn't return a new array or undefined
to us.
Some will always return true or false.
Now if we change this condition to see if the value is greater than 4.
None of these values will return TRUE from that expression.
So the entire function returns false.
Now that we have an idea of how to use the sum function let's try to implement our own version.
Let's remember how some works.
It iterates through an array runs a callback on each value in the array.
And if the callback returns true for at least one value the entire sum function returns true.
Otherwise it returns false.
Just like before.
Feel free to pause the video if you'd like to try to do this on your show.
All right.
Let's create a function called sum which accepts an array and callback.
And instead of this function I'll start with a for loop and initialize a variable.
I had zero I'll loop as long as I'm less than the length of the array and I'll increment by one after
each iteration inside of the loop.
I'll check to see if the callback when passed the value index an array returns true if it does I'll
just return true right away and exit the loop and function.
No need to keep iterating if the loop has finished and we have not returned true and none of our values
have satisfied the condition.
So we need to return false from our function.
Now let's see how we can use some in our own functions.
Here we have a function called has even number which accepts an array and returns the result of the
sum function where a value is divisible by 2.
Notice the two returned keywords.
Just like with map and filter Woelfel you're starting to see the pattern here.
If we pass in an array with at least one even value the function will return true.
Otherwise the return false.
Let's see another function called has Khama which accepts a string and returns true if the string contains
at least one comma in this function and converting the string into an array using the split function
and then using the sum function on that array in the callback.
I'm checking to see if the character I'm at is a comma.
Is any of these characters or a comma.
The entire function will return true in the next video.
We'll look at a very similar function called every Seether.