It with a couple of small c s s fixes to make.
So if it were to refresh this page you would see that this log out and new message don't really look
as good as the sign up and log in.
So if we were to take a look at what's going on here probably has something to do you know an app.
Yes.
I just make sure that the HD is the same and there we go.
It's not.
I just added an extra dash which is not a valid bootstrap class.
That will fix most of our issues.
Let's go take a look at this image timeline.
And as for this image timeline here we're going to read a little bit of our own s s.
Let's go back to our index that's the SS and target the classic timeline image will give us a border
radius of 50 pixels get a nice circular image.
We'll make sure that we have some height on this image that he thinks to be 40 pixels and that 40 pixels
who also had a with 40 pixels a little bit of margin so add two pixels 3D pixels 10 and 10.
That should give us a little breathing room will also make sure that all of our buttons when we hover
over them have a cursor pointer and for any of our buttons that are anchor tags that have a class of
PTEN danger and undercover States as well.
We want to make sure that these all have a color away.
It's going to be a bit easier and cleaner to see the.
So take a look.
And that looks much better right away.
So you can go to any message that says delete me the message.
You can see that delete button looks a lot cleaner.
Let's also move the logo to the center so to the class of Napp are Hetter going to be sure and targeting
that anywhere else.
So we don't duplicate that rule.
So at a margin of 0 1 and just essential that and that looks good right over there in the middle.
You can now log out.
We can sign up that whatever functionality we want here.
E-mails this is still valid.
We don't have a photo here and that's OK.
Maybe I'm a server will want to validate e-mail address and so on.
But that's a lot of additional functionality that you can make a new message.
That's as awesome an average to leave a message.
Looks like that's working.
Let's also find a valid image that when you sign up we make sure that that's working.
So we'll put in some dummy information right here.
And here let's go.
Gotta admit you are out of HTP colon slash slash Lauren Fix all dot com slash 200 slash 200 and let's
give that a second.
Lauren pixel sometimes takes a little bit of a while.
So let's go make a new message.
Hello.
Well that I'll give that a second.
And there we go.
Nice picture of a dog.
So are images working need to leave functionally working and functionality all backed by a mongo database.
With persistence done all on the front and back and using redux or hydrating we're doing all sorts of
really nice things in this application to make it work.
So we'll talk about in and off with is adding a little bit more functionality and deploying this to
rogue.