Welcome back.
In this video will quickly recap what we've learned over the past couple videos we can easily create
constructor functions and prototype methods using the class keyword.
But just remember that the class keyword is an abstraction of using functions and objects.
Yes 22:18 does not add any built in support for classes under the hood.
We're still using all the same tools we saw with yes 5 constructor functions and prototypes to add class
methods with yes 2015.
We do not place them directly on the constructor.
We use the static keyword and to implement inheritance we use the extends keyword and use super to invoke
methods by the same name in the parent class.
Finally all the yes 20:15 class syntax we've seen is an abstraction of using functions and objects.
There are quite a few people in the javascript community who do not strongly endorsed these new features
because of the abstraction.
But you will see the Klasky keyword quite frequently in frameworks like re-act angular and much more.
Thanks again for watching these videos.
Looking forward to each of you some more.
Yes 2015.