Welcome back in the last video we built a simple pie chart now that we've got the basics in this video.
I'd like to get the range impot working so that we can see how our data changes over time.
I'd also like to talk about a few other enhancements we can make to our pie charts with D-3.
First let's tackle this range and put to start I'll calculate the maximum year using D-3.
This will then allow me to set the min max and value properties on the input with javascript next.
I'd like to add an event listener for input events on the range input.
Here's where I'd like to do things a bit differently.
As you may recall from the histogram videos I ended up with a fair amount of duplication between the
code that set up the graph and the code that updated the graph inside of my event handler.
In the solution video to the histogram exercise we saw that one way to avoid this duplication was to
write a helper function that's responsible for rendering the graph using the general update pattern
so that's what I'd like to do here.
I'll write a function called Make Grath which takes a year as its argument inside of this function.
I'll move the code that filters my data set so that only values matching the year variable are kept
also moved my code that uses D-3 that pie and D-3 got arc into this function in the last video.
We only needed to use the Enter selection to get our graphs to show up but in order to make our code
more flexible we'll need to use the general update pattern as we've seen before.
First need to grab the update selection and store it in a variable.
Then I'll hop into the exits and remove any unnecessary arcs next or move to the enter selection.
Append a path element for each new piece of data and give any new arcs a class of Arc.
Finally merge the enter an update selections and set each Arc's fill stroke and D attribute just like
before.
Now that I have this function I can use it in two places first.
I'll use it when the script loads and passing me near.
Second I can use this function inside of my event handler and pass it the event target value converted
into a number let's save and refresh great this range input seems to be working.
There are a couple of small enhancements we can make to our graphs as well.
If you want to set padding between wedges you can set it either on D-3 that guy or D-3 that arc on D-3
are.
You can also run the corners if your wages which can be a nice enhancement.
If you're using padding take a look at how these two lines change the shape of our graph.
Also it's important to note that you can change the default sort order for your arcs in the last video.
We learned that the PI generator automatically sorts arx by value larger arcs come first.
But if you want to sort by something other than value you can use the sort method on the generator and
passing your own comparator function.
The sort method will run over pairs of data points.
Call them a and b if A's should come before B in the chart.
The competitor should return a negative number if a should come after me the comparatives should return
a positive number.
And if you are indifferent between a and b the function should return 0.
Here's a quick example.
Suppose you wanted to visualize your data group by continent and then by birth count.
We could use the sort method and pass in a competitor that checks the continent property on a and b
if A's continent comes before B's alphabetically.
This comp. should return minus one if A's continent comes after the comp. should return plus one.
Otherwise the two data points have the same continent and we can simply return the difference in their
birth counts.
Let's save and refresh as you can see now all of the arcs of the same color are grouped together.
That's it for pie charts.
By this point you've seen how to create a wide variety of visualizations with the three try to apply
what you've learned in the exercises for this section.
In our next set of ideas we'll talk about some enhancements you can make to the graphs you've already
created.
I'll see you in the next video.