All right.
So if you can tell by now that fetch is cool.
It's easy to use.
It's a lot cleaner shorter and more modern than having to write a bunch of essay charts all over the
place.
So what's not to love.
Well the main problem at the moment has to do with browser support.
So this is the most recent browser compatibility chart from the MDA docs.
And as you can see there's a lot of no support for some experimental features.
OK that seems fine but everything supports that looks like nothing does.
But this is a big problem.
Internet Explorer has no basic support for French at the moment.
So keep that in mind if you're using it.
It's also the reason that I'm going to show some libraries right after this video that can help you
get around that.
So wrap that up.
I like fetch.
You should like fetch.
But keep in mind it does not currently work in Internet Explorer which is a big bummer.
So now we're going to talk about Jay queery in x years.