Welcome back.
In this video we're going to discuss a very useful operator that as 2015 gives us cover the rest.
Operator which collects the remaining arguments to a function and returns them to us in an array.
Let's see what we mean with an example.
I'm going to write a function called Print arguments which accepts three parameters a b and using the
rest operator.
The rest of the arguments.
Notice that we're using three dots to denote the rest operator inside of this function.
I'm going to print out each of these parameters so let's cancel that log a cancelled out log B and cancel
it out log C notice that we are only using the three dots when defining the parameters to a function.
Now let's see what happens when I invoke this function.
Notice that A and B are numbers but C is an array of all the arguments.
Pretty neat.
But when is this useful.
You may work on problems where you need to access the arguments array like object and manipulate it.
But since the keyword arguments is not actually an array you can't use methods like for each map or
filter unless you convert it into an array which is a bit tedious.
Let's see what we mean by that.
Here we have a function called some arguments which iterates over the arguments array like object.
Notice that we can use a for loop because even though the arguments array like object is not exactly
an array it still has a length property inside of the for loop.
We're building a total which consists of each argument added together when the for loop is done.
We return the total if we wanted to we could get a little fancier and convert the arguments array like
object into an array using slice and call.
If you're not exactly sure what's going on here we're using the slice method on an array.
But setting what we would like to slice as the arguments array like object using Dom call.
Now that we have an array we can use the reduced method to sum all of these values.
This will do the same thing as above.
How can the rest operator help us.
Let's see how this would work in 2015.
Don't be too scared by this solution.
We're using the rest operator as well as aero functions to write a concise solution.
We're using the rest operator to gather all the arguments as an array so that we don't need to use the
array like object arguments were then doing the same exact reduce as above but using an arrow function
so we can place it all on one line to really reinforce these concepts.
Try running them in the chrome Council to see how they work in the next video.
We'll see the same three dots but not used as a parameter to a function.
See that.