In the previous video we saw some good use cases for call and apply.
We saw how to explicitly set the context of the keyword this and pass arguments to the function that
is being altered by call or apply.
In the case of call arguments are passed as comma separated values and with Apply arguments are passed
as values in an array and works just like call.
But instead of immediately invoking the function it returns a new function to us with the keyword this
bound to the value that we pass as the first parameter to bind.
So when is bind useful one common use case is when we do not know all of the arguments that will be
passed to a function which means we do not want to invoke the function right away.
We just want to return a new function with some of the parameters.
We call this partial application.
In the example below we can see that bind is returning a function to us.
So we still need to add an extra set of parentheses to call that function.
What's neat about bind is that we do not need to know all the parameters to the function when we bind
it.
We only need to know what we want.
The value of the key word this to be it's a bit tricky.
So make sure to pause the video and take the examples on the slide and play around with partial application.
Another very common use case of BIND is to set the context of the keyword this for a function that will
be called at a later point in time.
Very commonly that happens when dealing with asynchronous code or code that does not run line by line.
Before we take a look at these examples let's quickly review the asynchronous set time out method set
time out is a method on the window object that is used to execute a function of once after a specified
amount of time.
Remember that said timeout is a method on the window object.
That's something we're going to need to know for a later example.
The first parameter set timeout is a function to be executed.
And the second parameter is the amount of time in milliseconds to wait before executing the function.
Let's code a quick example and cancel that log.
Hello world.
After 20 seconds I'm going to invoke a set time out and as the first parameter passed in a function
that will cancel out log hello world after 20 seconds.
Now that I have called this I can do other things like to find new variables or continue running code.
This is what we mean by asynchronous.
Our code is not blocked while we wait for 20 seconds.
We can do other things while we wait in the next video.
We'll come back to talking about the key word this.
And take a look at a tricky example where bind really helps us out.
See that.