Welcome back.
We've learned a lot about forced directed graphs but so far we haven't been able to apply what we've
learned to a real world data set.
In this video we'll dig into a data set for an actual network along the way.
We'll also see how to update our simulation if the number of nodes changes.
Here's a link to some starter code.
As you can see I've already thrown together some HVM elenchi SS in the app genius.
He's in D-3 that cxxviii to grab some ESV data on United States senators.
There are 100 senators in the United States most of whom are either Democrat or Republican this data
from 20:17 highlights which senators are on different committees one in one of the committee Gollum's
indicates that a senator is on that committee.
I'd like to visualize this data as a force directed graph in order to see what the relationships are
between senators on these committees.
I'd also like to toggle which committees I care about and have the graph only show senators from those
committees.
This will involve the general update pattern.
Since I'll need to add or remove nodes and links based on the committees I've selected.
First though let's just get all of our data showing up on the page.
Notice that I'm formatting this data so that each node has the name of the senator their party and a
list of the committees their own.
I can get all of the committees without too much trouble.
Remember that the third argument in the form matter is an array of all the CSP headers.
The first and second header are named party.
But after that the remaining headers are all committee names.
This filter gives me an array of committees for each senator.
One of the challenges was building a force directed graphs that you'll rarely find both Noad and link
data readily available.
Instead you often need to generate one of these sets of data yourself.
In this case I've got data on the nodes from this ESV but I don't have an explicit Lincs array consisting
of objects with source and target properties.
So the first thing I'll do is write a function called make links that will take in my array of nodes
and generate the appropriate link structure for the simulation in order to generate links.
I'll first create an empty WINX array then I'll write a double for loop over my nodes so that I can
look at every pair of senators inside this nested loop.
I'll store each node in a variable and then look over all of the committees in the first note if any
one of those committees is also in the second nodes list.
Then that means these two senators are on a committee together and I should create a link.
I only need to create the link once even if the senators are on more than one committee together.
So after this I can break out of the innermost loop.
Finally I want to return miling Saray let's console log the return value to make sure this looks good
as you can see there are over 1000 links.
This is something you'll need to watch out for.
In general the number of links can be very large compared to the number of nodes in the worst case where
every node is joined to every other node.
The number of links is roughly proportional to the square of the number of nodes.
Now that I've got my nodes in my links I'll set up the force directed graph.
This is something we've done before so I'll move a little more quickly here.
First I'll store my links in a variable then I'll set up my SPG in the usual way.
I'll also create groups for my links in my notes.
Next I'll start my simulation by passing in my nodes.
Adding a center force of many body force and a linked force
I'll make the many body force stronger than the default and to help spread out the nodes all increase
the distance property for links to senators that are on multiple committees.
I also need to specify that the senator's name should be used as the ID for the link.
After that I'll need to use the same pattern that we saw before inside of the event handler for tick
events on the simulation after each tick only to update the position of each line in the linked group
and each circle in the node group.
This should take care of the simulation.
Next let's write out the code we'll need to get these SVGA elements to show up on the page.
Since I'll be using the general update pattern I'll write a general function called graph which takes
in an array of nodes and an array of links inside of this function.
I'll first generate a color scale for my notes.
Democrats will be blue Republicans will be red and I'll make independents Gray next.
I'll use the general update pattern for nodes and links only to use key functions here.
Since I'll be adding and removing elements based on the committees I care about for node's I can use
the senator's name as the key.
Then I'll paste in cover the update pattern we've seen so often before I'll do the same thing with links.
Though there's no styling on me to do here.
Note also what I'm using is the key oinks target may not be unique but the combination of target name
and source name will be let me call this graph function and pass in my data.
Now when I save and refresh my nodes are showing up great before adding functionality to add or remove
nodes.
Let me quickly add the drag functionality we saw previously as well as an tooltip logic.
I'll just paste in this code.
The drag and drop is the same as we saw on the last video and the tooltip logic is very similar to what
we've seen before too.
The biggest change to the tooltip code is in the rendered page.
Now here I am creating an ordered list of all the committees that a senator is on let's save saving
refresh good.
It looks like this is a working.
Now let's do something we haven't done before.
Had the ability to update the number of nodes and links in the simulation.
What I'd like to do is add a bunch of checkboxes to the page one for each committee.
Initially all of the committees will be checked but if a user unchecked one of the committees I want
to ignore that committee from the visualization and remove any nodes or links based on that committee
do this or write a function called set up checkboxes this function will take an array of committee names
and they will generate the checkboxes on that page as well as manage the event handling for clicks on
the checkboxes.
First let me build all of the checkboxes.
I could do this by hardcoded TNL but assuming I already have a list of committee names I can also just
select my checkboxes div make an M.D. selection join to my array of committees and append.
I store the selection in a variable because I need to use it twice once to make labels for the checkboxes
and once to make the checkboxes themselves for the checkboxes.
I'll give them all a name property of committee and a value based on the data.
They'll all start out as checked but the click handler is where the real complexity lies.
When someone clicks on a checkbox I'll use a filter to grab an array of all committees that are currently
checked.
Then I'll map over my nodes and return a new collection of nodes where each senator has list of committees
only includes the ones that are checked.
I could use an object that to sign here for now I'll keep things simple.
Note that I also need to carry over the properties from the simulation.
Otherwise the animation won't be smooth when I click on a checkbox.
Once I have this new collection of nodes I'll filter over it to remove any senators that are only on
the committees that have been unchecked.
Then I'll create a new set of links based on these new notes.
After that I'll update the graph.
Then I'll call my setup checkboxes function and passing the columns for my nodes ignoring name and party.
Note that you get this column's property for free whenever you import data from CXXVI using D-3.
I haven't quite done enough.
The simulation breaks when I update the graph alone.
I also need to update the simulation by passing in the new nodes and the new links after that.
Also warm up the simulation a bit so that the nodes will rearrange themselves based on the new forces.
Let's save and try again.
Now you can see that if I want to ignore certain committees I can.
The simulation will update based only on the committees I'm interested in.
I haven't added any transitions here or any visual cues for the committees and the styling of the page
is definitely a bit lacking.
So there's more work to do here if you'd like to continue working on this visualization when you're
ready.
Feel free to move on to the final project where you can continue to build on your understanding of the
advanced graph types that you've explored here.
I'll see you in the next video.