Are right it's time to deploy the front end portion of this application.
So once again I'm going to remove this docket folder so that I can put it in its own separate repository
instead of one parent repository for the client and server model.
So I'm going to get in it and then I'm going to place my node modules please that text inside of a dot
get ignore file.
You could do this however you'd like I'm just doing this as an easy way in the command line but this
will ensure that when I add and commit my node modules are not included which will just take additional
amounts of time if they are.
So what we need to do now is create a Heroku application.
But instead of just doing Heroku create We're going to use a build pack which is simply a collection
of tools given to us to allow for an easier time deploying this application.
So we're going to take a look at Create react and Heroku.
And this is going to take us to create react and build pack which includes quite a few other things
that we're going to use especially for proxying our backend.
So in order to get started with this we can follow the instructions right here on the left and we've
already done the Create react tap and the get in it.
We're going to go from this step right here.
This Heroku create.
So what I'll do is I'll copy and paste this.
And when I paste I'm just going to press control C right away to stop that because I don't want to call
this dollar sign.
Aptonym I'm going to call this something like warbler client.
Yes just for my initials.
We want to make sure that we use this build pack so that we get some built in configuration settings
that will make deploying much much easier.
When that's done here's what it should look like.
Now the next thing we can do is add and commit and push to Heroku.
But there's one thing we need to do first we need to make a file called static dot Jason.
And inside of our static dodgiest on we're going to place some logic related to our re-act router and
for proxying.
So we're going to start here with a key called root and the value is build slash.
And this simply means where should we start serving content from.
And when we deploy our application there's a script that's run which is this built script right here
that will modify and compress our assets and really make our application production ready.
So inside our static Jaison We're also going to include a key of routes and the value of slash.
Star Star which means basically any route that we go to fall back into the index that each time I'll
file is a file that really kicks off our re-act application.
We're also going to pass in a key of proxies.
And here is where we're going to specify a proxy that we have anytime that we go to slash API.
And anytime that we go to slash API the origin or you are all that we want to point to is each colon
slash slash warbler Dasch server dasht vs Heroku app dot com that's the server side application that
I just deployed.
You would call yours whatever you want right here.
So we're going to see this right now going to go back to the terminal and I'm going to add and I'm going
to commit and here will say ready to deploy.
And then going to get push
Heroku master and this will deploy my code to Heroku.
And as I do this I'm going to check in on my server side application and take a look at the logs right
now because if we're doing this correctly we should see requests being made there as well.
So I'm going to take in Heroku logs Dashti dash a warbler server.
Yes.
And this is going to show me the tail end of my logs.
And as new requests come in I'll see them in this window in the terminal.
So I'll give this a second to deploy and once this is done we should be able to type in Heroku open
and press enter and they should open up a browser with our application and we take a look right here.
It looks good.
We're deployed.
Now let's try to sign up.
When I click sign up I'm going to go to test at gmail dot com.
We'll put in a password of secret a user name of secret and let's try to sign up.
And when I sign up we can see right here.
That our node application is getting started looks like it was just kind of falling asleep for a bit.
This is what happens when you use the free tear on Heroku.
So right now we can just see that we made a post request to slash off slash Sign-Up.
Let's try this again now that it's actually working.
So I'll go back to slash sign up and what I put in is a sign up and I'll go to secret at gmail dot com
with a password of secret username of secret and let's click.
Sign me up and right here it's going to say not found.
So the reason we're getting this not found is because we need to add one more thing to our static Jaison.
If you notice here we're going to slash off slash Sign-Up.
But the problem is this should all be prefixed with Slash API.
So inside of you we're going to make sure that we add a slash API in our static Jaison when we're dealing
with things on Heroku we also need to make sure we add again.
We're going to commit saying adding API to end of proxy and let's make sure we push this up again.
So we're going to get push Heroku M. It's a pretty common mistake.
Just forgot the slash API here.
Otherwise it's going to take every single u r l and add the path onto it.
So let's make sure that we add that slash API as well.
We'll give this a second to deploy.
Now there are lots of other configuration settings we can make for production.
You can see right here there is some environment variables that I haven't set but I want to just start
really simply get this up in a production environment and then you can alter whatever you'd like.
So let's give this a second to deploy.
Once again let's type in Heroku open and let's make sure we saw that correctly.
This should open up a browser with our Heroku application.
Let's keep these server side logs open and try to sign up again.
So I'll sign up with user at gmail dot com password secret username secret and let's click sign up and
it says that username or emails already taken.
OK let's try a user plus one at gmail dot com.
Let's click sign up.
And here we get that user name is already taken.
So it looks like we might already have that in our database.
So let's try something else.
We'll try another at g mail dot com and we'll have a password of secret and a user name of another.
Let's try this right now.
Well click sign me up and there we go.
Looks like we're logged in and I don't have a profile image or I'll here that's OK.
Let's go out a new message of hello world.
Let's go at that message and there it is.
Looks like someone else had a message previously.
So when I click on this right here to go back I can log out and it looks like our application is working.
We can see that all our server side logs are coming in and we make requests.
With these new users or other user names we can see the Mongul queries being run to make sure we're
doing this correctly.
So what we want to do is make sure that in our static Jaison we have the slashy API at the end here.
What this means is that any you are l that matches slashy API in my client side application will be
sent to this u r l right here and we're also going to make sure we add a slash API at the end there
that will make sure that those Uriel's match.
So it looks like our client side application is deployed as well.
Our server side application is deployed as well and we have an application in production.