Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over solutions to the maps and sets exercises.
The first thing we need to do is create a class for a message board.
And in our constructor we'll assign a property called messages to be a new map and a property of ID
to start off as one.
Just make sure you attach these properties onto the keyword.
This the first instance method we need to implement is add a message here.
We're going to pass in a parameter an inside the message is map set the key of the ID and the value
with the parameter passed to the function will that increment the ID and return the instance so that
we can change the method.
The next method we need to implement is Find Message by ID which except some ID and returns a message
here it will just return the stop messages and use the get method and pass and Id next.
Let's implement Find Message by value here we're passing in a value and we need to iterate over all
of the values in the message as map.
Let's use a for loop and see if the message we are iterating over is the same as the value passed to
the function.
If so we'll return that found message the next method we need to implement is remove message which accepts
an ID and uses the delete method on maps to remove that message.
Let's also return the object created from this class but we would also call an instance so that we can
change the method.
The next method we need to implement is number of messages which just returns this stop messages dioxides.
Remember maps have a size property to tell us how many elements are in it.
The last method we need to implement is messages to array here.
We can use the Handy yes 2015 array from and past in the messages that values function to easily convert
this into an array of messages.
The next function we need to implement is unique values which accepts an array and returns the number
of unique values in the array.
This is a great case for a set.
So let's just return a new set with that array passed to it and return the size property to see how
many values are in that set.
Remember sets only contain unique values for the next function has duplicates.
We can simply compare the size of the set from an array and the length of that array.
If they are the same this function should return false.
Otherwise it will return true.
And we have duplicates the last method we need to implement is count pairs.
What we'll do here is create a new set from the array pass to the function.
We'll be using this to see if the other pair exists will then initialize account a 0 and iterate through
the array and at each value remove that value from the set.
This will prevent us from dealing with a pair of the same number.
We'll then see if the set has the complement to the pair.
And if it does will increment the count once we're done iterating will return the count from our function.
The algorithm we've written will try to find the complement of the pair or what other number needs to
exist to sum to the second parameter.
This one is a bit tricky but try to code it on your own so you can see exactly how it's working in the
next section.
We'll see how yes 2015 and help us manage asynchronous code using promises.
See there.