Next up we'll talk about promises.
Now We'll also visit this topic later in the course but it's important to see it here before we talk
about asynchronous code and Ajax in the next section.
So let's get two objectives.
First will define and promise then we'll add a dot then call back to a promise then a dot catch call
back to a promise.
Lastly will wrap a set time out with a promise to create an asynchronous example.
So what is a promise.
A promise is an object that represents a task that will be completed in the future.
So you're getting back an object that isn't the solution to your problem but it will be the solution
in the future.
An analogy here is if you go into a government office and you take a number to get helped.
That is like your promise that piece of paper represents a promise to be helped and once you actually
go to the counter and get help hopefully pretty quickly.
That's like your callback being invoked.
So getting the ticket is your promise and getting help or getting the resolution to your problem later
on is the callback later getting invoked.
Here's an example of creating a promise.
First we are using the promise constructor.
The constructor takes a single callback function that function has two parameters either a resolve function
or a reject function.
So our asynchronous task will decide whether or not to call or invoke resolve or reject depending on
how the asynchronous task goes.
So if the asynchronous task completed successfully resolve will be invoked but if it didn't complete
successfully if there was some error reject will be invoked.
Now once we've created this problem is we have the object as one.
The next thing we want to do is define a callback in the then function.
So with this one dot then we're defining a callback that will be invoked when resolve is invoked inside
of the promise.
So one two three four here gets passed into this callback that gets invoked and then you can see here
will cancel log promised P1 resolve with data 1 2 3 4.
Let's take a look at that in the console as well.
So I got my promise P1 and then I'm going to specify that then callback which will invoke this callback
function whenever resolve is invoked.
And as you can see P1 has been resolved with the data.
One two three four.
So this console that log came from within our callback function inside of then
our previous example only handled the successful promise.
So it only handled the case where resolve was invoked but reject can also be invoked from the promise.
So in this example we've got our same promis setup we're creating a new promis with the constructor
and we have either resolved function that we can invoke or the regex function.
And here we're invoking rejects when reject is invoked from within the promise.
None of the data then callbacks will be invoked.
So instead we'll go directly to this catch section catch is the callback that will be invoked whenever
reject is invoked from within the promise so in this example we'll only see promise one was rejected
with data air in the con..
And where did that air come from.
Well just like before when we invoke rejects the string the replacing here air will be passed into this
callback in the catch.
So our data here is going to be equal to the string air that was passed from object and then it will
be Konsole logged here in our consul.
In this example we're combining both the resolve and the reject.
So here we have a 50/50 chance of either invoking resolve or invoking reject depending on what our random
number returns.
So if resolve is invoked we'll pass that number that was randomly generated and we should see in the
con. success and whenever that number was if we get a number that's greater than 0.5 and reject is invoked
then we'll see console log air and we'll see whatever value we've got there.
So let's see this running in the consul
so because we're using a random number here we don't know if we'll get a success or an error.
Let's take a look.
All right we've got success which means our random number was point to five and resolve was in boats.
Let's try again.
Success again.
Let's try to get on air.
There we go.
So now we got a random number that was greater than 0.5 which then invoked rejects and we got our air
Prince the consul air points 7 9 1 1 etc..
Next we'll see an example that actually use asynchronous code.
So all the examples we've seen so far don't really have an asynchronous component.
Whether invoking resolve or reject right away.
But here we've got a set time out inside of the promise.
So this promise will be created the set time out will be invoked and then four seconds later four thousand
milliseconds will invoke resolve.
So now you can begin to see the beauty of the promise even though this code won't have finished running
yet will have an object already that we can attach a callback on to.
So this promise objects will immediately be returned even though the set time out is not done and resolve
has not been called.
And then we can decide what callback functions we want to add to that then.
So inside this DOD then function we're providing this callback which will console log random pass to
resolve and be random and that we got.
Let's see how this looks and the consul.
So I've got a code here.
And remember this promise will be created first before the set time out finishes and resolves.
So when I hit enter here we've got our promise and we're going to wait for seconds before we see the
results which is now printed here.
Random passed to resolve three.
So think about the stack again.
All of these functions are off of the stack before the set timeout gets invoked and then resolve gets
invoked which will in turn call callback function
will end our video here.
Next up we'll talk about more advanced concepts with promises.