Okay the next property we're taking a look at it's called order and order is another one of those that
applies to the individual items in a flex container rather than to the flex container or to the parent
on the whole.
So instead it applies to items and what it allows us to do is we can specify in order for how things
should be displayed inside a flex container so we can write them one way in the time out in the markup
and without changing that at all.
WE CAN YOU SEE assess and reorder them so that the user will see them in a different order.
And that's particularly useful when you're working with responsive layouts.
You might want things to be in one order in a wide layout and then you might switch them up.
When you go to a mobile lab for example.
So the way that it works it's kind of unintuitive at first.
So if we tried to say Box 1 and in reset order to be two you might expect that box one would just move
to position two.
But what actually happens is it goes to the very end.
Well that's kind of weird.
What's happening is that by default everything has an order of zero.
So when we set something to have order of two we're not specifying position two.
We're saying that everything has an order of zero by default.
But this one other item has an order of two.
Well two should go at the end then because that's the greatest number.
But we can take advantage of the fact that all items by default have order of zero by using negative
numbers.
So if I set box three to have order if negative when it comes to the beginning.
So if I actually wanted to do something like make Box 1 the second box in line like we have here so
goes to 1 3 4.
It's a little more involved.
I need to specify box one has an order of 2 box to has an order of 1 and box 3 and 4 have an order of
three and we could do other numbers to be clear.
It doesn't matter 1 2 and 3 as long as they come in the correct order from lowest to greatest I could
use negative numbers.
I could use 110 111 112.
It doesn't matter.
What's more important.
The only thing that matters is how they relate to one another.
So you wouldn't typically have something like this where you're giving every single thing in order.
Usually when you're reordering content you know if you wanted to do something like that you just have
to think swap.
You would probably just do that in your markup where it's more common as if you have something at the
end you want to move it to the beginning or you have two things that you want to come after another
two in the case of a mobile lay out.
Imagine if this is collapsing.
Well I guess I could do that.
You won't really see what I'm talking about but imagine that that's happening and we want these four
and the two to go off on their own and disappear or go to a second line.
Maybe these are advertisements and this is our main content in the middle.
I could use order to facilitate that.
So that's a more typical use case.
Let's play around with it briefly.
So we have our container and our flex items.
We have nine of them let's say lucky number seven.
So again if I go to box 7 and I just say Order eight just put to that yet because Box number 7 has an
order of 8.
Everything else has a order of zero.
So goes the end.
But then if I come and do Box 1 and I say that has an order of seven.
It almost moves the end but not quite.
Because box 7 has an order of eight.
So these all have order of zero.
And then this has seven.
And then it says eight and I was kind of confusing when there's also numbers on these boxes but that's
how it works.
And let's say I wanted to have box 9 go to the very beginning which is the easiest way to do that.
Give it a negative one or negative anything.
So let's do that box 9 order negative 9 never go and I could change it to negative 100.
Same thing.
But as soon as I give it a positive number it goes back to where it was because all of these have zeros
and if I gave it 10 it would go to the very end or 100.
OK.
So I think you get that by now.
By default the order is zero.
And most of the time when we're working with orders I usually keep things that order zero.
And then the thing is I'm manipulating.
I move them to the end or the beginning using negative one or one.
Let me also add that if I change our flex direction to ro reverse we go from nine to one.
In this case visually that's what happens.
But remember it's just our main access goes from right to left.
So if I want to reorder something I go box nine and I say Order is negative to it hops to the beginning
even though it's moving to the right.
This is where the main axis starts and it goes that way.
Sometimes students do get confused about that because they're just used to things going from left to
right.
But we're changing the main axis direction and that's what indicates or determines the order.
OK let's go back to our regular room.
And that's it.