Welcome back.
In this video we're going to look at one last array method.
Reduce reuse can seem a bit confusing at first but we'll break it down step by step to make sure you
really understand it.
The idea behind produce is that we can take an array and turn it into another data structure.
It could be a string a number an object an array of arrays and much more.
The way the reduce works is that it accepts a callback function and an optional second parameter would
use iterates through an array and runs a callback function on each value.
The first parameter to the callback is either the first value in the array or the optional second parameter
that reduce accepts this first parameter to the callback is commonly called the accumulator.
Finally the return value from the callback becomes the new value of the accumulator.
The most important thing to understand about Reduce is that whatever you return from the callback function
becomes the new value of the accumulator.
That's a lot to take in.
So let's diagram this.
We have an array and call reduce on it reduce excepts as its first parameter callback and has a second
parameter an optional starting value the function to reduce except for parameters we'll call the first
parameter accumulator and the second parameter next value the third and fourth parameters are the index
an array just like we saw with the other functions.
So don't worry too much about those.
If we do not pass a second parameter to reduce the value of the accumulator will be the first value
in the array and the next value will be the second value in the array.
You keep understanding reduce is to break it down step by step.
So lets start with a simple example.
As we iterate through the array we're going to see the change in the accumulator and next value what's
with an array of 5 numbers 1 2 3 4 and 5.
Let's invoke the reduced method on this array.
And inside of here we'll return the sum of accumulator Plus next value.
Remember you mentioned that when you do not pass the second parameter to reduce the value of the accumulator
starts as the first value in the array.
In our case 1 and next value will be the following value in the array which is the number 2.
So in the first iteration accumulator is 1 and next value is to the return value from the callback is
1 plus 2.
The most important thing to remember about Reduce is whatever you return to the callback will become
the new value of the accumulator.
So in the next iteration accumulator is 3 and next value is 3 and our return value is 6.
Since we return 6.
The value of the accumulator in the next iteration will be six in the next iteration accumulator is
6 next value is 4.
And our return value is six plus four or 10.
Once again this means that in the next iteration the value of the accumulator will be what we just returned
10 in the final iteration accumulator is 10 and next value is 5 and our return value is 15.
Since there is no next value abuse we'll simply return the value of accumulator Plus next value which
is 15.
Wow that was quite a bit of work.
Just to add numbers in an array but I promised the more you do this the faster easier it will get.
We mentioned that if we do not pass in a second parameter to reduce the accumulator will start as the
first value in the array.
Well if we pass in a second parameter to reduce the value of the accumulator will be in that second
parameter and next value will be the first value in the array.
Let's see what that looks like in this example.
We're working with the same array but in our reduced function we are passing a second parameter with
a value of 10.
This means that the value of the accumulator in the first iteration will be 10 and the value of next
value will be 1 in the first iteration we return 10 Plus 1 or 11 which will be the value of accumulator
at the next iteration before we step to the next set of functions.
Pause the video and try it out on your in the next iteration accumulator is 11 and next value is 2.
So our return value is 13 in the next iteration accumulators 13 next value is 3.
So we return 16 16 is now the value of accumulator and at the next iteration 4 is our next value.
We then return 16 plus 4 which is 20.
And that will be the value of our accumulator in the final iteration.
We now return 20 plus 5s and since there is no next value after we return 25 from our function try to
use Reduce to summer values in an array.
And always remember whatever you return from the callback to reduce will be the value for the accumulator
in the next iteration.
But our common mistake is to not return anything to the callback which will set the value of the accumulator
to be undefine which is what we do not want.
Most of the time in the next video we'll discuss how we can use Reduce to build up other data types
like strings and objects.
Try this with your own simple reduced functions that add numbers in an array and I'll see you in the
next video.