Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over solutions to the inheritance exercises for this exercise.
We need to pass along the methods and properties from the vehicle constructor to a new constructor function
called car and a new constructor function called motorcycle.
First let's make a constructor function for a car inside of here.
We don't need to copy and paste all of the code from the vehicle constructor.
So let's invoke the vehicle constructor using apply passing in the keyword this as the first argument
in order to inherit the start and two string methods from the vehicle prototype.
We need to set up prototype to be an object created from a vehicle prototype so we'll use object that
create to do that on the next line.
We need to make sure that the constructor is reset for the current prototype.
So we'll set up prototype that constructor to be the car constructor will do the same thing for our
motor cycle function here will also use apply passing in the keyword.
This is the first parameter and arguments as the second will then specify this dot number wheels to
be to in order to inherit the two string method from the vehicle that prototype will set.
Motorcycle that prototype to be an object created from vehicle that prototype finally will reset the
constructor on the motorcycle prototype to be the motor cycle function and that's all for the inheritance
exercises.
You in the next video.