Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over solutions to the call apply and bind exercises.
The first function we're going to implement is called array from which accepts an array like object.
Here we're going to return the result of invoking the slice method but using dot call so that the target
of slice is not the array but the array like object.
We can return this value and that's it.
The next function we're going to implement is some even arguments.
The first thing we can do is make a variable which is the result of converting the arguments array like
object into an array.
You could even use your array from function that we just implemented.
Once we've converted the arguments array like object into an array you can call reduce on this array
and incited the callback to reduce check and see if the next value is divisible by 2 and if it is will
return the accumulator Plus the next value.
Otherwise we'll just return the accumulator and make sure that we start a zero for a next function invoke
Max.
We accept some other function and a number of times that it can be called.
The first thing we'll do is declare a variable called Max and assign it to zero will then return another
function.
We're going to be using closure to solve this problem inside of the inner function.
We'll check and see if Max is greater or equal to the number that we passed in to invoke Max.
And if so we'll return the string next out if not we'll increment max by 1 and then return the result
of the function being called with apply.
We don't care about the value of the keyword this.
So we'll just pass in whatever the value of the keyword this is.
At that time.
But we do want to use apply so that we can pass in the array of arguments to the inner function.
Remember arguments for to the arguments passed to the inner function when it is invoked every time a
function gets created.
He gets his own key word this and it's own arguments for the next function once we're going to pass
in a function and some value for the key word this will declare a variable has been called and assign
it to false and then return a function.
Once again we'll be using closures here in the inner function.
We'll check and see if has been called is false and if it is we will set it to True and return the result
of the function that we pass to once invoked using apply here.
We can specify the value of the keyword this and pass in the arguments array like object from the inner
function.
Here's where things get fun for the next function bind.
We're going to pass in some function and some value for the key word.
This first thing we're going to do is create a variable called outer arcs which is the result of the
arguments array like object being converted into an array or going to do here is pass a parameter to
slice.
We want to collect the remaining arguments that get passed to the bind function.
We don't want the first parameter or the second parameter.
We just want any remaining ones.
We're then going to return a function and inside of this inner function we'll make a variable called
Inner arcs which is the result of converting the arguments array like object into an array.
What will then do is make a variable called all arcs or we will concatenate the outer args with the
inner arcs.
The idea here is to build up one large array of arguments which we can pass to apply.
So on the next line of this function we're going to return the result of the original function being
invoked with apply as the first parameter and passing in for the value of the key word.
This our second parameter toboggans.
And then as an array of arguments passing in both the outer and inner ones for a last function Phlip
we're going to accept a parameter and some value for the keyword.
This just like bind.
We're going to collect the remaining arguments passed to flit by converting the array like arguments
into an array and slicing from two.
We're then going to return an anonymous function and inside of this function we'll make a variable called
Inner args just like we did with byde.
However we want to make sure that we invoke our function with only the number of parameters specified.
Since we're going to be calling the arguments in reverse.
So in our all args variable we will concatenate the outer args with the inner parks but we're only going
to make a copy starting from 0 to however many parameters of the function that we pass to flip.
Except this part is hard but all functions actually have a property called length which return the number
of arguments that the function accepts.
We can use the land to figure out exactly how many parameters are all args arrays should include.
Finally we can return the result of invoking the function using apply and as a first parameter specifying
a value for the key word this which we passed in the flip function and as the second parameter will
use are all args variable we'll just have to make sure that we call reverse on are all args variable.
These problems are quite challenging.
So if you couldn't solve them all go back and see if you can try it again.
Feel free to let us know if you get stuck and we'll see you in the next video.