All right.
So we almost made it.
We have one more round to define.
This one is a delete route to the same path as the previous two or we have to do id variable in the
path instead of updating or retrieving information.
We're going to delete that too.
So this is where we would send a request when a user clicks on the trash can or the X button to remove
it to do for good.
We would then send a delete request to this you know of course this idea is going to be 5:06 blah blah
blah a KBG you know what I mean.
The idea itself.
So we're going to do that and to do that we're going to pop over to cloud nine and define our router
dot delete and just copy that.
It's going to be the exact same.
So rather than a put or a get to delete request then we need our Goodall's callback here.
And we can start off with a basic Let's just do a red dot send.
Ok ok i'll delete something.
Just make sure we're able to trigger this and to do that.
We're going to need to use postman again so we can go to the same path we have this idea here but rather
than a PUT are going to find delete.
And let's see what happens.
There we go.
We get ok ok i'll delete something.
So rather than responding with that we need to use DBI to do the magic line is dot remove.
And all we have to do is give it an object that gives it a key and value.
So the key that we want it to remove by it's going to be the ID and the incoming ID is request up harams
dot to do Id.
So whatever this ID is used that to then go find it and delete it.
And then when that's done we're not going to have to do really to send back.
We don't want to do that so we can just rest up and rest.
Jason a message and let's just say message is we deleted it just like that and we'll have to catch that
says if there's an error let's send error.
OK.
So let's make sure that this works.
Restart the server.
Let's send our get request to see all the do's and let's pick one to delete.
Let's get rid of bake croissant.
I no I'm picking on that one.
Let's take that you are well Senator request as a delete request and it says we deleted it.
Let's go back and do a get.
I'll just repeat that get request to slash API slash traduce and it's gone.
So we're done.
It works perfectly.
That's it to delete.
Very simple.
We now have five functioning routes.
All that's left to do in the last video is to refactor this a bit so that our main to use file is a
little less cluttered.
We'll actually reduce it down to five or six lines of route code by moving things into a helper.