Welcome back.
In this video we're going to recap what we've learned about prototypes.
We saw that every time the new keyword is used.
And under Prato property is added to the object created from the constructor function.
The Dunder Prato property leaves the object created from the constructor function to the prototype property
of the constructor function.
This link allows objects created from the constructor function to access methods and properties on the
prototype object.
The prototype property also contains a property called constructor which points back to the constructor
function.
Next we should strive to place properties and methods that we want to share amongst all objects created
from a constructor function in the prototype as these properties and methods only need to be defined
once and not redefined for every single object.
Finally we saw that we can pass methods and properties from one prototype object to another using prototype
all inheritance.
This process involves setting the prototype property to be a newly created object using objects that
create and resetting the constructor property.
Thanks again for watching this section and as always if you have any questions be sure to let us know.
We're always here to help.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next section.