Welcome back in this section we're going to discuss some helpful object enhancements that yes 2015 gives
us.
We're going to start with a new feature called object shorthand notation.
Let's take a look at the object below.
We can see here that the keys and values are the same name.
In 2015 we can refactor this code and if the keys and values have the same name we do not have to repeat
that declaration.
Another nice feature that 2015 gives us is the ability to write succinct object methods.
We're defining a method as a function that is placed on an object.
So let's see what that will look like in S-5.
It should be pretty familiar.
And if you remember back in our discussion on perio functions we mentioned that we should not be using
aero functions as methods in objects.
The reason for this was because our functions do not get their own key word this and we might accidentally
not get the correct value for the keyword that we want in 2015 we simply omit the colon and the function
keyword and place parentheses after the name of our method.
We can see below.
We're not using aero functions for the function keyword.
One last thing we'll look at is a handy feature called computed property names.
That might sound like a lot.
So let's see what we mean within five.
Example You are making a variable called first name and assigning it to the string.
Ellie if we wanted an object to have the key with whatever the value of the first name variable is we
would have to use bracket notation and let javascript evaluate that.
Unfortunately in S-5 we first have to make an object and then assign a value using bracket notation.
In 2015 we can assign a value using bracket notation while defining our object.
Let's see what that looks like here.
We simply add brackets around the name of the key to let javascript compute the name of the property.
That's exactly what computed property names are.
Before we recap what we've learned in this section it's your turn to practice a bit with some 2015 object
enhancements.
Good luck and I'll see you in the next video.