Welcome back in the previous video we saw how to create promises using the promise constructor.
And we saw that we can chain promises together using that in this video.
We're going to discuss a method on the promise constructor called promised dot all promised not all
accepts an array of promises and resolves all of them or is rejected once a single one of the promises
has been rejected.
We call this a fail fast behavior.
If all of the past in promises fulfilled promise that all is resolved with an array of the values from
the past and promises in the same order as they were cast in the promised ball promised that all does
not guarantee that these promises will resolve sequentially that it will return an array of resolve
promises in the same order that you pass them in to the function you may have seen something like this
with dollar signs out when Jake Querrey or.
Q And it's important to note that the promises don't resolve sequentially but promised not all waits
for them to resolve.
Now let's see what it looks like.
Let's make a function called Get movie which returns a promise to us and not invoke the function a few
times.
Remember the value of these variables is a pending promise.
It has not been rejected or resolved.
There is simply a promise for some future.
Now instead of changing all of these promises together with a van and another dot then another dot then
we can simply place them all inside of a promised not all invocation.
Here we see all of the promises being passed in as an array and then resolved as an array of objects
which we can iterate over and print out the year for each one promise that all is easily one of the
most common methods you'll be using with the E.S. 20:15 promise constructor.
So it's essential that you get some practice with it.
Now that you've seen how to work with promises it's your turn to practice a bit.
Good luck on these exercises and I'll see you in the next video.