OK so we have two out of four down the next two properties are transition delay and transition timing
function.
So we're going to start off with delay.
It's pretty simple all that it does is it allows us to specify how long of a pause there should be before
the transition actually begins.
And there are two versions we can use we can pass in a single time like four seconds.
And this would say okay this transition wait for seconds until it begins.
As soon as it's triggered pause for four seconds.
Horrible experience for the most part as a user.
But you know you can work with milliseconds sometimes using delays if you want to transition to happen
but you want one to happen immediately and then another one when that one completes or when that finishes.
And the way you could do that is with this second version down here where you pass in comma separated
values.
So just like we did with transition property where we had color and opacity and then two different times
or durations that correspond to the properties.
You can do the same thing with transition delay.
So this one would apply to whatever the first property we're transitioning is and this would apply to
the second and so on if we have more than two.
So let's go to code Penn and play around.
All right.
So we have these two boring and animated boxes.
And right now there's no delay on animated.
So it's as simple as saying transition delay and let's do something like two seconds to make it really
clear.
So this is unchanged of course but this one that has the animated class I hover and then the transition
kicks in.
Two seconds later.
Now remember we're not transitioning the scale that's happening here.
So it does immediately double in size but the transition doesn't kick in for two seconds which is for
border radius.
And then also for background color.
And then if we wanted to we could do something like this transition delay will be one second for our
background Khama to 0.5 milliseconds for border radius.
So let me actually make this even clearer.
Let's do two seconds.
So what this is saying is that OK the background transition should take five seconds but don't start
it until two seconds after it's been triggered and the border radius should take one second to complete.
But wait half a second you know point five milliseconds isn't going to get us very far.
We won't notice that insanely fast.
I meant to do point five seconds.
So let's try that again.
You can see it weights half a second.
Then the border radius kicks in.
But the background transition doesn't kick in for a while.
And let me speed this up so that background takes one second and border radius take one second so that
it's a little clearer and let's say the transition delay is five seconds for background and two seconds
for border radius.
So now there should be a two second pause before it turns into a circle and then adds that finishes
there should be a short pause and then the rest of the background should transition.
All right.
So that's all there is to using transition delay as you can see the order does matter if you're going
to assign multiple transitions that have differing values.
OK.
So that brings us to our next and final property here for transitions at least which is the transition
timing function.
So I did save this one for last on purpose now because it's particularly tough or challenging to get
it's just harder to notice the changes that it makes sometimes.
Essentially what it controls is the acceleration of our animation.
So we could have 10 different animations that take 10 seconds.
Let's say we're animating background color we could have 10 different things that are the exact same
colors from red to purple let's say over 10 seconds.
But in those 10 seconds there are so many different ways that the animation could proceed.
It could start off really quickly and then slow down for the last second or it could take ten seconds
and basically go at the same speed the entire time.
And there are more complex curves that we can define.
You can see down here as well where we can actually specify different values along a curve for it to
follow.
So this can be a little bit difficult to wrap your head around.
There is pretty cool.
Easing functions that I found at easing dot net and what this does it shows you some really common shapes
or curves that you can use for your easing functions.
So here's an example if you hover over one of them is in sign.
Notice that little red may zoom in a bit.
The red flag on the right side.
That's the thing that's being transitioned or animated.
And watch it.
It doesn't go at a constant speed.
It starts off slow and then it speeds up a bit towards the end or for you to a more drastic one.
How about is this to ease out and back this one so what this does if I can get it to trigger.
There you go.
Is it basically goes very pretty quickly at the beginning and slows down and it goes a little bit too
far actually and then comes back to our End Point.
So watch that again.
And let's see.
Let's do one more about is in out Sercq.
So what's happening here.
Start slow and it speeds up and then it ends slow I don't know if you can pick that up on the video.
One thing of note this section down here is actually reserved for things that you can't do with just
c s s so things with these more complex curves like these bounces these are actually accomplished with
javascript plus VSS.
Or you can do them when we talk about keyframes in just the next section coming up.
But with transitions on their own you're limited to these types of curves.
OK.
So it's kind of hard when we just talk about it without actually seeing example.
I like the examples on the transition timing function page on D-N.
So I'll scroll down and you can see if it loads under examples there are that six eight different red
squares that are all identical but they have different timing functions but they're doing the same thing.
So they go from a Red Square to a smaller blue square that's also moving it's being transformed or translated
across the page.
But notice that even though they start at the same place they end at the same place they take a very
different journey to get there.
The acceleration is different.
So these are transition timing functions that are controlling that and they're really important towards
making your animations feel natural making them feel sort of like they're alive sometimes.
So let's let's play around.
We're not going to do anything crazy but let's go to our transition playground and I'm actually going
to undo all this commented out.
For now of this code and what we're going to do instead is say the animated box let's do all boxes when
they hover when we hover.
Do a translate X let's do 300 pixels.
So we'll have it move across the screen.
There we go.
Perfect.
Now we're going to do is add a transition to the animated box animated class so that animated will just
do transition property which is going to be transformed.
Let's do a duration.
Let's have it take two seconds so we can see these changes happen and then we'll add in.
We don't need a delay that's fine.
Well the transition timing function and we'll start with linear which is one of the the values that
we get by default.
And you can actually see those values here.
So we have ease ease and ease out ease it out linear steps start and step and are the predefined ones.
But then we can also define our own function.
If you are familiar with cubic bezier as the air curves never know how to pronounce that you can define
your own.
And there's also a tool that I'll show you.
But realistically most of the time I'm just using is in easy out.
Those are kind of the most common ones and there their defaults for a reason.
OK so if we go back we just have it as linear as I hover.
You'll see it goes from point A to point B over here in a linear speed.
Takes two seconds and it goes the exact same speed the entire time.
But I can change that to something like is in.
And if we look at the graph for that let's go to this page this is another tool I'll go to ease and
this is called Sezer.
SS easing animation tool.
It's in the Resources page.
This is what the graph for the curve for is and looks like.
So as it is is it go slower and then it picks up speed towards the end.
So let's try it out.
We have easy to find it go slow and then it speeds up towards the end.
Hopefully you can see that change happening.
It takes a little bit and then it gets going.
So we can do the same thing but change it to ease out which works the opposite way.
So goes quickly and then slows down sort of like I don't know if you know baseball you're running towards
a base.
You go quickly and then you start to slow down as you get there.
Maybe that's a terrible analogy.
Sometimes people speed up and slide.
But whatever the point is that in this case the acceleration is greater at the beginning the speed is
greater at the beginning and then it slows down as it gets closer.
So it makes a big difference if we get rid of that line.
Rather than just going at a constant speed so you can play around some of the other ones let's do is
in dash out and if you take a look at what that one looks like.
Kind of eases and go slow at the beginning and then speeds up and then go slower at the end as well.
So let's take a look.
Quicker.
Slow down.
So one more time.
He goes slow and then quick and then slow hopefully you can see that it might be a bit hard over the
video frame rate the screen casting software captures that well.
The last thing that I'll say is that you can capture your own so you can do things like define your
own equation.
Let's say that you like this is Outback.
So it goes past and then comes back you can click on it on this Web site and it actually will give you
the cubic bezier curve that you want so you can copy that over and I can just replace this is in out
with that curve.
So now as I do this and see what happens.
There you go.
You can see that hover.
It goes a bit too far and then comes back.
So this definitely isn't a math course but if you're curious and you want to define some of your own
timing functions this tool is really fun and useful.
What you can do is find something that you like say you like this and then you can tweak it so totally
change it to something like this.
Let's have it go really really quickly.
At the beginning and then slow down towards the end.
Every go so we could do this.
And if you wanted to actually grab the code to do that down here you can copy this transition timing
function.
Copy that and bring it over and paste that in hopefully you can see that.
So it's going very quick and then slowing down.
So it's like an exaggerated version of E's out.
OK so the last thing that you should know.
Just like with these other properties.
Transition delay transition duration and property.
You can have multiple timing functions assigned and the order matters of course just like the other
three.
So if we added in transition timing function whatever came first let's say ease in would correspond
to these values and whatever came second would correspond to these values.
And you are not limited to two however many values you have you just need commas to separate them.
But I'll stick to this for now.
Hopefully you get the idea.
And that wraps up the key for properties that have to do with transitions.
So we had transition property transition duration transition timing function and transition delay.
So in the following video you actually see a way of combining all four properties into a single line
a single shorthand property that can make your life a lot easier and makes my life easier a lot less
typing.
So I'll see you there.