Welcome back.
In this video we're going to recap what we've learned so far.
We've seen quite a few Array methods.
So let's go over each one and how they're used for each iterate through an array and runs a callback
function on every value in the array for each always returns undefined.
Map iterates through an array and runs a callback function on every value in the array and adds the
return value of the callback to a new array.
Gnab always returns a new array of the same one as the array that it was called the filter iterates
through an array and runs a callback function on every value in the array at the callback function with
that value passed to it returns true that value was added to the new array.
Remember the callback function to filter will always be evaluated to a boolean filter needs to know
whether or not to add the value to the new array.
Some iterates through an array and runs a callback function on each value in the array.
If the callback function for at least one value returns True some returns true.
Remember the callback function to sum will always be evaluated to a boolean.
Since some needs to know whether to return true or not every iterates through an array and runs a callback
function on each value in the array.
If the callback function for every single value returns true every returns true.
Once again the callback function.
Every will always be evaluated to a boolean since every need to know whether to return true or not reduce
iterates through an array and accumulates a value which starts as the first value in the array or is
an optional second parameter.
To reduce the callback to reduce except for parameters and accumulator next value index and the array
whatever is returned to the callback function of reduce becomes the value of the accumulator in the
next iteration.
Be sure to practice with these exercises as well as some additional materials we have for you to work
on understanding how to use for each map filter some Every anti-abuse is essential for reading code
and reading more complex code.
You'll see many of these methods quite a bit when you learn about libraries and frameworks like Riak
D3 angular and more.
As always if you have any questions be sure to reach out to us.
We'll be here to help see you in the next section.