Welcome back in this section we're going to continue learning about 2015 and we're going to go over
a concept known as destructuring and see how to structure objects and then the next video the structure
arrays the word destructuring may sound a bit weird.
So let's define it.
Destructuring is the idea of extracting values from data stored in objects and arrays.
Let's see what we mean by that first examining when this might be useful.
You can see here that we have an object called constructor with the keys a first name and last name.
If we wanted to create a variable called first name and assign it to the value of the first name property
on the instructor object and do the same for a last name variable.
Here's what that might look like.
What we're doing here is extracting values from data stored in objects.
This process is quite a bit tedious and only gets worse as we have more nested objects.
Restructuring allows us to unpack values from arrays or properties from objects into distinct variables.
The code here might look a bit strange at first.
So don't be too intimidated.
This is a really helpful addition to javascript.
Over here we have the same object as before but notice our variable declaration of first name and last
name.
Left hand side of the equal sign is wrapped in an object.
What we're doing here is creating two variables.
First name and last name which are the structure or unpacked from the instructor object.
If we take a look at first name and last name we can see they are the same as before.
Now the catch here is that we have to name our variables the same exact names as the keys in the object
we are destructuring.
What happens if we want to make different variable names.
No problem.
You can simply add a colon and a new variable name.
You can see here that we have now made two variables.
First and last a destructuring instructor objects.
Now let's take a look at a more complex example of one destructuring really helps in this example.
We have a function called create instructor which accepts a single parameter called options inside of
this function.
We're checking to see if a value for the options parameter was passed in and if not we're signing it
to an empty object.
We're then creating a few variables called name and is hilarious.
Which are either values inside and the options object or default values that will make finally or returning
an array of values.
The first property can last property on the name object and the value of the IS HILARIOUS variable.
If we invoke this function a few different ways we will see that we can get some default values and
if we pass in our own options we can modify the output of the function.
Now let's see how this can be refactored using destructuring.
This is going to look quite strange at first.
Let's try to walk through it piece by piece.
What we are doing here is passing in a deep structured object as a parameter to a function and specifying
the keys of name and is hilarious with default values at the end of the parameter.
We're assigning the whole thing to be an empty object so that as 2015 knows that our default parameter
is a structured object.
If nothing is passed in we default to the structure object as the parameter.
To recap we're passing in a structured object as the default parameter where assigning as the default
value an empty object.
So that 20:15 knows we are restructuring an object.
If nothing is passed in we default to the structure object as the parameter.
Now let's take a look at another useful case where we can restructure objects and pass in fields or
keys in an object as parameters in S-5 if we wanted to display properties from an object we can pass
that object in as a parameter and return some values.
Here's what that might look like.
So how can the structuring help if you know the names of the keys that you will be using from a single
object.
You can be structure those keys as parameters.
Here we have a function called display info which accepts an object with bickies of name and fame color.
If we create an object with the keys of name and fame color we can invoke this function and restructure
the instructor object you'll see object restructuring quite a bit in popular frameworks and libraries
like react and angular to since it's a very useful way of unpacking values from objects and even nested
objects.
Destructuring is not the most intuitive concept.
He is 2015 and it takes a bit of practice to get the hang of it in the next video.
We'll see how to structure arrays and then we'll practice a bit more with destructuring.
See you in the next video.