In the last video we introduce component lifecycle methods.
Next we'll talk about some example use cases of lifecycle methods.
If you remember back to our boxes exercise where we have 32 boxes that change color randomly.
If that component were a part of a larger application you would want the set interval to stop after
this component gets unmounted.
So in order to do that I've got the constructor here and this is pretty much the same code we've seen
before where we're going to make 32 boxes give each one a random color and then set up a set interval
that calls set state and changes one box's color randomly.
Now say this component gets unmounted will want that interval to go away.
So we've saved the interval ID to the component instance and then inside a component will unmount we'll
clear that interval.
So this is the use case for using component will unmount some sort of cleanup like a set interval where
you know you want to stop something from happening when the component amounts now is talk about component
did mount a common use case for component did mount is to make an Ajax request because the component
did mount method will only happen once per the life of the component.
It makes sense to make your Ajax request here for something like getting all the data for you to demonstrate
let's build the following up.
This is a fairly simple app that shows all the top stories on Hacker News right now and we're getting
the data by calling the Hacker News API so I can click on any one of these links and it will take me
to the corresponding story.
And it also says who posted the story.
Let's take a look at what the Hacker News API gives us.
So in order to make this work we need to get requests first get requests of the Hacker News Top Story
API which just gives us a list of story ideas.
Once we have that we'll need to make the following GET requests for each ID.
So if we were to make the GET request for the first ID 1 5 3 0 0 0 6 9 it would look like this.
And we get back the following results.
There are actually more keys in the results than what I'm showing here but these are the ones we care
about we care who posted the article.
The idea of the article the title and the link itself.
Now let's work on implementing this
in cloud nine.
I've set up a new app called Hacker News and so far it just looks like this.
It's just a constructor A render method and inside the render method we're just rendering this views
and views only has loading right now.
So not much going on yet.
The next thing we want to do is implement a component amount to get our data
and what data do we want to store what we want to store a list of stories in our state.
So let's make some default state.
Next we'll use fecche to get the data from the Hacker News API.
I'll start by making strings for my your Elle's that I'll make get requests to
and this store you are all based is not for your.
It's only the beginning of it we still need the story ID and then a dot J sign at the end.
So at that we make the request.
Now let's start by making a fetch to the top stories euro.
We want to add a dot then method and convert our result into Jason
that Jason returns a promise so we can add a dot then to that because of promise chaining
Let's scroll down.
Now if you remember the result of making this request is an array of IDS an array of story IDs.
So we're going to map over that array and make a new get request for each array.
And now will use the story you are off base in order to create the full Euro
and because we know each one of these requests is going to require us to convert the result to Jason
lets out a dot then to this
since we're using a map here.
This then will return an array of promises.
And the next stop.
Then we can use promise chaining
to take that array and pass it to a promise that all.
Now once all those promises have been resolved we'll have our array of stories.
Now let's just render a string and find array to prove that we're getting data.
And as you can see we're definitely getting data from the API.
Now we just need to convert that data into links.
I'll do that by mapping over the stories.
Now this check is important.
We only want to map if we have some data for the stories if there are no stories we want to keep the
loading view there.
And that's just good UI.
You should always have a floating visible while your Ajax request is happening so that the user sees
something.
Now we'll just return a paragraph tag with Arlington side.
So as you can see we're rendering the link with our your l.
The title of the story and also who post the story.
And lastly we need to render our views.
So let's replace a string of high.
Let's see if that works.
All right.
Looks good.
We've got all of the elves and we've got the poster as well.
Now it's your turn.
Next you're going to work on an app that uses component did mouth to make an Ajax request and also takes
advantage of all the reacts features that we've learned so far.