Welcome to the next section now that you understand the basics of D-3 and SPG it's time to learn about
some more intermediate topics.
Here are some of the things we'll be learning about in this section in this video.
Learn how to use D-3 to calculate extreme values of data sets and to scale data.
These calculations will definitely ease the process of building visualizations with SPG in the next
video.
We'll use what we've learned to build our first scatterplot and D-3.
After that we'll improve the readability of our graphs by learning how to add axes grid lines labels
and titles to them in the final set of videos for this section.
We'll learn about some D-3 helper's that will make building histograms and pie charts much more straightforward
now.
Let's focus on extreme values and scales.
When we left off last time we built a bar chart to visualize births around the world by month and by
year.
There were a few issues that came up when building this visualization.
For one we had to inspect our dataset to find the first and last years.
We also had to manually identify the largest value in our dataset based on that largest value.
We also had to do some arithmetic in order to make sure that all of our rectangles always fit inside
of the SVGA.
Fortunately D3 comes with methods to help us with these common tasks.
If you want to pick up where we left off.
Here are some links to the existing code.
I'll be modifying the app japes we had from before.
Directly in my text editor the first helper method will look at is D-3 dot max which takes in an array
and returns the largest value in the array.
You can also pass in an optional callback specifying how you want to associate a value to elements in
the array.
This can be extremely helpful if you have an array of objects and want to find the max based on a particular
key.
Similarly there's a D-3 dustmen function which finds the smallest value instead of the largest.
Here are a few examples.
If I just pass an array of numbers and 3 that Max I'll get the max.
Unsurprisingly something similar happens if I use the three men in this case.
I'll get the smallest value instead of the largest.
Now lets suppose I have an array of people objects where each person has a name and an age.
If I want to find the largest age in my data set I can use D-3 dot Max and pass in a callback then grabs
each person's age.
I can do something similar if I want to find the shortest name in the dataset using D-3 Gutmann.
Let's apply these functions to refactor some of our previous code we can use D-3 Max to find the maximum
value in our data set rather than trying to eyeball it by looking through all of the values.
We can also refactor our many year and next year variables to use these D-3 helper functions.
Once we know the maximum number of births we can base our scale on it.
Once again D-3 comes with a helper function to assist in creating the scale.
There are a number of different scales you can use for your data but the most common one is D-3 dot
scale linear given a domain and a range scale linear returns a function that maps values in the domain
to values in the range before applying this function to our visualization.
Let's look at an example.
Suppose I want to map values one interval say from 1 to 17 to values in another interval say from minus
4 to 52.
With some algebra I could write a function that would not all use on the first line.
Values on the second line.
But this is precisely what D-3 scale does.
Here's the syntax for the domain.
I'll pass on the array one comma 17 for the range I'll pass and the other interval negative for comma
52.
Cool.
This scale will now map values in the domain to values in the range for example scale of 1 returns minus
4 scale of 17 returns 52 and every value in between 1 and 17 gets mapped to its appropriate value in
the range.
We can use scale in here to create a scale mapping our data values to our SPG dimensions.
Here's what that looks like.
There's one small change we've made to the scale here compared to our previous example.
Note that we've mapped to 0 to the SPG height and Max birth's to zero.
This has the effect of flipping the y axis in this way y scale of zero gets mapped to the bottom of
the SPG.
This makes reasoning about coordinates a bit easier since after scaling y values increases you go up
not down.
Now that we've created our scale let's use it to modify our data so that the bars all fit in our SVGA
we no longer need to hard code in our scaling factor.
D-3 does this for us all we need to do is set the Y attribute for each rectangle equal to the scaled
y value.
Then we can set the height attribute equal to the SVGA height minus the scaled y value.
This code is much more flexible than what we had before.
It doesn't depend on the specific set of data points.
And if we decide to add or remove data from the data set later on we won't need to modify this code.
That's it.
On extreme scales for now in the next video we'll see how to make a basic scatterplot using D-3.
I'll see you there.