Welcome back in the next couple of videos we're going to continue learning about 2016 and 17.
Fortunately these new additions to the language are much smaller than as 2015.
We're first going to examine two new features and yes 2016 will then talk about 2017 by introducing
new string methods and one of the most impressive features of 20:17 async functions.
Finally I'll talk about some new features that are coming to javascript soon.
First let's talk about 2016 and two very small features that it gives us thankfully yes 2016 is much
much smaller than 2015 so there are only two main additions to the language.
Let's learn about the first one.
The exponentiation operator in quite a few other languages.
There exists an operator to figure out the value of one number to the power of another for 2016.
This was done using math not power.
But now we can use a handy operator with two asterisks.
Let's see what that looks like here.
We're simply using two asterisks instead of not but how it's a more concise way to calculate a value
if we'd like.
We can also use the exponentiation operator along with an equal sign similar to the way that we do.
Plus equals minus equals and many more.
Anytime you find yourself using math DePauw refactor it with the 2016 exponentiation operator the second
helpful feature is something you might have already been using without knowing it's part of 2016.
In 2015 we saw that strings now have a method called includes which returns true if the value passed
to it is included in the string otherwise it returns false.
In 2016 arrays now have an includes method as well which is an excellent replacement for using index
of to see if a value exists inside of an array.
It works just the same way as string dot includes.
We can go from using index of and a comparison operator like greater than or triple equals to using
a method that directly returns a boolean.
If you find yourself needing to see if a value exists in an array you can now use includes And that's
all we have for 2016.
I hope that wasn't too underwhelming.
After everything we saw earlier but remember the time difference between 5 and yes 2015 was almost six
years.
So they had a lot more catching up to do.
Now that you've seen these two features to yes 2016 let's learn a little bit more about 2017 and practice
with some exercise.
See you in the next video.