They're welcome to the next section.
So this section is all about CSSA fluxbox.
Fluxbox is a new ish layout module.
It's been around for a while or a couple of years at least but it wasn't widely adopted and it wasn't
widely supported across all the major browsers.
But that's now changed.
Making this a really good time to learn.
So what is fluxbox.
Well according to the docs I did not write this.
It's a more efficient way to lay out a line and distribute space among items in a container even if
their size is unknown.
So what this really means is that the days of hacking together weird kind of buggy layouts using floats
and clear fixes and tables whatever other tricks you know are over.
If you use flex boxes like Xbox makes laying things out inside of a given box whether it's a div a section
and NAV whatever the content is it makes it much much easier to distribute it and not only distribute
it in one place but have it grow or shrink change depending on the size of the screen.
So basically it makes it very easy to lay things out and to make Responsive Web sites things that traditionally
were very difficult like vertically centering content or having a bunch of children instead of a parent
div or a parent box and having them take up the exact same width and height.
Even if the width and height is unknown Those are all very very doable using Fluxbox.
But what I will say as a quick word of warning is that there is a little bit of syntax that you have
to get used to up front if you've never come across text box until now.
There are a bunch of properties we're going to go over.
I've done my best to try and order them in a nice way.
Fill the section with lots of examples lots of practical things but there's no way of getting around
the fact that there's just a lot of properties we have to talk about.
So that's the only hurdle to using it.
Once you actually understand it it's very simple it's easy to use but there's a couple of things you
just have to get past conceptually before it starts to click.
So with that said I have a simple visual example here.
Imagine that you have three items.
These three things here red orange and yellow representing images or divs or maybe columns of text.
Anything three items.
They don't even have to be the same the same size but I made them in this case.
This is one potential way of arranging them in a container.
So they're inside of something else.
This little white border here.
So what I'm going to show you are some of the ways using Fluxbox that we could rearrange this very very
easily with a single line.
I could shift them all over to the right side.
Not something that's you know incredible that you couldn't do with flex or without flex box but I can
also space them evenly across this container with a single line.
Or I could take this middle box and make it take up twice as much space as the left and the right boxes.
Also with a single line or I could do something like this I don't remember.
I think this is eight times as large as what I calculated.
Basically I can make this a lot larger and then have these two other units columns whatever these are
on the right side be much much smaller.
But I could also do something crazy and switch to a vertical lab have columns or a single column instead
of a row.
Also just a single little line to do this here.
Now not everything in fact spikes is a single line that is not the point I'm making more the point I'm
making is that we have a single box filled with three three items whatever they are doesn't matter.
But using Fluxbox we can arrange them in tons of different ways.
Just three items.
So imagine now we have multiple items multiple rows multiple columns all the possibilities but just
with three items there's already a lot.
And this isn't everything.
This is just kind of a quick preview.
In fact I highly recommend that you check out this VSS tricks a complete guide to fluxbox.
If you have any questions and it just makes a great visual reference but it's full of diagrams like
the ones I've created here and it really is a great reference.
So if at any point you have questions about the properties I'm showing you you can see already how many
properties there are how many diagrams there are here to illustrate things.
Don't let that intimidate you we're going to go slow and go through all of the important properties
in a relatively well-thought out order but just keep this open.
If you're someone who likes to refer to visual docs so as I mentioned all of those potential odds are
things we could do just using Fluxbox and without really having to write much code at all.
OK so before we go on to actually writing code and learning the properties I just want to give you a
heads up a little roadmap for whoever going.
So there are two types of properties that we're going to learn the properties that apply to a container.
So the big white box here and then properties we apply to the individual items inside those containers.
We're going to start off by talking about the container properties.
There's five that we're going to focus on.
And along the way we'll build a couple of little projects and nav bar a side bar and then we'll move
on to flex item properties and build a couple of projects as well.
So I'm doing my best to incorporate real world examples along with that conceptual underpinnings of
fluxbox and try to make that the least boring possible so that further ado let's get started talking
about container properties.