In this section we're going to talk about 2015 and quite a few of the new additions that it brings to
the javascript language.
We'll understand what 2015 is and how the term came to be.
We'll refactor code to use LET and Konst and template strings to avoid concatenation.
Then add erro functions to write less code and see object enhancements to write cleaner code.
We'll discuss a new kind of loop and explain what default parameters are and then we'll learn about
rest and spread and how to unpack values from arrays and objects using a technique called the structure.
Before we dive in let's quickly recap what exactly yes means and dispel some confusion around some of
the many terms that there are in order to do that we need to go back to 1995.
Back in 1995 Brendan Eich of Netscape was tasked with writing a programming language for the browser
that was initially named Mogae later live scripts and finally javascript at that time.
There was another browser competitor Internet Explorer which was built by Microsoft in order to compete
with Netscape Microsoft reverse engineered Brendan.
Ice language and named a js script since there were now two different languages for different browsers.
It became difficult to build applications for both.
So Brendan like looked for an organization to help standardize the language to stop this problem.
And in 1996 the European Computer manufacturers association or eczema was brought on to help standardize
the language.
In 1997 the first version of ECMAScript called Yes one was released and implemented in browsers and
as the language grew.
Yes two and yes three were released in 1998 and 1999.
Yes.
Four never ended up being released and in 2009 a large update to the language was added with S-5 in
June of 2015.
Another large update to the language came with ESX but since the popularity of javascript was growing
so much the TC 39 which is the committee votes to add new features into the language decided that they
would be releasing new changes every year so they renamed ESX to 2015.
And since then every year new features have been added and will continue to be added to the language
in this section.
We're going to start learning about 2015 and then explore new features to the language with as 2016
and 2017 in the following section.
These features are commonplace in more modern code bases and frameworks and libraries like react and
angular too.
We can see that as 2015 gives us quite a bit of enhancements but don't be too intimidated by this list.
By the end of the next two sections you're going to know what all of these things are.
We've admitted a few Yes 20:15 topics which you will see far far less frequently.
But there are links in the section notes where you can read about those topics.
So let's get started with as 2015 and a brand new keyword Konst.
See you in the next video.