So on the last screencast how data flows through out a redux application we saw how to make a store
how to pass in a function to create store.
We call that a reducer and we saw that our reducer is where we define our initial state and where we
can make changes to our state by returning a copy of this.
How do we make changes to the state member that we dispatched in action.
Dispatch is really just the idea of sending some kind of action.
The store is in charge of dispatching these actions and actions are simply objects that have to contain
a key of type.
So we saw how to do this in the crumbed up tools.
We're going to take that example at the counter and just build a very simple application with a little
bit of query to show how that works.
So I make a directory and I'll call that redox counter.
And inside here I mean two files can make an index that each terminal and we'll just make a script yes.
Mikita real simple and all open this all up in a line.
So in sublime right now I have an index that each DML is going to start with a very very simple each
one with an ID of counter.
And when I really don't have anything here we're going to set the text depending on whatever our count
is and redux is actually going to store count.
So we'll make a button will give us an idea of increment and we'll have the tax increment and then we'll
do the same thing for a button of Declan's that's going to be decadent.
Now we're not going to get very far without Gigue query and redux.
So let's go back and grab a G Querrey CDN.
We'll go over here and we'll get the uncompress version.
So are there any errors we should be in good shape.
Let's get a copy that will also grab the redux ZDF.
So go grab this right here.
Make sure the script tag and get at sarcy of that right there.
And it looks good.
We're also going to need a script about that to our script yes script.
Yes that looks good.
So we should have a script for Jay Querrey script for Reebok's and a script for a script that yes
so if I open this page right now in the browser I should just see increment and decrement but nothing
really happens when I click these buttons and that's for good reason because I don't have any event
listeners or anything happening so I'm going to start in my script base with a couple of things.
We need some redux story.
But before remember we need a producer we can call that whatever we want but let's call it root reducer.
We need some redux store and initial state and then we need some way of changing the state.
So let's start with a reducer.
Member do sers are just functions and that function we can call root reducer and it accepts some kind
of steede and some action that's coming in.
But remember the first time that this reducers run we need to set some kind of initial state.
So once again we could do something like If the state is undefined then we can do something by setting
this date.
But let's keep it real simple.
Using default parameters all make a variable.
In fact we can make this a constant.
We'll call that initial state.
And this is going to be an object with a key of count and a value of 0.
And inside of here we're simply going to say if there is no state we'll pass the initial state.
And remember there is no state passed to this the first time that that route reducer is run.
Once the first time that the route reducer is run when we run redux that create store remember that
dispatch comes in with an action with a type of redux in it.
If you don't remember seeing that.
Take a look at the previous screencast and I'll show you again even in this one.
So inside accrete store we're going to pass in our reproducer But remember for now we always just want
to return some kind of state and what we're going to do just to keep it simple is set a debugger right
here and make sure that we're getting to our root reducer.
So I'm going to go open this up in the browser and let's go keep our dev tools open and we refresh the
page.
We should see that we've made it to the root reducer.
Remember the first time that you call create store which would really only be once we're going to dispatch
an action with the type of redux.
And this is all done internally by redux to figure out what your state starts off as.
So we can see right here what we call store that gets the we should have count of zero.
Let's say you forgot for some reason to pass in some kind of initial state right here.
When we go refresh the page in our debugger we should see that state is undefined.
So our initial state right now is actually undefined and we don't want that.
We want to make sure that we start off with some kind of initial state to make sure you set that parameter
right here.
So we're going to need some way to increment and decrement But why don't we start with a little bit
of a worry.
I'm going to start with a quick document already and we'll end it some of the listeners will say when
an idea of increment is clicked we are going to run some kind of a function and here what do we need
to do.
We need to dispatch some action to increment the count and we can actually do the same thing with detriment
decrement unclick.
We need to dispatch some action to decrement the count.
Now where do these actions get created.
Well remember actions are just objects.
So we could do here is simply call store dispatch and pass in an object.
Remember our actions which are the objects always have to have a key of type.
So let's give it a type of increment and we can call this whatever we like but remember that when we
dispatch this action it's going to go back to the reducer.
So why don't we for now just put a debugger here.
Before I load the page.
Think how many times we're going to hit that debugger once before I load the page remember this debugger
is going to be reached the first time that we call create store.
So we set some initial state and whenever I click this increment button we're going to go right back
here.
So let's see this let's go back to the browser and refresh the page.
The first time that I go back here I get an action with a type of redux in it that's just redux setting
up some initial state.
What happens when I click increment again I go back here but the action now has a type of increment.
Great.
So what do we do with this new action or with that type of increment.
Well let's write a little bit of conditional logic.
We could do something like.
If action doc type and this is what we did in the last screencast.
But what I want to introduce is a more common way you'll see of handling different action types and
what we're actually going to do is use a key switch statement.
So we are going to switch on the action that type and what we're going to do here is say in the case
of increment we are going to set a debugger 8 now and return the city.
Now remember with all of your key switch statements you always have some kind of default which is what's
going to happen when there's nothing there.
So in this default action I'm going to return.
That's the that's going to save us.
So let's go back to the browser and refresh the page.
When I increment I'm back here in side of the switch statement.
So all we've done is instead of using if.
We've used a case switch statement and you probably haven't done kids switch statements in a while so
feel free to take a look at it and then to see how this is all happening.
We're moving pretty quickly so let's take a step back and talk about what we've done so far.
We've set up a simple each one with an idea of counter.
It doesn't have any value right now because this is where we're actually going to increment and decrement
those values.
We've loaded up a little bit of the query and some redux so that we can use a query for dominant relation
and redux for managing our state.
We're not going to make some global variable for the count because imagine that the variable or data
needed to be shared amongst different files would be really nice if we had one centralized place to
store that information.
And that's exactly what redux lets us do.
Finally I'm just loading a script called script Geass which I have right here before I worry about any
of the dominant violation or waiting for the dom to load.
I set up some initial state remember initial state could be an object it could be an array.
Most of the time you'll see it as an object.
And here I have a property of count and a value of 0.
In order for our store to be created we always have to pass a function to it.
We call that function a reducer.
In this case we only have one reducer so we'll call it the root reducer.
This excepts some kind of state and some kind of action.
Actions are simply objects that get dispatched or sent by the store to make changes or to see what the
state is the first time that I call create store redux dispatches an action with the type of redux in
it.
And this is simply just to get our default state.
But in the future if I want to dispatch different actions I just call store dispatch and remember actions
are just objects and they always have to have the key of type because in that because in the reducer
I'm going to figure out what the type is and if it's increment I'm going to do something here.
So what should we do if it increment.
Why don't we just do state that count plus plus and return the state.
In fact let's get fancy Let's go see a case decrement.
All we need to do here state count minus minus.
So we're just going to increment count or decrement that count.
Now when I dispatch the type of increment that works out really well but I actually have to change the
value of each one.
So what I'd like to do is after I dispatch that value of increment I would like to figure out what the
city looks like.
Specifically to account and set that to be the text of my H-1.
How do we figure out what the state is of the store.
Well we have a wonderful way using store that gets state has a built in method to our store.
So I'm going to get the state which should be changed after I'd dispatch this action and I'm going to
set on my Each one which I believe I gave an ID of counter.
I'm going to set the text to be current state DOT count.
I'll do the same thing here actually inside of detriment.
But instead of dispatching potato increment I'm going to dispatch a type of document when decrement
is clicked.
Dispatch decrement it's going to go to the reducer.
Take one away from the state the Count property specifically and return that's the.
And then I'm going to set the text of the counter to be whatever the current state is.
Let's go try this out and then refresh the page you know increment and it looks like it's working.
Well that's pretty cool.
If we wanted to be a little bit fancier we could do something like when the downloads get the current
state and once again that's the text of that counter to be the current state.
Now there's a lot of repetition here and we could refactor this with some helper functions but I'm just
going to keep it simple for now.
So when ever First the page I see zero we take a look right now at Stuart I gets the 0.
How about when I increment got looks good when I decrement.
That looks good.
But there's still something that's not great about what I've done.
Remember that our producers have to be pure functions.
And what that means is that we cannot modify state directly.
We should always make a copy of our state.
So we'll make a variable called Nusi and we'll set that to be whatever the state was before.
Now another way that we could do this is by using object design just remember with object that assign
your first parameter should always be an empty object.
That way we don't overwrite the object instead of making a copy of it.
Remember the first parameter should always be an empty object to object a sign.
So I can make a copy of that state using this right here or I can do what I have above here I can say
new state DOT count plus plus.
And then I can return the new state will do this as well with our document.
But instead we're simply going to subtract those values.
I'll say this.
And let's go refresh the page and see what it looks like.
Ooh new state has already been declared.
Let's see what I did wrong here.
Looks like he's Lekki word more than one time inside of my switch statement.
So instead of let let's just use var.
I'll keep it real simple right now.
Let's try to increment and decrement isn't working.
How come decrements not working.
Well let's make sure we dispatch that type of decrement.
So let's make sure that we're actually hitting this in the debugger.
So we'll guess that a debugger right here is your first page and or in the debugger.
But what's the problem right now.
We're returning state.
Silly me.
Let's make sure we return new state.
Let's go see this reverse page increment is great and Eckermann seems to be working.
So sometimes you make some silly mistakes.
Just make sure to set a debugger really help you out.
So it looks like increment and decrement are working and we're simply making a new copy of the state
each time.
You could do this above if you'd like but I want to be really verbose here.
So it seems like what we've got is a simple working counter where you can increment and decrement and
we're using a pure function in our group reducer.
Let's take one more step back and Moktar everything that we've done in our index that HMO.
We have a simple counter.
You have a button to increment and a button to decrement.
We have our scripts for Jey query redux and our external script script database.
The first thing we do is declare some initial state in this application we're just using a count and
going to start it at zero.
We then have a root reducer and we saw that except some kind of state and some action that is being
dispatched the first time that an action is dispatched is when create store runs and that's where the
redux init action comes in.
Remember that's just for the purpose of creating an initial state.
So what we do is in the event that there is not a state yet.
Let's just use this initial state and return that in the future.
We're going to see what the action type is and if it's increment or decrement we'll make a new copy
of this state.
And in this case will increment and decrement will make a new copy of the state and Dechert as we then
make our read store and that's pretty much the bulk of the redox work that we do when the downloads
we see whatever the state of the story is.
This should be an object with Count of zero.
We then set the text of the each one to be zero.
That way we can just start with whatever the current status.
Now it's nicer to do this than to hard code the number 0 right here because imagine that maybe we're
using a database to persist things we don't want to hard code some kind of number.
What if last time we left off our counter was it two or negative five.
Any time we click on a button with an idea of increment we're going to dispatch an action member all
of our actions always have to have a key of type but we're then going to do is see what the state is
at that point.
Imagine this is the first time it might look like this.
So we'll set the H-1 text to be one.
Let's imagine that we go in decrement or click on the document button.
We're going to dispatch once again in action with a type of decrement.
Remember any anytime we dispatch an action we always go back to the reducer and run this code.
Since our action duct tape is detriment we should reach this code right here which makes a copy of the
state subtracts one from whatever the count is of that copy and returns it we then grab whatever is
in the state.
Let's imagine at this point that will divide count back at zero and then we set the H-1 text to be zero.
So this would be just an idea of loading it incrementing and decrementing Let's see that one more time
in the browser or over the page.
There will be incrementing and decrementing we can always take a look at our good state because we've
put that store in the global scope.
You can see what your store can do.
We're really just going to use dispatch and get state at this point.
We'll keep it real simple.
You take a look at some of this code.
Take your time walking through it and try to practice and build this on your own.
Just remember reducers are pure functions.
Stores are created using those functions which we call reducers and stores that dispatch actions which
are simply objects that always have to contain the key of type and when an action is dispatched we go
back to that reducer and change the state by making a copy of it and then returning that copy.
That way we can always have a pure function.
So try this out again and I'll see you in the next video.