OK.
Welcome back.
So we're going to start off by just getting our Express up to serve a simple aged him I'll file.
So right now our route route has this response that we get.
Hello from the route route.
And then our API is located here at slash API slash to slash whatever else.
So eventually we want this page to be an HMO page with a bunch of C Ss and a bunch of javascript to
create our single page to do list.
So it should show up here.
And the first step is to just get it to respond with a page and aged him up a page.
So rather than rest send We're going to make a couple of changes we want to be able to do a rez send
file and then the name of our file which for now will call index dot h t m l.
So it doesn't exist yet.
So let's go make this file.
We're going to make a View's directory new folder called it views and then here we going to make a new
file just called index HMO and we'll start off with this is the index page.
And how about maybe a paragraph that just says to do list will go here.
Perfect.
That's right off the bat.
This actually won't work and that's because Express doesn't know where to find this file so appear are
going to add a second line app to use.
And then in here we do express dot static and then parentheses double underscore dir name.
So that's a variable that holds the current directory name plus slash views.
And now we should be good to go.
So basically by referencing index it aged him.
It actually is referencing our current directory slash views slash index study him.
And now everything should work well tested out.
Refresh our page.
There we go.
So our content is now showing up.
So next let's get a little bit of CSSA working.
So what we want to be able to do when to remove this for now or I'll cut it out and I'm going to add
ahead and then we'll add our body so our body will have each one and our paragraph and then our head
is where we might want to link to a stylesheet.
Well let's say that we make a stylesheet and let's call it apt.
Success doesn't exist yet.
So where do we go to put this.
Well it's up to us.
But the standardized way of doing this is to make another directory and we're going to call this public
and then in public we're going to make our file where we'll have to see assess and we'll also be able
to put our appestat J.S. there in just a moment.
So we'll start off with this.
It's still not going to work and that's because we need to do the same thing we did here once again.
But now we need to do it for public.
So we'll do use express that static public and if we restart the server
andwell we won't see anything.
Let's go to our APS-C SS and add in how we make all H-1 purple the best most under-rated color.
And I refresh now our CSSA is connected and we have this purple H-1.
So one thing you might be wondering is why do I use this dear name here and not here.
And there is a difference.
Both of them work in this case.
But if we tried to run this if we tried to start a server up from another directory so not exactly inside
of our API folder but we were somewhere else then this would not work.
So instead we wanted to use dear name at all times just to be as explicit as possible so that in any
scenario it will know how to find the public folder or the public directory just like it does with views.
So if I restart shouldn't be any change.
Everything still works.
So just to reiterate that this will always work what wherever we're actually starting the server up
from because it will start with the current directory that we're starting the server in.
So we could be in our home main directory appear and referencing Tutu's API index J.S. down here and
it will still be able to access the public directory in the views directory.
So here we're just telling express disserve these static files.
Here's the path to get there.
Lastly let's add a javascript file.
So if we have a longer app or a larger application we might want to have a script's directory and a
Stiles directory but we're only going to have one style sheet and one javascript file as far as our
front end Javascript.
So I'm just going to make an app dot J.S..
We don't need to worry about anything else then in there.
Let's start off nice and simple with an alert.
Hi from J.S. OK and then we'll go to our index page Timo and at the bottom of the body which can include
a script with source equal to app J.S. which will work because it's in the public directory and everything
in the public directory is being served as a static file.
So we have access to it in our index page to restart the server refresh the page and we get high from
apps.
Yes.
So we have all the pieces in place.
We have each time a file being served and it itself is linking to a C S S file.
So we're getting our styles and a javascript file.
So we're getting this beautiful alert message.
OK.
The last thing I'll point out because I know that this will come up is that if you're tired of restarting
your server which it does get annoying there is a package we can use called gnomon so we can do NPM
install dash G which stands for Global node mom like that and what this will do is basically watch for
changes in your code and automatically restart the server for you behind the scenes so you don't have
to stop and start the server.
It will do it for you.
And so you can make changes and just refresh your page and everything will work.
All we do is instead of node file then we do gnomon indexed.
Yes and now you'll see it's watching our files.
And if something changes let's say I changed the name of this to index 2 which doesn't exist and I saved
the file you can see it restarted and it started back again and I didn't have to do it myself.
OK.
So we'll leave off there.
We have everything in place to now start working on our app.