Welcome back.
In this video we're going to go for solutions to the restructuring exercise.
The first function we need to implement is called displaced student info and it accepts an object inside
of this object.
Will this structure the keys of first and last and then return a string.
Your full name is first and last.
You can use template strings to help clean up our code for the next function.
Print full name will be doing something very similar except here will directly restructure from the
parameters so I will place an object with the keys of first and last as a parameter to the function
inside of this function will return the string.
Your full name is first last and once again use template strings to help clean up our code in the next
function.
Create student.
We're going to pass in a structured object that has a default parameter with the keys of likes javascript
and the value of true and likes.
Yes 2015 with a value of true.
We also need to make sure that we assign this to an object.
Now let's create a string called Start with the value of the student and then write a little bit of
conditional logic to see if likes javascript and likes.
Yes 2015 are both true.
If so will concatenate to the string likes javascript and yes 2015 if likes javascript is true will
simply just add like javascript.
Otherwise we'll see if likes.
Yes 2015 is true and if so we'll add likes.
Yes 2015 to the string.
If none of these conditions are true we'll simply add does not like much.
Finally all return our strict for the final exercise we're going to write a function called reverse
array which is going to use array destructuring to swap values in an array.
Will Start by creating a loop and initializing a variable.
A zero will loop as long as I is less than the length divided by two.
Since we're going to start from the beginning and end we only need to go up to the middle we'll then
increment by one at each iteration inside of the loop.
We're going to take the value at eye and the value add array Len minus one minus I which will start
at the very end and go towards the middle and we will assign it to its opposite.
What we're doing here is destructuring the array and swapping the values in the beginning and the end
and working our way to the middle.
When we're done looping will return the array and that's it for the destructuring exercises.
See I'm in the next video.