Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over a few more methods that yes 2015 gives us.
Let's start with find which can be used on race find accepts a callback function and inside of a callback
function we can return a condition if that condition returns true.
The first item found to us is return.
That might sound a bit confusing.
So let's see how it works.
Here we have an array of objects and would like to find an object with the name property of Tim using
sign or return to us that object or if we cannot find it it returns undefined.
Find is a very useful way of searching through an array and returning a value without having to use
a form the same way that we can use find to return a value we can use find index to return the index
at which a found value is that if that value is not found find index returns negative 1 Another useful
method that yes 2015 gives us the includes method which works on strings.
Let's imagine that we want to see if a string includes the character X. We could use a for loop to iterate
over all the values in the string and see if we get the right character or we could use the index of
method which returns the index at which a character exists in a string index will always return negative
1 if the value we are looking for is not inside the string.
So we commonly write conditional logic that looks like the code right here.
Instead we can use includes which returns true or false if the value passed to it is included in the
string.
It's a more concise way of using index of or a for loop and is very useful with conditional logic.
The last method we're going to be looking at is a static method on the number constructor called number
that is finite.
Unfortunately checking to see if a number is not a number can be a bit tricky since type of Not A number
is actually number.
We can't really use the type of check.
So we have to use that is not a number function.
If we want to see something is a number and is not not a number we have to change even more conditional
logic together and it gets a little messy.
Thankfully we can use number and it is finite to help us out since anything that is not a number will
return false and not a number is not finite we can refactor our code to use this helpful method.
If you also want to see if a number is only an integer there exists a number that is integer method
which can be helpful as well.
Before we practice with these methods let's review what we've seen so far.
The map data structure is useful when creating key value pairs and the keys are not strings.
Sets are useful for creating unique data sets and do not require key value pairs as 20:15 promise constructor
allows for creating promises and resolving an array of promises with promise not all.
We also saw the generators are valuable when creating functions or methods that can pause and resume
at any time.
Finally we saw that 2015 provides a few useful methods for converting arrays like objects into arrays
making shallow copies of objects and handling issues with not a number and type of number.
Now let's practice a bit with these East 20:15 methods and afterwards we'll discuss Yes 2016 and move
toward some of the cutting edge features to the javascript language.
See you in the next video.