Welcome back in this video we're going to go over solutions to the 2015 methods exercises.
The first problem we need to implement is the copy object function.
What we'll do here is use the object that assign method.
So let's return object or assign and pass an empty object and the object we'd like to copy.
Remember we don't want a reference to the previous object.
So we'll pass in an empty object as the first parameter the object assigned.
The next function we need to implement is check if finite which will accept some value.
And here we can return the handy number God is finite method.
This will return true if that number is finite and false.
If we pass something that is not Next we need to implement a function called are all numbers finite
which accepts an array and checks to see if every single number is finite.
Here we can use the every function on the array and pass in a number that is finite.
This will return true if every number is finite.
The next function we need to implement is convert array like object which accepts some object and returns
a converted array.
Here we'll use arayed up from and past in that array like object to convert it into an array in S-5.
We would have had to do this using array that slice dot call but a got from is much friendlier.
The last method we need to implement is display even arguments.
What we'll do here is convert the arguments array like object into an array and filter all of the values
that are even using filter.
We can use erro functions here to clean up our code a bit.
You might have solved this using the rest operator and that's totally fine.
There will be plenty of times where array up from or the rest operator will accomplish the same thing
and that's all for the 2015 exercises.
See you in the next video.