Now you're going to work on an app to make a country flag guessing game.
And this should use component didn't mount to make an Ajax request plus all the things we've learned
previously about props and state the application looks like this.
You're presented with a random flag and four options.
You'll make your choice.
I'm not sure which flag this is
and then if you're wrong it'll tell you the correct answer.
Let's see if I can get one right.
And if you're correct Cuba will tell you that and you essentially just keep going this way every time
you click next.
You get a new random flag.
One of these options is the correct option.
And the other three are incorrect options.
So how are you getting this data.
We'll use the rest country's API in your component didn't mount you make a get request to this your
L and you'll get back an array that looks like this.
All the properties aren't shown here but the things we care about are in each object will have a name
and a flag.
So you make a request on component and mount get all these results and then use the results in your
application to randomly pick four countries one of which should be your solution.
Good luck on this one.
And like always we'll have a solution after.