Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be introducing a new keyword that 2015 gives us Konst this keyword is an
alternative to the VAR keyword for declaring variables.
The keyword allows us to create constants or values which can not be redeclare.
Let's see what that looks like.
By comparing and contrasting Konst with the VAR keyword.
I'm going to open up the crumbed tools and create a variable called first instructor and assign it to
the string cult.
I'll then change its value to Ellie and that works fine.
Let's now see what Konst looks like.
I'll create a variable called another instructor and assign it to the string.
Tim if I try to redefine this variable I will get a type are telling me that there is assignment to
a constant variable and if I try to reuse the keyword for the same variable I'll get a syntax error.
The rule with the Konski word is that we can never redeclare a variable by the same name.
There is a bit of a gotcha with conc though.
Let's see what happens when we assign the value of a constant to be an array.
I'm going to make a variable using the Konski word called numbers and assign it to an array with four
numbers in it.
Now I'm going to add another number to the end of the array using the push method.
Since this variable is a constant Do you think I'll be able to do this.
The answer is actually yes.
We can still change the value of an array or object even if it is assigned.
Using the Konst cured be mindful of this even when you are using the cons keyword.
You are not able to change the value of primitives.
These include strings numbers booleans no undefined and a new primitive called symbol.
But when you are working with an object you can actually change the value of a constant Konst is very
useful when you want to explicitly declare variables that should never be read declared.
Even if you're able to change the value you're still forbidden from creating a new variable with the
same name which is useful for variables that you only want declared once Konst however does not stop
an object from being modified.
When we talk about data that cannot be changed we call that data immutable.
Remember constant does not make objects immutable in the next video will introduce a new keyword that
as 20:15 gives us to declare variables.
The let keyword and will introduce a whole new kind of scope in javascript.
See you there.