All right.
Welcome back.
And welcome to our first main event of the section where we'll actually see how to make our first request
using javascript.
Good stuff.
So outside of the JavaScript world there are a ton of ways of making requests.
You can make them from an iOS app.
There are libraries to do it.
You can do it from an Android app from.
From refreshing your browser from a Java app or rails out from your command line using curl or some
other utility.
So many ways of making requests and that's kind of the point is that it's a standard way of communicating
between computers.
But how it's actually done the actual thing that initiates that request is different usually at least
and in javascript that applies.
There are multiple ways of making requests.
You can see a couple of them here and in this section we're going to survey a couple of them.
The key important ones and you'll kind of come to learn both the history of Ajax is we're going about
them in a particular order.
But you'll also see how things are built on top of one another and how things have gotten much easier
as time has gone on.
So we're going to start off with the worst named one of all the options.
SML HTP requests such a mouthful to say just call it X H R for short.
This was the original way of making requests from the browser.
I think it was in Netscape.
If you're familiar with that one the old early browsers I think that was the first browser to include
this way of making requests.
And so when Ajax first came around back in 2004 2005 and when gmail came out with kind of its live updating
e-mail inbox and a couple of other apps as well it was using X-amount HTP requests to power it.
So let's see how to make one VND talking about this.
It's not the nicest syntax.
I'll be blunt about it.
This is not how I ever I mean pretty much never make requests this way anymore but that doesn't mean
you shouldn't know how it works because libraries that will use things like Jay Querrey or X-ers another
one are built using this underneath the hood.
So it's good to know.
And it also explains a lot about how the request actually works.
So the syntax like I said is not great.
To help us make the most sense of all this I think it's best just to type it and kind of talk about
it as we go.
So I have an empty code pen here.
I've minimized everything.
We're just going to be writing javascript in this video.
So our end goal is to request an API and get data back and the API we're going to work with to start
is a very very simple one.
It's kind of a joke.
It's put out by get help.
It's part of their much larger get have API that contains way more information but the endpoint API
get hub slashes.
Every time you hit that end point every time you request it you get a little zen quote.
Usually it's not just traditional Zen it's tech Zen or business and they focus over features of Word
administrative distraction.
Yeah not the most interesting thing ever.
But it's a really nice quick API for us to just play around with.
So we're not getting bogged down with the data.
But we will be working with more interesting data in this section.
So what we want to do is request that you are all just like I'm doing here except through Javascript.
So to do that we're going to use the next H.R..
So the first thing we want to do is create a new variable.
Call it whatever you want.
I usually call mine x h r but that's totally up to you and it needs to be equal to new XM.
H TTP request
and this will be totally honest with you has always thrown me off that the Exham is capitalized but
HTP isn't even though HTP is also an abbreviation or an acronym very confusing to me.
But anyway this makes us a new instance of the SML HDP request.
So our end goal is going to be to request this API API.
I get updates.
Com slash then.
So what we want to do to actually make that happen is reference our ex-aide char variable whatever you
named it Dot open.
That's the first important part.
And then there's a second thing ex-aide Charcot send.
So this is in complete just yet but send is what will actually send it off will actually initiate everything.
But ex-aide Charcot open is where we tell it what type of request to make.
If you're not familiar with HTP request verb's there's a couple of different options.
We're going to make a get request.
There's other things like post request put patch delete a couple of others.
We want to make a request because we are retrieving information.
And that's how the API is set up.
We're not sending data we're not updating or deleting data we're simply retrieving it.
Then the second thing we need to provide is that you are out.
What are we requesting.
So in quotes we'll put our API.
You are well and safe.
So on its own this is kind of the bare bones to actually make that request.
So if I open up the console let me also refresh the page to make that code run.
Nothing happens and that doesn't mean that the request isn't being made.
It just means that we're not doing anything about it.
We're not retrieving the data we're not displaying it we're certainly not counseled not logging in to
do that.
We need to understand a little bit more about how the requests actually work.
So there's a property called Ready state on every request.
It can be one of five different options.
They're all numbered starting with zero up to four and they correspond to a different state of the request.
So it starts off with unsent all the way up to done along the way.
There are a couple of steps.
So if you care about the details basically the order is this the request is unsent.
The Open method has not been called then open has been called that's the next step.
Then after that send has been called Finally not quite finally but after that we get content downloading.
So it's on its way back.
It just might be taking a bit depending on how much data is coming back.
And then there's done where everything is finished.
So what we want to do most of the time at least is basically have the record go off and then do something
when it's done.
That's what we care about when our data is back.
So we want to be able to check is the ready state done and the way we do that is by taking advantage
of an event called on ready state change.
So this will call a function.
Every time the ready state changes so it goes from zero to 1 1 to 2 2 to 3 3 to 4.
And then inside of that we'll be able to check ok is the ready state done is it done is it done.
And as soon as it is done we can do whatever you'd like with the code.
So let's go back to code pen and we add this event listener so ex-aide Charcot on ready state change
equals and then we give it a function and then whatever we do in here will happen any time that ready
state changes.
So let's do a console Dalt log.
Ready state is.
And then add X H.R. dot ready state.
So if we do this and that's actually capitalized I believe and I move my semi-colon to the end.
We open up our con..
I have a bunch of them already but let me clear that out.
Refresh the page once you can see we get the first change where it starts from zero and it changed to
one triggering event.
Then it changed to two to three into four.
And then it's finished.
That's it.
So what we want to do is check if the ready state is for.
That means it's done so we can just do a simple IF statement if and then we do X a chart ready state
equals equals number four then we'll save and we'll do something in here.
And the magic line if we want the data that's actually coming back it's an x 8 char dot response text
capital-T.
So that let's consider log it
exit X age our response text.
So if we just tried doing this from the very beginning without this if statement there won't be response
text when the response hasn't finished.
So we want to make sure we're waiting until ready state is exactly for meeting that the request is done.
OK.
Refresh the page check our council over here and we get our data back.
Every time I refresh.
Every time I run this code which right now that's how the code is running.
We're getting a new set of Zen API whatever you want to call this little tidbit coming back.
So the last thing I want to talk about is what happens if the request doesn't actually work.
What if are you are our requesting is down the servers down.
It doesn't exist anymore or potentially we have a typo.
You know what if I tried to go to get up about com slash Zann 10 blah something like that.
Well we don't have a way of handling that just yet.
In fact if I tried that and open up my console it clear this out just to make it clearer and I refresh
can see you get this get 4 or 4 not found but then more importantly my response text is wittered.
So we can actually handle that in our code.
We could have an edge case where we're checking did the response or did it actually work to the request
go through.
And what signifies that to us is the status code.
So you've probably seen four or four pages before or some other status codes.
If we want to check if something worked.
We're going to check if the status codes 200.
And then we'll have an otherwise so if it's 200 that means we're good.
Otherwise there's a problem.
So we can just write x h.
Our dot status.
So if it equals 200 then we'll cancel that log the response text perfect and we can add an else that
just checks or that says otherwise let's do consulate log.
There was a problem just like that.
So again we're checking first if the request is done.
Ready state equals four.
And then within that we have an extra layer to check was the status code.
OK 200 if it was then do something and we're only constant logging so that won't break things.
But if we were trying to insert an image into our into the DOM if we're trying to update an H1 maybe
add a UI card manipulating the DOM and we need to use response text and it's not there or we're getting
something weird back.
It could potentially break your app so you want to make sure that something will be there.
Otherwise there's a problem.
So right now are you or Al is ridiculous.
Refresh the page and we get there was a problem.
Cool.
So if we go back to our normal API to get have dotcom now we get faver focus over features.
Speak like a human.
Cool.
OK.
So let's wrap it up.
There's a lot of syntax here but it really comes down to the way that these requests work.
They're very bare bones.
All the innards are exposed to you can see every state that it goes through.
It starts off at zero where the request hasn't been opened or has it been sent.
It's basically just waiting.
And it goes all the way up to done we're just ready state for that's the one we care about.
Basically these two bits if you want to write requests your typical S.H. our request will be using these
two things a lot checking if it finished and checking if it was OK if it worked.
There are so commonly used that you often just have them in a single line like this.
But like I mentioned there are better easier ways of writing requests.
This is kind of a lot of work.
There are better ways that we're going to see in just a couple of videos.
All righty.
Take a break.
It's kind of a lot.