Talk about pure functions pure functions or functional programming concept that's pretty important to
understand for re-act Our objective will be just to define a pure function so pure function is a function
without side effects meaning it does not modify its inputs and it does not modify any global state one
test to see if a function is pure or not is to ask is it repeatable given the same inputs.
Do I always get the same outputs.
And that's not always true of the function modifies its inputs or modifies global state.
Here's an example of a function that's not pure.
So this function takes in an array and doubles every element in the array.
But this violates one of the tenets of pure functions which is you can't modify the inputs.
If I were to run this function multiple times with the same input array the result of this function
would keep changing my array.
So the one test for pure functions to say is it repeatable fails in this case.
This is an example of how to refactor that code to make it appear function.
So rather than modify the inputs in this case we're using a radar map.
Remember a radar map returns a new array.
So our input is never altered.
And if you run this function again and again and again with the same input array you'll always get the
same output array.
Here's another example of a function is not pure in this case we're modifying global state.
So this add job function will add a property called job to the person object.
So this is a classic example of causing a side effect.
How can we refactor this so that it is pure will in this case we're taking that person object as a parameter.
Since that data is involved in what we're doing in the function it should be a parameter to our function.
Also we're not modifying that person object directly.
Instead we're using objects that assign to create a new object which is the combination of the original
object and our new value that we want to add job.
Here's another way to write that same function also as a pure function.
But this time we'll use the object spread operator.
So the spread operator takes all the keys and the values from that object and puts it in this new object
that we're we're creating.
And any any key to the right of that spread operator overwrites any key that may have been an object
on the left.
So if Person object in this case had a key called Job Job would be overwritten.
And if it didn't have a key called job then we would also have the new job.
Now that we've added to this new object also notice that we're using the shorthand here.
So this is the same as saying job Colan job because we have a key called job and we also have a variable
called job well that's all well and good but what does this have to do with react.
And the point of this video is that changes to state should be pure.
You should never modify that state directly.
You should always use this said state and you should always give it a new objects for your state.
You should never change the object in this state.
Of course that's easier said than done.
So up next we'll have an exercise to solidify this concept where we have to update some state that's
a little bit more complex than the last example that we saw.