Welcome back.
In this video we'll use what we've learned about working with men's axes and scales and D-3 to build
our first scatterplot.
In keeping with the theme let's graph some more birth data as always.
Here are a couple of links to some starter code.
This time around I've got data not only on earths but also on population land area and life expectancy.
This data is organized by region and is from 2011.
Let's visualize this data with a scatterplot on the y axis.
I want to measure life expectancy on the X-axis.
I want some measurement of birth's rather than looking at the birth numbers directly though.
I'll look at births divided by population.
This will give me a measurement of births per capita rather than yes the total number of births in the
last video.
We learned how to use various D-3 methods to help us work with our data here will need to use those
methods again.
First let's create a scale for the y axis in order to do that will calculate the minimum and maximum
in our dataset.
Since the y axis is measuring life expectancy.
This is the property will need to return in our callback function.
Note that from here on out I'll be using aero functions for these callbacks wherever I can.
Once we've got our man in RMX we can create our scale as in the previous video.
We're mapping our minimum to the height and our maximum to zero.
If you don't remember why we do this.
Go back and re watch the last video.
This looks pretty good so far.
But before we move on it's worth mentioning a small reactor we can do here.
There's a fair amount of code duplication in our logic calculating them in and the max we could pull
the callback out into its own named function.
But we can also use D-3 is built in extent a function which calculates both the minimum and maximum
in the dataset and returns both values to us in an array.
Here's a quick example.
In this case we've got an array of people and want to know the range of ages the extent method will
return to us an array with both the smallest age and the largest one we can call this function inside
of our scales domain indirectly.
Let's do that now.
That's better.
Now let's move on to our x axis here we'll want to do basically the same thing just with a different
scale.
We'll want to return Deedat births divided by Deedat population rather than just D-CA life expectancy
cool.
Now let's make our first scatterplot first will set the width and height of our SVGA then we'll create
an empty selection of circles and join our data to it.
After that we'll hop into the enter selection append new circles and begin to style them the coordinates
of the circle are based on our scales pronounce.
Just to get something showing up on the page let's set the radius of each circle to be five.
Now let's refresh the page one circle for each region.
As you can tell there's a fairly strong negative association between life expectancy and births per
capita.
The higher this measurement of birth rate the lower the life expectancy so far so good.
But there are a couple of issues with this visualization.
One is that the circle's towards the edges of the SPG are getting cut off because their centers lie
along the edges of the SPG the most common way to fix this problem is to set some padding for the SPG
and then update our scales to account for this batting now and we have a data point.
It's a man or a max.
It won't be mapped to the corner of the S.A.G. but will be offset by our padding value.
Let me add some padding quickly and then refresh the page that looks better.
Let's add some more functionality right now our scatterplot helps us visualize the relationship between
two variables life expectancy and births per capita.
But we can visualize even more relationships by adjusting other aspects of the circles.
To other attributes we could adjust based on the data or the fill in the radius.
Let's use these attributes to make our visualization a little more interesting.
For the Phil will adjust the color based on the country's population density.
That is it's population divided by its area let's cover things so that low densities are green and high
densities are black.
How can we do this scale linier is got us covered.
It can do more than Map numbers to numbers.
It can also map numbers to colors.
Check it out this scale works by converting colors to R.G. B values.
So the smallest density gets mapped green the largest gets mapped to black and so on with this scale
we can now adjust the field based on the population density
nice as you can see.
It looks like one country has a particularly high density Wesley.
Let's use the radius to provide us with some more insight on what the radius of each circle be based
just on the number of births not on the births per capita.
For this we'll need one more scale.
There we go now our scatterplot helps us to visualize the relationship between four variables births
births per capita life expectancy and population density.
That's it for now in the next video.
We'll keep working on this graph so that we can improve its readability.