OK.
So it's time to learn our flex box property.
It's not one that's actually on this list and that's because it's a property that is not specific to
flex fluxbox that property is display which you're probably familiar with but we're using it with a
value that you may not have seen before but we'll get to that in just a moment.
First I want to show you our starting point.
So this is a flex box.
Let's lay out if you want to call the lay out a very simple thing to create.
We have four divs inside of another div..
Another container.
And by default those four divs are going to be on separate lines as you can see here one after another
in this section.
I've made a bunch of diagrams.
Really a lot of telegrams using this sort of language is visual language of just divs or blocks whatever
you want to call them colored boxes that are being arranged in different patterns.
So again here's what it would look like without flex box no styling aside from the color and the font
size just for divs inside another div.
But if we change one property of the container this outside div they're all inside of where there's
this big border I can suddenly get them to all go on the same line.
And that first little bit of magic looks like this display flex.
So as I mentioned this is not a flex box specific property.
Display is something you're probably familiar with but by setting display to flex we are setting the
container div or whatever the boxes that we're working with a header section and NAV whatever it is
we are setting it to flex which makes it a flex container.
And this is what we get.
So those four boxes that were one after another vertically are now all together.
Shoves the left side of this box.
Now I'm not saying that's what you want.
I'm not saying that's the end result but just that one little line makes a big impact.
Let me just illustrate that to you.
So here I have the exact same thing except I have 10 divs are actually nine divs different colors and
they're inside of a div called container.
So nine boxes inside a div called container.
And if I just select that container and I set that display to flex immediately they all go in line like
that and let me give my container of border 10 pixels solid black and you can see that this container
goes all the way across.
But there's a bunch of unused space for some reason and everything is shoved onto the left side.
The order is still the same but the divs themselves are much much smaller.
If I get rid of that display they take up a lot of space.
Now display flex they're much more condensed so I'm going to leave it at that.
That's the magic of display flex.
Why would you want that.
Well you'll see in just a bit that this is for you a lot of control.
You can move things to the right you can space them out.
You can move them up and down.
Basically this is just starting the process.
This is the first property that anytime you use fluxbox.
You have to apply to the container.
I'm trying to keep the video short in this section so that's all I'm going to talk about in the next
video.
We're going to talk about some basic terminology.