And that brings me to my next point I want to bring up is why the animations really matter.
Yes.
The flashy part of things is interesting it's cool to see what people can do.
You know you can add glitter to your page add some sparkle.
But beyond that is there some real utility for learning how to do CSSA animations.
And I think the answer is yes this is a medium article written by Michael velar Mikael Vlaar.
I apologize.
I'm butchering his name is a user interface developer at striped stripe.
You have probably come across if you buy things online frequently.
It's a payment processing company slash API.
Probably put through that as well explanation.
But the key thing here is that this article I think does a great job of summing up a couple of the reasons
why animations matter.
So at Strype the payment experience is what they do right.
That is their product really is having a solid payment experience.
So it really matters for them to improve that to optimize it.
And this article talks about why animations are used and how they're used to improve that process.
So things like animations can add context.
So here's an example of how an animation could provide some utility to a user to make things clear.
So in this example when the user clicks the Remember Me check box there's a nice little kind of slide
out or three dimensional foldout animation where the phone number and put slides down.
And that really shows the user that there's a connection there that there's context.
You only need to input your phone number if you're checking the Remember Me checkbox and that they're
important they're connected.
So other things would be providing feedback to users.
So a common one is this shaking or a jiggle I guess to mimic sort of the shaking of somebody's head
in a negative gesture.
So when you try and pay without filling any information out or you're missing a component you get this
error feedback.
And it's more visceral I guess it's more visual that's clearer.
Ideally what's happening something that this does this article doesn't touch on.
But that is related to this point has to do with accessibility.
People who have visual impairments often can benefit from animations on a page.
They can.
Like I said draw people's attention make things clearer as this is doing here rather than just having
us you know a small red icon having the actual shake clearly indicates that this is not going to work.
The next topic he goes into is what he refers to as sleight of hand essentially creating an illusion
of speed or snappishness deceiving your users a little bit by using animations making the experience
seem better.
What's happening here is that they're sending a verification code to a mobile device and takes a bit
of time.
And they have this little animation that says starts off with sending code sent and then we just sent
a text message to your phone number.
And the point he's making is that it's actually not true.
They are sending it.
But the animation is not in sync with that.
You may get your text before that or afterwards.
They don't know exactly how long it will take from the front end side of things.
But this animation kind of provides this step by step process that is potentially more engaging for
a user rather than just loading loading loading loading and just kind of waiting.
And you could be staring at the same state here the entire time they decided to break it up even though
on the back and this has zero connections to influence.
There's no relationship between what's actually being displayed and what's happening.
The animation makes it seem nicer.
One more thing.
This transition here he talks about how there are two states.
There's this first state payment info.
You click that and it transitions to the pay button.
But it uses the exact same transition as the above content.
So if you notice one time sort of slides over and the button does the exact same thing and he writes
about how the reason he did that the reason he has that match the button matches the same transition
as the content above is to highlight that the actions are linked to that button.
So as it as it changes the action changes well and then we get to the last point he makes which is what
he calls a bonus round.
This one sticks out a bit but I still think it's really important.
So it's not something that makes or breaks the actual flow as he mentions it could be removed without
any serious consequence.
It's just a nice looking flashy animation but the reason he thinks it's important is that it indicates
to users that this is a new site.
This is something that is currently being worked on.
This is not a company that it's 10 years old with an old static site where animations weren't an option.
This is something that was released recently.
It's sharp it's fresh.
I think you get it hopefully you get what I'm trying to say.
It can kind of lend your site and therefore your company some credibility an air of professionalism
if you will.
So while it may seem minor I do agree with that.
That having animations having a Polish site makes a difference.
OK.
So that wraps up kind of the key points I wanted to talk about around why you should care about learning
animations why it's not just flashy sparkles that you're throwing on to a completed web page but why
it's actually an integral part of designing a website designing an application.
So before we dive into any code there is one quick point I want to make when we're actually learning
this stuff how do we transition something we see assess how to create a simple animation.
How do we do a hover animation whatever we talk about in the next couple of videos.
I think you'll see that getting things to move getting things to animate is easy that's actually the
easy part.
So it might seem intimidating at first but if somebody asks you move this over 20 pixels to the right
when a user clicks on it that's actually not very difficult.
As far as the syntax in the code but what is hard about animating and this is something that I learned
personally when I started out with animations something that I have seen a lot of students encounter
and get frustrated by.
The hard part is that planning how things should work conceptualizing the animation designing things
is hard.
So getting things to move is easy but planning how they should move is hard.
And I think that's true of a lot of things but especially animations.
So if you have some great idea implementing it often it's not that difficult.
Maybe if there's some crazy curves and complex trajectories you need things to follow where you have
to get into some math and trig.
Yes that could be difficult.
But typically most web apps most of the animations you see are not that difficult to implement.
Again the hard part is conceptualizing it.
That's where having a design background or having a designer on your team can really help.
And I'm not a designer who can be upfront about that.
I do my best to make these examples look good to come up with real world animations but it's something
I struggle with as well.
When I'm designing my own apps I always talk to somebody about how the animations should work because
usually my first instinct is not great.
OK.
So with all that said we talked about why animations matter.
We saw some cool things you can do with animations.
Now we're going to dive into code.
All right.
So in the next video.