So be last left off with a bit of an issue where we could simply create messages for any kind of specific
user.
And in fact you didn't even need to be logged in to create a message.
So what we need to start introducing is some ways of intercepting the request to make sure first that
a user is logged in and that they are the correct user to do that.
We're going to have to write a little bit of middleware.
And that's what we're going to put inside of here.
So I'm going to add a file called off us inside of my middleware and here I'm going to bring in any
environment variables that I need I'll use require
that you and the load to bring in any of those I may still be able to get away with this dot in the
config.
But I want to be super sure that the load in those at the correct time.
I'm also going to bring in my Giese on web tokin module and that's because we're going to need to decode
the tokens that are passed.
So we're going to pass in Jason.
OK.
So we need two functions right here.
We need one to make sure the user is logged in another to make sure we get the correct user.
This is the idea of authorization and this right here is the idea of authentication are your credentials
correct.
Have you actually been logged in before.
If so great.
Now are you actually allowed to do this.
So we are going to export two functions log in required and that's going to be a function with wreck.
RAZ And next.
This is actually going to be one of the only easting functions that we don't make and that is because
the GWG module still uses a callback pattern.
So we're going to use callback functions just because we have a promise of five this library yet.
So let's start with our log in required function.
What we're going to do is first try to get the token from in each TDP Hetter and then each VDB is really
just some metadata or higher level information about that request.
So we get that from rect-Al headers and the name of the header that we're going to use is one called
authorization.
And the way that this Hetter usually comes in is something first called the realm which is kind of the
way that we're doing the authentication that we're that we're going to use by convention is the word
barer followed by a space and then the entire token.
So in order to get whatever is after that space we are going to split this strength.
We're going to split it by a space and we're going to get whatever is at index 1.
The problem is if correct I header's that authorization is undefined.
Maybe someone just tried to access something and didn't put in that header.
This would come up as undefined.
And if we called undefined data split javascript would give us the Tiber.
So even though this is non-racing function we're still going to use a try catch to handle that potential
situation.
Always make sure we have that parameter inside catch that looks good.
Now what do we want to do inside of here.
We want to decode that token.
We're going to do that using JWT to verify.
And the first parameter is going to be the token.
The second parameter is going to be our secret key.
This is what we're going to use to try to successfully decode that token and when we're done we're going
to run a function.
We potentially could get some error.
The second thing that we're going to get back is the actual payload that we're going to call decoded.
You can call that payload as well if you want.
And right now I don't really care about what's in the payload.
All I want to know is if it exists if there is a payload.
If we have successfully decoded this token Well then we're don't return next.
You're logged in.
Move on to the next piece of middleware that might be making sure you have the correct user or validating
something else or just letting you go on to whatever handler that we have.
Otherwise something went wrong.
Well what went wrong.
The tokin could not be decoded.
It means that either you tried to tamper with the token or you just haven't put in something correct.
So we'll say status of 401.
That is unauthorized and we'll add a message of Please log in first.
This is pretty generic.
Someone could have potentially tampered with the token or tried to mess up something.
So instead of telling them something like I see that you're trying to hack my web site we're just going
to say Please log in first.
Better to be generic with this kind of stuff than give anybody any kind of hint or indication.
And if there is an issue with this or not being passed in or not being interpreted correctly we're going
to return next as well.
But that same message is simply just so that they don't make any typos going to grab what's inside of
this object as well.
So once again how does this function work.
Well we're going to add it as a piece of middleware.
It's going to go in between the request and our handler to create a message.
That way if you're not logged in you can't create a message.
We're going to try playing around with this in a little bit before we do that though.
It's nice that you're logged in to create a message but it still doesn't solve our problem of creating
a message for someone else.
So what we want to do is make sure that we authorize those users as well.
And the next screen cast will write a function called the correct user that performs this authorization.