So we left off the last video just starting to build an express application.
And I briefly showed that we could make a request to this back end using the curl command if you're
not familiar with Perl.
It's a simple way to make each TZP request from the command line.
You've seen postman.
Or maybe some other nice interface to do that.
What I want to show you is the command to start.
But once we start making more complex API requests what I want to show you then is a tool called HDD
pie.
This is a tool that I use quite a bit in development.
So we left off by starting our server using gnomon and then we made a request and we saw all of this
kind of gross.
Each TNL what I'd like to do is instead build a small error handler that sends back Jason or a five
hundred status code which means that something would be wrong.
So I'm going to do that inside of my handlers.
I'm going to make a new file and I'll call that error.
Yes.
And inside of ordinary us we're going to simply create a function called error handler and error handler
is going to accept as its first parameter in error.
It's also going to accepter cost response and indexed.
So remember requesting response that's the wreckin rez that you've seen many times before.
In Express applications.
But what we're going to do here is build a piece of middleware.
This is going to be used after our 404 handler and we will return a response that status of the error
status or 500.
If you remember what our error status was back in this index yes it was a 404.
If we don't make it to the 404 that means that there has been a route that has been found but something
went wrong on the server.
So what we're going to do here is attack the Jason method so that we can then return an object.
This object will call error.
And inside it will give it a message property that's going to be whatever the message of that error
is.
Or a generic message maybe we'll see something like whoops something went wrong.
What will finally do here is export this function so we can see a module that exports is equal to error
handler.
So you might still be wondering what's the purpose of this code that we're writing and the idea here
is simply to make a generic function that is going to respond with the status of the error.
Whether that's a 404 or maybe custom errors that we make or 500 which means that something has gone
wrong on the server.
So where do we actually get to use this error handler.
Well back in our index yes we first have to import it.
So what I'm going to do up here say Konst error handler.
Is the result of require.
And here we always have to specify a relative path because if we don't specify a relative path Express
is always going to try to look in the node modules folder and that's not where our handler lives.
So at the very bottom of my code right before my laptop listen I'm going to add another use for this
error handler.
And what this is going to do is it's going to take any incoming middleware within error and it will
print out a NACER display using Jaisalmer.
So let's go back and start our server and see what this looks like.
So my server still started actually thanks to gnomon.
I'm going to make a request to localhost 80 81 and you can see right off the bat.
I get this NACER just on message that says error message not found.
This is what we're going to be using to send back to the client when errors go on.
And it's really important to have a very good standardized error handler so that one front end developers
start working with your API.
They know exactly what to expect.
It's sometimes very challenging.
We have a very cryptic error message and the front end developer has to work or change that error message
to display something that you might want.
So what we've simply done here is build a standard error handler.
This is a very simple way.
Of kind of bridging the gap between sending back some HDMI which wouldn't really work.
Remember we're building an API so we really just want to send back song so to do that we've written
this nice error handler function that should help us out.
So what we're going to do in the next video is start actually adding some data to our application.
We're going to build a model for a user.
We're then going to start adding some routes and some handlers for that user.
We're going to see if we have the ability to create users and send them in as well or even get to introduce
authentication and some web tokens as well into the mix.