In the last video we looked at re-act router setup and some basic functionality.
Now we'll talk about a few more advanced features.
So objectives will be to use the L parameters for out defined route props defined with router and last
passing your own props to a component in a route component and this will be the difference between using
render inside that raw component or using the component prop Inside the Raw component.
First up your L parameters.
So just like on the back end if we have some parameter that we care about within the drill we can add
a colon and then première name here.
So in this case call in name and then if we want to render whatever's in that route or use whatever's
in that route we can use Match.com up harams so matched up harams that name is the string that matches
from this route.
So if I had a path like Slash Tim this component would say Hello Tim.
What does this match pro-ams Where does it come from.
Well those are route props.
Any component that is rendered from within a route component gets three props.
The first which we just saw is called match and that's info about how the path inside the route matched
the current Eurail.
The next one is the location and that's information about where you are now similar to a window location.
And the final one is history which is similar to the HCM L5 history object.
It allows you to do things like go back and change the oil.
All three of these props can be pretty useful at times but they're only available when that component
is rendered from within a route component.
But there's times when you want those three props outside of or out component.
And that's what with routers for.
So if your component is not rendered from within a route component you can wrap it you know with router
function and then you will receive those three props.
So here's an example of a component that wants to use the history prop.
Now history is normally a prop that gets passed in if you're inside of a route component.
But in this case this button code is not inside of a route component.
So we want history because when you click on that go home we want to change the oil to slash.
That's what this push does here.
In order for this history prop to be defined we need to wrap this switch demo in a with router function
with router will return a new component that gets all three of these props history match and location.
Another problem that you run into is that when you use a route component the component that you end
up rendering you want to pass additional props too.
But the component property won't allow you to do that.
So in order to solve this problem or use render instead of component and as a word of warning down here
the route component can either use render or a component you should not be using both.
Let's look at example.
So in this example we've got a component called teachers and it expects a teacher's prop which is an
array of teacher names.
Here it's just going to be Tim man Ellie.
So it's going to loop over that teacher's array and it's going to just display each teacher an ally.
Now inside of our main app we want to use that teacher's component but we also want to pass that teachers
prop in.
So in order to get that to work we'll use render rather than component render essentially takes a stateless
functional component.
The first parameter is prop's the props that we're going to get and those props are the props that you
get inside of her out component like match location and history.
Now when we render that component we want to spread out our props so that this teachers component will
get matched location history and then we'll also want to provide our additional props in this case the
teacher's array is equal to that teachers are we created up here now in this renders the teachers component
will get the props that it expects and everything work.
The last thing I want to mention is that you should go check out the re-act router docs.
So here's the beginning of the Web documentation and there's tons of great examples in here let me make
that a little bigger.
There's tons of great examples in here.
So it's definitely worth checking out if you get stuck or if you just want to learn a little bit more
on your own.
For example there's information about auth which will cover later animated transitions.
So lots of good use cases here.
I would definitely use this as a resource because next up we're going to be doing an exercise involving
the re-act router.