Well come back.
So this video will be very very quick.
But we just need to hammer out some basic terms that we're going to come back to that we'll refer to
throughout these next couple of videos and they're really important actually.
Usually terminology stuff maybe is not that exciting or that important but in this case a lot of the
properties that we'll talk about there very definitions depend on some of these terms.
OK so there's a couple of things.
First we have a flex container and that refers to whatever item whatever container has the display flex
property.
So in this case when we assign display flex to our container div it becomes a flex container.
Beforehand is just a container.
Now it's a flex container.
The next bit are the individual boxes or whatever the content is.
If they are inside of a container with display flex we call them flex items.
So they worked they'll actually behave differently than just a traditional item or whatever you have
inside of a device.
We've already seen when we did this.
Here is how they were behaving before by applying display flex to the container.
The children the flex items are behaving very differently.
So when we refer to flex item it's just something inside of a flex container.
OK.
Now the two most important things I should point out all of all three of these are flex items.
I just didn't put the text flex item over here because I thought it was confusing.
You might think of us labeling this arrow.
So yes all three of these are flex items.
Ok so now onto the two most important bits of jargon.
Main axis and cross axis.
So these two axes are very important.
They'll pop up in pretty much at least the next five or six videos possibly every video in this section
underlying every move of the content that we make whether we are shifting things to the right or down
or centering them spacing them out.
It happens along one of these axes.
So the main axis in this case is not always I don't want to make sure that you understand it's not always
from left to right like this but in our case it is in this demonstration where this is our first flex
item or second or third.
They are arranged in a row.
The main access by default goes from left to right and then the cross axis is always just the opposite
perpendicular.
In our case it moves from top to bottom but that's actually not something you could tell from this diagram.
If it wasn't labeled but if I had 10 different flex items on a couple of rows they would float downwards.
So the next row would happen here.
The next row would have and below that the cross axis is pointing that way.
But as we progressed through the videos we'll see ways of reversing the main axis so that our content
starts here and goes that way or by inverting it entirely and making everything into a column so that
the main axis is actually going from top to bottom and the cross axis is going from left to right or
from right to left.
So not to overwhelm you with that but just be aware there are these two terms.
May the axis cross axis perpendicular and we're now going to learn a bunch of properties that allow
us to manipulate how things work across these axes axes right axes.
All right.
Now for that let's get writing some code.