All right.
So we've seen how the base dollar signs that Ajax method works.
We're now going to focus on three shorthand methods which allow us to make common types request easier.
So those three are get post and get Jaison.
So I have a code Penick created and it has three buttons in it.
One that has an idea of button.
Another post button.
And the third get Jason button.
So as we click each one I want to fire a respective Jay query method.
So in this case the get method to send the GET request.
So the Duxford J queried don't get any time.
By the way if you see query don't get it's the same as dollar sign at dollar sign it's just a shorter
alias for it to find these Darcs it's under Ajax shorthand method.
And then Jay querido get is the one we're focusing on.
So if you look at the syntax the first thing you'll see is repasts in you are l that's the only mandatory
thing to pass in.
And then we can optionally provide data and a couple other things.
If we look at an example further down scroll to the bottom this is it to send a simple get request to
a row.
This won't do anything with the results that are returned.
But this is how we send it.
Now if we want to do something afterwards this is where we come in with our DOT done and or fail if
we want to handle errors.
So I'm going to make a get request to have API you IRL.
So it's just a matter of dollar sign get.
And then the are.
So that's the euro I'm going to use.
Feel free to use any other you are l that will allow a valid get request and then we'll just add are
done and all we'll do is print the data.
So inside this quick handler forget button I click it is fires dollar signs get which behind the scenes
is doing the same thing as a dollar sign.
Ajax or we set method to get.
And then you Arel to this you are real here.
So it's a shortcut.
OK.
Let's make sure it works.
Save quick get.
And there we go.
We get our data back.
Remember the way that this works I didn't specify this Jason but it inferred that it made a guess.
If you want to be explicit You can see if we can provide data type but we actually specify it as a string.
So no longer as an object with key value pairs we just pass in Jason cool so we can also add in our
fail.
We wanted to.
I want to do this for all of them.
Let's just to fail.
Cancel that log error for now that's it.
So dollars and I get again it's just shorthand.
So you don't have to write that entire AJAX call.
Next up we have post which works in the exact same way except it sends a post request.
So when I click the post button nothing happens right now but I'd like to do is send a signed up post.
We specify a URL.
So I'm just going to put any you all that probably won't except a post request I'll just do it.
Cats are cool and so are dogs.
Dot com.
And after that we'll do our dun function data.
We're not going to get anything back.
Most likely that log.
And then we'll also have our fail
and end here.
We're just going to cancel that log error.
Ok so all we care about is that this is actually sending a post request.
So I'm going to open up my console here click Post get an error for a 4 triggers our error.
But if we go to our network tab can see it attempts to send to get more information a post request.
And if you look at the docs if you want to provide data that is the second parameter.
So after the you are l we can option the optional specify some data to send as you can see here.
So let me show you that we can do it this way or we can make a variable.
I'll do that.
So our data equals make it an object and I'll just say name is Charlie and I don't know city is Florance
like that.
And then I can just pass in that data object.
Now if we look and inspect this go to our network tab ex-aide jars center post scroll way down we can
see our data is in here as well.
It's equivalent to go back to the docs doing this up here.
Where would you dollar sign that Ajax type post or method is post then providing the URL and then providing
the data.
But instead we can do it with a much shorter syntax.
Then finally get Jaison.
So get Jaison is a nice shortcut that automatically send to get requests to the euro.
But then also parses it as Jaison it doesn't have to make an intelligent guess because by using get
Jaison we're specifying this is 100 percent based on that you're getting.
We don't have to specify the data type it just knows because we're using get Jason and it parses it
for us.
So it's equivalent to this specifying the euro and the data type as well as the method or type as gets
which is the default.
So they don't put it here but it's the same thing.
So let me show you that we can use the same API you are here and I have this get Jason button when we
click it.
I'm going to do.
Dollar Signs get Jason and pass it in RL and that's it.
Done and fail.
So for Don I'll just do the same to that log that data for fail.
I'll just cancel that log.
There's a problem
perfect.
So nice and easy syntax.
Make sure it works quick get Jason.
And there we go.
I get my API data already parsed back as Jaison so very simple.
We don't have to write out the entire dot Ajax or dollar sign but Ajax and specify all those different
parameters or options.
So three shortcut methods.
But as I told you earlier they are all in the source code and you can see them here.
If we scroll down I'm on let's see what is this page.
Jay query source Ajax slash or slash Ajax dodgiest scroll way down there where they actually make this
method just kind of interesting.
So they make them get imposts together so they have this array for each string get and post make a method
called whatever the string is so make a method call get and make a method called post and all that it
does is call J querido Ajax and it sets you around to the Euro type to be the method which is get and
post so as you can see it defines these automatically or procedurally using this each.
So then we end up with get in a post method and then further up we have get Jaison and although that
does is it returned J.
Query does get.
And it specifies that the data type is Jason.
So Jason is built on top of get and get and post are built on top of the base Ajax base.
Ajax is built on top of the base SH are all right.
So that wraps that up.
Hopefully you feel OK but using these methods.
Personally I use JS on all the time.
It's probably the most commonly used for them.
Just because it's the simplest and the most common use case but it's good to know that these others
exist.