Welcome back.
Over the course of the next few videos we're going to build this marketing page for mountain travel
together.
In this video we'll build everything you see when the page loads the nav bar the background and this
text in the middle of the page.
Let's take a look at the code we're working with.
I've gotten assets folder with a blank stylesheet along with five pictures of mountains my HVM file
is pretty minimal so far.
I've got some Medhat tags and I'm loading a couple of months but the body is empty.
Let's start by building out the headers in my HVM owl.
I'll create a header element and give it to children and H-2 and NF
inside of the H-2 I'll put in a tag with the name of the site.
Mountain travel
inside the nav I'll add three more 8 x 1 for tours.
One for about and one for contact.
Since these links don't actually go anywhere I'll set all of their Tref attributes equal to the hash
tag which will just send the user back to the top of the page so far this page is pretty Doleac.
Let's hop into the CSSA and start styling first I'll set some general styles to avoid any consistencies
across browsers.
I'll clear out all margins and paddings and I'll set the box size of every element to be border box
next on the HVM Eltang.
I'll style the font by setting values for the font property and the color property.
After that how style the nav and the atax for my nav I don't want to see bullet points.
So I'll set the list style to none and for the atax rather than the default browser behavior.
This scene underlines I'll set the text decoration to none but I'll trigger a different opacity when
you hover over a link.
Now let's get into style specific to the header
for the header itself.
I'll use fluxbox
justify the content to use space between the line items in the center.
I'll also give the headers some padding
next.
I'll use the Google quicksand font for the H-2
for the Navajo side of the header.
I'll again set the display to fluxbox and nudge it over to the right a bit
also give the list items inside of them have some margin
that's looking better.
Before moving on from the header though let me quickly add the CSSA transition to have it fade in.
For this I'll set a 1 second animation on the header using an animation.
I'll call fade in the fine fade and using a keyframe which specifies that when the animation is finished
the opacity should be one to trigger the fade.
This also means I need to set the initial opacity on the header to zero save and refresh.
OK great.
This seems to be working next.
Let's add a section to hold the background image and title text.
When the page loads I'll put everything inside a section with a class of hero
inside of this section.
I'll create a div with a class and background image also passing the you are l to the background image
as a style attribute I'll talk more about why I'm doing things this way in the next video.
After that I'll create a second div for the hero content
inside of it.
I'm an H-1 for my title and H-3 for my subtitle
and an ATAC with the class of Beati N or the contact us button.
This seems to be loading.
So let's hop back into this.
SS Now I'll need a few more general styles.
First I'll add some styling to buttons.
I'll give them a border radius make their text uppercase bold and centered
had a background color
and give them full opacity.
While I'm here I'll also use fluxbox for every section.
I'll use a column layout on line items to the center and give every section some padding to ensure that
the content we've written so far will take up the full display height on page load or need to use some
positioning for my hero class.
I'll set it to position relative
center of the content using justified content in text align
and set a min height of 100 th
for the background image.
I can then use absolute positioning
and set my top and left values to be zero which will place this div at the upper left corner of the
euro section I'll set the width and height to 100 percent
the background size to cover
and I'll make sure the image is behind any other elements by setting z index to negative 1.
Lastly I'll also give it a background color based on the image content so that you won't see a white
flicker before the image loads.
Next I'll style the content inside of the section
I'll set font and margin bottom properties for both the one and three elements.
Both of these will use the open Sans font.
I'll also set some styling on my button.
This is close but now the header is getting in the way.
To fix this I'll also give the header absolute positioning and give it a width of 100 percent.
Almost there.
Before we add the second animation let's fix our font colors.
I'd like to use a white font for all tags.
As well as all text inside of the header
and all text inside of the hero.
Finally let's add an animation for the hero area.
I'll start by giving this area an opacity of zero
I'll also push you down 100 pixels.
Then after one second I'll give it a 1 second animation called slides 8.
Once again I'll use keyframes to transition the opacity to one and the top margin to zero.
Now when I refresh the page the nav fades and and then the content of the hero area fades in and slides
up.
OK this is a good place to pause in the next video.
We'll tackle a couple more sections on this page.