It right at the moment you've all been waiting for some time to connect react with redux.
There are quite a few steps to make this work.
So we might even have to break this one into two screencast But what we're going to do is simply start
by building a reactor application and then we're going to introduce redux.
We're going to start with a good old fashioned tried and true to do app.
So what I'm going to do is create a new re-act app and we'll call that re-act redux.
That is what's going to give that a second to install and what we want to think about here is how to
build a small re-act application as well as make sure that we integrate redux with this.
We're going to use Rydex to store our dues and we're going to use react to display those to use and
in order to do that we can't just install redox we need to install another library to connect the two
together.
And that library is beautifully named react redux.
And just when you thought you were getting a grasp on redux and things get more complex Unfortunately
we have to add a little bit more complexity to this.
So inside of here I'm going to install redux and react dash redux react dash redux is essential for
connecting redux and react.
How do we use it.
Well it's a bit of a two step process before we worry about any reactant redux why don't we start by
building a very simple to do application but we're going to do this all in react.
So we're going to start simply inside of our SIRC folder.
We're going to make a new file we'll call that to do list.
Yes will also make something call to do that yes.
So let's imagine there was no redux in the mix.
How would we build a very simple to do list.
Well we'd start in are actually asked by taking out a whole bunch of stuff maybe inside of here will
say See Archdukes and all we're going to do here is render that to do list component.
So inside of this to do list we're not going to get very far if we don't import it.
So we're going to import to do list from dot slash to do list.
Now we actually have to do some work in this to do list component.
So we're going to do the tried and true.
We're going to import reactors as well as component from reactor.
What else do we need to do here.
Well let's go actually make this component.
How do we do that.
Let's make it class.
We'll call this to do list and we can export this as the default as well.
And that is our to do list and it extends component.
And what do we want to do inside of here.
We want some kind of constructor with some props or call super props if we ever want to pass anything
down and maybe we'll set some state.
That state is going to be object and it's going to contain some to deuse maybe those to do's will eat
eat and sleep and go home.
And what I'd like to do is render all of those to Duse.
So inside of my render function I'm going to return all of those to do this but I don't want to just
return the text.
I want to return a component that contains that text.
So what I'll say is let my dues be this that's the DOT to use and I'll map over all of them and I'll
get that to do and some kind of index.
And you might know by now it's not best to use an index for keys but we're going to keep things really
simple right now what we're going to do is simply make a to do component but to do component is going
to have some kind of task which is going to be let's call this just a task that's going to be the task
and some kind of key of index is all we're going to do and we don't even need to close this make that
self-closing.
So we're going to pass those to do's down there.
But how do we do that we've got to import to do from dot slash to do we have made this component yet.
But that's OK.
We're going to return a div and inside of this div we'll place our two.
So let's go back to our to do component and remember our to do component is going to get some kind of
Propp of task.
So how do we do that.
Well we could go back and import react and everything but what do we really want to make here we can
just make a stateless functional component is all they can to do is going to be a function and we can
be even fancier and use an arrow function right here because we can simply just return some value from
this arrow function and we're going to get some props and we can be even fancier and the structure just
the Propp of task.
So all we're really going to do here is actually instead of making this a div we're going to make this
a div and then inside when we can an ordered list and inside of this unordered list will place our to
do is make sure that a little bit cleaned up and that looks better inside of my dues.
I'm going to just make a list item.
Simply going to be a list item with the task right here.
So let's go back and start this up with NPM start.
We should see this pop up in the browser and if we've done everything correctly we should see our two
do's but we might have some bugs.
Who knows.
Let's give it a second and see what it looks fail to compile.
Export default was not found in Dotts last to do.
Hmm let's go make sure that we're exporting that.
It doesn't look like we are an export default.
You got to make sure that we export those to Dewes.
We're not going to get very far.
Cannot resolve react and react redux to dues S or C cannot resolve react.
How do we get that problem cannot resolve react.
What happens when you run into that.
And this happened because I actually forgot to NPM install when I first loaded this application.
So we already have a reactor on the arm.
So I want to just make sure that I NPM install.
So let's give that a second make sure I install all unnecessary dependencies and then start my application.
Got a little too excited here building all those components have to make sure I actually run NPM install.
So I will give that a second home that we hopefully shouldn't see any more error messages.
And there we go.
We eat sleep and go home now.
There's not much dialing here and it's not very pretty.
Trust me I know that one but it looks like we've got some Tildy was on the page.
What I'd like to do is think about all of these to do's as individual objects that are not stored in
react but actually stored in redux.
So what we're going to do is connect our redux store to our react application in order to do that we
actually need to make our read store.
And in order to make a redux store we also need some kind of reducer.
So we're going to go and make a couple of files in this application.
We're going to make a file and we'll call that route reduce or yes will also make another file where
we can store all of our action create.
So we'll call this action creators database.
Now ideally you would have folders for these as you have more but we're going to keep it really simple.
What we're going to do inside of here is make a couple constants.
Make one for ADD to do.
And that's going to be called to do and we'll make one for removed to do.
You may be wondering why we're doing this.
And that's to make sure that we don't mess up with typos and if things change it becomes much easier.
We're going to export out a bunch of functions we'll export out one for adding a to do export a function
called add to do.
And here this is going to return some kind of object with a type of ad to do some kind of task.
We'll pass that in right here.
It's going to be key and a value of task.
How about removed to do what's go export out a function called remove to do it's going to have some
kind of ID and it's going to have a type of remove to do.
So these are what are action creators look like who may have not seen action creators and a little bit
but they're simply functions that return objects that we we don't want to hard code the object that
we're passing in.
We simply just invoke one of these functions and I shouldn't say that that looks a little bit better.
Just where are we going to use these actual creators what we're going to use them we can react and redux.
But before we do any of that we're going to need our brute reducer.
So what we're going to do is we are going to make a function.
But before we make a function we want some initial state.
So we'll make some constant called initial state.
And this is going to be pretty similar to what we had before.
Some do's and some kind of ID who are also going to do is import all of our constants from action creators
that yes action creators and what are we going to import we can import add to do and remove to do.
Because remember these are simply the strings that we made before.
What's nice about that is if these ever change it works everywhere.
It's still going to be at to do it's going to be removed to do if you call this something like add another
to do.
It wouldn't make a difference.
It would still apply here as well.
And in our reducer so you might even see these action creators in another file.
These are really just called types right now are action types the type of the action we're doing this
so that if this value ever changes it's still going to be the same variable across our action creators
and our producer.
So we brought in our action creators.
What's the time to do now.
Well let's export a function export some function called a root reducer and this right here is going
to accept two parameters.
Just like before some kind of state which is an initial state and some kind of action.
And inside of here we're actually going to use a lot of the code that we use before we're going to switch
on the action type.
And what are we going to do here.
Well if it is add to do remember we don't have the hard code that string or anything we're bringing
that all in from our constant in our action creator's file if that's the case.
Well same thing is before we can make some new state and maybe you found a better way to refactor this.
I encourage you to look at those.
I just want to be really explicit right here.
Grab whatever is in state.
What do we then want to think about doing.
All we want to make sure that we take that new state and we increment that ID by one good.
That looks pretty good.
What else do we need to think about doing.
Well we want to make sure that we then return some kind of object.
So we are going to turn some specific object with a key of everything from state as well as our traduce.
And these are going to be all of our state data dues and then some kind of task which is whatever the
task of that action is.
And the ID which is new state that Id lets keep this simple for now it looks like there's a little bit
of a syntax error that I have to import add to do remove to do equals action creators.
That's no good either from action creators.
That looks all the better.
Silly syntax error there.
Get to brush up on that syntax.
So I made a simple function called the root reducer and while we're at it we could actually add the
same logic for removing it to do so in the event of removed to do what do we want to do here.
Same thing will say that dues are going to be whatever we get filtered out by some value.
We'll make sure that Valder ID is not the same as action that ID here will be able to pass in a number
such be a little bit easier.
When that's done we're going to return a copy of state and our ideas in the event that none of these
happen we're going to simply return the state.
So this is what our reducer looks like.
All we have is to do and removed to do.
And those are coming from these action creators that we've made and to do and removed to do so we're
exporting out those functions.
And that's it it had to do and really to do so when we go see this and take a look in the browser we
can refresh the page and see what's going on.
Now you might see something wrong and that's because we're not actually exporting out these Constans
want to make sure we do that as well.
Otherwise we're not going to get very far with importing those things too.
So we make them.
But we have to actually export them as well.
Another silly mistake on end a lot of this you can kind of see by making your own mistakes.
I've done this before a bunch.
So I understand but you may run into some problems and that's ok find yourself just repeating this over
and over again and learn a lot by repeating it over and over.
So what's next.
We've made our action creators.
We have these functions that return objects that looks great and then we have our to do list which looks
good.
Well we have to connect react and redux.
And the bulk of that work is actually going to be done in our index.
Yes we are going to import the create store function from redux.
Now how come we're destructuring create store because remember the default export is redux right here
and create store is a function that lives on redux.
So we're going to just grab creates Orford redux.
We also need our route reducer from dot slash route reducer.
This one is not structured because in my reproducer it's the default export right here.
What else do we need.
Well that's actually for now.
We're going to make store and there is going to be the result of pre-AIDS store with the reducer.
And one more time let's remember when we used the redux dev tools.
We want to go and grab that code that we saw before we took steps towards.
Let's go to the second one.
Let's go down a little bit and let's make sure that everything is working right there.
Grab this right here and make sure that we get that story.
Once again this is not code you're going to have to memorize.
You're just going to find yourself copying and pasting this when you just get that initial set up so
I need the store but how do I tell my re-act application about it in order to do that.
We are going to import an essential part of the re-act redux library re-act redux.
We are going to import something called provider and we can see that here.
Just quick refresh.
Looks like we're all going there.
The provider component is what we use from re-act redux to connect our reactor application with our
redux store and the way we do that is by wrapping our app with provider.
I'm going to make sure that I wrap the application with provider and let's go see this.
And you can see right here I got this nice formatting.
I'm going to pass to provider a prop called store.
And what do you think we had in right here.
Well our redux store right there.
This right here is the glue between our re-act application and our redux store.
It's all done through this component called provider.
And once we add this provider component we allow any component that we make to get access to the drugstore.
And that's a really important thing to understand.
We previously saw that the only thing that could dispatch actions was the redux store.
But when we connect react and redux actually see that any component that we want when connected to the
redux store we'll be able to dispatch actions on its own.
And that's really cool because we're going to want our to do list action because we're going to want
certain components to dispatch certain actions and to be connected to the read box store.
So I'm going to save this and I'm going to go back to my to do list component and here I don't want
any state can react.
That's it I don't want any state on this specific component but where am I going to get my seat from.
Well now I'm going to get it from redux in order to connect a re-act component with the redux store.
The first thing you have to do is make sure that we have that provider component.
The second that we have that provider component we can import a special function call connect we're
going to import connect from re-act redux and to see that and what we're going to do is instead of exporting
the default rate up here we're going to export the default connect which is going to return a function
with our to do list inside of here.
I'm going to save this right here and I'm simply going to put a debugger line right at this Reber.
I'll save this code right here and refresh the page over here.
Cannot be property to do as of now.
Well that's a bummer.
Let's go see this let's go refresh the page.
And before we get some errors we actually see this debugger and this is just because I want to show
you what our component looks like.
Our component has a property called props.
And you might be wondering what is this right here.
Well where does dispatch come from.
Remember that redux gives us the ability to dispatch actions.
But previously we only saw that the store was in charge of dispatching actions.
We now anytime that we connect a component to our redox or that component has the ability to dispatch
actions of its own which is pretty awesome.
But we're going to see right now that we're using distorts the map and we're getting a bunch of errors.
So I would like to get some state but I don't want to get it from re-act I want to get it from redox
that's where the first parameter to connect comes in.
Well we're going to do quickly is review what we've seen and then we'll go in the next screencast fix
up this issue to bring it all together.
We started with a simple recap.
We added some reaccelerate and showed some to do's and made a stateless functional component for two
days.
We started adding a little bit of work for redox by bringing in a reducer and bringing in the code that
we saw from the previous screencast for creating it to do.
This is really not going to change that much.
What we did make though is an action creator file inside of here we made a couple of constants so that
if we ever change this value right here that variable can stay the same.
We made a couple action creators which are functions that return objects.
We're going to use these action creators a little bit later when our components dispatch actions.
What I encourage you to do is take a look through some of this code and try to get this far yourself
code along understand what this code is doing and just let us know if you have any questions in the
next video.
We're going to start grabbing state from our drug store and putting it into our components.
The only way we could possibly do that is first making sure we've installed react redux.
We have our provider component and finally that we're connecting our individual components to the Reebok
store.
So in the next screencast we'll start adding that functionality.
I'll see the.