Welcome back.
In this video we'll draw some letters on Viji using the text element.
Let's revisit Carstares Viji from the previous video and that a text caption to the bottom of the SVGA.
Here's a link to the code pen.
When using the text element at a minimum you should specify where you want it to be using the x and
y attributes the x and y coordinates passed in refer to the position of the bottom left corner of the
text.
As you can see this can make for a text element that's off center.
If you want to center the text there are a couple of ways to do it.
One is to use the DX or D-y attributes to shift the text element from its anchor point horizontally
or vertically.
However this requires you to know beforehand the amount you need to shift by a simpler approach is to
use the text anchor property which you can set either as an attribute on the element or using VSS text
anchor takes one of three possible values start middle or end.
If you set it to middle then the x and y coordinates will refer to the position of the bottom middle
of the element.
If you set it to end the coordinates will refer to the position of the bottom right corner for vertical
rather than horizontal alignment.
You can also use the alignment baseline attribute.
It has a number of values but for centering vertically you can set its value to middle.
Let's center our tax by setting text anger to middle.
We can also set other CSSA properties such as font size and font family.
We can even set colors however unlike fonts outside of SVGA we need to set colors using fail and stroke
just like with other SVGA elements.
We can also rotate text.
This is particularly helpful if you're trying to label axes and need text to be vertically aligned to
rotate.
You can use the transform attribute and pass to the value that specifies the rotation in order to rotate.
You should specify the degree of rotation and the coordinates of the point you want to rotate around.
Here's an example.
The same technique can be used to rotate other shapes who we've looked at such as circles and polygons
that about covers the text element in the next video will cover a much more complex SPG element the
path element.
I'll see their.