All right we've set up a very simple error handler but we don't even have any routes.
We don't even have any data going on here so let's bring in a mongo database into the mix.
So inside of the models folder I'm going to make it a couple of files.
We to make an index that yes which is going to be responsible for connecting to a mango database and
setting up mongoose.
And also going to make a file called user dodgy apps which will refer to my user model and I'm going
to make one more file here while we're there.
We'll call that message.
Yes.
I'm not going to be using this too much but I'm going to eventually need a model for my message.
So let's put this here for now.
Inside my index yes.
I need some pretty standard boilerplate to bring in mongoose.
Mongoose is our idea.
It's essentially a little wrapper on top of Mongo that allows us to make queries a little bit more efficiently.
So we're going to bring in mongoose.
We're then going to use the set function and we'll pass in Debug of true.
And this is really useful if you ever want to see the actual Mongo queries that are being run in the
terminal.
We're also going to specify what promise library we want to use.
And those are going to be the needed years 2015 promises so that we don't have to use a callback pattern.
In fact this line of code is very important because we're going to be using as 20:17 async functions
to build this application.
And remember that our easing functions return promises.
So we really want to make sure that our mongoose methods are returning promises so everything works
correctly.
We're going to do is connect to a database and that protocol is going to be Mangu D-B colon slash slash
localhost and then whatever data base we'd like I'll call this warbler.
What we're going to specify here as well are a couple of things to make sure that our connection is
stable.
Set in keepalive of true and we're also going to specify the property or use of Mangino client of true
as well.
And this is important just so we don't get some warnings about Mongo.
Don't worry too much about this stuff is really just the idea of connecting through mongoose with the
latest technology with Mongo.
Now let's go make our user model number.
All we've done here is simply just connected to a database set up some code to debug a bit easier and
make sure that we use promises.
But let's go make a user.
And you've seen this pattern before with models.
So let's do it right now.
We're going to bring in a mongoose.
We're also going to bring in the secret library.
Remember that the secret library is going to be used for password hashing.
It's going to take a plain text password and turn it into something that can not be reversed or you
could require be.
So we'll save this.
And let's go make our user schema our user schema is a new mongoose schema and this excepts an object
and inside of this object we're going to specify the fields that we want each document to have.
We want every user to have an email.
And what about this email that should be a type of a string.
We should also make sure that it's required.
We should also make sure that it's unique because we might want to log in users by their email.
And if so we want to make sure that they have an email and that it's unique.
We all want to people with the same email will also have a user name property so that if we display
that maybe and warble we can do that as well.
So we'll also give that type of string.
And just like before we'll get that required of true as well as a unique of true.
Don't want to users with the same username.
What other fields are we going to need.
We're going to need three more password and this password is simply going to be some kind of string
also going to be required.
And I'm sure that's true.
One more property.
I said there were two more that we needed after this but we're just going to do one because we're not
bringing messages into the mix yet.
We're going to simply have a profile image.
You are out and that way we can have a nice picture of ourselves in this application will give that
type of string.
So every single object that I make from this schema is going to be done through a model.
And how do we create a model.
You've probably seen this pattern before.
We're going to make a new model.
We'll call that capital you user.
And that's going to be a mongoose that model the first parameter here is what we want to reference that
model adds and that is the string user.
And then the schema that we created with it is going to be our user schema.
We are then going to export our user.
And if you'd like you could just add a module that exports Rayder here.
I'd like to put this on two lines.
It's a little bit more readable for me.
So we've made a simple user schema.
What does this mean when we use our user model we can now create queery find update delete whatever
we like to do using all these wonderful mongoose methods.
The problem is if we were to create a user right now we'd be doing something that's very very bad.
We would be storing the password in plain text in our database.
And that's something that will actually get you fired on the job.
So in the next week we're going to talk about the idea of password hashing so that we can make sure
that when we store passwords in the database they're secure and can not be reversed.
This is the idea of a one way password hashing the way that someone's going to log in they're going
to put in a plain text password.
We're going to run that same hashing algorithm and we're going to see if whatever that ends up with
is the same thing we have in the database.
So we'll talk about that a bit more in the next video and introduce be correct.