Welcome back.
In this video we're going to continue learning about 20:17 async functions.
And there's a bit of a gotcha with Issing functions and the Awake keyword when Meeking HTP requests
that we take a look at the code below.
We are making two requests sequentially since the Awake keyword will wait for a promise to be resolved.
Response 2 will not begin until the entire response.
One promise is resolved the second.
Each TDP request here does not get made until the first promise is resolved.
Imagine if each of these requests took a couple of seconds to make our application with slow down quite
a bit.
So how can we be smarter about making each DDP requests when using the Awake keyword.
The answer is that we can return the promises right away and make these requests in parallel and then
simply await the promises once they are done resolving.
Here's what that code would look like.
Even though it's quite similar to what we've seen before.
There is a tremendous performance difference when you're making each TDP requests sequentially versus
in parallel.
If you find yourself making lots of HTP requests using the Awake keyword and your application is slowing
down.
Be mindful of this refactor.
The last thing we're going to discuss is how to combine the promise all method with the Awake keyword.
And here's where you can do some pretty incredible stuff.
In the example below we're waiting for an array of promises to resolve using the Awake keyword and promised.
All remember promised not all accepts an array of promises and returns a promise which when resolve
returns an array of resolved values instead of using a dot then and a callback function.
We can simply await the resolution of promised at all and then access those values in our movies list
array using async functions with promised not all is quite common when you have multiple promises that
you want to await resolution for.
Although the code here is asynchronous it reads very synchronously and once you get used to async functions
they become more and more readable.
At the time of this recording Issing functions are not supported in every browser.
They will be in the near future and in more recent versions of Chrome Firefox Safari and Noj yes there
already support it.
So you're only going to see them more and more.
If you look at modern re-act redux node and angular code bases you'll see async functions quite a bit.
Now that you've seen how to use async functions it's time for you to practice with some exercises.
Good luck and I'll see you in the next video.