OK.
Next up we're going to get our to do's to accurately reflect their completion status if they're done
or not.
So if completed is true we want them to have strikethrough and a grey out applied automatically and
have actually created a class for that.
I just called it done.
So we want to conditionally apply that class done if the to do is completed so we can actually just
add in an IF statement to say if new to do got completed.
So if that's true by default it's false.
So every new to do is false but if it is completed then and we could do this on a single line but this
isn't very long so do it on a second line.
We're going to new to do that add the class done.
So that's only if it's completed.
And before that let me actually go in here and add in to do completed as well.
Let's refresh our page and you can see they're all currently falsified she is false she's false but
she's falsified she's False her car false.
So we actually can't see anything.
So let's remedy that.
Let's take this first bite.
She's going to go to postman ascend to get request to get all the recent dues you know to take you out
here or that Id paste it in.
You only need to do this if you don't have any to do set or marked completed.
And we're going to do a put request in the body we're going to instead of doing name or mood we're going
to do completed and set that to true because right now it's false.
Send that and you can see we get it back it says completed is true.
If we do a get request Well let's do or get request to slash API I-Slash to do it.
We have one that is now completed.
Let's take a look and if we refresh our page you can see now we have true showing up but we're not getting
the strikethrough that we want and that's because of a silly mistake.
If we look here I'm referencing if new to do is completed but new to do is what we've created here.
So it doesn't have anything to do with completed.
It's just an ally.
So we want to do that completed which is for each part of data for each thing in the array.
We're calling it to do so to do that completed that should do the trick for us.
And there we go.
So things are loading correctly as refresh the page.
We get data from the very beginning if things are completed they are reflected here.
So we'll get to the updating them so that we can click to toggle that status to send an update request
in a future video.
Next we're going to focus on actually creating new to.