Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over solutions to the closures exercises for our first function
special multiply.
We're going to pass in two parameters A&amp;E And first we'll check to see if only one argument has been
passed to this function using the arguments array like object.
If only one parameter has been passed to this function we're going to return a new function with a single
parameter b inside of this inner function.
We'll make use of closure and return times b.
Closure exists here because the parameter A is part of the special multiply function which has returned
by the time our inner function is using it.
If we pass more than one parameter to this function we should just return a times b for our second function.
Guessing game.
We're going to declare a couple variables.
The first will be an answer which is going to be a random number between 0 and that we can do this using
math stuff floor and math at random to find that number will then initialize another variable called
guess's and assign that to zero and then initialize a variable called completed and set that to false.
All of these variables will be used inside of an inner function and by the time that that inner function
is run the outer function will have returned inside of the inner function that we return.
Well except a parameter called Guess which will be some user input.
The first thing we're going to do is make sure that if completed is false we will continue.
Otherwise floor return a string that says that they're all done playing.
Now let's increment guesses by 1.
Because if this function has been run a guess has been made.
Now let's check to see if guess is the same as answer.
And if so we'll set completed to be true and return the string.
You got it.
If the guess is greater than the answer will return the string.
Your guess is too high and if the guess is less than the answer or return the string your guess is too
low.
Finally if the number of guesses is the same as the amount of guesses allowed will set completed to
true and return the string.
No more guesses and let the user know what the answer was and that's it for the closer's exercise.
See you in the next video.