Welcome back.
So let's finish up this Moxey component with our hobby list.
So if I go back to the code we've got this heavy list class that I'll copy over
and then I want to make a new file for that.
Let's open a new terminal so I don't have to keep killing the server and I'll go into my re-act folder.
And hello world.
And then I'll touch source Havi list.
AS.
Now I've got that file I'll just paste in my code and
remember we don't need re-act component but we do need to import react.
So import reacts and component Honan's from reacts.
Here we go.
And then last thing to do is export defaults hobby list.
Right now our components all set up the last piece of the puzzle is to use it in the pet.
So inside of Petraeus I'm going to throw in imports
the list from the slash Havi list and then I'll use that component right here.
Oh and I asked my semi-colon and from there we go now with those changes we should see our lists and
we do great.
So that's it.
Now that we have all the introduction to create re-act up out of the way let's talk about prop's.