All right.
So we've seen enough of Ajax with Jay Querrey it's time for a quick exercise.
So we're going to build super simple random cat photo generator whatever we want to call this.
There's a button click a button we get a random cat photo.
Oh that's a good one.
Click it again you get another random cat photo.
And again you can keep going up another QAD.
So you know I know we get a lot of cat lovers.
We did a dog photos app get to do cats as well.
I looked very hard.
Found an API.
I've included the link in the resources but the URL is random dumb cat slash meow.
I like it and all it gives you back and Jaison is a single key file.
And then the property is that you are no.
So I'm not going to give you any starter code.
No need to do this yourself.
Basically require a query set up just a simple button don't really style it.
I mean if you want to go ahead button and then an image and you're just going to update the source of
that image by making an API call and you might want to use one of the shorthand methods it's up to you
getting this you Aro taking the data back and then appending it to or actually not pending it but updating
the source of that image.
The only thing I'll mention if you're not familiar with a query you may want to use this method.
TR for attribute to update the source of the image.
That's all I'll say.
OK.
So give it a shot.
No need to make a code pen or fire up sublime or whatever you want to use for quite a query.
Get a button going and image going and then get some random Casco.
All right.
I have a solution in just a moment.