Welcome back the next array method we're going to examine is map we mentioned before that for each always
returns undefined and very commonly you'll want to transform one array into another array with different
values.
Or you could make a new array and use for each to push values into the new array.
There is an easier way to do that using map.
Let's examine step by step how map works.
Try an example and then implement our own version.
The way the map works is that it is invoked on an array and the first thing it does is create a new
array.
It then iterates over the array it was called on and runs a callback function for each value in the
It takes the value return from the callback function and places it in the new array.
And when it's done iterating it returns the new array create.
That might seem like a lot but it will make more sense when we see an example.
Always remember map returns a new array of the same length as the array it is invoked on.
Let's see an example.
I'll create a variable called R which will have the numbers 1 2 and 3 inside it.
I'll even invoke the map function on the array and just like for each the first parameter I pass is
a callback function.
In this callback function we get access to the value index an array just like foreach.
However we have to make sure to return a value inside of this callback because the value that we return
is what will be placed inside of the new array.
That map creates.
Now let's run this and see what I get back.
Nice.
A new array with all the values doubled.
If I omit the return statement here I would actually get back in array with undefined for each value.
Just remember we always get back an array of the same length.
So how does map work.
Let's examine what an implementation of map might look like.
A great way to do this would be by implementing our own version of the map function which would accept
an array and some callback function just like for each member of the steps.
And that creates a new array.
It then iterates through the array passed to it.
It then runs a callback function for each value in the array.
It pushes the result of the callback function into the new array and finally it returns the new array.
If you would like pause the video and try to implement this on your own.
All right so let's create a function called Map which accepts an array and a callback function.
I'm going to start by creating an empty array called New Are all.
Then make a for loop and then initialize a variable.
Zero.
I'll keep looping as long as it is less than the length of the array passed the map and increment by
one after each iteration inside of here.
I'm going to invoke the callback with the Value Index and array as parameters and take the result of
that callback and push it into the new R variable.
Once we're done iterating we have to make sure to return the new or a created and that's it.
Now that we have a better understanding of how map works let's see how to use map inside of a function.
Here I have a function called triple values which accepts an array and returns a new array with each
value triple.
Notice here that I have two return statements 1 for the result of map which is a new array and then
another inside the callback function to make sure that my new array has the correct value.
Inside of the callback function I'm returning each value multiplied by three.
You might be wondering why don't we just use for each to solve this.
The answer is that we could use for each.
But map is a bit more friendly since it already returns a new array to us.
For each can be used if you want to overwrite values in an array.
Or change something externally or when you would like a new array to be returned to you.
Especially one of the same length Knapp's should always be used.
Let's take a look at one more function on the first name.
Here are mapping over an array and returning the first property on each value in the array.
We are assuming in this function that we will pass an array of objects and they will call have a first
property when we invoke this function.
We get back an array of just the first value that we can see.
Math is very helpful when you want to extract values from an object and place them in an array.
Just remember you always need to return something in the callback to map and that map will always return
an array of the same length as the array that it was called.
Or what happens if we want to filter out some values and not get back in array of the same length.
Thankfully there is a better method for that but before we move on but practice a bit with map.
Good luck and I'll see you in the next video.