Welcome back.
In this video we'll continue building this marketing page for mountain travel.
In the last video we took care of what you see when the page loads.
Now let's work on what we want people to see when they scroll.
I'll start with the HVM out first.
I'll create a new section and give it a class of destination's
inside of this section.
I'll create a title
and then I'll paste in some marketing text inside of a tag.
Next hour including H tag.
After that I want to include some images of mountains.
I'll do this with a UL.
I'll give this UL a class of grid and inside of it.
I'll lay out my four images so that I don't need a unique class or ID for each one.
I'll add the background images as inline styles.
I'll give two of them a class of small end to a class of large.
When I save and refresh I can see the text but not the images.
So let's hop into the stylesheet and fix the look of this section.
I'll start with some general styles.
I'll make all UL's have a list style of none.
And for my grid class I'll set the width to 100 percent
enable fluxbox allow the content to wrap and center the content
also style my H R tags.
I'll give them a fixed width and height set a background color
and give them some large I'll also clear out the default border that many browsers give to these elements.
Next let's tackle the text inside of our sections.
For my titles I'll make sure each word is capitalized.
And I'll add a few different properties for the font.
I'll also give my titles some margin and centered text.
For tags inside of my sections I'll set a maximum width of 775 pixels and the line height of two I'll
also give these elements some padding and margin
and once again Center the text.
This is looking better.
Next let's get those images showing up
to do this.
I'll add some styles for Elmis inside of my grade class inside of my destination class.
First I'll give each allys some height and padding.
Next eclipse the image to the content area so that the padding is reserved for white space.
I'll make sure the images cover the L.A. area and center them to.
Now I just need to specify the difference between small and large list items.
I'll use flex basis here and have small items take up 30 percent of the width
while large items take up the remaining 70 percent
there are images
great.
I think this section is complete Let's quickly tackle the next section.
Once people have seen the images our next step is to give them an overview of the packages we offer.
So once again I'll create a section this time with a class of packages inside I'll make another title
pay some tax inside of a p tag and add in a jar.
After that I'll include another grid.
This time the grid will have descriptions of different packages.
Each list item in my grid will have an icon an H for with some title text and a tag with a more detailed
description of the package.
If you remember from the intro video each one of these packages had an icon accompanying it to add these
icons.
I'll use an icon library called font.
Awesome to include Fogelson.
I just need to add since DSS inside of my head once I've done this.
Adding the icons is pretty simple.
When I find an icon I like on the web site
I can click on it to see what class name I should use.
Note that each icon also comes in multiple sizes.
You can pass any one of these scale classes like F to X or f a 3x to increase the size of the icon.
For my first ally I'll use a compass icon to represent guided trips
next.
I'll use a camera icon to represent photo trips.
Then I'll use a bicycle icon to represent bicycle trips.
And finally I'll use the checkered flag icon to represent racing trips.
Notice that I'm also using the 4 x icon to make these icons larger
great.
We can see all of that content showing up on the page.
Now it just needs a little bit of styling love.
First I'll add one general rule to stripe our sections
excluding the hero section.
I'd like every other section to switch between having a white background and a light gray background.
Finally I'll need to style the list items inside of my package's grid
for the list items themselves.
I'll give them some padding set the flex basis to 50 percent and center attacks.
I'll also change the font color of each icon
finally bump up the font size for my age for elements
and gives them some margin on top and bottom
nights that takes care of the packages section.
In the next video we'll tackle the rest of this page.
I'll see you there.