Welcome back.
In this video I walk through my solution to the scatterplot on methane and CO2 emissions that I showed
you in the last video.
I've already created the HDMI Olens DSS for this project as you can see my HDMI is fairly simple.
Inside the body I just got my SPG my range and put in my tool tip inside of this.
SS I've just got some simple styling for the SVGA and the range and put along with some styles for the
tool tip.
This should almost be the same as the styling we built in the tooltip video but with different colors
and a slightly different location.
This tool tip will show up above the mouse not below it.
Before hopping into the app J.S. Let's talk about the data.
All of my data I obtained from the World Bank.
Here's an example of one of the pages as you can see I can download the data as a zip file.
I've done this for all of my data sets.
Unzip them and put the corresponding cxxviii files inside of a data directory for my project.
Here's an example file.
Note that each row represents a region and the columns indicate the statistic being recorded followed
by values for years between 1960 and 2016.
OK let's move to the J.S. here I've already set up a queue and made requests to each of the cxxviii
files I downloaded.
Amusing in a way.
Oh to wait for all their responses and inside of a callback and first console logging the data.
When I hop into the console though this doesn't look right it doesn't seem like D-3 has parsed the data
correctly.
The problem is that the first row in each CXXVI doesn't have the headers it's some meta information
about the datasource the actual headers don't appear in the fifth row.
In order for D-3 gutsiest V to work properly I'll first need to remove these few lines from each CSFB
file.
Next only to format the data I'll pass each of my CXXVI files through a formatter and inside of the
callback I'll format the data again by passing it into a function called format all data.
To save time I'm just going to paste in a bunch of formatting code and then walk through it.
Let's look at the formatter first.
One of the problems with the data set is that it doesn't just have data on countries.
It also has data on collections of countries like Arab world.
I've gone through and grabbed names for all of these rows that I don't want to keep.
If the region matches one of these in my array I'll just return undefined in the formatter so that the
row will be removed.
After that I'll grab every key that's a number.
Since these correspond to a year column and convert each value to a number or to know if no value is
present for that year that's the formatter.
But what about format data formatter callbacks for you got.
Yes we are great at formatting individual rows but sometimes you also need to format data crossroads
or across files.
So that's what the second function is doing.
It's easiest to understand if I throw a debugger at the bottom and up to the console to look at data
versus year.
B.J. as you can see data as an array of arrays where each array consists of rows taken from one of the
CSB files but the year obey J is structured differently.
It's an object whose keys are yours and whose values are arrays of objects with data by region format
all data just converts what I get from this ESV files into this new structure.
There are D-3 methods that would help with this if you're interested in trying to refactor.
You can research a method called the 3.10 test.
For now I've just used a bunch of loops I loop over the array of arrays and grabbed the indicator such
as CO2 or methane emissions.
Then I loop over the array region objects grab the region and then loop over the years.
If I've already added that region for that year to my year object I just add the new stat.
Otherwise if it's the first time I've seen that region in that year I push a new object to the array
for that year.
After doing this there are a number of years where no country had data on all of the variables I'm interested
in.
So at the end of each year I filter out any region that doesn't have data from each cxxviii file using
a small hoper that I've called Vallet region.
This helper just checks to see that a region has data for all of the indicators.
If not it returns false after filtering if no region for that year had enough data I then delete that
key from the year object as you can see from a console.
This restricts the set of years from 1990 through 2012 formatting your data can sometimes be the most
difficult part of building the visualization but now that we have our data in this form building the
chart should feel quite familiar.
Also variables for width height padding and the extent of the years in my dataset.
Then I'll set up the Viji stored in a variable and append axes axes labels and the title.
After that I'll grab the range and put set its properties based on the extent of years and add an event
listener as we've done before.
How abstract the logic here into a function called Drop plot which I also call outside of the event
handler to initially draw the graph.
As for the drop plot code it should look pretty similar to what we've done before.
So I'll just paste it in first and grabbing data by year because of the structure of your LBJ.
This is just a simple look up.
Then I'm creating scales and updating axes in the title based on this data.
After that I'm using the general update pattern to update the circles for the exit selection.
I'll shrink the circles using the transition and then remove them for the enter selection position them
in the right place and set stroke and stroke with then I'll merge and transition existing circles attributes
based on my scale.
I've got a bit of duplication here was setting C-x and C-y but I'm ok with that if I don't have these
lines in the entire selection then it looks like the circles are shooting out of the origin of the Viji
which is a little much for me.
Lastly on the enter selection I'll attach a ventless and search for the tooltip.
Note that I can combine events using the space.
So I'll listen for mass move and touch move at once and for mass out and touch and at once.
Here's the tooltip code.
It should also look familiar on mouse move or make the tooltip visible adjust its position and said
it's in or age Tamil based on the data on mouse out.
I'll hide the tooltip again.
Let's save and refresh.
There we go a working scatterplot with all of the enhancements we discussed in this section.
I hope that working through this goto is helpful when you're ready.
I'll meet you in the next section where we'll learn about working with some more advanced Grath types
using D-3.