All righty.
So we looked at for Jay Querrey methods that help us make requests.
We saw Ajax get post and get Jason.
So those are useful.
But keep in mind there are only four methods out of 100 maybe 200 methods that J.
Querrey come to it.
So Jay query helps you write less code.
It simplifies the process of doing a lot of different things not just writing AJAX calls.
So things like animations fade in fade out slide and so on event handling working with forms manipulating
the DOM and a whole bunch of other features all come with Jay Querrey.
So if you don't need those and increasingly so people feel that you don't actually need all those features.
There's this site you might not need Jay query it made waves a couple of years ago basically making
the argument that Jay Querrey these days isn't really saving you all that much code and it's not worth
including a separate library.
If you're using it to do things like manipulate the Dom as you can see a comparison on the left is a
J quick version on the right is the vanilla version.
They're pretty similar for most things except the most blatant discrepancy is around AJAX calls.
So even if you're someone who doesn't want to use Jay Querrey you still may want some of the functionality
that it gives you around simplified AJAX calls with a nice syntax.
Fortunately there are a bunch of third party libraries out there that do just that.
There's all these javascript HTP clients and the one we're going to focus on is called axioms.
So it's a lightweight request library meaning that all it does is it provides a couple of methods to
help you make requests and nothing more.
So none of the extra J carry weight.
And if we look at the documentation it lays out its key features or goals pretty clearly.
So it helps you make SML HTP requests from the browser.
You can also make them from node J.S..
So that is nice if you use node you can use X iOS on the backend using the exact same syntax to make
your requests so it supports promises.
The other thing I'll highlight.
It automatically transforms Jaison data that comes in it will automatically parse it for you.
And of course browsers support always important looks great everywhere and that's just because it's
built on top of the X H.R. API.
So there's no fancy technology here.
It's just a library that is written on top of the default ex-aide chars.
Oh and I should point out it's pretty popular.
If you look at the repo 200 or 25000 people it.
There's 600 forks.
That's pretty substantial for a small little library like this.
All that does is help you make requests.
So here's the basic syntax we require Expo's which we'll do in just a moment.
And then you can just refer to actually X-post dot and then whatever method you need.
So the simplest one is don't get.
There's also a post and there's a couple of others we'll talk about but we'll start off with don't get
seapass in a row.
And just like fetch We have our then in our catch.
So let's hop over to code pad and give it a shot.
So before we can do anything we need to include axes and if you go to the documentation you can either
download the script itself and include it manually or they give you a CVN link right off the bat.
I'm just going to use that.
So copy the script tag put it in my HMO and it should be good to go.
Now the API that I'm going to use for this example is this open tribut database open TB TB outcome.
I'll include the link.
What it does is it gives you trivia questions and answers.
We're just going to get the data.
We're not going to do anything with it.
But like I said it's in the resources and if we look at it here we're going to get an object back with
a results array.
It has one item and in that item we're going to print out the question.
So let's do that hop over here and let's assign this to a variable.
So to save r u r l equals that you are l and now we just right or ex-U.S. code to it's X-post dot get
that you are l and then to handle it then.
And I'll also add our catch.
We'll talk more about handling those errors in just a bit.
So let's just leave it at this and then we'll just print out the response.
OK.
So let's see what happens.
So if I refresh the page I don't have it hooked up to a button.
So it's just running one time at the beginning and looks good.
We're getting this response object back.
So notice it gives us the response doesn't just give us the data we care about.
There's a whole bunch of other things in here.
But the data we want is in data.
So rather than constantly logging rez let's do rez dot data save now we get this inside that we want
the results.
So let's do that now that results zero and now we're getting to the data.
Let's do that question as well.
Area and left for dead.
What is the name of this special infected that it's unplayable.
Oh OK.
I have no idea.
I have played that game but I have no clue.
So tough trivia questions but the API works just how it's supposed to.
We're making a simple get request to a u r l and we have a then and Dot catch.
So that's all I want to do in this video.
There's a couple of key takeaways.
One square is great but if you only want the Ajax functionality.
Use a library like X-ers.
There's no reason to include all these extra methods.
All this extra code if you're not going to use it.
So accuracy is great.
Very short little modular library but it also provides a nice clean syntax as you can see here.