Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over solutions to the math exercises.
The first function we need to implement is the double values function.
So we're going to map over the array passed to the function and inside of that callback function return
each value multiplied by two.
We can store the result of this callback in a variable and then return it.
Or we can just return the result of this function entirely to keep our code more concise.
We'll just return the result of map directly for the next function Zao TIMES INDEX.
We need to map over the array and return a new array with each value multiplied by the index it's at.
So I'll return the result of mapping over this array and then inside of the callback function I'll accept
the value and index and return the product of those two numbers.
Break for the next function.
Extract key.
We need to iterate over an array of objects and return a new array of just a specific key.
So our map over the array and then return each object at that specific key that I'm looking for.
Notice here that we're using bracket notation to access a key instead of that notation because we need
javascript to evaluate that variable and not look for a key with the name of key for the last function.
We need to iterate over an array of objects and return a new array of the first and last properties
concatenated together so our map over the array and return the first property on each object plus an
empty string for whitespace and then the last property on the value object.
Great.
In the next video we'll take a look at another method filter for returning arrays of the same or smaller.
Let's see if there.