Welcome back in the next few videos we'll explore some helper functions that can be useful for specific
types of graphs.
First we'll talk about creating histograms D3 a histogram is a special type of bar chart in which values
in a dataset are placed into bins.
The height of a rectangle in histogram represents the number of data points in that bin.
In this video we'll build the histogram to visualize birthdate and by region for a specific year.
Here's a link to some starter code.
Here I've got some data from a different UN data set on birth's by country and year.
The data set isn't complete.
Only four regions have data reported from 1967 for example but it's still instructive to try to visualize
this data in order to bucket our data into the bins we need for a histogram.
I could go through this data.
Create arrays of arrays based on year and based on the birth ranges I am curious about and then plot
that data.
Fortunately I don't have to do all of that work on my own D-3 comes with some built in methods to help
take some work off of my plate this process will look very similar to the way we built a bar chart but
with one key difference we'll be using the dot histogram to automatically buchen our values into groups
for us to get started.
Let's set up our with height and bar padding.
We also need to determine the width of the rectangles in our histogram and create a y scale so that
we can be sure that the bins all fit in our SVGA.
But in order to do this we need to know how many bins will have and how many pieces of data will be
each bin.
Here's where D-3 got histogram can help us out.
D-3 got histogram is a function that returns a function to us if we pass our dataset into the function
that is returned D-3 will create bins from our values.
If we pass the histogram generator an array of numbers.
This process is automatic but more commonly our data will be an array of objects and in this case we'll
need to specify for D-3 how it should be polling data from each object in our array.
For this we can use the value method on D-3 histogram which accepts a callback that specifies how D-3
should obtain a value from each object.
In our case I'll start by generating histogram for just the first year in our dataset to do this.
I'll use D-3 dot main to graph the first year then filter out any data that doesn't come from this first
year and store the filtered array in a variable called year data.
Now let's use the histogram generator.
I'll create a variable called histogram and set it equal to the return value of the 3 histogram.
Also to Unical to the values so that I can specify that I want a histogram of birth counts Finally I'll
pass my data into this histogram generator and store the result in a variable called bin's.
Let's dig into this output of it as you can see Benz's an array with two elements.
Each of these elements is again an array.
This time the arrays have birth data these arrays also have two additional properties.
X zero and x1.
For instance the first array inside of bins consists of three data points.
Each one has a birth total between 161.
The value of x 0 and 100000 the value of x 1 with the data placed into bins.
We now know how many rectangles we need to draw and what are y scale should be.
So let's calculate the width.
We can also generate a y scale for the birth counts using scale linear per domain will go from zero
to the length of the largest been and the range will go from the SPG height to zero next.
Let's select the SPG set the width and height and then join our data to elements with a class of bar
for each enter node.
We'll now append to group L I'm doing this because I want two elements in the SPG for each data point
a rectangle and a text element with the description of the data inside of each group.
Let's now append our histogram rectangles.
This pattern should look very similar to what we did when we first learned about our charts.
Set the attribute so that each rectangle was offset by the bar with plus the bar padding for the Y attribute.
We'll use our scale Similarly the height will just be equal to the SVGA height minus the scaled value.
Finally the width will just equal the bar with.
While I'm at it I'll also adjust the fill as I mentioned earlier there isn't a ton of data from 1967
but already we can see that most regions that reported data had a relatively small number of births.
Before we move on it's worth pointing out that you'll very often see histograms created with the help
of scales as well as y scales whether you want to use an X scale is totally up to you but it's fairly
common and allows us to do a bit less arithmetic involving our rectangles.
It also allows us to fix a small issue with our current approach.
Right now both of our bodies have the same width even though the second one spans a larger range of
values than the first.
So before adding text labels Let's quickly refactor what we have to use a scale.
I'll create the scale before defining the histogram function.
I'll have the scale go from zero to the largest value in the dataset.
And as we've seen before we'll have the range go from zero to the SPG with once we have this scale we
can avoid calculating the bar with directly.
Instead we can use the zero and x 1 properties of each bin to calculate the appropriate width specifically.
We can pass x 0 into the scale to figure out where the x coordinate of each bar should be.
As for the what it should be equal to the difference between the scaled value of x 1 and the scaled
value of x 0 minus the padding
so far so good.
However while the bar with are now more accurate they also look a little weird.
It would be better if we could simply generate bins that have approximately the same range so that the
rectangles would automatically have similar widths.
There are a few things we can do to get our wits more consistent First we can specify the domain of
our histogram by using the domain method.
This method is called on the histogram generator and it allows you to specify the domain of values that
you'd like the generator to use when it creates bins.
If you don't specify a domain the generator will default to using the extent of the data set.
Let's modify the domain so that it uses the domain of our scale.
This will help ensure the first Baine is the correct size to avoid duplication.
We'll just call domain on our scale.
This will get the domain we used when we originally created the scale.
We can override the default thresholds or ranges of each band using the threshold method on the histogram
generator.
We'll talk more about this method in the next video.
For now all you need to know is that you'll often see the tick marks of the scale used to overwrite
the default thresholds.
We can get these ticks by calling X scale ticks which just returns an array of evenly spaced intermediate
values to us.
Don't worry we'll talk about this text method more in the next video too.
Lastly you'll often see range round used on the X scale instead of range.
This method is very similar to the range method we've seen before.
The only difference is it makes sure that the wits are all round into the nearest whole number with
these changes.
You can see there are more rectangles the floor.
We'll talk more about controlling the number of rectangles with the thresholds method.
In the next video for now let's finish things up by adding a text label to each group in our labels.
Let's include the endpoints of the bin.
Let's also include a count of the number of regions inside of the bin.
This will wind up being a lot of text so I'll rotate the text 90 degrees and align it so that it'll
show up in the middle of each bar and at the bottom of the SVGA.
In practice getting the positioning right will probably take some guess and check.
So don't worry if you don't get this exactly right on the first try.
Cool.
That looks pretty good for now.
This seems like a good place to pause in the next video.
We'll talk more about the threshold I said and finish up this histogram.
I'll see you there.