Welcome back.
In this video we'll discuss how to pass methods and properties from one class to another in object oriented
programming.
This process is called inheritance.
Before we look at 2015 let's first see how inheritance is done in S-5.
In the example below I have two constructors person and student.
I would like to say hello method on the person prototype to be accessible from objects created by the
student constructor in S-5.
This process can be accomplished in a few different ways but the most common way is to set the prototype
property of one function to be a new object with a dunder Prato property of another constructor functions
prototype.
This is done by setting the prototype property of the constructor to be an object created from another
prototype property and resetting the constructor property on the constructor function in 2015.
This can be done through the extends keyword.
If one class extends another it will have all the methods that that class which it extends from has.
This is how we can implement inheritance in 2015.
Let's see what that looks like.
Here we simply add the extends keyword on the Student class and everything works.
Let's look at this code in the Crome Council and we can see that student that prototype that say hello
exists and that student prototype constructor triple equal student returns true.
The subtraction can be helpful because it reduces the amount of code we need to write but it's essential
that you understand what is happening here under the hood in the next video will introduce one more
reserve keyword in 2015 to help us remove duplication in our constructor functions.
See you there.