Welcome back.
So in our last video we made our first component with GSX and now we're going to look into GSX a bit
more and see what it can do.
Our objectives are to first write javascript inside of the GSX.
Secondly to use a style attribute in Gas-X so you can actually have some styling now in our component.
And lastly to add a class name attribute to GSX.
Now let's go look at some code.
Our goal now is to add some styling to this component that we used in the last video.
So remember we've got a re-act component called Pet that returns a div and inside of that we've got
moxie and our image.
So this is jazz sex that we're going to add some styling to.
Right now the component looks like this when rendered.
So it's just a picture of Moxey and then the name Moxey let's make it look a little nicer.
So first of all we're going to include this CSSA file with some classes.
And the one thing that will take effect right away is this ID app which is used right here by this dev
ID app is going to get some styling to use fluxbox will display flex give a flex direction row and justify
content center.
So let's see how that looks when we add the SS.
So here I've added the link for my CSSA.
I call that first component that saves us
and you can see that we've centered the image in the H-2 but not much else has changed.
So let's add some styling to make this look a little nicer.
Specifically we're going to make the font here different and a little bigger.
We're going to give this a border and a background color
there already some classes that we can use in the CSSA file.
So let's take a look.
In here we've got a card class and the card will give background and some layout properties to the div
inside of our component.
Again I'm not going to go over every line but some of the highlights here that again we're using Fluxbox
so that everything inside is a column.
We're going to justify content center line item center.
And we're also going to give a new front to the card.
How do we actually use that in our component.
Well let's go back to the GSX.
You may assume that we could just say class equals card here and for most attributes in GSX that's true.
But the problem here is that we're using Babbel.
And remember babbel compiles from GSX into standard Javascript.
And the problem there is that Babel doesn't know the difference between an aged CML class here and a
javascript class.
So in order for this to work any reserved keyword in javascript we have to name it differently.
If it's inside the GSX.
So if I don't want to use a javascript class here I need to name it class name.
Let's take a look at the Web site and see what it looks like now.
Now our card styling is being applied to our component so it looks like class name works.
Let's see what else we can add.
Now if we take a look at our CSSA will see that we also have this name class and that gives some styling
to the title Moxey.
So let's add that in as well.
I'll give this H2 a class name equal to name and then take a look at what that looks like.
And now you can see names applied there as well.
So that's great.
We've added some classes but let's also look at how we can add styles programmatically through javascript
in order to add some styles.
I'm going to create a little more content that we can style.
So I'm going to give Moxey some hobbies.
Let's make an H5 for hobbies and then underneath that all lists her hobbies.
So Moxi likes to first of all sleep.
And second of all to eat
so see that content.
OK so you've got hobbies and sleep eat down here but it doesn't look too great.
So let's add some inline styles before I get started I should mention that if you're coming from a different
framework or just a shemale you probably even told the inline styles are basically the worst thing ever.
But in react they're actually not so bad because the way you build the component everything is bundled
up as one.
So your classes your component code and your inline styles are all in the same place.
So you don't have the same confusion in an HMO when you might have a class doing one thing in mind style
doing the other and it's very difficult to debug.
So keep that in mind as you code inline styles in reactor actually not a bad thing.
Right.
How do we add styles.
Well first of all in reacts we can add a style using javascript.
So we're going to give it a javascript object that represents our CSSA.
I'll just do it first and then explain.
So first of all let's make a lifestyle and I'll set it equal to font size of 1.5 E-M and then I'll use
that in my eyes.
And as you can see our allies are now larger because of that font size that we added.
So how's that working well first of all a style always takes an object which represents our CSSA.
But this isn't CSSA this is a javascript object.
So normally in CSSA I'd write something like Fonte dash size but this is an object and we want to keep
with javascript standards we're going to use camel case instead.
Also notice that is a javascript object so we can't just use 1.5 E-M by itself that wouldn't compile
in Javascript.
So we have to always remember or to quote any strings that we use here like 1.5 cm or so I want to make
it 40 pixels or anything else.
It would be in quotes whereas CSSA it wouldn't be.
I'll change that back.
OK.
So that's how we have to format our style objects of what's going on down here inside the GSX.
Why do we have another set of curly brackets in GSX.
Anytime you include curly brackets you're saying I want to evaluate javascript here.
So when you include style it accepts and objects and this lifestyle is an object.
But in order to evaluate that object we put inside of curly braces again.
So using curly braces to evaluate Javascript isn't just limited to styles.
Anywhere inside of GSX we can use it to to evaluate some javascript code and have it be part of part
of our GSX.
So here I'm going to evaluate some javascript to say five plus five.
And also maybe I'll say green plus blue
and I expect these two things to be evaluated and rendered as part of my CML.
So let's take a look.
As you can see I've got 10 green blue.
Now as part of the DOM.
So this is a pretty powerful tool being able to evaluate javascript inside of our GSX and we'll see
it being used a bunch as we go.
Let's finish this off by getting rid of this here and adding some styles to our title.
I could create an object up here separately but I could also write my object right in mine.
Remember the first curly braces are saying evaluate Javascript.
And the second set of curly braces are creating an object which defines my styles.
So I'm going to make the font size here 14:00.
I'm going to give it a margin of let's say 2 x to get rid of that default margin and then let's take
a look and see what it looks like.
All right there you go.
So that's our finished Moxey component or pet component.
It's got plenty of styling and I think it looks much better than before.
So next up we'll do a little exercise to help solidify some of these concepts we just learned.