Next up we'll see props in action by creating a recipe application.
Our objective is pretty straightforward we're going to use props in an application and the application
we're going to build is this recipes app.
So to start with.
Of this functionality above will work.
This is all just for show.
But we'll be able to see different recipes with images and ingredients and instructions and a title.
So let's build this.
The first thing you always want to do when you're thinking about a new project is to break it down into
components.
So when I'm tackling this problem the first thing that I would work on is I probably make one component
for a single recipe.
So this recipe card here will be one component and then I can write another component that contains
recipe cards.
So let's let's start that way.
Let's start by making a single one of these recipes.
Let's get started by going over to cloud nine and creating a new application.
So as you can see I mean re-act directory and I'm going to say create re-act up recipe prop's starter.
All right our app is all created.
And this time let's go into this directory go into packets Jaison and we'll update the version of re-act
we're using.
So again if your version already says 16 then you don't need to do anything here but at the time of
making this video reac 16 is not quite out yet so I'm going to specify sixteen point zero point zero
dash RC dot 3 and I'll do the same for re-act.
All right.
Now that I've done that the next thing I want to do is reinstall my modules.
So I'm just going to go in to hear CD into my recipe Propp starter.
I'm going to remove the package lock Jaison file and I'm also going to remove no modules.
Now do NPM install again.
All right we've got our modules installed.
And let's just run it to make sure everything works.
I'll open this up
and we've got to react 16 Up up and running.
All right.
Now let's get started with a recipe.
The first thing we'll do is go back to our code and rename this app that jast to recipe app.
So it's rename that file to recipe app and we'll rename it here as well.
And Nurse we got an error there because of the rename.
All right.
Now both files are renamed let's open that up and I'll import recipe app that's VSS instead of app that
C-s us and then I'll also rename this to recipe up and down here recipe.
Up next we need to fix index just so let's go there.
And inside of here we need to change everything from app to recipe app.
Now remember the name here doesn't really matter I could keep it as app as far as the the name of the
import goes but I'm just going to make a recipe out for consistency.
Let's check the server.
No errors we're looking good.
Next thing I want to do is create a recipe component.
So let's start that over here.
Make a new file and I'll call it just recipe dodgiest and then also give it a CSSA file.
Now inside a recipe Jasp will have the normal code.
Now we have a component that should just render something.
So let's add it into our recipe app Jass and make sure it works.
So I'll just get rid of all of this because we don't need it for now.
Import recipe.
And then use the computer here.
So we should see the text recipe and it's not too exciting right now but it shows up.
So that means is working.
Now let's start working towards making this look more like a recipe.
So if you remember what this looks like we've got a title of some ingredients instruction string and
an image.
So let's go back to our recipe component and the first thing I might want to do is pass something to
this component so I'll check out recipe.
And I'll say a title is now let's just make some pasta.
So now inside a recipe.
Yes I have access to pasta via this stop Propst that title so I can render that simply by saying stop
Propst that title and I should see pasta on the screen.
And I do.
But a common practice here is to restructure this object so I can also say conc title equals that's
not prop's if you're not familiar with destructuring like this you might want to go back in the course
and check it out.
It's used all over and react essentially we're creating a variable called Title as long as the stop
props has a property in it called Title.
It's a shorthand for saying title equals this not perhaps that title.
OK.
And I also want to remember to update the title here so now I've got a variable I don't need to use
this dot props.
All right next let's add ingredients.
So if I go over here ingredients there's a list of things so an array makes sense.
I'm going to say my ingredients are equal to an array inside of curly brackets because we want a javascript
array.
And I'll just give it two ingredients flour and water.
All right.
Now inside of my recipe component I want to use those ingredients to generate some some GSX so I'll
make a concept ingredients equal to the stock prop stock ingredients that map and the parameters here
are going to be my ingredient and then my index.
And to wrap those Bremner's
and commonly here when there's only a one line return like we have here we've got to have sex rather
than use curly braces and have to explicitly say return.
We just use parentheses which just wraps this statement for us.
So now we don't have to use return when we return from our map.
And what I want to return is a list of allies.
So for each ingredient I want to make an ally make the key equal to index.
Remember the key needs to be unique for this array.
So the index should work because I don't think my ingredient list is going to change.
And then I also want to include my ingredient and I want to close off my ally.
All right.
Next up let's render this list of ingredients so I'll make a UL here and then I'll close off the UL
and inside of that render that array the ingredients array.
And remember this is array of jazz sax elements not of strings anymore.
So we could just render it directly like that.
One other catch here is that we can never return multiple GSX elements next to each other.
So I just need to wrap this in a div.
All right.
Let's see how that works.
As you can see we are showing flour and water.
So we're on our way.
We're not quite at this recipe component yet but we have a list of ingredients and we have a title.
This video is getting a little long saw and it there.
Next up what instructions and an image and we'll add some CSSA so it doesn't look terrible.