So we left off and I mean just by adding a route to slash which would render our home page component.
So let's first include that main component inside of our objects.
So let's import mean does mean inside of our apparatus.
And inside of the class of onboarding What's that mean component.
This will allow for all my house to be configured as well inside of the main component.
We saw that we brought in home page but we actually don't have this component yet.
Let's go to that.
So inside the components who's going to could do file called Page dodginess.
This is going to be a very simple component.
It's acting essentially as a landing page.
It's going to display the message list which we're not going to get yet.
We're just a standard landing page that as the user to sign up.
So we're going to import re-act from Riak this will be another Segal's functional component so we don't
need a structure component.
We'll also import link from re-act Rotterdam.
We're then getting a function called home page and this is a seamless functional component.
We'll pass some props later but for now all we're going to do is return to make sure we wrap this in
parentheses.
What we're doing a little bit of GSX.
So let's start with the class name of home hero which will style and a little bit.
So I going to do it now but that's OK.
We're making each one says what's happening.
Well then we can each four as new to warbler and then a little call to action with a link component
to slash Messiah.
We don't have any of these routes built yet.
We're just adding a little bit of each team now to get us to those routes which will add a little bit.
Give us a class name.
Beauty and beauty and primary pre-standard bootstrap.
Let's just make sure we spot primary correctly and hear what the cause of that wing component.
And it's I will just add the text Sign-Up here would say this and take a look in the browser and what
we have so far is going to tell us export default imported as home page was not found in component's
home page.
Well we're going to make sure we export that default home page.
Pretty common mistake I'll make.
Take a look.
Alan untied is invalid expected a string but not an object.
Check the method of AB.
So what's happening here.
Well this is happening because we accidentally didn't raft with router and include mean you ought make
sure that with router includes everything connect as well as your component.
So if we take a look now we should see what's happening in order and are about now we need to solve
it.
So let's go back to our index that's Yesus and let's make sure that we style this correctly using command
to jump to files on a different machine or setting that might be different.
But I'm a man and those text editors will allow you to do the certain type of work the next CEO says
Let's start dialing this home page component after that.
Onboarding if Gnab are let's add some rules for our home hero let's dial this home here so I'll give
anything a classic home hero.
Some with and some I will get this with a 100 you part with I'll give it a high of 100.
I will make sure I completely covers the entire page will get the position of absolute and start positioning
it in the top left.
So at the top of zero left of zero we also want to make sure we get the say display flaks a line items
of center and justify justified content center so he can center horizontally and vertically.
We also want to make sure that we get the background image.
So what are we going to use.
How that's going to be a u r l and here we'll go to slash images slash sign it.
So I sign up home.
So I signed out on GBG that should give us our initial image and it's completely covering it.
But that's not looking too good yet.
Well we need to make sure that we give it is the index of negative one that we love for our NAV bar
to post on top of it.
One to make sure we still see our neighbor Meskin center a little bit more Missoulian that it takes
a lot of center for any text inside of there.
We'll get this a little bit of breathing room so we'll give it one more padding.
We want to also make sure that we have a background position.
Of center center center.
So that image is completely centered in the middle.
We also want to make sure that we get as a background size as well of cover to completely cover that
page.
So it's getting a little bit better.
But all of our text here is displayed horizontally as a row and so we want to make sure we change our
direction to how not as a row.
And now everything centering vertically now looks good.
It's a lot of as we wrote so take a look in the previous sections on fluxbox and I'll add some notes
on background positions and so on to help out that.
So we got this nice little page right here.
I think we're ready to sign of users but there's a little bit more styling that I want to add.
Give us the color of white.
So it pops a little bit more and that's a little bit too white.
So let's get fancy here and add a little bit of texture.
So all we really want to do here is just add a little bit of blur so it gives 0 0 pixels and then we'll
give it a color for that texture because look at a brownish color.
Make sure we get that semi-colon.
So if compiling successfully so we were freshest and that works better.
So anything that takes time to parse out a little bit touch on was a really nice way to get that to
happen.
So the next action will start putting more together.
Start signing up and logging in users and building those components that.