OK so we saw the basics of sending a request with X years and this video I want to talk about how we
handle any potential errors.
So it works kind of the same S.J. query and is fetch but also a little bit different.
So to illustrate this I have an example.
And rather than having you watch me type all the code I already have it completed and we're going to
focus on this code at the bottom a function called handle errors.
But before we get there I might just explain what you're looking at.
So this very ugly silly demo.
It's not going to be very exciting but I have a button when I click the button all that happens is that
I send a request to an API called Jason placeholder.
So this some place holder has a bunch of different endpoints.
Basically it's mocking or modeling data that you might get from a real API whether it's comments data
or posts or photos or to Duzer users.
I'm working with comments and as you can see the data itself is just Lorem Ipsum jibberish.
So it doesn't mean anything but the structure is representative of what comments look like.
There's an ID of the post they belong to a name an email body and so on.
And the route we're actually working with is down here.
Slash comments.
And then as a parameter post ID equals one.
So this gives us all the comments that correspond to a post with idea for one that doesn't really matter.
But I did it just so that I could show you what it actually shows.
You can actually pass in an object and in there I'm specifying post ID is one.
So rather than doing a question mark post ID equals one like that you can do it this way and this might
seem a lot easier putting in the URL until you come to a situation where you want this to be dynamic
and you want this to be a variable.
So you want this to be I no ID and that's set somewhere else by the user.
So rather than hard coding it in even though I am here this gives you a lot more flexibility.
OK but that's not the focus of this video.
What the focus is on is actually handling errors.
So I make a request.
When you click this button all that I'm doing is getting data back and I'm going through the data and
just printing out the emails of the commenters so you can see here nothing brilliant.
And every time I click I'm not even clearing it out.
So it just depends.
Those five e-mails every time but they're coming from the API.
But what I want to talk about is what happens when something goes wrong.
So I moved it to a separate function called handle errors.
It's down here and I want to call your attention to this bit of code here and this bit of code here.
So actually most X distinguish it has a property called airdate response and another one called request
that will allow you to distinguish if the error is happening with the response or with the request.
So suppose you send a response to our route that doesn't exist even though the domain does exist.
There is no slash comments pop up but but if you tried to send a request to that save which one of these
you think will trigger is there an error with the response or the request.
Well let's take a look.
Click the button and you can see it's a problem with the response.
So our request goes to the correct you RL But the server doesn't know how to handle that because it
doesn't actually expect any requests to come to such comments blah blah blah blah blah.
So we get a problem with response which is because we have error response so we could do the same thing
but give it an invalid you URL in the first place like this.
And now if I make that request it's a problem with the request itself.
So this is a nice little feature just this response dot request part of the error.
We're able to determine where things went wrong.
So that's it for error handling.
Of course you don't want to just cancel that log things.
You probably want to display an error to the user or you may want to have some additional logic in here
but I want to focus on the fact that actually access gives us these built in little handlers airdate
response and request.