This assignment you'll implement a component called random box and the random box is just a div with
some text inside the text random box.
And every time this div is rendered you'll get a different random font size here and a potentially different
background color.
I only chose four different background colors so it could be red green blue or black.
But essentially the idea is every time you refresh something different can happen to the styling.
As you can see after the refresh I've got a different background color and a different font size.
And I'll refresh once more.
And now I've got red background color and slightly different font size.
So that's the idea there's some structure below give it a shot and we'll have a solution right after.