All right.
So this will be a quick video.
I just want to show you how you can provide options to fetch.
So when you run the Fed method the first thing you always have to provide is that you know that the
request is going to but Optionally you can include an object here that contains key value pairs for
the options you want to provide.
So things like method the default of course is get which we've been making without specifying method
but you can override that or change that to the post.
You can also include things like a request body send some data along.
You don't have to use this Jaison to string a five by the way but this makes it a lot easier.
So you don't have to manually make each of these a string and worry about quotes and double quotes and
all of that.
The other important thing is we can provide headers so we can specify things manually.
So let me just show you how that works.
We go over to fetch options example I've created.
It's basically the it's exactly the same code we had from last time.
All it does is make a request to this bitcoin API and then print some of it out and if we monitor it
right now if I go over to my network and then look at a chart and I refresh the page and I resize this
a bit we have our fetch.
Made here as you can see no longer next H.R..
This is coming from code pen by the way.
So we have our fetch and if we actually look at it like this a little easier for you to see it's a get
by default.
OK.
So all of that just to prove how it works by default.
But now if I change it by passing in the Options object and I say method is now post and I save all
refresh.
The first thing you should know is that this API does not have a post and point.
So it's not going to be happy about me trying to make a post request to this but that doesn't matter
for our example because we can see here if I look at it it was sent as a post the status code was a
five hundred not good but it was still a post.
OK.
So that's method.
We can also do things like send body along the way a lot of people like to format.
This is like this.
So we'll have.
Body is equal to.
And you could just pass in plain data like a string like this is the body the request just like that
and I need to make sure this is still the post because get requests don't have bodies.
Now we do this Refresh will still get an error 500 error.
But if we actually look at the request and I think we have to scroll down to see the body.
Here we go.
This is the body of the request.
So this is all just an interface for manipulating the request.
We're going to send it as far as Jason docstring ify.
I'll just copy this over to see can see how it's commonly used.
So something like this body.
And then it's equal to adjacent string of phi an object with some strings in it.
And if we look at what sent scroll down you can see it here if we view the actual source.
It's all strings.
So we didn't have to manually turn that into strings just on that string afraid does that for us.
All right.
So I promise I'd keep this video quick.
Let's wrap it up so you can provide an options object containing key value pairs of the various options.
We've seen method and body.
There are more.
Those are probably the most commonly used but there are more.
If we go to M.D and I'll include this page in the resources you can see we can also specify things like
headers so we can manually specify headers and their values or credentials.
That's pretty commonly used as well if we need credentials for a request but there are other things
like redirect and refer refer policy signal I don't actually I have no idea what that is but basically
if you want to learn more about these options and the various options that you can provide you can read
more about them on these docs.
OK.
So that wraps up the basics of providing options to refresh your quest.