Welcome back.
In this video we'll combine our knowledge of D-3 and SPG to create a simple bar chart.
Let's start by putting the data and data visualization.
Here I've got the data from the UN on the number of births around the world by year and by month.
The data goes from 1967 through 2014.
Our goal in this video is to make a simple bar chart along with a way to adjust the year and see the
bar charts update.
Here's a link to some starter code for this project including the HMO and the birth data.
Here's a link to the live site which so far it doesn't do anything because we haven't written any code.
Our first goal will just be getting some bars on the page without worrying about changing the year.
I've already created an apt J S file where I'll be writing my D-3 code before I forget a link to it
in my HDL now.
Let's start coding first you'll notice that my range slider doesn't have a min max or current value.
I'd like to base these on the first and last year in my dataset.
So the first thing I'll do is grab the first and last year and then update the min max value attributes
on our input this code assumes that the first year comes from the first element.
My dataset in the last year comes from the last element in my dataset.
In the next video we'll learn about a way to use D-3 to find the largest and smallest values even if
they don't follow this simple pattern.
Typically I'd write this code inside of an event listener that waits for the dom content to load.
However for these tutorials I'd like to be able to easily look at my variables in the console.
For that reason I'll just make everything global for now.
In your own projects though you should be sure to wrap your code inside of an event listener so that
you don't pollute the global scope with a bunch of variables.
Let's refresh the page cool.
It looks like our input tag is updated next.
Let's set a width and height for our SPG and try to append some rectangles since the inputs current
value is for the first year 1967.
I'll only want to join data from that year to my rectangles.
I'll use a filter to remove any data that isn't from that first year.
There's also a helper method called D-3 nest which will allow us to restructure our data but let's keep
things simple for now.
If I run this code now I rectangles want to do a whole lot.
I also need to figure out what attributes to set on each rectangle.
One of the hardest parts about using D-3 to visualize data is usually not the data binding.
It's figuring out how to translate the join data into the appropriate visuals before we try to get an
accurate bar chart.
Let's first just try to render our bars in the SVGA with some with the night.
I'll pick a width for each rectangle say 25 pixels and for now let's have them spend the full height
of the SVGA.
This means that the y coordinate of each rectangle should be zero.
But what about the x coordinate.
Well we want the first rectangle to be on the left.
The next one to be twenty five pixels over the next one to be 25 pixels over again and so on we can
express this mathematically.
If we keep track of the index of our current piece of data in the birth data array we can then use this
index to offset the x coordinate of each bar based on the bar with cool.
It might look like we've got one rectangle in the SVGA but these are actually all of our rectangles
all squished together.
If we want to space them out a bit we can add some padding and then shift our x coordinate over by the
width plus the amount of padding.
Let me also change the default fill for the rectangles.
Now it's clearer that there are multiple rectangles in our SPG.
Setting the bar with to be 25 pixels was fairly arbitrary.
And in this case we wind up with a bunch of unused space in the SVGA.
Very often you'll see the bar which depend on the width of the SPG itself along with the amount of padding
you want in between bars in this case a better approach would be to take the SPG width divide by the
number of rectangles we have and then subtract the amount of padding.
This way the total width of the number of bars plus the amount of padding per bar will be the same as
the SPG width.
OK great.
Now let's tackle the heights of these rectangles.
This part is a bit tricky because of the way coordinates work with SVGA.
Remember that the 00 point is the upper left corner of the SPG not the lower left corner this doesn't
matter so much for the height attribute which we know should be based on the number of births.
Let's just make the height equal to the value of the births property for each piece of data.
What about the y value.
It isn't zero.
Instead we need the value for this attribute to be the y coordinate of the upper left corner of the
bar.
This means that we need to take the height of the SPG and subtract off the desired bar height in order
to obtain the correct y coordinate.
OK this looks good or does it.
If we refresh the page things don't look right at all.
Total births recorded in our dataset for 1967 were relatively low especially compared to now.
But all of these bars look the same as before.
If we look in the elements tab we can find the problem because our hides and our y coordinates are tied
directly to birth numbers.
Their values are much much larger than the dimensions of the SVGA.
What we need to do is scale the data so that it fits properly within the bounds of the SVGA.
For now let's do this manually in the next video.
We'll learn how to automate this process.
No month had more than 2.5 million births.
So if we divide all of our birth numbers by 2.5 million and then multiply by the squeegie height we'll
get values between 0 and 600 cool.
That looks much better.
Our last step is to get that range and put working with these D-3 to add listener input events on the
input the event target value will be a year from 1967 to 2014 and we'll want to convert that to a number
once we know the new year.
We just need to grab each rectangle and update the height and weight attributes based on the number
of monthly births for that year.
Be sure to scale your data appropriately.
With this code in your app yes the range input should now be working.
There's plenty more we can do here.
For example the graph isn't labeled at all.
It would be nice to have labeled axes or at least labels for the individual bars.
So it's clear what they represent.
We also had to do a lot of math to figure out how to draw these rectangles.
Fortunately as we all learned in the next section D-3 can help us out with some of this arithmetic quite
a bit but we'll save these features for later.
Right now go check out the exercises for the section.
When you're ready we can learn about some more functionality that D-3 provides to help make SVGA manipulation
a little more seamless.