Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be talking about prototypes.
We'll first understand what the prototype object is we'll then describe and diagram the relationship
between under proto prototype and constructor.
Well then add methods and properties on the prototype object to write more efficient code and explain
the difference between adding methods and properties to the prototype versus the constructor function.
Finally we'll define and implement inheritance through the prototype object before we get the prototypes.
Let's quickly review one more time what the new keyword does first.
It creates an object out of thin air.
Second it sets the value of the keyword this to be that object created in the previous step.
Third it adds or return this to the constructor function.
Finally it creates a link which we can access as Dunder Prato between the object created and the prototype
property of the constructor function.
Let's talk a bit more about that point.
Better yet let's diagram this relationship.
Don't be too intimidated by this diagram or walk through it step by step as a guide.
A circle is a function and a square is an object.
So here we have a person constructor function which has a property called prototype which is an object
that object has a property on it called constructor which points back to the original constructor function.
If properties or methods are placed on the person prototype they can be accessible from any object created
from that constructor function.
Finally the way in which these objects which are created by the constructor function get access to the
prototype object is through a link called Dunder proto.
This link gets a step list when the new keyword is used.
To recap every constructor function has a property on it called prototype.
This property is an object which can have methods and properties placed on it.
These methods and properties are shared and accessible by any object that is created from that constructor
function.
When the new keyword is used.
Now let's see what this looks like with a code example.
I'm going to copy and paste some code in the chrome console and we can walk through each line of it.
First I have a constructor function called person with a property called name.
Since I have created a function we can already see that there is a property on it called up prototype
in javascript.
Every single function has a property on it called predicate.
Now I'm going to create two objects called an alley from my constructor function using the new keyword.
Since I use the new keyword a property has been added to each of these objects called under Procope
which points to the prototype property and the person constructor will discuss in the next video.
Why this prototype property is so useful.
Finally the prototype object has a property on it called constructor which points back to the original
function.
The constructor property is not something you'll be using or manipulating frequently but it is an important
part in a concept called inheritance which we'll discuss in a leader video.
To recap I actually want to jump back a couple of slides to the diagram so we can go over it again.
Remember circles are functions and squares are objects.
So here I have two objects called L-E and colt which were created from the person constructor function.
Since I use the new keyword when I created them.
Each of these objects has a property on it called under Provo which points to the prototype property
on the person constructor in the next video will examine the prototype object and see just how useful
it is.
See Idan.