Welcome back in the last video we started making a recipe component so let's continue where we left
off.
If you recall we've got a recipe component and so far it takes in two props a title and a array of ingredients
and we don't have much styling or anything going on so so far it just looks like this.
In this example we passed and pasta for the title and flour and water for the ingredients.
Now let's add the remaining data.
I'm going to assume that my props will have an image and an instruction passed to it or instructions.
So that should be all the things that my component needs now.
Title image instructions and ingredients.
Let's actually display that so I'll just throw a tag here and then put the instructions in and just
to get the image show up also at the image tag.
My source is going to equal my image and my old text I'll just set equal to the title.
All right.
So that should do it for the component.
Let's pass it in on the jazz side.
And I'll make this multiple lines just so it's easier to see.
I want to give it some instructions.
I'll just say Mix ingredients and my image.
I've cheated a little bit here so I've already copied over to the public folder a spaghetti file through
that.
So this spaghetti that Jay peg is just an image that I got in order to put it in cloud 9.
You could just drag and drop from your desktop into the folder and it will be uploaded for you.
So because spaghetti is being delivered in public I can just reference it.
Like that
there's a different way to include images and re-act that we'll see later similar to what's being done
up here with the logo.
Speaking of which I'll get rid of this logo because we're not using it.
So the other way of importing images that actually uses web pack will learn later.
Remember this public folder isn't part of the web pack build process.
So spaghetti won't be packaged up by web pack which is generally something you want to do.
All right.
Now that all set.
Let's see if it all works.
I need to close this P-TECH
I need to remember to start my server up again so I'm going to get into that directory recipe Propp
starter and then say NPM start
and then I'll open this up.
And now our image is showing up and our instructions are here too.
So now we've got all of our props inside of this component.
We're rendering the data that we've passed in.
So that's a great step.
The next thing we want to do is style this so it looks reasonable.
So let's do that now.
Let's start by looking at this recipe Geass and rearranging HCM so that it fits better with the card
that we saw before.
So remember in this version the image is on top then the title then this Ingredion string list of ingredients
instructions and then the instructions text.
So lets match that.
All right.
First of all put div up top here and inside that div I'll add my image.
Next up let's create another div and inside of that div we'll put the content of the card.
So I'm going to change this day and age 3
I'll remember to add my ingredients here.
Mactan for
then I'll also put a label above here for the instructions.
OK let's see how that looks.
Looking better looking more like our example a little bit more like it.
Now let's add some classes that we can then style.
So first I'll give this a class name of recipe card.
Give this one a class name of recipe image
excuse me recipe card image that I did before.
And then this one will be my card content.
And I'll give this one a classic recipe title.
All right let's move on to the C Ss.
So again I won't focus too much on the CSSA but I'll show each class.
So here's the class for our recipe card.
We're going to make it take up a third of the screen so that we put three cards next to each other and
above that we'll use fluxbox so that the latter makes more sense.
But see what else there is a border background and some border radius.
We're giving the card content a little bit of padding so it's below the image a little.
The recipe card image div will take up 50 percent of our whole card and then we'll give some some width
and height to the image itself.
Lastly the H-3 for the recipe title will have no margins so it doesn't take up as much empty space.
All right now we've added the CSSA and we'll just double check that we've included that CSSA we have
not.
So I'll include it.
Now with those changes I'll double check to make sure things are running.
It is it looks much more like a card at this point.
So a lot of progress but there's still a few errors so it's going fix those.
So I forgot when I first created this app to get rid of all the styling app that's DSS.
So let's go there.
It's recipe app that the SS now and I'm just going to delete all of this for now.
In fact you delete it all and then one other thing I want to do is I want to add a font.
So let's just see that change.
Yeah it looks a lot more like our other example.
But if you notice the fonts here are different.
So this is the standard what font.
I think this is rubato.
So let's let's grab that Fontenette it.
All right.
First thing I'm going to do is go into indexation Chimo and I'm just going to throw in the link for
that one.
So now I've got this robot font from Google.
I'll say that.
And then inside my index SS I'll make some changes here.
So I'm going to change the font family to.
And then I'll also change the background to this color here.
It's grayish color.
So with those changes let's take a look.
OK.
Looks good to me.
So that looks pretty close to our solution let's compare.
Yeah yeah.
Pretty good.
So that's it for making the recipe card component.
Next up we're going to take a step back and talk about default props and prop types.