So we spent the last couple screencast learning about readouts and connecting reactant redux and connecting
the Riak router with redux what we're going to do now is start building the backbone for a full stack
application.
We've done a lot of work on the front end.
What we're going to do now is actually start persisting our do is using a database and building a node
backend.
So what I'm going to start with is by making a simple folder and I'll call that to use back in and I'm
going to CD into that folder and we're going to create a simple node application.
I'm going to end it and I'll pass in-dash y.
So I to fill in all the blanks and I'll make a file called index that yes.
And with this note application we're going to keep it really simple.
I'll make a folder for my models as well as for my routes and I'll install some necessary dependencies.
I'm going to install express body parser.
What else do you think we might need.
We're going to need mongoose and one more important thing we need to think about is actually cores.
And this is a bit of middleware that's going to allow us to make requests that are cross origin.
Remember this back end is going to be starting on localhost three thousand one or 5000 and our front
end application is going to have a different port number and when there are requests from one domain
to another right off the bat it's a violation of the same origin policy because those port numbers are
different.
They might both be local hosts but they're still going to be different ports.
So we want to allow requests from different domains to come into our API and to do that we're going
to use this nice Corps module a little bit of middleware that's going to allow for certain headers to
be sent and set to allow for cross origin requests.
So let's get started with this.
I also realize there's one more dependency that we're going to add and this is going to be for a little
bit of debugging that is going to be Morgon so NPM and Morgan that's going to allow us to see requests
that are coming in to our data.
So let's get started with some code.
What I'm going to do with my index Geass is just go and bring in all of my necessary dependencies and
you express.
So I'm going to require express.
I also want an app variable.
So I'm going to invoke the Express function.
I also want to bring in cores so cores is going to be requiring the cores module and I'm going to do
this with Morgon as well.
Make sure that we bring in Morgan.
And let's go to make sure that we bring in two more.
We have a body parser to make sure I call this body Dasch parser.
And there's one more that I'm going to want which are going to be my routes so I'm going to call this
to do routes and to do routes is going to be the result of bringing in whatever is in route slash to
use.
So in order to get that to work I need to make sure that I have a file called to do's dodgiest.
So inside of here I'll make a file called the dues that G-S inside of my models as well.
I'll make a file called to do that.
Yes I'm going to have a simple to do model.
So what else do I need inside of here.
Well let's start using some of this middleware.
I'm going to use Morgan and we'll pass in tiny.
This is simply going to give me a little bit of logging.
I also want to make sure that I use body parts or you might see body parser You are all encoded.
We want to make sure we're using body parts or Jason since those are the kind of requests that are coming
in.
We want to make sure that we also use cores and then we're going to specify that any routes that come
in will prefix them with API sloshed to use and that's where we'll include all of our to drought's.
You can see a more complex folder structure with the handler's folder and so on.
I'm going to keep things really simple here.
I just want a little bit of middleware so I'm going to say if there is any kind of request that comes
in that we don't know about we'll make a new error.
We can say let error be a new error and we'll see here not found.
There's going to be simple 404 handler.
We'll set the status to be four or four and then we'll simply call next with that error.
This is just a little bit of fancy error handling.
The next thing we can do is we're really not worried too much about building this in production is will
simply say let's use another piece of middleware which is going to catch that or whatever rack arrays
and indexed and inside of here we're simply going to say that our status is whatever that status is
or the five hundred.
This is very similar to the middleware that you'll generate when using the Express generator for some
stuff that you've seen before.
I'm just quoting this line by line so we can see what's actually happening here.
What we'll then do is simply send a error message will pass in an object with a key message and that
will be whatever the messages.
And that will pass in some kind of error which will be whatever error we get back from our next handler.
Finally let's make sure that we listen and we can listen on port three thousand one.
Let's keep it real simple.
We'll run a function and when we start listening we'll say the Consul got a log server starting on port
3000 one.
This is not something that we're going to worry about deploying in productions or we're really just
going to start with a simple develop and server.
So this looks like a pretty good index that.
Yes but we're not going to get very far if we don't have our routes and we're not going to get very
far if we don't have any kind of database persistence.
So we're going to bring in mongoose.
This is going to be our odium that's going to wrap Mongo and allow us to quickly store information save
information and retrieve it.
We're going to connect to a very simple database we'll call that Mongo D-B and slash slash host and
we'll call this Dewes back and we'll see that.
Let's make sure that we pass and debug of truth so we can see the Mago queries being executed for debugging
and we'll make sure that we use.
Yes 2015 promises by setting a mongoose that promise to be the promise library that is built in.
To know what we'll then do is make a quick scheme and that's going to be a new mongooses schema which
accepts an object and all we're going to have is a task that's it.
Our task is going to be a strength.
The next thing we do is create a model from that schema Mangu start model what do we call it to do and
what schema creates it to do schema.
The last thing we're going to do is just export out this to do model.
So all we want to do in our model here is bring in mongoose connect to it log any Mongo queries for
debugging and make sure that we're using E.S. 2015 promises.
We then are going to build a very simple schema where all are Tadeusz we'll just have a task.
Finally we'll make a model and then export out that model that looks pretty good.
How about our wraps up here.
We need to think about the kind of routes that we need in this application.
So first off we've got to bring in Express when we bring in Express will require that.
And what are we using with Express we're going to use the express router.
Finally we're going to bring in a to do model so that we make sure that we go back to folder and grab
that to do model for any kind of database interaction.
Let's just make sure right off the bat that we export out that router.
And here we really only need three ruffs.
We're going to have to get requests to slash.
Remember everything is prefixed with API I-Slash to us.
So we're going to go to a router that gets flash when that happens we'll run a function with rec.
RAZ And next.
And inside of here we'll simply find all of our traduce and then run a function with those cities and
we'll just respond by sending all of those to Dewes.
If something goes wrong we'll get some kind of error and we'll just call next with our code looks pretty
good.
This is simply going to go get all of our tatoos.
This is the route where our index route to grab all of the tools.
What about creating a new to do.
Well that's not a guess that's a post.
And when that comes in we will create with whatever comes in in our body.
Now this is not the most secure.
This is just a simple application.
This will give us some kind of to do and here we can even send a status of 201 which is created.
And then we'll send that to do that we just made if things go wrong we'll send that to the air handler.
The last thing we want to do right now is simply just Meeka a route to delete to do this and when we
go to slash slash to do slash some somebody we're going to use the very handy find by id and remove
and what are we going to remove.
We're going to remove whatever comes in as this I.D. rate here.
We get that and read that harams and express and then we're simply going to send that to do that we've
deleted.
Next thing we're going to do is simply just send that to the air handler.
So how do we know if this is working or a really good way is first to make sure that we can start this
server.
So we're going to run Nordman and it looks like we're starting this.
And it's telling us use Mongo client to connect.
I'm not too worried about that.
You can take a look at that deprecation.
We're just really building something very simple.
Right now what we want to do is test our API.
So in a separate terminal window we could start making requests but I'm going to use a pretty friendly
library called HDD PI and HDD Pi is a modern command line.
HTP client you can scroll down a little bit and see how to install it.
It's quite easy.
You can use Brou.
And I'll show you how to use it.
So we're going to start by making a request to HTB.
We're going to get a local host colon.
Three thousand and one slash API slash to use.
And what we can see right now is we get these nice headers and then we see a simple array of what we
get back.
Now if we want to see if we can create these Let's HDD be but we're going to post localhost three thousand
one slash slash to use.
We're going to pass in a task of it.
Let's go try that out and we can see that in our server that we're actually running that insert this
right here is coming from our debug true.
We can see the Mongo queery this post-trade here is coming from Morgan.
So it's really nice to make sure that we're doing that correctly.
Let's go try to add another one HDD.
We're going to post to localhost three thousand and one slashy I-Slash to do with the task of code.
Let's go try that out and we can see we get back this new to do that we meet if we want to see all of
our to do.
Remember the rap for that HDTV get Post three thousand one slash if eyes flashed addy's.
Let's go check that out.
And there we go.
There are the two issues that we have.
How about deleting one.
Well we need to delete by the ID so I going to grab this ID and I'm going to run each DDP delete localhost
three thousand one.
What's the end point again.
API to Doo's some ID.
Let's go take a look at what this looks like.
When we delete.
You can see we're running find and modify we're passing in the ID and it looks like we've removed this
one successfully just a triple check that we can make sure that when we get all of our dues we just
have one remaining.
So it looks like our back ends actually in pretty good shape.
We can run these three requests we're just testing from a command line you could use postman you could
use Kerl and using each T.T. pi.
That's the wonderful module that you can brew install should pi and you can use it right away.
It's a much cleaner way of worrying about passing and headers and string of information.
It's a really nice way to work with things.
Unfortunately we're not really going to be using each PI to work with our application.
What we need to do next is Connect re-act the router and redox with this back end that we built.
We're going to start a server on 3000 which is going to be our create re-act up and we're going to modify
information on a server with 3000 thousand one.
So we're going to have to introduce communication between our create react up and are no Bakan.
And that's all we'll do in the next video.
But before we start let's go take a quick look at the code we've written here.
We started by bringing in some dependencies express courters remember what horses cross origin resource
sharing.
This allows us to make a request to local host 3000 and one from local localhost 3000 which is going
to be our create re-act up.
Remember these ports are different.
So by default the origin policy which is a security policy on the web says that we cannot make those
requests because we don't want to write any kind of malicious javascript on another domain.
But since we're using cores we enable cross origin requests we enable Ajax requests to be made to this
backend.
We don't have that corps request we're going to get a big error around the same Orjan policy.
We brought in Morgan for some server side logging body parser.
So when we make post requests we can grab our body and then we brought in our Toddie routes.
We use this middleware and we prefix all of our routes with slashed API slashed adieus.
We have a little bit of logic related to error handling in our routes.
We have three endpoints local three 3000 one slash API I-Slash that use get all that to do as opposed
to that same route to create it to do.
And then the final one to delete a to do by.
We're using these nice mongoose methods that we have those mongoose methods come from our mongoose model
right here which has a schema which simply contains a task.
We're going to keep it real simple.
Right now so try to go this back and as well make some requests using curl or using postman or HTC pi.
However you're comfortable with that.
And the next screen cast will put it all together pull the full stack application with some react some
redux and discuss how asynchronous actions can be triggered in redux using a library called P-doc stunk.
See you in the next pre-cast.