All right it's time to start adding a little bit routeing to sign up and log in functionality.
And this is where things are going to get a little bit trickier.
So let's make sure that we have a component to sign in and sign up users.
So we want to try to do here is just make one single component that we'll call off or call that form
such as So we want make sure we use the same component for logging in and signing up so we don't have
to duplicate all that functionality.
So when we go to this form it's they're going to allow us to sign up or log in.
So we use a little bit of conditional logic if the user has tried to sign up or logging.
So routing logic is going to help us out with that.
Let's go to our mangy ass and have a couple or else we'll had a route that is going to go to an exact
path again of slash seinen
seinen.
We're going to render it component with some props.
So just like we did before we run a function with props and here will render a certain component just
watch your syntax inside here.
It's a little bit tricky with those curly braces and so on.
So inside of here we're going to return our offering.
So let's turn that off one component.
Which is going to contain a couple of props.
We don't have this form yet but we'll do that in a bit.
So let's pass in all the props that we're getting especially from the Riak router that's going to be
helpful as well as some additional props.
Let's Adsum props like a button text which will say loggin will also have a heading.
It's going to say welcome back.
And these will be dependent on the kind of form that we're rendering.
We're adding some sensible defaults here.
So we load a specific component.
We don't have too much of a problem displaying whatever button text and heading are depending on if
they're trying to sign up or log in inside a sign up will change what these values are.
So based on these routes we can determine the text that we want on the page.
So it is a me over here just like it has no corresponding tag.
So the did does actually have a closing tag which is closing but the route is not closing.
So we see that nice auto format and we're actually going to copy this route and it's going to be very
similar.
So what changes for sign up.
We're going to have some props as well but we'll change our button text which is something like sign
me up and a heading that once a welcome back it'll say something like join warbler today.
So we have here is really just some boilerplate for an offer.
It's now time to actually start building this software.
We're not worrying about errors or if you submitted incorrectly or if you're like Generally that's for
another time.
Let's build this up piece by piece.
So when is this form.
I have to import all form from data Flash components flash or so let's go see this.
And let's go back and see what our actual page looks like.
And actually before we do that let's go rename this component to our capital form and make sure that
we rename that file to all four.
So let's go make this component.
So what do we need inside of our off arm component.
So this is actually going to need some Riak state because we're only building a form and the inputs
we want to have control over.
So let's import react and the structure component from re-act
will also make a class called a form that's going to extend re-act component or just components since
we destruction it.
So if we'd like to export this as the default just makes everybody on correctly and we'll make a constructor
in here we'll pass in some props we'll call Ron Krasik any parent props Mozart was busy and there are
lots of more modern ways of creating your initial state.
But we're just going to start with what we've seen before is keep it real simple.
So it has some standard default state an email username password and some kind of profile image.
These all as empty strings and we might not actually need all of these properties and state depending
on the kind of form that we render but that's OK.
We're going to we just have a little bit of anti-state
now we'll start rendering this component so let's render make sure that's inside of our class so will
render and inside of here.
What's the structure.
A couple things from state.
Grab you email username password and profile image.
You are all Magreb that from this that's the we're then going to turn a component inside of this component.
We're going to return some GSX some of the acts what's going make sure first that I have this set to.
So I get that Emmets syntax and what's gone right.
A little bit of GSX.
So this is pretty boilerplate in terms of a form will have to contain everything and a class of row
justify content.
And the center as well as tech center so ease and bootstrap styling to get our form in the center and
the inputs in the center as well as any text inside that looks good.
We'll also put this inside of a div called Mt 6.
So we want to center those columns right off the bat.
Inside let's make a form.
And when this form is submitted we're going to run some function that will call this that handles so
that will make this in a Lovat
inside of this form.
We're going to add in each two and here we'll have whatever the prompt is of I've had it.
But what is adding.
Well heading comes from this that prompts that we pass down from our main J s component but we have
to structure them from prop's if we want to write it that way.
So as a heading what are their proofs that we get.
We got a button text as well.
So let's go make sure that we grab a button text as well.
And we're going to structure that from this props so that we can use heading inside of there without
prefixing everything with this thought process that looks good.
Inside it's easy to make a couple of labels and make a label for you know we'll give out the text of
you know and we'll also make sure after the label that we have an input that corresponds to that label
and then this input we're going to add quite a few props we'll give it a class name a form control.
This is used you have to get that full with was also had an ID of email to match up with the for in
our label want to give us an email that's important for our stay.
We'll get this in onchange property of a function that will call this that handle change well into the.
And a little bit I will give this a value property of email.
So if it exists in the case of any kind of errors we'll still be able to pre-populated that with whatever
the email is at the moment.
So this is our e-mail and put that looks good.
It's also make sure that we add another label and input but this one's going to be for a password we
call that password as the text of the label is going to be password to match up with the label name
is going to be password as well.
We really want to make sure that the type is not text the type his password.
So we don't see the password as the users typing in.
We don't want to value here so that we put in a password again.
We don't either.
But we still want onchange.
So in the next video we'll add some code to make sure the handle changes working and handles it is working.
And then make sure we add logic to determine those extra two inputs correctly.