Welcome back.
In this video we're going to discuss how to test time dependent code and asynchronous code.
First let's examine how to test time dependent code.
This includes timers like set interval and set time out as well as operations that use dates.
The jazzmen tool will be using to help us test this type of code is called clock to get started with
clocks.
We need to invoke the jasmine dot clock dot install function.
This is commonly done in a before each callback.
We also have to make sure to uninstalls the clock after each spec to make sure we do not have any unintended
side effects.
This uninstaller is commonly done in and after each callback.
So does this look like let's see an example.
The set time out and are before each were going to create a dummy function called sample which we will
use inside of a set time out and then we'll install our clock.
We'll also make sure that our clock resets after each callback to it so that we can test without any
unexpected side effects inside of our block.
We will invoke a set time L to run our sample function in 1000 milliseconds.
Note here that sample is just a spy that does nothing but we want to test that after 1000 milliseconds
it gets called on the next line.
We will use the tick function to move our clock ahead by a certain amount of time.
We are then making sure our function has not been called yet.
And after one more millisecond our function should be called.
So these tests will pass.
You can see here that we are using the tick function in passing in an amount of time to test our asynchronous
code.
Let's see another example with set interval.
Here we have a similar setup with a dummy spy that will be invoked in a set interval.
We are also installing and uninstalling the clock in our before each and after each functions as we
move the clock.
We can see that there are a certain amount of times that the function was called in the same way that
we tested that time out.
You can test set interval and also check how many times the function has been called.
Now let's discuss how to test code that is asynchronous.
Examples of this kind of code include timers like said time out and set interval as well as each GDP
requests with something like Ajax.
So how can we test this kind of code.
Thankfully with Jasmine it's quite easy.
All we have to do is pass a parameter to any of the before or after methods or to the callbacks to it.
Like all parameters with javascript we can call this whatever we want but it is commonly called done.
It's important to note that a test will not complete until the done function is invoked.
Jasmine has an internal timer which it runs before the test fails to make sure that the test is not
waiting too long.
This is a setting you can change in Jasmine.
That's not commonly done on story short testing asynchronous code is not that bad at all.
We just have to make sure to add a parameter to specific callback functions and invoke it.
Let's see what that would look like with a small example.
I have a function called Get user info which accepts a user name and returns the result of the query
get Jason method inside of the Get Jaison method.
I am making an HDTV request to the get hub user api and searching for a username passed to this function.
Remember that all of the Gigue Querrey Ajax methods return a promise to me.
So in my tests I'll be using doc then to handle the resolved promise in my tests.
Notice that I'm passing a parameter to the callback of the function.
On the second line I have named that parameter done.
But you can call it whatever you'd like.
However I recommend that you call it done because this is what you will commonly see when testing asynchronous
code in some of the callback ticket.
I'm invoking the get user info function and passing the user name of Ali and then attaching a dot then
the handle the result promise in passing a callback to dump then which contains the data.
I get back from the get hub API inside of this callback.
I will test to see if the name property on the deed I got back is my name which is expected.
Once that expectation has run I will invoke my gun function to make sure the test does not timeout.
The most important part here is the done function which I am passing to the callback of the IT function.
Without that I'm not able to successfully test my asynchronous code.
Now that you've seen how to use clocks and the Done function to test asynchronous code it's time for
you to practice a bit.
Good luck and I'll see you in the next video.