All right it's time to delete some messages.
So let's go take a look at how we can get started with that.
So we need to make sure that in our actions for messages we have the ability to get to our producer
to remove a message so we take a look at our actions for messages.
We have the ability to fetch messages.
We have the ability to create messages.
But what about removing
what we have is an action type for a move message.
So let's first create an action creator that will move which except some kind of ID of a message that
we want to remove.
And here we return an object with a type of remove message and some kind of ID.
How are you going to dispatch this action creator.
Well let's going take a look.
We're going to explore a function call move message and move message is going to be a function that
accepts some kind of user ID and message ID.
We're getting both of those to get to the correct end point we're then going to return dispatch.
And inside of here we're going to make an API call wealthily to slash FBI slash users.
Slash whatever the message slash whenever the user ideas slash messages slash whatever that message
ID is.
And if that works out well run a function and we'll dispatch remove with that message ID
if this for some reason fails we'll then run a function and we'll have that error.
With the error message sent in over to our producer to display the air.
So I mean a function call or message is asynchronous.
So we're going to wait until the API call finishes.
And then once it's finished we'll have to remove or will dispatch adverts make sure we actually dispatch
that error.
So once we dispatch the action to remove the sensor the reducer a type of remove message.
So let's make sure that in our search for messages we can handle removing a message so in the case of
a move message we want to return all of the messages except for the one that's removed.
So we want to write a pure function and that we do that easily is the use the filter function.
So we're going to return state after this offer to each message that we get over and all we're going
to do is get the ones where the message ID is not the same as the actual ID which is the idea of the
message that we want to remove.
Those are not the same.
Omitted from the list of messages and load messages will show us all the messages except for the one
that's removed.
So what we want to do now is make a button to delete these specific messages.
So inside of our message item make sure that we have a button to delete individual message.
We're going to have to allow our messages to.
So where we're fetching those specific messages we also want to make sure that we pass in our removed
message function and we're going to remove message to each one of these items.
But we want to make sure that we get the correct IDs.
So we'll call remove message and we'll bind with the value of this.
And then the correct message user ID and message ID.
So this is how we can add that remove message that correctly gets the right user ID and the correct
and the correct message ID once we pass this to our message item.
We should now be able to add a button.
So inside of here we'll add an anchor tag.
Let's keep it simple.
What good is a class name BGN BGN and danger.
Pretty standard bootstrap styling right here and unclick will call remove message.
And that's a problem we're going to get that we want to make sure that we do structure inside of our
parameters to message them as make sure that this causes.
And there's also an inside.
Here is the text only.
So let's see this.
And let's refresh the page and it looks like there are delete buttons for everyone.
So testing in the late McInally it's actually see how this works.
And we look on the lead.
It's not working.
So we're going to cancel.
He's got a little bit so looks we have another area that will quickly fix.
And this is more of a warning but you want to make sure that we call that class names so let's fix that.
Let's refresh the page and we still should see an Arab It actually looks like nothing's happening right
now.
So how would you go about debugs.
Let's first take a look in our redox store and see if anything has actually changed.
And it doesn't look like anything is being dispatched so let's make sure that we're passing in everything
correctly inside of our message list.
We bring an remove message but nowhere do we actually place that on dispatched to prop's So that's a
fresh page.
Well see now in redox if anything changes so we click on this.
Nothing changing.
So why that be the case.
You might add it to dispatch to prop's but you may forget to restructure.
We want to make sure that we actually place it in our component.
So you need those two steps now with literally we're getting an error.
Let's see what this is.
We can click on there and we click the response we can click on the response from the server and it
says error is not defined.
So this is actually a pretty interesting error.
This is not happening on the client.
This is happening on the server.
It looks like inside of our messages model it looks like we forgot to fix a couple of things inside
of our remove.
So once we fix that was her first page when we're deleting that looks good.
If we try to do the math we're actually going to get back for a want of an otherwise.
And that's a good thing.
The server is actually stopping us from deleting other people's messages.
But we want to do is not even display that delete button.
If that's not the current user and the next section that's exactly what we'll do.