In the last video we went over the recipe component of our recipe app.
And in this video we'll take a step back and look at two important concepts related to props called
default props and prop types.
Our objectives will be to use default props to give our props a default value and secondly to use prop
types to specify what props a component is expecting.
So this sort of creates a contract between our component and the user of the component.
Let's start off with the default prop's example so deep all props give you default values for the props
that you're using inside of your component.
So in this example if you think back to our recipe component we had a list of ingredients.
Well we could turn that into a separate component.
I called this component ingredient list and it's going to expect a array of ingredients.
Let's assume the user of this component whoever is using it in their render method doesn't provide an
ingredient prop.
Well if we just have this render code down here this stop Propp start ingredients would be undefined.
So this not prop's that Ingredion stop map would result in an error because we can't call map on an
undefined value.
So what default prop's does up here is it provides a default value for this Propp start ingredient.
Excuse me there's not Propp start ingredients when the user of the component doesn't provide this ingredient
proper.
If the user does provide an ingredient Propp then this default prop's isn't used.
So it's a nice thing to have when you have an optional value.
If the value is optional for your component you can provide a sane default.
If the user doesn't provide one so this is another way of specifying a default Propp.
And this is just normal javascript so you'll notice in the last example we used a static because a default
Propp isn't something that is specific to one instance of a component.
It's something that's shared for all components.
So you can think of this if you're familiar with Object-Oriented Programming as well as a static value.
So similarly we can rather than put it static keyword inside the class after the class is defined we
can say ingredient list that default prompts.
So specifying the default prop's this way and specifying the default prop's this way are equivalent.
I prefer doing it this way just because I like to keep everything inside of the class.
But again it's up to you
here's an example of using default props to load some data for a component.
Hint hint.
This is something that you're going to be doing very shortly.
When you build the full recipes app.
So in this example in the app components or the highest level component I'm loading in some data.
In this case an array of recipes and each element in the array is an object that has title ingredients
instructions and an image.
So again if you remember this is exactly what we had for our recipe component that we created earlier
and now down here in my render method that props start recipes already has that data.
So I can map over it and put all those elements into props for that recipe component.
Now if you notice in the last example I had to list out every prop explicitly go back title ingredients
image and instructions.
We can also actually write it this way.
So the key all specify here and then for the rest of the values I can use the rest.
Operator dot dot dot are which basically takes out all the keys and the values from that object and
passes them to my next component as props.
So then this component will get a prop of title and that value ingredients in this array instructions
and this string and finally image and spaghetti.
So this is a shorthand way of expanding our object.
Now I wouldn't recommend doing this all the time only when you know exactly what you're doing because
this can end up with some code they get sloppy when you end up passing props to a component that you
don't need to or mean to pass
now on to prop types.
So prop types are development time checker for your props.
What I mean by development time is they only work when your app is running in development mode.
So when you have your react to app running in production prop types will do nothing but in development
it's very useful for checking any mistakes you may make in your code and what Propp types do is they
specify requirements for your props.
For users of that component.
Let's start off with the installation.
So the first thing I'll do is NPM install dash dash save prop types prop types used to be part of the
re-act library itself.
But now it's a separate package so we have to install it.
And this is an example of Propp types.
So the same component that we saw earlier the ingredient list.
Let's say we don't want to provide a default parameter of an empty array anymore because it doesn't
make sense to render this component without some data.
So in this example rather than give a default Propp of an empty array we're saying that this ingredient
array must be an array and it must be an array of strings and that array is required.
So if you don't meet any of those checks if the ingredients data that you pass in is not an array.
And if that array doesn't have strings and if that array is not present then you'll get a warning in
the console.
And that warning again will do nothing in production but it's a nice useful thing to have when you're
in development environment because it can catch a lot of bugs.
You don't mean to introduce.
So again prop types are just for development.
But I think super handy and there's lots more to learn with Propp types.
But I'm going to let you explore that on your own.
So over here we've got the Propp types stocks from react.
I'd suggest reading through this.
There's a lot of good information about all the different Propp types you can specify.
You can generally specify any type of props and any sort of combination of required or not required
with all these properties.
So take a look at it.
The URL for that one is Facebook.
Get her bio slash re-act docs slash type checking with Propp types such as CMO.
So I'll end the video by saying Go check out that your El read about it.
And next up we're going to talk about our recipe app again.