So this will be a super quick video.
All they want to do is talk about how we respond with Jason.
Our goal here is to build a baseline on API.
So how do we actually respond with Jaison.
The answer is pretty simple actually an express resod send is dynamic depending on the content we send.
So if we're passing a string it will render this or respond as h Timo.
But if we pass in a javascript object like let's say the message is.
Hi from J.
Yes object.
Something like that and I restarted the server.
I refresh if I go to our slash or route route notice it's treated as Jason.
I have the Chrome extension Jase on view so it makes it a little prettier.
But this is Jason here.
So if we provide an object to rest that send it to the Send method it will convert it to a string and
then send that as japes on.
But there's also a red dot Jay sun method which will do the exact same thing in this case.
If I restart shouldn't notice any difference.
Yep nothing different.
And that's actually because in the red does send the source code.
It actually calls presta Jaison.
So send is sort of the parent that in its source code has a check that says OK I passed an object if
I was then pass it down to the J method which in turn I believe calls Jase on that string of phi and
then responds with Content-Type Jaison.
Anyway so you could use dot sand or dot Jaison.
I like to use Jason because it's more explicit that this is Jason even though it doesn't really matter
as long as we're passing in in objects like this.
The only thing I would add if we passed a string like this rest and this let's do data.
A bunch of numbers and I send that restart our server.
Notice that it's not treated as Jason and that's because it's not just on it's actually edged him out
because I use send and send the text strings.
So it assumes that sieged him out.
But if I passed the exact same thing.
Let me just change this to Jason.
It's a string containing an object.
But this will treat it as J song it might be hard to tell.
But if we use postman which if you're not familiar with it it's a really nice utility that helps you
make and inspect requests.
So if I send a request right now using redstart Jaison instead of our express app we get content type
is application slash Jaison.
And if I go back and change it back teres does send restart and I send the same request the same you
or I get request this time it says text but each time.
So bottom line I like to use that Jaison it's more explicit that this is Jason that you're responding
with even if you can get by with send.