Welcome back.
In a previous video we saw that when the new keyword is used a property is added to the object created
from the constructor function called Dunder proto.
This property links to the prototype property of the constructor function.
But what value does this prototype property have.
The prototype property is an object which can have methods and properties placed on it.
These methods and properties are shared and accessible by any object that is created from the constructor
function.
When the new keyword is used in this example where adding a property on the prototype called is instructor
and setting the value to be true.
Now all of our objects that have been created from the constructor using the new keyword have access
to the is instr. property.
But how in the world did that happen.
We added a property on the person that prototype object and all of a sudden two seemingly non-related
objects have access to it.
The answer lies in Dunder Protel.
Since these objects both have a link to person that prototype they can both access anything inside of
it.
This is actually the exact way that javascript finds methods and properties on objects and what we have
just described is something called the prototype chain.
Let's talk a bit more about that.
We just saw that when we added a property to the person that prototype object it was accessible from
objects created by that constructor function using the new keyword.
We then said that the reason why this was possible was because of the way that javascript looks for
methods and properties.
Let's see an example.
I'm going to make a variable called our and set it equal to an empty array.
What I actually did was shorthand for writing new array.
I used a built in constructor to javascript called array and made a new object from it.
We also know in javascript that our arrays have a method called Push which adds something to the end
of the array.
But where is this push method defined.
And how does javascript know how to find it.
The answer is in Dondre proto.
Let's cancel that the are the are variable and we see all that this object has a property called once.
But where does the push method come from.
Well let's examine what the Dungarpur photo of this variable is.
It is in fact the array prototype.
We can prove that by showing that our dog Dunder pro triple equals a radar prototype returns true.
So the way the javascript finds methods and properties is by looking at the object and if it cannot
find the method or property you're looking for it goes to that objects donder poda.
This actually keeps happening until the property or method is found and if it is not found javascript
returns undefined.
We can see this even further with another example in javascript.
Every object has a method called has own property which accepts a parameter and returns true if the
object has that property.
But where is this method located.
Let's take a look at our variable with cons. daddy.
You can just type Diyar as well.
Doesn't seem to be here.
So what does javascript do.
It goes up the prototype chain and finds the next Dunder Prato.
We can then see that the next donder POTO is the object prototype.
And here is where that method is found.
To recap we analyze how javascript finds methods and properties using the prototype chain.
We saw how javascript will look at an object and see if the method or property you're looking for exists
and if not it will go to that object's Dunder Kroto and repeat that until there is not another under
protest in the next video.
We'll talk more about the value of the prototype property and practice with an exercise season.