CodePipeline connects a lot of different resources in AWS,
and to run a demo pipeline, there are a few resources we need to create.
In this video, we're going to do just that.
We need to create a CodeCommit repository for our source code
to live and be connected to CodePipeline.
Then we need to create an Elastic Beanstalk application and
environment for our pipeline to deploy to.
Let's start with the CodeCommit repository.
The demo code for this course can be found either in the exercise
files here in the Pluralsight course or in GitHub.
Get the code however you like.
We first need to create a repository in CodeCommit that a source
action in CodePipeline can be connected to.
We'll have this set up so whenever we push new code to the repository,
our demo pipeline will begin execution.
So let's create the CodeCommit repo.
In the AWS console, go to the CodeCommit dashboard.
Click the Create repository button.
For the repository name, let's name it hbfl.
There's no need to give it a description or tags.
Now click Create.
The repo has been created, but there's no code there yet.
We need to push the code from our local folder with
the demo code up to the repository, and to do that,
we need to configure access from our local machine to the repository in AWS.
If you've used popular source control options like GitHub before,
CodeCommit has a little bit more complexity.
For command line authentication to CodeCommit,
you won't be using the username and password you use to log into AWS,
but instead a special username and password created
specifically for the Git connection to CodeCommit.
This will be configured at the user level,
and then we'll give IAM access to the user for CodeCommit.
Before we go further, there are a couple of prerequisites.
First, you need to have a non‑root user in your account.
You don't need to be logged in as that user,
just as long as they've been created.
We can't configure access to CodeCommit for a root user.
Next, make sure you have Git installed at your command line.
You can get information on how to install it for your
platform here at the Git website.
Now in your AWS console, go to the IAM dashboard.
We'll follow a best practice and create a group with the
access to CodeCommit that we want.
Go to Groups and then click Create New Group.
Let's name the group hbfl‑code‑committers. Now click Next Step.
There are two ways to go with the policies here.
We could give the group full access to CodeCommit,
or we could only give them access to the HBFL repository.
Now in a real‑world setting,
I would restrict it to the HBFL repository access only.
But for this demo project, let's just give the group full access to CodeCommit.
In the search box type awscodecommit and select the
policy titled AWSCodeCommitFullAccess.
Now click Next Step and then Create Group.
We need to add the user you've selected to the hbfl‑code‑committers group,
so click on the group we just created.
On the Users tab, click the Add Users to Group.
Select the user you want to give access to CodeCommit, and then click Add Users.
Now our user has permission to access CodeCommit. Next is to
create CodeCommit credentials for them.
You can click on this hyperlink to go straight to the user
details for the user you added to the group.
On the Security credentials tab halfway to the bottom,
you should see a section titled HTTPS Git credentials for AWS CodeCommit.
This is where you can generate a username and password for the user to
access CodeCommit. Click the Generate credentials button.
The password that's generated will only be visible right now,
so either copy it into a text file, or you could just
download the credentials as a file as well.
Now, move over to your command line and navigate to
the root of the demo project.
Run the command, git init to ensure Git is configured for the folder.
Now we'll add the AWS remote to be able to push code to CodeCommit. First
we need the remote URL for our repo. In your browser, go back to the
CodeCommit repo we created. In the top‑right corner, click the Clone URL
drop‑down and select Clone HTTPS.
This will copy the Git URL to your clipboard, so go back to your command line.
Enter the command git remote add aws, and then a space, and
then paste the Git URL that you copied.
Now run that command.
This is going to create a new remote called aws that you can push to.
Now let's go ahead and do that.
So first,
create a commit with the command git commit ‑am "first".
When that's finished running, push the commit up with the
command git push aws master.
This'll prompt you for a username first, so copy over the
username that was created with those credentials.
Then it'll ask you for a password, so copy over the password.
Once you enter both of those,
your code should upload to the CodeCommit repository.
Now we just need to create the Elastic Beanstalk application and environment.
I've already created a CloudFormation template that'll do that for you,
which should be much quicker. Since you're in your command line,
just run this long command that I have here,
which is going to create the Elastic Beanstalk stack with CloudFormation.
Once it's done, an Elastic Beanstalk application with the name hbfl,
and environment named prod will have been created.
These are all the resources we need created for our pipeline, so in the next video, we're going to create the pipeline itself.