Let's build our first pipeline with CodePipeline.
In this video, we're going to build a simple pipeline with two stages.
The first stage, as required by CodePipeline,
will contain a source action that pulls in code from
that CodeCommit repository we created.
Then that action will output the source code as an output artifact.
The next stage will just have one build type action that uses
CodeBuild to install our application dependencies and build
the client code with webpack.
The demo project for this course is the new web experience for Hamster Ball
Fantasy League that Emma and her team are developing.
All of the basic functionality is already completed,
and only the pipeline needs to be built out.
Go to the CodePipeline dashboard in your browser,
then click on the Create pipeline button.
First we'll name the pipeline.
Enter hbfl here.
AWS will prepopulate a name for a new service role to be
created specifically for this pipeline.
It'll also attach all the necessary policies for the role.
If you had an existing role you wanted to use,
this is where you'd attach it,
but we're just going to use the AWS‑created one in this demo.
Now if you expand the Advanced settings section,
you'll see you can define a custom S3 bucket for the Artifact store or
change the encryption key used for those artifacts.
The defaults here are fine for us, so go ahead and click Next.
Now we need to add a source stage.
This is a requirement for all pipelines, which is why you can't skip it.
In the drop‑down, you can see the available providers.
This list has actually grown in the past couple of years as AWS releases new
services and adds functionality for third‑party providers.
Select AWS CodeCommit.
Now you'll have some new prompts.
Click into the Repository name prompt,
and it will open an autocomplete drop‑down.
If you only have a few repos in CodeCommit,
then you should see hbfl here without having to type it in.
Select hbfl.
Now we need to select which branch in the hbfl repo that
this source action will actually pull from.
Click into the input box and select master.
Now there are two detection options here for detecting changes,
using CloudWatch Events or polling for changes.
Polling was previously the only available option for
initiating a CodePipeline execution,
but now CloudWatch Events are the default and recommended method.
Leave this selected and click Next.
Now we have the option to set up a build stage and action.
Click in the drop‑down,
and you'll see the available build providers. Select AWS CodeBuild.
The region will default to whatever region you're currently in, which is fine.
Now we have to designate a CodeBuild project to run here,
but we haven't actually built one yet,
so we can use this Create project button to build that, so click it.
This will open a new window to create this new project.
Let's name it hbfl‑build. No need for a description. And
then next we'll define the environment that we need for our
CodeBuild project to run on.
We're going to use a managed image,
and we'll just use a regular version of AWS Linux. In the Operating
system drop‑down select Amazon Linux 2. In the Runtime drop‑down select
Standard. And then and the Image drop‑down, select the option using the
x86 architecture that ends in 2.0.
The rest of these options are fine as is. Now, CodeBuild uses
build commands to know what to do. It runs them.
I've already created a buildspec YAML file,
which is in the HBFL source code,
and we can use that to actually build our project, so
leave the box that says Use a buildspec file selected.
Buildspec.yml is the default name,
so we don't actually need to define a special name for it here.
The default CloudWatch logs is fine for us.
And now that we've defined the environment and what needs to run for the job,
go ahead and click the Continue to CodePipeline button.
After some time,
the popup will close, and the job we just created will
be populated in our build action.
Now we can click Next to continue.
Here's where we could add a deploy stage,
but we're just going to skip this for now and add one in a later video in this
module, so click the Skip deploy stage button and then Skip.
Finally, here are all the details of the pipeline we configured.
If everything looks good,
go ahead and click Create pipeline. And now your pipeline is
complete, and it'll kick off its first execution.
You can watch it in real time, as the UI will update as the execution proceeds.
And when it's completed,
it will have pulled your code from the CodeCommit repository and then built it on CodeBuild in that build action.