Building code and deploying it to production as soon as
code is pushed to a repo sounds great, but let's be honest,
no one writes perfect code,
and it's important to test an application before it goes to production.
Luckily,
we can also use CodePipeline to run our automated tests before deployment.
If any tests fail, then the code won't be deployed and we can fix the issue.
Let's start by adding a test action.
You may remember that I mentioned in a previous video that
stage transitions do add some latency.
Because of this, I want to add the test action to the existing build stage.
So first, let's go to the hbfl pipeline.
Click the Edit button in the upper right‑hand corner. On the build stage box,
click the Edit stage button.
Here we have the option to either add testing as a
parallel action or as a serial action.
We want to test the built application that's going to be deployed,
so let's set it up to run after the build action.
Click the Add action group button under the build action.
We'll call this action test.
The action provider will be under the test section, and select AWS CodeBuild.
Then for the input artifacts, we want to select the BuildArtifact.
Now we need to create a new CodeBuild project to run our tests.
Click on the Create project button.
We'll name this one hbfl‑test.
We're going to go with the same environment as our build project.
Select Amazon Linux 2 in the Operating system drop‑down.
Then in the Runtime drop‑down select Standard,
and in the Image drop‑down, select the one with x86 ending in 2.0.
Then scroll down to the Buildspec section.
I've already created a buildspec file for this testing job,
but we do need to define the file name here,
since it's not going to be the same as the default
one we used in our build step.
In the Buildspec name field, enter buildspec_test.yml,
and it'll run the correct one.
Now scroll to the bottom and click Continue to CodePipeline.
Back in the action creation screen, we don't need to change anything else,
so go ahead and click Done.
Then click Save and then Save again.
And now our pipeline will run automated tests before deploying.
Let's try out the newest incarnation of our pipeline.
Click the Release change button and then Release.
I'll speed my video up here and then uh, uh, oh, no.
Okay, um, looks like our pipeline execution failed.
Well, that wasn't supposed to happen.
Uh, well, let's make this a good learning experience.
You can see the entire build stage failed,
and inside the build action succeeded, but the testing action failed,
the one that we just added.
We should figure out what went wrong in this testing action.
This Details link will take us to the specific CodeBuild job
execution that failed so we can troubleshoot it.
So go ahead and click that and then click Link to execution details.
Now, here are all the details.
We're most interested in the logs portion here.
If we scroll to the bottom, let's see, ah, yes, okay.
So looks like the test that I put in to fail on purpose and give
us a chance to troubleshoot failed as expected.
Well, we can fix that.
But let me quickly explain what we're looking at.
Whenever your CodeBuild job runs, it outputs a lot of things.
These logs are all saved in CloudWatch,
and the first thousand lines are visible in the CodeBuild execution details.
You can see CodeBuild is very explicit about what phase it's in,
any output from commands you run and why the job failed,
if it did.
This is really good info if you're trying to figure out why a failure happened.
Now let's fix that test failure.
Open up your code editor with the demo project and go to the
handlers folder and open the hamster.test.js file.
Comment out lines 8 or 11 to disable the failing test.
Now save the file, switch over to your command line,
and we're going to commit that change with the
command git commit ‑am "fixed test".
Now run that, and then we're going to push that commit up to CodeCommit,
which is going to kick off the pipeline by running
the command git push aws master.
If you switch back over to your pipeline detail,
you can watch it in real time as the pipeline runs again.
This is a good time to mention that when the test action failed,
the pipeline did not continue.
That's perfect,
because you don't want to deploy code to production that has failing tests.
Now the test action has passed,
and our code update is being deployed to Elastic Beanstalk.
Unit tests are great,
but the gold standard of testing is integration tests,
where tests are run on a live environment.
If you wanted to do something like that with CodePipeline,
you'd ideally want to deploy your built code to a testing environment first
and run some integration tests against that environment.
Then, if those tests pass,
you'd deploy that same built code to a production environment. Here's basically what a CodePipeline with that setup would look like.