They're welcome to the next video.
So in this video I would really like to do spend a couple seconds introducing myself as well as introducing
blue.
This is our course teej.
You'll see her pop up a couple of times in the course hopefully you don't have a problem with cats anyways.
So my background really is that I've been teaching people to program in person for the last five or
so years I've been teaching a web development bootcamps in the San Francisco Bay area pretty much nonstop.
So if you're not familiar with who camps where did all the camps that is the way they typically work
is that there are three to six month long programs where students basically commit their lives for that
duration to learning to cope and nothing else.
It's a very very intensive program.
We take students who have zero programming experience all the way up to the point where they get web
developer jobs.
So really rewarding work.
I fell in love with teaching five or seven years ago and recently I decided to try my hand at taking
my in classroom approach and trying to bring it online.
So this is my second course and this course as you know is on my ass.
Q Well it's kind of the next logical step to teach online.
So I used to teach this in person as well.
I'm now trying to take my curriculum and bring it to the classroom on Monday.
All right.
So that's enough about myself.
If you have any questions if you're curious or you're actually interested in in person bootcamps you
have questions.
Absolutely reach out to me.
Send me a message or post a question on the discussion boards.
All right.
See you in the next video.