Either Welcome to the next section.
So this section is really important.
It's where we actually start talking about code.
It's where we install everything.
And by the end you'll be running your own sequel commence.
So some big things we're doing to start off we're just going to talk about what makes something a database
what makes a database compared to.
I don't know just a programming language.
What's the difference.
And then we talk about the difference between sequel as well and Maia's.
Q Well a really common question and something that's basically fundamental to all databases are all
relational databases at least and then from there we're going to move into installing stuff.
Really important step for this course.
You'll install my Esky well get it up and running.
And by the end of this section for some of the challenges and exercises you'll be running your first
bit of my ask you all code.
So nothing crazy we're not working with any you know complex data yet.
We will be but not yet.
We're starting off nice and easy.
Just some simple commands but still something.
So by the end of the section we'll be doing that.
All right let's get going.