So in this video we're going to talk about one of the more common questions that comes up early on which
is what is the difference between my ask her will and as well or I usually just say sequel.
But what's the difference between these two.
Obviously sequel is contained in the name of my essay.
Well what's the significance of that.
So let's start off with discussing sequel which stands for structured query language.
So the sequel is the language that we use when we talk to our databases.
It's the way that we interact and access the data update data delete things and basically manipulate
the data in our databases.
It's the language we use so it's how we do things like find all users.
Now what I'm showing you here is not actual sequel code you'll see that in just a second.
These are just humanised versions.
Find all users who are 18 years old.
Add a new user with username jumbo Jim or if you want to get crazy.
Delete every single user.
So these are the sort of things that we use sequel to do.
So we write these lines which are called queries structured query language.
And once we hit enter or once we run that sequence code it's executed and it goes off and it talks to
our database and it does it for us.
So if you are curious what it looks like here's a really quick one line preview.
The English version find all users who are 18 or older is translated into this select star from users
where age is greater than or equal to 18 semi-colon.
So hopefully that actually seems pretty straightforward.
Now we're going to dive into a sequel.
All throughout this course you don't need to worry about this exact statement.
What's important though is that you can see there is a special syntax we use and that this query here
is going to be sent off to interact the database somewhere.
So the next point I want to make is that when we work with my AS Well we're actually writing sequel
all the time.
So my S Q Will is what we talked about earlier.
A database management system and there's a bunch of them out there.
Here's some common ones.
Post gresse sequel light Oracle.
Those hundreds of others and there's dozens of popular ones but hundreds of them all over the world
that maybe aren't as popular.
So all of these ones here that I've highlighted use as Cuil or sequel.
That doesn't mean every database ever does.
But what are called relational databases do.
And we'll talk more about that later when we discussed tables.
But for now the point I want to make is that as well it's not unique to my school or to postscripts.
That's why they all have this as Cuil in their name.
They share this language so structured query language sequel is a standard basically that these relational
database management systems like my Escuela implement.
So it's kind of a lot of jargon and terminology again but the main takeaway is that when we use something
like my Eskil will actually be writing sequel all the time.
So here's an example of what a line of sequel code looks like to do the exact same thing in my sequel
database and a postgresql database.
Here's the my as well.
And here's the post press and hopefully you notice they are identical.
Both of these are different database management systems.
They have differences to them but they both use as well.
You will be writing as well when you interact with these databases.
So just to hit that home there are slight differences in the syntax.
They are not identical but they are very very similar.
Oh and I'd better not forget to mention the sequel standard.
So the way that this whole thing works is that there is a standard for how sequels should work.
It's kind of it's actually written down.
You can read it online and all these different database management systems basically are tasked with
implementing that standard in their own database and making it work and they deviate sometimes a little
bit.
But for the most part they're very very similar.
So the two takeaways here.
One is that once you learn sequel it's really not that hard to switch to another database that also
uses sequel.
So you're learning my ask.
Well you could pretty easily switch to postgresql or to sequel light with not a lot of time needed to
get up to speed.
And the second thing is that what makes databases or database management systems to be specific what
makes them unique are the features that they offer.
Not the sequel or the language itself.
So if we go back to this diagram all of these use as well but that doesn't mean that they're identical.
And yes you might write the same line of code to do the same thing here.
So what makes these different or the features that they implement things like.
How secure is one versus the other how.
How fast is it how much how big is the download.
How do user permissions work and on and on and on.
And we'll talk more about what those differences are when we get to a point where they actually make
a little bit more sense.
I don't want to just talk to you.
OK.
So this was about my ask Cuil versus sequel.
Sequel is structured query language it exists separately from my well and my well is a database management
system that implements as well.