Warning this video may contain extremely frustrating installation instructions for experienced developers
only it's advise that you install use in cloud 9 to avoid Nuvo period.
All right.
If you're still here after the stern warning I'll talk about how to install my ask you out on Windows.
Of course remember you will probably run into some sort of issue depending on your computer and what
you have installed already.
It can be difficult.
So that's why I really really really recommend that you use Clubine skip windows until the end of the
course.
OK that's enough of a broken record.
Let's get started.
So to install my ask you all on a PC you need to go to my s q l dot com and then click on the download
section and then click on community and other community.
You can actually click on any of these if you click on download what it's going to suggest for you if
you're a Windows user is that you actually use the Maia's installer rather than downloading things individually.
Basically it's a package that will help install a bunch of my Escuela things all at once that you may
or may not use that you may or may not need.
Make sure that you have the correct version selected depending on your architecture.
And click down.
And it looks like it starts downloading but it actually doesn't.
You have to click another button at the bottom.
No thanks.
Just start my download and then fast forward through this takes a little bit to download Panay on the
Internet.
But then once it's done all you want to do is open it up run the installer.
OK.
So then we have a couple of options.
We're going to select developer default and then click next and then depending on what you have installed
in the computer you may need to actually install some other requirements.
So I did hear.
So I basically had to go through a couple of times.
Double click click execute.
Wait for something else to go install.
In this case visual C++ and then I had to repeat that a couple of different times.
Now that will probably be different for you and your machine but then once it finishes click on execute
again.
And this will actually start the installation process.
So there's a bunch of components installing But once they're complete click next.
And then we move on to configuration and all we really care about is configuring the server.
So we'll click Next again.
Basically click next.
Another time we don't need to change anything.
And further another time.
Click next.
OK.
So we're now at the point where we need to decide on a root password for my as well.
So you can decide on whatever you like.
I just chose password the word password.
It's not a good password but I want to make it simple easy to remember.
So you type it in twice tells me that it's weak.
And then I'm also going to add a user here.
You don't have to do this.
I'm just going to make one with the name Colts and also the password will be password and then confirm
the password also tells me that it's weak and I'll click OK.
So really all that you need to do is remember whatever password you type for the root and then click
next and then we'll click Next one more time.
And then finally again will click execute and it will start to apply the configuration.
And it may take a moment or two.
Then once it finishes everything should be installed.
So I'll click Finish and then get out of here.
So that's how we install.
Next important thing is starting up the command line client which you can find just under my ass Q Will
command line client.
Click on it and then you'll need to enter your root password which in my case was Password.
And now we're able to actually type some code something like show databases which we haven't talked
about but you can type code in there.
You can also try typing things that aren't sequel and you'll see you get error messages but all that
we really need to care about is that we have the command line client up and running and we can type
stuff into it.