So as I mentioned we have a really quick activity now and the point here is to get you thinking about
data types and thinking in data types or in terms of data types.
So what I would like to do is draw or write or just think about a tweet table.
So modeling tweets If you're not familiar with Twitter that's going to be a tough one I guess.
But basically there are three things that need you to at least three things that I want you to model
and these are the columns.
So a user name.
So when someone tweets let's say I tweet in I have I don't actually use Twitter but if I had an account
and I call that coffee lover colt I mean that's just terrible.
But if I did it would need to be maximum 15 characters long.
So how do you specify that.
What data type is it and the content of the tweet.
Whatever the tweet is itself can't be more than 140 characters.
And then the number of people that have favorites that tweet basically like it or did it.
So you don't have to draw it out but if you want to draw it out in a tabular format and then fill in
some fake data or even real data that you find Go ahead and do that but just you know think about what
these data types are in terms of what we just learned.
And there's really only two choices that we saw.
So hopefully it's not too difficult.
So we'll be right back with a solution.
OK.
So let's start talking about the answer to we had user name which is a maximum of 15 characters that
would be a Vardar and you would put 15 nodes in parentheses to specify that it's no more than 15 characters.
Then we have content of the tweet max of 140.
It's very similar.
It's also var chards text.
But this time we restrict it at 140 characters.
Then we have favorites which is just a number.
So we use it and then hear some mock data that I did if you take a look we have cool guy who tweeted
My first tweet.
Now as one person who liked it or favorite it.
Then we have guitar queen who tweeted I love music.
Smiley face.
How endearing.
And we have 10 favorites on that.
And then lonely heart this sad guy or gal who tweeted still looking for love and that has zero favorites
because nobody wants to be depressed.
All right.
So next up we're going to see how to take the stereotypes and actually tell sequel or Maya's well how
to implement a table using those data tips.