All right.
So it's now your turn to give this a try and get some practice using the insert command.
So we'll be working with people this time.
You're going to create a new people table.
So actually this is going to combine both creating tables and inserting data.
So the table you need to define will have three columns.
First name that has a 20 character limit.
Last name also has a 20 character limit and age which is a number.
So once you've defined that table the next step is to insert your first person.
And for this person her first name is Tina.
Her last name is Belcher and her age is 13.
So once you inserted her make sure that you've done it correctly use that select command to see what's
happening.
Make sure she's in there the next person will be Bob Belcher who is 42 and it's up to you.
But I would like for you to try and answer this one using a different order for the values.
So if you had said first name come a last name come of age and the previous one maybe try last name
come age come first name doesn't make a lot of sense to do it that way but give it a shot just to prove
that you understand that the order matters.
And then lastly write one insert that will insert three different people at once and that will be Linda
Belcher who's 45.
Philip Fronde who's 38 and Calvin fish owner who is 70 so insert all three of those at once.
And go ahead and give it a shot.
And in the next video we'll have a solution.