All right.
So it's your turn to put some of this into practice with a single exercise.
It should be pretty quick.
All you need to do is define a single table.
So here are the demands.
Well the man sounds a little strong here the requirements define an Employees table.
So let's say we're a company trying to manage them.
Employees will definitely need more data than this to actually make it operational.
But for now this is all we need.
Seven different fields seven columns ID last name first name and middle name and then age and current
status.
And actually I can't count.
This is six.
So Id it's relatively self-explanatory.
It should be a number.
I'm not telling you the data types but you should know at this point what they are.
So a number that automatically increments it's mandatory so it can't be left off and it's a primary
key.
Last name and first name are both text which is in that data.
Again you need to use the actual term and then neither of them can be left blank either.
They're mandatory but middle name.
Well it's also text it isn't mandatory because not everyone has a middleman so we can leave that blank.
Then we've got age which is numeric and it is mandatory can be playing.
And finally current status which is essentially like their employment status if they're employed or
if they're fired.
And it should be mandatory so it can't be null.
But if no status is provided when something is inserted it should default to employed.
So we'll have two statuses employed and terminated or fired or something.
I guess turbinate is more professional.
And so it should just default to current status is employed if nothing is provided to insert.
OK.
So go ahead and define this table type it out.
Try running it to make sure it works and then try inserting some data as well to make sure that it works
ok.
If you want a solution have it in the next video.