They will come back.
If you're looking at my desk right now and you're asking wow why is there so much crud on it.
Well you're onto something.
This section is all about crud.
Yeah.
So crud is an acronym it stands for four things.
C R U N D.
Create.
Read update and delete.
And they are the four basic actions that we want to be able to do to our data.
So we've actually seen two components already.
We've seen how let's say we're working with users.
We've seen how to create users with the insert command we've seen how to read users take them back out
you know spill the milk out of the database.
That is the read section which we did with select.
Now we also are going to review more about select and insert.
But primarily we're going to see how to update and delete information.
So how do we change something in our database if we made a mistake or let's say a user change their
password they clicked forgot my password and they want to reset it.
We need to change it in the database and then delete.
Let's say every user decides to leave our site for some really bad reason we can delete him or her.
So that's the focus of this section.
We're going to have a ton of exercises because we're seeing a lot of commands and now that we have those
four commands in place we'll be able to go do a lot of stuff.
They're kind of the fundamental for things of any database or any data.
So tons of challenges coming up.
Look forward to that and I'll see you basically in the next section when I have to do another one of
these videos.
So you know it.