OK so before we see any new code or new commands I want to clean up the data that we currently have.
If you remember we kind of added a bunch of different cats databases of cats and cats 1 and Cat 2 and
Cat 3 and so on.
But I want to do is delete the original catch table and then we're going to remake it.
But with a few additions because our original cat's table was the most basic.
It only had name and age.
But I want to add some other data in like an ID that autoincrement and so on.
So basically we're just going to remake the cat table and add new data in.
So if you want to make a bit of an exercise out of this the first step would be to delete the catch
table.
So do that now and the command if you want to see it is drop table cat.
So let's do it.
Drop table cats.
There we go.
Now that we've dropped the table we want to recreate the table.
So this is what we want here.
We're going to have a cat ID integer not know autoincrement really have a name that Safar char a breed
that's our char as well and age that is an integer and cat ID is our primary key.
So if you'd like go ahead and type that out or just copy paste it in perfect.
Of course we could make sure it worked.
Describe cats.
There we go.
All right.
So the last step here is to add new data.
And I would like for you to have this same data because we're going to use it throughout the section.
There'll be a couple of activities and questions and it will be much easier if you have the same data
as me.
So we've got one two three four five six seven cats.
Each one has a name breed and age.
Some of them there's a couple of Maine Coons couple of Tabby's and a couple that have the same age which
we will use in just a little bit.
So copy this or if you're a masochist you can type it out paste it in perfect.
And now we have seven cats in our database.
Seven rows.
OK.
So now we've prepped our data.
We've deleted the original catch table remade new special cats table with some more interesting pieces
of data and then we've inserted data in there as well.
Awesome.
Next we're going to move on to talking about searching or reading data out.