All right.
So before we go any further we have a couple of quick exercises that are just going to test you basically
on what we just learned select and where.
So the first one I'd like you to write the sequel that will select the following.
And this is using our cats so the same data that we already had which is why I asked you to hopefully
you inserted the same cats.
Basically it's like all the cats but only get their ID and then the next thing I'd like you to do.
Of course you can post a video and do it and then move on when you're ready to the next question which
is right the sequel that will select the following.
Name hen breed only so we don't want the we don't want aids.
Just name and breed in that order for all of the cats.
All right.
And the next one is a little bit more complicated.
You'll need to combine both things we just learned the select expression and the WHERE clause.
So in this case you're going to only select the tabby cat.
So the cats that have breed equal to Tabby and we only want name and age.
And then finally this is a little bit of a challenge because I didn't show exactly how to do this but
hopefully you'll be able to figure it out.
We'll talk about it and answer video either way but hopefully it's not too difficult in this case.
What you're doing is selecting the instances where cat I.D. and age are the same.
So if I go back to the data here when I select all of them if you look here cat I.D. and age they're
not the same one in four to 10 but egg eggs.
Cat ideas for an egg is four years old and Jackson is has an idea of seven and is seven years old.
So how can you say like just those two and I don't want you to cheat.
Don't select based off of their name or their breed or something.
I want you to select where cat ID is the same as age.
And we only want I.D. and age as well.
OK solution video is coming up next.