All right.
So now we're talking about less than we just talked about greater than and greater than or equal to.
So this one should be much shorter.
In fact the total time that it will take will be less than the previous video.
So it works the same way although it does the opposite.
If you're familiar again just the less than bracket the angle bracket I think it's what they're called.
Just remember that.
So shift.
And then on most keyboards is a comma so we can do things like this.
So rather than selecting all books released after 2000 we just switch it to the less than sign in our
select star from books wherever released here is anything below the number 2000.
So if we try that select title and released year from books we do all of them.
And let's do our order by again released here just to make it easier to see where we have missing gaps.
OK.
So we want all of these to disappear or excuse me on all these disappear and only want to select these
five.
All we need to do is add in our where released here is less than 2000 And there we go.
OK.
So that's pretty much all say about it for now.
Along with that of course we have less than or equal to which works the same way that greater than.
Well it doesn't work the same way it works in the same way that greater than or equal to does.
So if I wanted to include the year 2000 for whatever reason I just need that equal sign after the less
than sign and now we get the same five books plus the one that was written in 2000.
Amazing Adventures of Kavalier and Clay.
That's pretty much it.
I will throw up a few exercises here if you want to try evaluating them and then moving on to some more
interesting and complex operators.
All right so I'm back here.
I typed up a couple of quick exercises.
Go ahead try these out.
I'll throw up that same graphic again and I'll be back in one second.
OK I'm back here.
So let's go through these quickly.
The first one is three less than negative 10.
Well I don't think so but let's verify.
You can see zero meaning false.
It's not is negative 10 less than negative 9.
Yes it is.
It's lower than negative 9 is 42 less than or equal to 42.
Ok need to add a space there.
And as you would expect we get yes we get one true because 42 is equal to 42.
Now on to the odd string ones it's the letter H.
Lowercase less than the letter P also lower case.
And if you remember to the last video of how this works H comes before p.
And they both lower.
So yes this should be true and it is OK.
So this final one is UPPER CASE Q less than or equal to lowercase q.
Well this should be reviewed from the last video because I remember that case doesn't matter.
So we see that yes indeed it is true.
Prickish Q is less than or equal to lowercase Q And if we get rid of the equal to this is basically
a duplicate of what we just said in the last video.
But I just want to hit this home that it is not lower it's not greater than they are equivalent.
Well that's a minus sign.
There you go.
They are equivalent.
As you can see we get true or 1.
OK.
Next up.
Moving on to much more exciting much bigger and important logical operators.