Hey welcome to the next section here.
This one we're continuing with our Instagram data and see if blue will do her trick again.
Blue can you get it.
Who is my adorable little kitty.
You can stand up like a human she's come so far just like you have come so far.
Yeah.
So we're working with Instagram data.
We set up the schema.
Now all we have left is to do stuff with it.
So the way this section works is rather than me giving you a bunch of tables you know showing you here's
the result I want.
We're going to do it a bit differently.
I'm going to ask you more of a real world's question like hey we're doing a sweepstakes.
How about we're doing a campaign email campaign to e-mail all of our inactive users and send them a
reminder that they should post.
So we need you to get all the active users e-mail addresses.
So something like that where it's kind of in real world terms not in the terms of a database like select
all users where blah blah blah but you'll have to translate it.
So we'll do things like that or will do things like hey we have a brand who's really pressuring us to
figure out what hashtags are the most useful way to generate generating the most likes and they want
to know what three hashtags they should use.
So then you'll have to go write the query to find that answer.
What are the best hashtags.
How do you know.
So hopefully that's exciting.
Trying to make it kind of a nice ramp off to the real world just for the data section.
And then after this like I said we have the web app portion of the course.
OK.
So lots of exercises all exercises and solutions in this section.
By.