Hey welcome back.
Very high energy because we're moving on to a very exciting portion of the course.
We've now seen how to take a database in my ass.
Q Well everything we know and combine it with a node file a single file that doesn't do.
I mean it depends on your impression of it.
It doesn't do a whole lot just inserts but it inserts 500 things are just pretty cool and they're all
randomly generated.
But that's not an application that's still useful for our application will be able to use that.
Just to recap the whole reason we're doing that is so that when we start up our application we have
some data in there.
We have something to work with rather than totally empty database or something that has two users.
We have 500 realistic randomly generated emails and created at dates.
OK.
So we've done that.
We have that.
Now we're moving on to the web application portion.
So remember this is join us our mailing apper waitlist app where there's a nice page with it looks style
that's nice it says join us in big letters.
It says how many users have currently joined.
And there's also a guarantee 100 percent.
It's not a cult.
And then there's a form at the bottom where you can actually enter your email to join the list.
So we have to get there.
We're going to start with the basics of a web app.
So just like we had to start with the basics of node we're now starting with the basics of building
web applications.
OK.
That brings us to something called Express.
So if you've taken the course or if you're familiar with node and you've used it in any web development
capacity you've probably come across the framework Express.
It's a Web development framework that helps us make applications faster.
So if you're not familiar with frameworks in 10 seconds what they are are tools libraries that are a
bit more complex a bit more controlling of how you write your code.
They dictate things for you.
You play by the rules but they help you make things faster.
So a web development framework helps you make Web sites faster.
There are iOS or game development frameworks that help you make games faster so they can limit your
freedom a bit but they empower you because they speed you up and they let it they let you focus on things
that matter.
So with all that said Express it's very simple a lightweight framework that allows us to do is once
we install it and included in a file we can very quickly make a web application.
So something like faker is a package that allows us to quickly get random data a very small kind of
feature that's it's useful but it's a small thing.
Express is a package that when you use it and install it it does a lot.
It sets up just a server for you it listens for incoming requests it figures out how to respond to requests.
It handles H-2 on CSSA in responding with that.
It figures out how to parse a response body all these things will go into but it does a lot.
So let's take a look.
Very quickly the documentation express J s dot com a fast and opinionated minimalist web framework for
no js.
As you can see you can just install it NPM install Express.
We'll talk about dash dash save in just a second.
And you can read more about it here.
Basically it provides a robust set of features for web applications.
It's light weight.
So what that means if I go over here to know yes frameworks is a site that I found it has a list of
some of the most popular Noad framework.
There are a ton of them out there because people love using frameworks for good reason.
They help you make things faster.
There's two categories that this person has categorized them into Sinatras like in rails like.
Basically this comes from Ruby.
These are two Ruby frameworks Sinatra and rails rails.
You might have heard of.
It's a bigger framework very popular in Ruby but it controls everything.
It's very strict.
Sinatra is much lighter weight meaning that you have more freedom to make decisions.
It's less opinionated which means that you can configure things how you want but also the advantage
of something like Rails is that you don't have to make decisions.
For example how to structure your files.
Where do I put my CSSA files in Rails.
You don't have a choice in Sinatra you have to decide.
So with that said there are all these frameworks for node.
EXPRESS Is the top one here that we're going to use but there are other ones there's sales and Gedi
or two that I've used.
Khoa I don't know if trench coat or Kellaway is one that's becoming popular now.
A lot of people are using too.
So anyway I'm just trying to point out here that there are a bunch of frameworks just like when I said
we could have used any language to talk to my ass.
Well we could use any node framework to make a web app where it happening to use Express.
OK.
So the first thing I'd recommend here is to look at the documentation for Express.
If you're curious if you haven't taken a course in it you're not familiar with it or you have never
worked with a web framework.
The documentation is pretty straightforward if you click on getting started.
You don't have to go through all of it.
But if we're actually going to do.
Hello world here's a simple app that we'll be making in just a moment but it has a nice can of walk
through using express how you write certain things with syntaxes and then there's a guide that much
more in depth.
And then there's a reference when you click on the API reference.
Make sure you're doing four point x.
The most recent and this is sort of like that.
Think of them I ask you all docs there's all these methods that we see over here and you can read about
them over here.
So we'll be referring back to these docs as we go through the course.
And for now that's where we'll leave off.
All I wanted to do in this video is introduce express tell you that it's a node framework show you the
Web site the documentation.
Then in the next video we're going install it and create our own first application.
First web app.