So why should you market your business on Pinterest.
Well essentially Pinterest is just another channel through which you can get in front of your potential
customers so you can drive traffic to your website and generate sales.
But there are a couple of unique things about Pinterest compared to other social media platforms so
I do want to really highlight those now and also give you some examples of how businesses are using
Pinterest successfully.
So the first thing to know is that Pinterest has over 200 million active monthly users.
And if we compare that to other social media sites out there we can see that Facebook's at the top here
with 2 billion.
Then we have YouTube then we have Instagram Twitter etc. and down here is Pinterest which comparatively
you would think of Pinterest is tiny.
Its not even worth my time but theres still 200 million active monthly users on Pinterest so it is a
massive audience there's a massive amount of people there.
And it's also not nearly as competitive as these other better well-known marketing channels so that
is a great reason to even be interested in Pinterest always where there's less competition is where
you want to be and in terms of the gender split on Pinterest.
A lot of first impressions are Pinterest is only for women but actually it's about 60:40 splash splish
And so even if you are a business that's more focused on males than Pinterest can definitely be a good
marketing channel for you as well.
Now to understand really how to use Pinterest as a business.
I think its first really important to understand how people actually use Pinterest.
Why did they even use Pinterest when they had all these other social networks out there.
And what I have here is a Pinterest profile of Lauren hunt Xander.
This is just a random person I don't know her but I found her profile and I think it does represent
very well why people would use Pinterest.
So she has a couple of boards here.
Boards are just a way to categorize her ideas and inside these boards.
You can see that they they have pins so these pins all they are are just images.
And then what happens in these pins is that you can see the link back to the original blog post her
site where there's more details on this.
So in this example we can see that Lauren here wants to create a dream has she creates a board so she
can categorize all those ideas together and then inside there when she searches Pinterest or is following
certain things that she likes then she just saves this to her board so that she has it there and then
she can always go back to the Web site to read more about it or to buy the product.
So the thing about Pinterest and why people really use it is that they're here to plan buy or do things
and that is very very different to say Facebook where there more there to just hang out with their friends
and catch up with news people on Pinterest are very proactive.
They really want to bring their ideas to life and they come to Pinterest in order to get the ideas gather
them together so that they can really visualize their ideas in a much better way.
So why is that good for businesses.
Well when you're dealing with very proactive people who want to see thing happen things happen in the
world.
You could say is a lot better than Facebook where people are very passive and they're just consuming
content.
And also in terms of you know what stage they're out in the buying process here Thorne for example for
a dream house she's very early on in the process of planning that idea.
And again that's something quite unique and it's something that actually Pinterest really sell as their
unique selling point for businesses to reach people early inspired them to act.
And that is also very different to say if you go to type into Google as a user they already know exactly
what they want whereas on Pinterest they don't know exactly what they want that and the paint they want.
So by having visual images of it here and catching their attention they go oh that's what I want.
They're going to add it to their board and that makes it very likely or at least more likely that they're
going to buy your paints or whatever in the future.
So hopefully now you understand why people use Pinterest.
It's really because they're looking for things to plan Byard do Karoubi even travel place want to travel.
Ideas for digital marketing that they want a group together that they might be using for later.
It could be weddings they're planning whatever they're really here.
They're very proactive people and they're very early on in the planning stage which is a great place
to catch them.
If you're a business now let's have a look at some actual businesses taking advantage of Pinterest then
as a marketing channel and driving a lot of traffic and sales.
And one of the biggest hands on Pinterest is Moria's seal.
It is an e-commerce store.
You can see they've gone over 900000 followers and their e-commerce store that sells handmade gifts
fashion home decor cetera.
Now what you can see that they've done here is created their own boards.
So really grouping together their different products etc..
And you can see here if we click in that these are actually just images from their e-commerce store
highlighting their products.
And if we click in here and visit this some bringing back to the e-commerce check page.
So I mean it's pretty cool for an e-commerce store as well.
They're just showing their products here.
Someone like Lauren she like those earrings they she could add them to her fashion board and maybe go
ahead and buy them later on.
So the key thing is for a business you're actually not creating a lot of new content.
All you're doing is making your content available on Pinterest so that people can address and create
their ideas so you can see here that these this is not new content that the e-commerce store has created.
These are just the images of their products that they've organized on to pit Pinterest into certain
categories and added a little bit more information about them here as well.
So that was an e-commerce store I think is a perfect fit for Pinterest.
And let's have a look.
In another type of site now as well.
So this is a blog it's called pinch of yawm it's a food blog.
And you can see what she's done here is just make sure that they have eye catching visuals here.
But essentially it is just going to be recipes that are on their size.
And if we click into this we can see if people want to make this then they come back to the Web site
to read the full recipe here.
So it's a great platform actually for getting people back to your site because you're only giving them
a visual preview of what you can help them do.
And then they have to go back to your site to actually find out how to do it.
And so it's a great way to just redirect traffic from Pinterest funnel it back to your Web site.
Now I do want to give you one other example.
And this is actually geared towards males.
So come back to this.
So this is a this is a Pinterest a can called beer to Holick obviously geared towards males.
They are helping those who want of a better beard solve problems and solutions guides for beard care.
Beard from a woman's perspective and much more.
So this is actually a Web site and they're actually an e-commerce store as well to sell products for
beards.
So if we look at beard grooming tips you can see that they have the images here are six reasons why
you should be using beard oil a quality beard oil.
And then you can see the article here as well which just brings it back to their Web site.
So very good way to get traffic back to your site.
Just using Pinterest and all you really need are those good visuals to catch people's attention.
So one final thing that you can do if you're still not sure if Pinterest is going to be good marketing
channel for your business now or in the future has just come in and use the Pinterest search bar so
you can type in anything here like say yoga and actually you can see yoga for men before and after pants
girl flexibility work and weight loss.
This search bar on Pinterest is actually something as well that makes it very unique compared to other
social networks.
Now remember Pinterest is really designed to help people plan and do things and buy things.
So that's why this search bar is extremely good and they have even they suggest a lot of the popular
terms that people are searching for.
So as a business you can come in here and just look at what they are suggesting and these are posts
that you can definitely put up in order to get ranked in the Pinterest search engine here.
And the cool thing is is that if you rank in the search engine here on Pinterest you can be liking Google
getting traffic for that term.
Back to your Web site.
For weeks months or even years.
So thats another cool thing about Pinterest is that it has that long term potential as a marketing channel
because unlike Facebook where it's filtered out after a day or two you can be appearing in this Pinterest
search engine for a long long time and that's another great reason to get in on Pinterest.
So to wrap it up why should you be using Pinterest as a marketing channel.
Well it's less competitive than others.
It's also very proactive people who want to get things done.
You can get them early on in their decision making process.
And it also has an amazing search engine which means that your content can really appear at the top
of the rankings for weeks months or even years which gives you a lot of long term Web site traffic and
sales.
So hopefully that has convinced you that Pinterest is a great marketing channel and at least clarifies
for you why you should be using Pinterest.