In this video you are going to learn how to create a page for your company on Cura.
And the advantage of doing this is that all of the questions about your company will be grouped under
one page.
And it also then enables people to follow your topic or company so that they can be notified any time
any question is added by your company so you can see here for you to me.
They have 37000 people following their topic or company.
And then any time the questions us about you to me all of these 37000 people will be notified which
kind of keeps that company in the brand in the minds of these people.
And also if you create your own page then you can follow the topic and make sure you're being notified
every time as somebody creates or has a question on your company.
So to do this it's actually very simple.
What you need to do is actually create a topic for your company so it's not really like creating a page
that you go and set it up like a Facebook page.
All you really need to do is create a topic so what.
To get started what you want to do is search for your company name so I will just say
my awesome site.
Now if I search for that there's no results for that.
So what I can do then is otic question and say something like is my awesome site good.
So I just really want to otic question first.
And then what I can do is edit the topics
and what I want to do is create a new topic.
So I'm creating this topic I know I can click on.
So what I can do is I've created essentially a topic around my company name and now any time that somebody
mentions this I say is my awesome site good.
How much does my awesome site cost etc..
Just answer your your company name there.
Then the person who's asking the question will have that option to this topic.
Then that question will appear here under this company page or topic.
So it's a little bit of a new way to create a page I guess on cure a little bit different than maybe
something like Facebook but the idea is still the very same.
You create a topic every time someone adds a topic to a question.
The question will appear here under your page if you follow your own topic then you will get notified
every time there's a question.
And it also enables people to follow your company and keep updated with questions other people have
a baddish So that is how you create a page for your business on.
Q Where once again is very simple.
Search for your company.
If it's not there out a question and then create a topic to make sure that your brand name is the topic
created.
So go ahead and test that for yourself.
If you want to create a page for your business on q or.