Once you set up your group or groups then you can create your ads.
Now these are the ads is actually what's going to appear in Google either on mobile or you can see on
desktop here.
And so we really want to create these so they grab the searchers attention and that they're going to
click through.
Now as they recommend here you should create at least at least three ads that closely relate to the
theme of your keywords and the reason that you'd want to do that is so that you can test out a couple
of different headlines descriptions and see which one really performs the best.
And when this video is set up want to really walk you through the process of it and you can go ahead
and create a couple of extra ones for yourself.
So the first thing that you want to put in here is the final you are l and this is really the landing
page or the page your Web site that you will be sending people to.
So for example for me that could just be my web site for Slash the product page name and you can see
that this is being updated in here.
Next thing that we want to put in is our headline which is appearing here headline one headline too
and the description that's appearing underneath and this can be a little bit intimidating to do.
What I would really recommend is rather than reinvent the wheel just come into Google really tie being
your product or service and just have a look at the ads already appearing for that underneath some of
your keywords.
What you really want to do is have a look at some of these ads and really have a look.
What are the headlines that they use.
Are they catching your attention.
Are they really.
Do they really make you want to click through.
What are some of the things that are really catching your attention.
81 percent were promoted after the quarter so that's a pretty good metric.
I'm not sure if I could use that personally because I don't measure that but there are some interesting
things here.
Now oftentimes you're not going to CNN that may be perfect so what you can do is look at a similar product.
And for me for example this could be if I don't see any ads that I like here and I don't find any good
headline ideas I could do something like.
Type in ethical hacking.
Of course online.
So essentially it's still an online course but it's a different product.
And by just changing the search terms slightly I can look at how other similar products but different
topics are being advertised.
So now I can see a couple of better headlines that I could use for myself.
So I like this layout here.
I'd say headline one marketing course.
So it is a great idea to put your product name directly in the headlines that when people look at this
ad they can go.
Yep that's exactly what I was looking for.
Now you've got the headline too.
I think this is pretty good.
Enroll today and get 20 percent off.
So roll today.
Get 20 percent off.
So again no need to reinvent the wheel.
Just use what's already there.
And then what you can also do is really you can see that there's 30 characters here that I can use for
this headline too.
And you can think about how could I use those last six characters to maybe squeeze more at that.
Then you have your display of the world so you can see that I've put in my new world that I want to
send people to and I can really decide I can really just take this and put that in there.
And that can appear here in the search terms and you can see that this is a little bit too long.
So what I can do is am marketing course maybe just leave it at that.
So there I had to play around with it a little bit to try and make sure it fit it in.
And also you can come and look at the other guys are setting this up as well and see if you can fit
it in the same way as then.
So it can be a little bit tricky to fit everything in.
But you can just play around with it until you do.
Now here in the description we've got 80 characters to play with.
So let's come back to some other odds and see if we can get a couple of ideas here.
So what I could put in is learn digital marketing
let's say go from beginner to advanced.
I think that would be pretty appealing to people.
Maybe something like 30 day money back guarantee could include and that's pretty much hitting the a
character limit so you can play around with that as well.
To really find one that's good and then you can go ahead and cook.
Done.
And then you're ready to go ahead and click save and continue.
And then if you come up to odds and extensions you can actually see or add here and you'll see that
status is under review.
So this won't go live automatically.
Actually Google needs to manually approve the ad that you put out and that can easily take one day.
And of course for your campaign to go life you do need to add your billing information on Tuesday that
you can come up here and then come to Bill billing and payments and then you can re out a payment method
in there in order for your campaign to go live.
And that really wraps up the process to set up your Google Adwords campaign.