In this video you're going to learn how to search for potential clients on Twitter.
And this is something you can uniquely do on Twitter and it is a great way to win business directly
from a social network.
So what you want to do is come up to the Twitter search bar and type in I need and whatever it is the
product or service that you deliver.
So for example if I was a web designer I'd type in I need a web site on what I'm really searching for
here are people that have tweeted hey I need a web site I want a web site.
You can see I want a web site.
I need a dope graphic designer.
I need a very good web site designer.
It's urgent.
I need a website designer.
Scrolling down I need someone to help me create a web site so you can see that there are a lot of people
tweeting out and asking for help.
So what you can do is reply to these tweets and let them know that you are a web designer and that you
can really help them.
And one thing to note is that you will probably be other people using this strategy.
So if we click in to the replies here we can actually see someone has responded already a web design
company.
Good evening we are an experienced digital agency and can handle your project.
Here is our portfolio and what type websites you want.
So they have already use this strategy to respond.
And even if I scroll down a little bit you can see some other responses.
So the key thing here is that when you reply to these to stand there from the competition you need to
give something unique in your message that's going to stand out.
So Message me please.
That's not going to work.
You can you can probably imagine that this person just ignore that straightaway.
This person definitely would have caught my attention.
But maybe they could even be more specific like we can get started straight away and have it done in
a week where you can do it for less than most Web sites we do for less than $200 something like that
that is going to really kick off the conversation and get you to stand out from any other messages that
pop up.
So having a great response that really communicates your unique selling proposition is a way to win
business.
With this strategy Don't say just message me please.
That is not going to get the client excited.
Now another way that you can actually win business in a less competitive way is not to look at the top
tweets but do actually come over and look at the latest tweets.
So the reason there's quite a lot of comments on these views because these are the top tweets.
But if we come to latest tweets then we can see the people who have said I need a web site or including
some of those words you can see this is only seven minutes ago.
Nobody has counted on this.
So that is something that you could just drop in and comment on straight away.
I need a brilliant Web site.
OK.
Again you could probably comment on that you'd have to read all these carefully to see what they say.
Now you can see that some of these tweets just include our Web site they don't see I need a web site.
And so if you want to narrow your search what you can do is put these parentheses around the search
and now you are only going to see tweets that have that exact phrase in it.
I need a web site so you can see the end here.
I need a web size I need a web site you could probably reply to that person straightaway.
I need a website who can get the job done.
DME etc. so it's a it's a way by filtering for the latest tweets and even the tweets that have that
exact phrase in it.
Again you can get those people and identify them who maybe aren't appearing in those top searches.
Now you can also search for not just on need web site but also maybe i need a web designer.
And so changer in the phrase is a little bit in order to really find what you need.
Another strategy as well is to look for people who are frustrated with an existing solution.
So what you could do is using those parents.
Again look at type in hate Wake's.
So what we're going to find here.
I'm thinking about switching from weeks to WordPress plus because I [REMOVED] hate wakes.
So what you could do here is really reply and say hey Katie if you want to if you want help with that.
It's very easy to switch from weeks to WordPress.
We can help you get it done in one day and you wouldn't lose any of your content.
Interested to learn more and then they might say yes and then you could say OK let's jump over to email
etc..
So looking for frustrated customers or frustrated customers.
Another solution is a great way to identify any clients that you can really poach on if they're really
frustrated.
Then they are really going to be looking for a solution.
Today I was reminded why I absolutely hate Wick's.
Hey works.
I think any business is going to get frustrated customers like this.
So the opportunity for us really to swoop in save the day when them as a client.
So just considering it's leave my whole sodding blog paid so much money for the site I have no support.
So again what you could say is hey don't worry we can help you.
There's no need for you to delete your site.
We can transition into say WordPress in less than a day and it's a very simple process.
So again swooping in and saving the day for those frustrated customers is another way that you can find
potential customers and really get a huge Your A-Y off Twitter.
So go ahead and check that out for yourself.
Come up to the search bar and search for he was saying I need a website graphic designer financial planner
personal coach etc..
You can use these parenthesis to narrow it down and you can also search for those frustrated customers
as well.
So go ahead now and find Try that for yourself to find potential clients or put this strategy in your
back pocket for later.