If you want to grow your own throughout the can then one of the best things that you can do is on a
weekly basis come in and review your Instagram analytics and to access your Instagram on links.
Just click the little analytics icon beside that your account name.
And this is going to bring you right into the analytics dashboard and it is fairly basic but this is
probably all of the information you really need in order to make decisions to grow.
You can see the number of followers you've got.
In the last seven days and the number of posts that you made and really this analytics information is
going to just be shown for the most part.
On the last seven days you can see also the number of impressions.
The number of it.
So the number of times your posts has been seen impressions the number reached the number of accounts
that it's been seen by the number of profile views.
And if you look at your profile the number of clicks on those call to action buttons on your underneath
your bio.
I need to get 100 followers before I can see my demographic information but that will be things like
the name or the Age and The Sex and the location of my followers.
I can also see in terms of my posts all of them for the last year sorted by impressions.
And so this can be a great place to come in and look out and say OK well I've made six boys posts this
week which was the one that got the most impressions.
Maybe I can continue to make more content like that because that is getting a lot of impressions or
maybe even click in see one of the hashtags that I use maybe was responsible for that higher number
of impressions.
So always come in here and study and and try to understand why you did not post get so many impressions
and continued to make more content like that.
So you can continue to get more impressions now.
Below are normal posts that appear in our profile.
We can also see metrics for our stories.
Now this is not going to be shown for the last year but for the last 14 days but really sorted by impressions
once again and this is a great way to see again where one of those stories that are getting the most
amount of media impressions and that our audience are liking.
We can also see then the analytics for any promotions that we're doing.
And also down the bottom here which can be pretty helpful actually is just a definition of some of the
metrics that are showing up here.
So impressions just as a reminder are the total number of times that all of your posts have been seen.
And what is cool about that is especially in this analytics section is that it's the main metric for
posts and stories.
So if we click in here once again sort of by impressions and for stories it's impressions as well.
So what that allows you to do is compare like by like so poets with stories and you can really see OK
well are my posts or are my stories getting more impressions if your stories are getting more impressions
while then maybe continue to make more stories and continue to make more of the stories that are getting
the most amount impressions.
So the analytics or the inside section here is fairly basic but to be honest this is all you really
need to do.
And the main thing you want to find out is which is which type of content posts or stories that are
getting the most time impressions and which of those posts or stories are getting the most impressions
again.
So you're just drilling down into the most popular content.
You make more popular content with the right hashtags and you're just going to grow your visibility
and impressions on Instagram.
I think it's actually great the way it's so simple sometimes you can really be overwhelmed by all the
reports in say Facebook analytics or Google Analytics.
So it's quite a simple analytics dashboard but nonetheless it can be extremely helpful to guide you
towards growing your Instagram account.