In this video you're going to learn how to add an admin to a Facebook page that you have created.
So to do that you want to come up to the settings in the top right hand corner and then you want to
come down into Page roles and the left hand side bar and it's in here that you can really assign a new
page RIL.
And this is very simple to do you just pop in their email and then you select the different type of
page URL and you can do this and to add colleagues to your Facebook page to share the workload with
them of managing the page you can add in the business owner.
If you have created a page for them and you want to hand it back then you can assign them as an admin
and then they can later remove you as an admin if they wanted to as well.
And you can also add in freelancers if they're going to help you run ads or respond to comments or even
just straight up to to advertise on your Facebook page.
So there are six different options and you can select them here and you can even get a short description
once you select an option underneath a bite.
What it does so it's it's quite clear on what the different options are.
But if you do want to see them side by side you'll see there's a little learn more section here at the
top which will bring you to the Facebook help center.
And then you can see a side by side comparison here of the six options on exactly what they allow you
to do.
Now for the most part not been if you were handing a page back to business owner you just make them
anatman than they could remain as an admin.
And if you're working with someone as a freelancer to kind of help manage your page you could sell them
as an editor and then they can even begin to edit the page itself delete posts go live.
Or you can start to restrict those options.
So as you can see admin has the most amount of rights.
And then as emu's then the rights become less and less so for example unlist they can view your insights
for your Facebook page and see published as the page so they can give you.
That's a really an analyst role.
Maybe this is only something that's going to exist in a much bigger company where they're actually just
analyzing your page and maybe many other pages as well.
So it's incredibly simple to are these page rules in but it is important to know how to do it because
you can really share that workload as soon as possible and get a number of different people working
on your Facebook page so you can really grow much faster.
Two heads are always much better than one.
So come into your settings section under page rules and in any colleagues or freelancers that you may
need to add in in order to help you out.