In this video you're going to learn how to add a segment to your Google Analytics reports.
And this is a feature of Google Analytics that can really take your analysis to the next level because
it allows you easily to look at a subset of data and compare that to the total data set.
So for example I've just come into the demographics overview report.
We're going to create a very simple segment we're just going to look at the data from a particular country
and compare that to the age and gender of our total data set.
So to get started we just click on the segment and then here you can see that there are already some
segments created and all of them are listed here.
Fernando we just want to create a new segment and we can really see now that this segment is really
just some filters that we're going to add in in order to create that smaller subset of data there right
now because we haven't selected any filters.
It's showing 100 percent of the users.
But once we start to add any filters you're going to see this number drop down.
For example if we just want to look at a segment of our audience of that age group we can see it automatically
filters down to 20 percent of the audience that's come in there and create a segment and just look at
all of our visitors from a particular country and we can select this to be Japan.
So no this should open days and we can see that our Japanese audiences just 1.7 2 percent of the total
users over the last 30 days we can use set create this as her name the segments as demographics Japan
and cook save.
And once it slows up what we're going to see is a side by side comparison so we have all of our users
100 percent.
And we have our demographics from Japan which is just 1.8 percent really what we are doing here.
Even though it's a very simple example it's just comparing a subset to the total data set.
So we can see that on age they actually look very similar.
And so the total average age and the age range is split by 40 percent between this age bracket and over
here in Japan slightly higher but only just 42 percent.
So very interesting to see that even in Japan compared to the total data set that the age range is still
very consistent with what we're seeing with the large data set coming then and looking at gender we
can see there's a little bit different male is at 68 percent on our total data set.
And here in Japan we're getting a higher percentage of males 78 percent.
So you can see in this subset of data it's actually even though it only represents 1.8 percent of total
visitors sexy.
Remarkably similar in this particular example but it won't be in every case and that's where the interesting
things really start to happen.
For example you could see a traffic source that is contributing way more sales than other traffic source
and that's where segment's start to really get interesting.
Now in terms of using these segments you can see that when you click through to any individual report
once it loads up you'll see that this segment is going to be carried with you into those reports.
And even if you go on into other sections of your Google Analytics you're going to see that the segment's
is going to be carried through to those reports as well.
So if you want to remove these segments early stage you can just come in and click on remove and you
won't that won't appear there any longer.
And if you do want to delete or edit your segments you can just click back into segments click into
the custom ones that you've created.
Select the segments and you can either edited or go ahead and delete that segments and start a can.
So that is how you add segments to Google Analytics reports and it's incredibly powerful feature that
can take your analysis to the next novel.
So maybe go ahead into Google and like secant and set up a segment's and test this feature ad for yourself.