In this video you are going to learn how to use benchmarking reports in Google Analytics to grow a business
benchmarking reports in Google Analytics appear here underneath the audience tab and really want they
allow you to do is to select from sixteen hundred industry verticals and to compare the performance
of your website to other Web sites that are in the same industry as you.
And that gives you a fantastic baseline to measure your own business and can also give you insights
into industry trends.
And with those insights then you can make changes in your business and grow in a particular way based
on how your industry peers are performing.
So the first thing to note is that these reports won't appear by default.
You do need to enable them so to do that come into the admin section of your Google Analytics they can't
click on a Can settings and then just click enable benchmarking here.
So what this is going to do is by sharing your information.
Of course it's all going to be anonymous.
There won't be anything to say it's from your Web site but by sharing it.
You will then receive all of the data back from the other websites who shared them as well.
So it's a great anonymous way of sharing data and receiving data and just gives everybody got better
insight into their industry.
So let's come back to the benchmarking reports here and have a look at how you would actually analyze
them.
So first thing you can see that there are three different reports here.
And the first one that we can look at is the channels report.
So what we want to do in order to get some good insights is to firstly select our industry vertical.
So we're here inside the Google merchandise store.
So what I'm going to do is to select the shopping vertical I'll just type this in to shift to safe speed.
So we're coming in shopping and I'm just going to leave it as all shopping here you can get more specific
if you want.
Now also what you can do is select the specific region.
So I'm going to narrow it down some comparing against a smaller and more accurate set of Web sites by
picking people and in like country just for example United States own regions.
Now to get a more accurate benchmark what I'm also going to do is narrow down by size of daily sessions.
So this is really the number of sessions that I get per day.
I want to find websites that have similar man.
So if you don't know how many sessions you get per day you can just come into your audience overview
report you can select and make sure it shows for the last 30 days and then you can see the number of
sessions that you have just take out a calculator and divide that by 30.
I've done this in advance so that's about eighteen hundred sessions.
So coming back to my benchmark reports I can just pop that in now and once it load so we're really going
to be looking at a set of Web sites then that are very similar to my own.
So here we go gives you range.
I'm going to select eighteen hundred that's between and this range here.
And while we can see then once this loads up is in the top right hand corner.
So there are four hundred and eighty three web properties contributing to this benchmark.
So essentially I'm comparing myself to four hundred and eighty three similar sites in the same region
in the same industry.
So while we can see Dan below here is now how my Web site is performing against the benchmark across
all of these different marketing channels.
So everything in green is positive this is where I'm outperforming the benchmark and everything in red
here is where I am underperforming compared to the benchmark.
So just to make this clear if we look at the referral and marketing channels so this is other Web sites
sending visitors to me directly I can see that these are my numbers here as the sessions over the last
30 days have been eight thousand nine hundred forty six on the benchmark which is the aggregate figure
for all of those four hundred and eighty three sites is three thousand three hundred and thirty one.
So I am outperforming the benchmark by one hundred and sixty eight percent.
So that's very positive to see that my referral channel is performing extremely extremely well on an
inside for me seeing this as well if that's performing so well I should continue to do that because
that gives me a serious advantage over other competitors.
Now if we look then at the performance of other marketing channels I can see that I am not as strong
on say organic traffic although it's down 20 percent.
But if we really look and say display advertising social media paid search compared to my competitors
I don't put as much effort into those marketing channels or at least I'm not getting the number of users
for them.
So how could I grow this site based on the information that I'm seeing.
Well I can see that my competitors and the 483 other sites are much more heavily using paid search social
and display advertising and potentially those are untapped marketing channels for me ad that I could
really use to get much more traffic to the site.
Now if we look at some of the other green ones here and this is just to look at other metrics not just
the number of sessions you know the number of users that come to the site per day essentially but some
of the other metrics so I can see even though let's say for paid search even though I use it much less
as a marketing channel than other marketing channels on my benchmark I can see that the pages procession
and the average session duration and the balance rate.
So these are all user metrics this is showing me that users when they come through paid search they
do spend a lot of time on my site because all of these metrics that indicate that are very positive.
So once again I would really if I was running the Google merchandise store and it was built for profit
obviously it's not it's more just like an example site to sell Google merchandise they could heavily
invest in paid search because the other people in their industry are the small amount and traffic they
are getting from this marketing channel is performing extremely extremely well and you could say the
same for social maybe not the same for display.
So if you really want to juice paid search would be the way to go.
So that was just the channels reports in the benchmarking.
We can also look at the location report now that location report compares your country or territory
data to the benchmarks for each of the countries and territories from which you receive traffic.
Now since we have selected just the United States we're only going to see the U.S. show up in this report.
But if you'd select the different regions you're going to see how you compare in different regions compared
to the other websites in your benchmark and that can give you great indication just like the marketing
channels where perhaps you're outperforming and where you're underperforming compared to the benchmark
and where there might be opportunities for you to grow.
Next is the device's benchmarking report and this compares your device's data to the benchmark for desktop
mobile on tablets sessions or traffic.
So what we can see here is that on desktop over the last 30 days the Google merchandise store has a
20 percent more sessions.
But what is very interesting is that on mobile and tablets compared to the benchmark we are underperforming
by 75 to above 80 percent.
So this is a great insight to understand why this is happening is are not our site not mobile friendly
enough is you know maybe an app something that we need to develop and this is a great insight that compared
to the industry we could be missing out on a massive number of sessions and sales.
So if we look back over and recap on how to use the benchmarking reports to grow a business in this
example we can say that in terms of channels we are outperforming and referral traffic so we should
continue to invest in that to have a advantage over competitors.
We could maybe invest in paid search because this is performing extremely well for the small number
of users that we have.
And our other benchmark are using this as a marketing channel if we look at locations we just selected
one location.
But there could be great insights if you can see how you're underperforming or over forming in different
regions and definitely on devices.
Now we can see that we are potentially missing out on a lot of traffic and sales on mobile and top tablet.
And if we make fixes to that and track this trend then we can really grow our business.
So go ahead now enable the benchmarking reports and check these out for yourself so you can get insights
to grow a Web site.