In this video I'm going to show you how to strike gold with second degree connections on LinkedIn.
So to get started what you want to do is come up and click on the search bar here.
The top of LinkedIn.
And then you already want to search for people.
And this is an incredibly useful part of Linked-In.
It's essentially the search engine for people.
And we can see right now it's showing a list of 300 93000 results for me and also then we have a huge
list and options here to really filter that list then.
Now I really want to show you the power of these second degree connections by first showing you the
how many first degree corrections I have.
So on this purse on my personal profile here I've just 970 connections.
So these are people I've directly connected with.
I've hit that connect button and they've connected back.
So those are the first people I kind of personally know now where it gets extremely interesting is when
I look at my second degree connections and those in now it's gone up to 392 thousands.
So almost 400 times the network that I could tap into is just one step away.
So these second degree connections are connections of my connections.
So I know maybe someone here can give you a real example of this.
I know Roy and Roy knows the Emma.
So what I could do if I wanted to connect with Emma is ask Roy for a personal introduction or I could
just simply hit connect.
And because we have so many connections in common She's probably very likely to connect back.
Now if you want to use this strategy just to grow your personal profiling get those connection numbers
up and you can just go ahead and connect on all these.
I would recommend you try and connect with no more than 150 per day.
And also another tip is if you want to use this strategy you could maybe it's outsource this to a virtual
assistant because it will take you a good bit of time to get through all of those.
Now if you wanting search for second degree connections in a more targeted way maybe to pitch them or
get on a call to sell say B2B software or something like that.
What you could do is start to use some of the old other filters here so we can see that if we click
on the drop and here we can see that we can even type in their name their company or their title.
So let's imagine that I was trying to really pitch our product to CEOs.
So chief technical officers I could just type that into the title field there and now it's showing up
in results.
So I could ask one of my connections again here for example let's open this up car so I could maybe
message Karl and say Hi Karl.
I'd love to talk to niall to me over at whatever company Fearn ago.
Would you mind giving us making me a quick introduction.
Or again you can just connect and see if he connects back and then you'll have the option to message
him directly.
So you can see from a network where I probably had very few Teoh's in it.
I've never and see Teoh's just through those second degree connections.
Now if you wanted to even take it a step further these third degree connections are really connections
of your connections connections starts to get a little bit more complicated and watered down.
So I think really the second degree connections are where the power is because they're just one step
away with you but as you start to add more people to your network remember that that pool of second
degree connections will continue to grow again.
So it's one of the amazing things about Illington it really shows the network effect and how powerful
it is.
And remember that in here in the search engine you can really find all these second degree connections
and filter them down to really find a targeted list of people that you can connect to it on LinkedIn.
So go ahead and try that for yourself or put this strategy in your back pocket for later for a client
or for a company that you're working for.