In this video you are going to learn one simple trick that is going to increase your youtube subscribers
by 400 percent.
All you need to do is set up this pop up box prompting visitors to subscribe to your YouTube channel
when they visit your YouTube channel.
And it's very easy to set up all you need to do is add this little parameter here to the end of your
YouTube channel you are l.
So if you go to your YouTube channel your L you should see something like this and then all you need
to do is this little parameter at the end and then boom.
Here we have the pop up box shown up.
So I've included this little parameter on the full link as an example in the description of this video.
So you need to do is just copy this and add it to your your L and now you're getting this pop up box.
Now where can you use this.
Where can you really put this link to prompt more people to sign up.
Well you can put it at the end of any e-mails that you're sending at any links that you might have to
your social media profiles through e-mails on your web sites or even on other profiles that you have
around the Internet so that when people put it through to check out your channel then they're automatically
prompted to subscribe and you would be blown away at how this little simple trick can really increase
your subscribers very very quickly.
Try it for yourself use it for your clients or put it in your back pocket for later.