In this video I'm going to walk you through how to create your first ad on YouTube.
And to get started you want to head over to Edwards doc Google dot com and create your own words you
can't because Google owns YouTube.
It's inside out words where we create our ad for YouTube.
So I've put the link to this in the description of the video.
You can click through and then create your outwards the kind of you haven't got one.
And if you do have one you can just go ahead and sign in.
Now once inside to create our advertising campaign want to click this button on campaign and then click
video campaign.
We can give our campaign a name so we can say test video campaign and now we need to adjust some of
the settings for our campaign here.
There are some options but I can walk through some of the most important things to set.
So daily budgets we can just put that in as take ten dollars for it daily.
But just in terms of where we want the honor to appear for this particular.
And I just wanted to appear on YouTube so I can de-select that.
So it doesn't appear on any part or web sites locations.
You can set the location.
I'm going to set it as the United States.
You can set the language that you want it to appear in English it is fine for me.
And then I go ahead and just click save and continue.
So now we create our I group.
And as I will be creating this odd were group around certain key words I'm going to name the group keywords.
It's in here now that you want to paste the your L to your YouTube video that you want to show as an
ad so you can just copy that from YouTube and paste that in.
We now have the option to select the format of the ad.
So I want to show it in stream out and really show over other videos that our people are watching in
YouTube.
So I can put in the URL of where I want to send people.
Now we can input our cost per view saying in a set this 15 cents an over on the right hand side here
I can get a prediction of how many views that is going to get me.
And I can raise my budget if I want to get more views.
It's usually good to start low and then as your campaign is live you can come back and raise this if
it needs to be raised.
Dan here is targeting and this is an important part of the ad campaign set up process so you can see
by default it's going to show to any gender age parental status or household income.
So I want to narrow this down a little bit and really only show two males of my target demographic age
and show to those people who perhaps have a little bit more income.
So can a select select that in terms of narrowing down my targeting options further.
I want to do this because I want to show this video only to people who are watching content that's related
to certain keywords.
You can also set up and put your out insert in front of actual videos and you can paste the URL of those
videos right in here.
So your ad will show up there.
But for this group is going to set up for some certain keywords so I'm going to pop these in here.
And if you want to find more related keywords you can click on this button down here and our words is
going to suggest some key words that you can also add to the campaign.
Seeking out those in if it makes sense.
And then out all of your key words and have them selected here.
So once you've got that tone you can go ahead and click save a group and the campaign is live.
So you want to.
And now the campaign is live.
So now it's your turn.
Come into our words and set up your first YouTube ad campaign following the steps in the course and
monitored success using this dashboard in it's.