In this video you're going to learn how to create a video views Kostin audience.
Another extremely valuable customer audience.
You can create and the great news is you don't need to have Web site an email list or even a lot of
engagements on your Facebook page to create this.
So what we're really talking about here is on your Facebook page if you have created videos you can
create a custom audience for people who have watched those videos.
So for example here we are on my Facebook page.
I have two videos here and you can see that I've got fifteen hundred views on one.
I read 600 views on another and what I want to do is really create an audience for those people who
have watched those videos and I could then target or not with another video for them or even follow
up with a related opt in to an email list or a product that was related to what I talked about in the
video creating a video of us custom audience is very very simple.
We just need to come once again into your Facebook Ads manager and into your audience's tab.
Once inside then you just click on Create audience here in the top left hand corner select custom audience
you want to come down and select engagements on Facebook and the type of engagement you want to use
to create this audience is going to be the video option here.
Now once inside you have the option to set the parameters for this custom audience how broad or narrow
do you want to be.
And the first variable here is how much of the video people watched.
So you can see here that people who watch at least three seconds of the video people who were viewed
are at least 10 seconds 25 percent etc. all the way to the end.
And obviously as you go and if for example you selected people who watch Ninety five percent of your
video.
Those people are going to be extremely interested in maybe your follow up campaign but it's going to
be a much much smaller audience.
And for example to give you a breakdown of some numbers for my video that I used to set up this custom
audience 1300 views when I selected to create a custom audience for people who'd watch at least three
seconds that was.
Twelve hundred people so almost everybody who watched the video would be included.
When I bump this up to ten seconds the custom audience was just 500 people so a third of the total amount
of views that I got in the video.
So as you can see the numbers drop pretty dramatically based on the setting that you take.
For now let's just select three seconds so we can include as many people as possible.
Next up.
Then you choose the video or videos that you want to include in this custom audience.
I've got two videos here on my Facebook page.
They're not really related to each other in terms of the topics.
So right now I'm just going to select one and one video here.
Now if I wanted to just show somebody another video in and it out to drive video views then I could
maybe select both of these because I know those people watch videos.
And so if I have another videos views and there's a good chance they're going to watch that.
However if I wanted to create a custom audience where I was following or put an opt in or product related
to this video it's probably better just to pick one video and keep it on topic.
Or if you've a number of different videos related to that same topic then select those.
You've selected your video.
Go ahead and click confirm.
You also the option to set the time parameters for this custom audience.
And you could set this to people who have watch videos in the last month.
I'm just going to leave it at 3 6 5 to include as many people as possible.
Then you want to give your audience name as usual.
So we're going to put in video views custom audience 365 days.
I'm already going set up some misspelling going to put in number two here so I can tell them apart.
Then you click Create audience and remember once again that it will take up to 30 minutes for your audience
to be ready to use.
You can click next.
And then you have the option to create an ad or expand your audience using a look alike audience.
So I'm going to click on there now as you can see this is populating that message might switch to your
audience is too small but just leave it a full half an hour that will change and you can see the audiences
that I've set up already here.
We have people who watch 10 seconds.
That was 500 people.
So a smaller number.
And then people who just watched 3 seconds of video a much bigger number 3300 people.
Now you might be wondering OK well I have no views on my videos right now.
If I publish a view to my page of get five or 10 views.
Well here is the workaround for you.
First thing you need to do is create a video and upload it to your Facebook page.
Then what you could do is to create a video views campaigns to come into your ads create to select your
marketing objective for video views.
Then you can go down and in the format and media here just select your video as the video for the campaign
on the back of that when you've got maybe a thousand views in that video or through your paid advertisement.
You could create custom audience from those video views.
And then once you have that custom audience you could use it maybe to follow up with an opt in to an
email list or product or whatever the next step in your marketing funnel is.
So that is how you could build up a video of views custom audience from scratch from literally having
no Facebook fans custom web site audience email Esther anything you can really start with a video.
Push that video in and build a custom audience on the back of it.
And then follow up with the next advertisement for an opt in.
Cetera.
So now they know how to set up a video views custom audience.
Go ahead and set one up for yourself.
Following the steps that you've learned in this video.