In this video you are going to learn how to out a profile image to your Facebook page.
I'll discuss some of the options that you have and then only even show you how to design a Facebook
profile image for free.
So the mechanics of adding a profile image are very simple you just click on a picture then you can
take a picture directly from your computer where you can upload a photo.
So if you do have a company logo or a profile picture that you always use you can just upload those
directly.
And that is really this step completed.
Now if you want a couple of ideas on what you should be putting in your Facebook profile for your Facebook
page there's two main options.
One as you can see here on Eudemus Facebook page is just to include your brand logo.
And really this should be consistent with the logo that you're using on any other social media profile
so that when people see it it's instantly recognizable to them.
Now a couple of things and best practices for this type of business logo is that you can see that it's
just two colors which keeps it simple see red on a kind of a gray background here.
So it needs to be simple.
And also you can see it at square here.
But when you move then to actually see a post and then this will happen will be how it appears in the
news feed of somebody following this page you can see even though it's small it's very recognizable.
And that this time is round but it still isn't being cut off or cropped.
So when you're designing your logo or uploading it makes sure that there is some space around the edges
so that when it does appear around that it will be cropped out.
Also keep it simple.
Two colors is really the best strategy.
Now if you are more of a personal brand or the face of your business than you can do what I've done
here which is just simply upload your profile picture.
And that's a quick way to get it done.
Now I do want to show you how to design your own business logo if you don't have one already.
And I think the easiest thing to do here is just as you did me have done just take the first letter
of your business and use that as your business logo.
So you you to me show you another example of this.
This is Bunson.
It's a restaurant here in Dublin Ireland.
And you can see they've done the same thing.
It's a little bit more designed.
They've got their brown color and a bit of Typepad graphy but essentially the same idea just the first
letter of their business name be Bunson.
Here's another example of that style so simple and an s so you can get up and running and have a pretty
attractive profile image on your Facebook page very quickly.
And I do want to show you a very simple way that you can design this for yourself what you want to do
is come into Kanva dot com.
It's absolutely free.
It's essentially like Photoshop.
But a lot simpler and totally free so you can come to Commodore com log in with Facebook or Google.
And then once inside you can make sure that you're on creative design and then you can come across and
click use custom dimensions.
And once that pops up you want to put in five 40 by 540.
Those are the pixels.
And then we're going to really design our Facebook image in here so you can see we've got to square
what we can do first is put in our background color.
Now we can select any of these back green colors.
And as we said you want to keep it as simple as possible.
So what I can do is maybe just select this orange or what you could also do is upload your own background
image so you can just upload your own images there from your computer.
And maybe I'll do that here.
You can delete this and then I can add in this image that I've uploaded previously.
Put that in as my background image.
I can even move that around if I want.
And the next thing that I want to do is add my text so I'm going to follow that strategy of you to me.
And the other companies we saw just putting the first letter of my business so I'm just going to stick
with S is my page name is set up demo.
Now I can select that piece of text I want to change the color to Weisse and now I want to increase
the size.
So right now it's 42.
I mean increase this to go away that you're
44.
OK.
Are probably when we change this font it's going to appear bigger.
So select this come over here to change the font and you can do it girl and through and pick any font
that you think is going to kind of represent the style of your business I'll just pick this one here.
And I can even type this in whatever I want to be saying and I've to just go up to something like 250
or maybe even 300.
You could see that it gives you help to really centered the text as well which is very handy.
But there I mean that is very simple.
Two minutes.
But I think it looks pretty good to get up and running and for the first profile image of the Facebook
page now to download this you just want to click download you can select PLG and then you can just click
download and it's going to download to your Downloads folder.
Now one thing you might want to do before leaving this is just click File Save so that you can come
back and do just this later if you want.
Now what I'm going to do is come into back to my Facebook page at a picture upload the photo going to
come to downloads.
I can see this here.
I did a practice one before and now I may need to reposition this or I can just zoom in and see him.
So it's the perfect dimensions there and then click save.
And now my profile picture has been successfully saved.
So there we go.
That is how you add a profile picture to your Facebook page.
We talk about some of the best practices and even how to design one for yourself for FREE.
Inside Kanva dot com.