In this video you're going to learn how to follow top influencers in your niche on Twitter.
And this is an excellent thing to do as soon as you get set up on Twitter because you can really model
these top influencers to see even have laid out their profile.
What type of content they're putting out and how you could really do the same to be successful.
So once you've created your Twitter profile you're going to see that there is an option here to find
people to follow on Twitter will really suggest based on your location.
So a lot of these accounts here are local to where I am now.
But what you really want to do is start building it and your Twitter profile is follow the top influencers
in your particular needs.
So to do that you just want to type in your keyword into the Twitter bar at the top here.
So let's just say I was in the personal finance space and I really want to find the top influencers
are on Twitter in that space.
So what's going to pop up once I see that here you can see across the top I can see the latest the people
the photos videos news broadcasts et cetera.
So we really want to look at the people up here are going to pop up some of the two most influential
accounts for this key word.
And if we open this up we can see really all of them here which is really interesting to see.
So what I'd suggest you do is have a look through some of these top accounts and maybe just follow five
people if you're kind of a business talking about personal finance maybe find those related business
type Twitter profiles if you want to promote more of a blog.
Maybe you could follow more of these individuals in an independent personal finance editor see and see
here.
Weisbrot get rich slowly.
Let's keep going then
bankcard and really anybody else that you know is a big influence here.
You can search for them online if you're in this space.
So for example I know one guy here Mr. Money Mustache.
He's actually a great blog on personal finance if you're in that sort of stuff.
And then the key idea here is once you come back to your home screen then your news feed will start
to be populated with what those top people are doing and see the types of posts that they are putting
as you can come into their profiles.
You couldn't really have a look at higher.
They're using the cover image water the type of things that they're putting in their profile.
Here you can see the profile and image the type of tweets they're getting water the type of things that
they're getting engagement's on.
And this is just a fantastic way to quickly understand what you need to be to doing on Twitter in order
to be successful because you are really modeling those people who have been successful if you come back
to your home page as well.
You can see in your profile the number of people that you're following.
And if you want to access those you can click on that and open them up.
And again you can just come in here have a look at those scans.
Have a look at their most recent tweets and see how were they getting so much engagement like this.
So you can see here this is a great example.
I think Bitcoin is ridiculous.
What are the most compelling stuff you've read wash written for or against.
So this is a perfect example of someone really engaging their audience on Twitter and that is why it's
getting so many likes read tweets and comments on it.
And it's a perfect example of something that you could do for your business to really ask the opinion
of audience and get that huge amount of engagements and the huge amount of read tweets.
So you can really learn an incredible amount by looking at people who are already successful on Twitter.
And that's why you should really come in and use that search bar and find those top influencers in your
needs and add them to your account.
So go ahead and do that right now so you can really accelerate your success on Twitter.