In this video you're going to learn about offer claim odds and how you can create a limited time discounts
so you can really drive more sales for your online or offline store.
You'll start by understanding really what an offer claim is and some of the benefits and features of
it.
Then we will start to look at some examples and some of the copy that you can use for these type of
odds in order to get better results.
And then I'll show you how you can set up an offer plain for yourself and give you an example of that.
So let's start by understanding a little bit more about Offer play Ahmad's the benefits and the features
of them.
Well the key benefit is that you can really grab attention with a deal or a discount if you want to
boost sales in your online shop or off lines.
Shop a discount or a promotion is a great way to really encourage people to act.
It is a tried and proven marketing strategy.
You'll see it when you go shopping.
SALE ENDS NOW this Christmas sales.
There is after Christmas sales.
There's a limited time frame on these things and there's often a 20 percent or 50 percent off number
that's shown in the window to really encourage people to act.
So it's a proven marketing strategy.
And now you are able to use it in your Facebook ads.
So let's have a look at some of the objectives for you if you want to use these claim offer ads.
Well clearly peer to you can reach more people with these offer a reach new people and it allows you
to call activate new people it gives them a great incentive to take notice of you.
Now you can reach these new people through interest and demographic targeting.
You can do it through location targeting.
If you are a physical store but as well as that you can reach existing customers with these offers your
Facebook fans a custom audience Web site visitors your e-mail list et cetera.
And once again the the outcome is Turi and what you want to achieve is to encourage them to take action
so you can increase your sales.
Now here's one cool feature of these offer claim ads you can send automatic reminders to people who
have claimed the offer and notify them when the deal is about to expire so that they really use it.
That's a great reminder function that is built in as well.
So the benefits of offer Claremont's are very clear.
Let's have a look now at the Facebook and skite and get a look at some of the copy that you could use
in an ad like this for yourself.
So here is an example for both desktop and mobile and you can see the text here.
Enjoy for us pro-Jew starting with a verb before the season ends.
So that sentence is creating a little bit of urgency.
I can see them below in the headline for the odd 20 percent off.
So that is the offer.
And I can see underneath that again it's an expiry date.
So this is a great way to create that sense of urgency as well.
Not only in the text here but also in the expiration date.
And you can see the call to action.
But News-Wall says get off for reading encouraging people to click that button and making clear what
the call to action is.
Creating a limited time offer for your business is very simple I'm going to show you how to do that.
Now inside the ads create tool which you will find inside your odds manager.
Now when you come in here the first thing to do as always is to set your marketing objective at the
campaign level.
Now you'll see here that a offer claim God is not one of the objectives that you can pick and that's
because actually the offer climat is just a way that you can reach one of your marketing objectives.
So you'll find this option inside traffic.
So getting people to web site with this offer plain you'll find it inside the conversions marketing
objective.
Now remember in order to use the conversions marketing injected you do have to have the Facebook pixel
set up and this is most likely going to work much better in an online store we can measure that through
the Facebook pixel.
So let's just take the example of traffic and really select this as our marketing objective setting
up the offer.
In either case is going to be the same process.
Now you'll see here that we have an offer on not as an option and we need to do is really enable this
select the page that we want to create the offer for and then click on Create offer.
And here you can see the little interface where we are going to create the offer.
We have a preview of it on the right hand side here and you can also see a preview of the notification
that a person will see if they claim the offer but haven't used it so that's the reminder notification
function that we talked about at the start of the visit video.
Right now there's no image in this offer but we can add that later on in the third level.
So what we can do in here is just say 20 percent off.
I'll just show you some of the fields that you will fill in here tell people about the offer learn the
buyers before offer expires.
You can select the end date and the end time which appears here right under your headline.
You can also select where people can redeem this offer and this is how you choose now if you want people
to redeem this offer online or in-store.
So for example let's start with the online offer your l.
Now a lot of e-commerce sites or other online platforms where you buy things enables you to put in the
euro with the coupon already in Attash.
So for example I'll take the example of one of my Uni courses here and you can see the inside of the
U R L their coupon code is already there so if they clicked on the offer they would be able to go straight
to the landing page where they would see the coupon already applied and that would require them to check
out without having manually to put in the coupon.
Now in-store it's going to be a little bit different.
You can choose the type of promo code so you can have no code you can have a code at which you can say
20 off now.
And in order to measure the success of this campaign you would have to have a system in your store where
you could note and how many people claim the offer then linked back to your campaign here inside the
ads manager and match up OK I spent this much.
You got this many customers and then you would be able to decide if the campaign was successful or not.
Now for either scenario you can limit the total offers available and you can also prevent people from
sharing this offer.
With this the deal dropped in now and you might want to do that.
And if you only want to get a limited amount of offers and don't want to disappoint people.
The final section here is then for terms and conditions and you can see that this shows up if there's
any other important rules here.
If there are things that you this offer does not apply to and you want to specify that this is the place
to do it.
Now if we look at the in-store example you can actually see it here as well because I've created this.
So let's just go ahead and create this offer now that offer is created in terms of selecting the audience
for this offer that's going to depend on your business.
Now you could select it for a location and add two particular locations.
You can do the radius targeting if you type in an address here you can use a custom audience any of
DeCosta more answers that you've learned how to set up you can use to save audience from a previous
campaign.
And in terms of all of the targeting and the placements and the budget we've covered that in previous
lectures so not going to go through that again.
I do want to show you just how to add in the image.
Very simple but just to remind you to do this.
So come into the library just add any image here and you can see now a full preview of what your offer
is going to look like.
So I can see my headline here.
Some of the text and the call to action button.
So now you understand what offer claim ads are and how to create a limited time offer for your online
or online store.
Go ahead and set one up for yourself.
Following the steps that you've learned in this.