In this video you're going to learn about local awareness sides and how you can create Facebook ads
to reach people on Facebook and Instagram when they are near your business location.
We'll start by understanding what local awareness sites are and some of the call to action.
You can include in those ads then we will jump into a case study here and see how this business that
pest Korea was able to build a lot of excitement around their business through local awareness ads even
before they launched.
Then we will have a look at this case study here for a medical center in Israel where they were able
to generate leads using local awareness ads.
Then we will jump into the ads create tool and I'll show you some of the things you need to watch out
for when you're setting up one of these local or innocence.
And also the difference between a local awareness ads and these store visits marketing objective that
you can see here to get started.
Let us look at the local awareness side understand a little bit better.
So as you now understand you use it to really get local attention and some of the messages that you
can use for these local ad adverts are to highlight promotions tell people about and offer happy hour
sale and give them that incentive to visit your business.
The key thing is that you want to keep it local and you can tell a story about your business roots local
products.
You can showcase a fun fact.
Does your location have any quality or interesting backstory tell people that in your business so those
are some of the ideas for the content of these local awareness ads.
Now let's have a look further down here and look at the call to action buttons that you can use in these
local awareness ads.
Now they are called local awareness ads but there are some cool to actions you can include like giving
people directions help them find your shop from their phone.
It's great for driving foot traffic.
You can include your phone number in these ads.
They can call you when one top and speak to you directly.
You can also include the call to action for them to send you a message.
And that is a great way to generate leads and people very close by and you can also just get them to
learn more and click through to your Web site for more information.
So there's more to these local awareness ads than you would think.
And those called the actions are going to be great for driving foot traffic.
And let's have a look at the first case study which is for this Italian restaurant franchise called
passcode here.
So what they did and what's interesting about this particular case study is that they really use Facebook
and Facebook ads before they even open the business to promote it and generate interest.
So let's scroll down a little bit and to see some of the details on this.
So two months before opening day the company began posting pictures of its dishes on Facebook.
The posts are aroused enormous interest and people began to ask for more information about the location
of the restaurant on the opening time on the opening day attracted 500 people who flooded the streets
and to get access to it.
So if we moved down here.
Here are some of the results.
So this is a combination of using Facebook.
It's page but also the ads as well.
So we can see that the Facebook is the number one source of new customers.
Seventy percent of the company's revenue is generated through Facebook.
They sold their signature dish 3000 of them in the first 30 days and 80 percent discovered thanks to
Facebook and 500 people attended the opening day promoted exclusively through Facebook.
So this case to be really shows that even a Facebook page is extremely powerful for a local business.
Now if we look up in terms of the actual ads themselves what they said is it seems to be after they
open they started to run the ads that they run ads to reach more potential customers the target audience
was defined by geographical location six mile radius of the restaurant.
And they have tested those boundaries over time as they've gone on to look at the different franchises
et cetera.
But I think that is just a great case study to see that you can promote through the Facebook page even
prior to launch and build up a lot of buzz for that opening day.
Now they don't seem to have mentioned it here but you could use an event response ad which will cover
later to really make sure that Opening Day is a big hit and you can get a lot of people coming in like
they did here.
In this case it seems like they were able to generate that interest organically but you could do that
with an event response ad for an opening day.
I'm going to show you how to do that later on in the course as well.
Let's move on to the second case study and look at how a medical center in Israel was able to generate
leads for their maternity services.
So we can see here that they got over 90 percent of target audience reached a quite a small audience
for these type of services.
Obviously there's not that many people having babies.
So it is a quite a niche market.
And they were able to meet to meet 90 percent of it in Israel which is pretty impressive.
14 percent of clicks converted into Leeds.
Eighty two percent of Leeds became customers.
So that's interesting thing that about 14 percent click through which is pretty high.
And then eighty two percent of those became customers which is very high again.
So they must have had a great strategy in order to make this happen.
So let's look at some of the ways that they do that.
Now in terms of the size of the audience nine thousand babies every year.
So you're talking about 9000 mothers which is pretty niche.
So let's have a look at how they did this so reaching parents to be.
Here's the interesting part.
The hospital wanted to reach pregnant women in Israel a relatively small audience at any given time
and a marketing team knew that they needed a very cost effective way to tap into this audience.
So first what they did is a targeted ad to relevant people based on age gender interests and location
then it used custom website audiences to retarget Web site visitors with a strong call to action and
people in the relevant locations who'd visited their campaign landing page was shown optimize lead ads
which encouraged them to make inquiry very quickly and easily.
So the strategy here for them was firstly because they didn't know exactly who the people were and who
would be interested.
They did a broader campaign based on age gender interests and locations.
Women of a certain age who might be pregnant and might have certain interests in things that they could
pick up on and of course location because they have a medical center can only serve a radius of people.
Then they followed that up once they knew who clicked through on that ad with a lead ad.
And obviously Facebook was able to pre field maybe their phone number email and they were able to follow
up.
And that's probably why they had such a high number of leads becoming customers.
Maybe they call those customers afterwards and conversion over phone is going to be much much higher.
That could be the reason that you're seeing such big results there.
But the strategy in general very interesting interest age demographic targeting first followed up with
a lead ad based on a custom audience.
Very interesting to see.
Now let us jump into the ads create tool inside your ads manager and really want to walk you through
the process of setting up one of these local awareness sites.
They're very similar to most campaigns.
There's a couple of things to say.
And also in here I wanted to just explain the difference between local awareness sites and store visits.
It seems like it's the same thing.
Why are they in two different columns.
Well the key thing about these store visits here is that these are still for people to visit your brick
and mortar locations but the difference is that these ads are really set up to serve people and stores
with multiple locations.
So the idea about these ads is that you have one create creative on that you can serve that to a lot
of different neighborhoods and that it will dynamically change the phone number that you need to call
the address that you want to go to if you want to give people directions even if they're separate reps
websites for separate locations.
You can include the you or else there.
So this is location based ads at scale and that's really the purpose and the difference between these
store visits.
Now if you want to setup one of these store visits ad and you've got multiple locations and you want
to show a different at each location then the first thing you've to do is set up your business locations
in business manager and you can click here to really get a walk through of all those steps.
Now as I don't have a Facebook page that is has a specific location in it's fortunate I can walk you
through all the steps but it's fairly straightforward and all of these steps are given out here.
But the key difference is really that this is ideal.
If you've got multiple locations if you're a franchise and you want to develop these ads at scale let's
come to the local awareness ads though and really have a look through this process so you can select
this as my marketing objective and then hear you to select the radius of the audience that you want
to cover the age the gender of course you want to target specific people like we saw in the medical
center example they were really focusing on women of a certain age and so think about not just people
who ran your business but the type of people as well coming down to the ad example here I want to show
you quickly how you can change the call to action for these type of violence.
So right now you can see the call to action is like page but as this is the local awareness site there
are much better options that you can choose from like you can get people to call now.
Now here's the thing is that if you want to call now the action is only available on the mobile news
feed an Instagram feed placements so you can't put this on a desktop.
So I'd have to remove those placements which I can do here easily if I want to do that.
So coming back up to placements let's just see where this is now.
It's not on the audience network.
I'm going to see here for Facebook.
It's just in the feeds.
I can pop that in and then for Instagram as well I can see it's in the feed.
So if I come then again and it comes down to coal now.
Now it just stick in my phone number there.
I can also put in get directions as well.
Pop in the street at the address.
So I think remember for these type of local awareness stands you're really targeting people on mobile.
So for those placements as well you want to make sure that you are really targeting people for mobile
and make sure that you're not putting say we have mobile only up here and just make sure that's set
as that.
In terms of your ad creative.
Well you can put in a lot of different things here.
If we go back to our original example some of the ideas that you can use you can highlight some promotions
so you could say it's happy hour or there's a sale on.
Unfortunately you can't put it like a coupon in here for this particular type of art but you can say
sale on now or happy hour in our drinks that the Special Prize and you can also schedule designs to
run at a particular time which is probably going to be a good idea if your local business is only open
for a particular time.
And in terms of odd scheduling you can run these ads on a schedule as well.
You do have to set up a lifetime budget in order to enable that but that could be a great idea for a
local business.
So this lifetime budget is you set the lifetime budget of the campaign.
And it's not done on a daily basis.
And the reason for that is Facebook needs to make sure that it can deliver and and spend the budgets
not might not be possible to do it every single day.
So you can really set those schedules and that's probably a good idea for local awareness.
And so to recap on some of these things that you need to watch out for just make sure the placements
are for mobile only in terms of budget and schedule.
You might want to do that on an a particular schedule if your business is only open uncertain times
or you have a happy hour at a certain time and you want to run that then down in the ad level.
Just think about that call to action and what that should be and use an appropriate and creative for
the promotion that you're running or happy hour etc..
So now that you understand what local awareness ads are.
Go ahead and set one up if you want to reach more people on Facebook and Instagram when they're near
your business location.