In this video you're going learn how to bulk manage with power editor which is one of the key benefits
of the tool.
We'll look at a couple of different examples.
Firstly how you can both manage ads.
That's then how you can both manage ads and upload new images and also how you can book manage with
Excel as well.
So let's start off by looking at how to book Manage an odd set.
Let's take this example of one campaign to really get started to select one campaign and say for example
there was one thing that I wanted to change in my onsets.
After the campaigns have run for a while and I've understood what's really working what I can do for
example is if I've noticed that a certain age range is really getting all the results for my campaign
and I want to narrow it down to that I can do that in bulk here in power Ed..
Otherwise I'd have to go through all of them one by one and change them.
But here it's pretty simple.
So what I want to do is firstly come to my sets tab then I can just select all of the assets that I
want to change or I can just select the ones individually that I want to change then I can come into
the edit button here.
Now what I'm going to see here are all of the values for these campaigns that I can really change.
So what you're going to notice here is because all of these odd sets of different names you're going
to see mixed values.
Also if you see in terms of share you'll start starkers mixed values here and also if we move them to
the audiences themselves there these are three completely different audiences.
So I kind of edit these in bulk I can reset them if I want them to be all the same.
But what this book management tool is allowing us to do is to both manage do things that are equal across
all of the campaigns.
For example the body is the same the end date was the same and also the age range was the same across
all our campaigns on the gender.
So what I could do for example for all three of these campaigns because this information is the same.
I can change this to maybe an age range of 25 to 34 because this is where I was getting all the results
for this campaign and going forward.
I just want to narrow it to that.
So essentially those changes have now been made is pretty much as simple as that I can come up here
on the top right hand side you can see the green box here review changes here.
I can really see the changes that Ive made to the campaign I can either apply them or I can click Cancel
and then discard them.
So you can change not only the age and gender but really any of those parameters that is that are same
across all of the sets.
Thats our first example just managing onsets in campaigns.
You can do a lot of different ways.
That's just one example to show you how to work the same process for all of the different things.
Now let's come down into the level and look at how we could update the images across all of our ads.
So let's come back again and actually just stick with the same example for this one campaign.
We've got three onsets.
And then in here we've got a number of ads.
Now what I may have noticed from my campaigns is that one image was I performing everything else and
I want to update all of the odds to be the same in terms of the image.
I still might have different copy across the different cards and that's why I still maintain them as
separate odds in the onsets.
So what I can do once again is just come in here and select all of the odds or the individual ones that
I want and in terms of how I could change the image just come into edits and then I could come down
into the image section.
Here you can see I could change the image I can use my own image library and pick maybe an image here
I could maybe pick this image would I put the text that was the one that was performing well or get
upload an image like no one who uploads stock images as we've seen before.
So if I selected this or another image I could select this here and then that would update this image
across all of them.
Now what I can do once again is really decide to actually counsel lot and discard those changes.
And it goes back to as it was here.
Another way that you can book Manage your power editor is actually to take the information out of power
editor an edited in Excel and then upload it back up.
So for example if I wanted to really like this campaign and all any information in it I could just select
it here then come to this little icon for export and import.
And I can really export this data that's selected and it's going to pop open in Excel.
Now what I can do is really edit this information here in my cell and then upload it back into power
editor.
So for example what I could do is the campaign starts here is paused.
What I could do is change this to active for all of these
assets and then what I can do is just upload that back up and it's the same principle for anything here
you can read just any of these things.
Now as you can imagine you would have to probably have to have a lot of bad sets and odds to really
justify exporting and doing it this way.
But it is great to know that this option is available and there's another reason that you might want
to use excel in order to create campaigns either as a freelancer or either as a business owner and that's
because you could actually give someone a template you can see download template here and ask them to
create campaigns for you.
Or if you're working as a freelancer create campaigns here send them to people and then it could upload
them into their power editor.
You also might want to use Excel to extract some information out to power editors so you can replicate
the structure of some campaigns.
The type of ads that I use and some of the ads setups for other clients or other campaigns so that's
another reason why you might want to export this so you can really transfer odds and different sets
and structures and things like that to other accounts very very easily.
So now that you know how to both manage handsets and images insides and even both managing Excel go
ahead and take a couple of minutes to play around with that.
Remember that you can always come here to review any changes and discard them if you don't want to follow
through.