In this video you're going to learn how to capture email addresses without needing a Web site.
I'll show you a perfect example of this.
Here is a Twitter page you can see that they say in their bio here that they're working with entrepreneurs
to solve the world's hardest problems.
Follow along through our weekly newsletter and then we can see a link actually here to a standalone
page where we can sign up to their e-mail newsletter.
Now you can see this is not going to their Web site.
It's just a page recone sign ups their e-mail lists.
So this is extremely handly handy way to connect or to collect e-mail addresses even if you don't have
a Web site.
So in order for you to set this up for yourself first do you want to log into your MailChimp account
and then click into the list that you've created and you want to come and to sign forms and then you
want to select general forms.
Notes in here that you can design your own standalone page like this.
You can see here that they have edited the list name.
So if you want to do that you'd need to go back to the list and edit it there.
But then in here what you can also do is add or remove any fields.
So let's say I didn't need to collect their phone number I could remove it and then click deletes and
that would be remove.
Now what I can do is take this link and paste that in my Twitter profile Facebook profile really anywhere
in content that I've created to encourage people to sign up to my e-mail list.
So it's a very handy feature of MailChimp and makes it incredibly easy to collect e-mail addresses even
if you haven't got a Web site set up.
So go ahead and check it out for yourself.
Once again you want to come in to your lists.
Then you want to come in to sign up forms and to do this you want to look at the general form and you
can edit it in their.