In this video I'm going to show you how to add a cover image to your Facebook page.
I don't even show you how to design one for free.
Tonight a cover image to your Facebook page.
You can click on this little button here in the cover image space and you can choose a photo or upload
a photo and you can even upload a video or a slide show in this space as well.
But for this video we're just going to look at it uploading a photo.
So what are some of the best practices for using this space and getting the most out of it.
Well let's have a look at an example here on you Timmy Dotcom's Facebook page.
They have used this in an interesting way.
They have included a picture of their ideal customer or their customer really in action using their
product or service.
So to me is an online marketplace that sells online courses.
And here you can see a picture of one of their students really using their marketplace.
You can see he's got the laptop.
It looks like he's at home.
He's taking notes.
And so they are using this space to really identify with the customer.
So when I see that and come to their page I say hey that's kind of what I'm doing.
And then I can identify with that.
It speaks directly to the customer.
Another way that you can use this cover image space.
For example if you were a local business like this one here which is a steakhouse in Dublin they have
taken a picture of the outside of their building and this is a great use of this space as well because
if I come to their Facebook page to find out if they're open a little bit more about them read the reviews
well then I get a clear picture of what it looks like from the street and that when I walk past it makes
it very easy for me to identify.
Yes that's the place I saw it online and that's the exact picture of it.
So I know I'm here or that's where I saw that review.
But the place that looks good.
So that's another interesting way to use this cover image space.
Now there's really unlimited possibilities for this.
And so if you want you can come in use the Facebook search bar search for a similar business to your
to yourself and check out how they are using them.
Now I do want to show you how to design your own cover image for free and to do that and you can come
into Kanva dot com.
It's essentially just like Photoshop but a lot simpler and completely free.
And the best thing about it is that they have templates for Facebook cover images so you can just log
in and then click on Facebook cover.
You can see it has the exact dimensions that we need.
So this really saves a couple of steps in the process.
So you can click into that and right now you can see that we have our blank canvas in those correct
pixel dimensions.
And then over here on the left hand side we have templates that we can actually use and drag and drop
into this blank canvas.
Now a lot of these are free and you can use those and just manipulate the text and the colors and the
images if you want.
And some of them do have some page image page images and or paid elements to them.
And that's OK because Kanva are providing a great service.
Obviously they need to make some money out of this.
And the cool thing is that if you see a template like this that has some paid elements to it it doesn't
mean you can't use it at all.
You can just go ahead and delete the paid elements so I can see here because it's got the Xs at the
back that this is a paid element.
So I can actually delete that.
And what I'm going to do is actually put my background in this and then delete the background here per
my own background that I've uploaded.
And actually I can see that this part of the image as well as the paid elements are actually going to
remove that and I'm going to replace that so I can come up in two elements shapes and I'm going to pop
this in here.
I'm going to
reposition this.
And you can see it gives you a lot of help to make things centered and I think that looks pretty good.
So once you have created a cover image that you like then you can just go ahead and click download and
save it as a ngi
and it can take a couple of seconds like this for it to download and it's going to move that to my desktop.
What I might do before I leave this is just click save.
So I have that for later.
And then they're going to come back to my Facebook page.
Click on Add a cover from a photo and actually I need to click upload upload a photo and there's my
design
I can just uploaded there.
And I think you'll agree that looks fantastic and we're really taking advantage of this prime real estate
on our Facebook page.
Now one final thing that you want to do in order to get more Web site traffic from your Facebook page
is to opt in your web site here under the Learn More button.
So I've just added in web site dot com This is just a test and you cannot in your own.
You were all there.
And then click on Save changes and we've updated our learn more button.
So anybody who comes to our Facebook page and wants to learn more they can click straight through to
our Web site and you can even test that to make sure that does actually go through to the right you
world that you've put in there so that you know how to create your own cover image for Facebook and
uploaded an ad in that link back to your Web site.
Go ahead and take these important steps to set up your presence on Facebook.