In this video you're going to learn how to set up your Google onwards account.
So you need to do is come into Google typing Google Adwords and this will pop right up at the top of
the search results and then you can just click through.
Then you just want to come in and click Start.
Now that might take a second to load up.
Then once inside you can actually skip this guided set up if you see that option.
This allows to get through the steps a little bit quicker and then you just want to follow the instructions
here to enter your email.
Country Time Zone and currency.
Now as it says here you won't be able to change the settings later.
So just make sure that you set this up in the currency and the country in the time zone of where you'll
really be working from and the currency that you'll be paying in.
So you just want to change the settings if you want and then click save and continue and then want to
sign in to Google Adwords put in your password for your Google account for your email.
And there you go.
Now you'll be inside Google Adwords and have your Google afterwards you can set up.