In this video you're going learn how to optimize your Pinterest account so that you can appear at the
top of the Pinterest search engine.
Animals are going to cover some of the key steps you need to do to set up your camps like adding a profile
image.
So let us get started with the profile image.
This is a key part of your account and let me walk show you some of the profile images from the can
that I'm following so we can look at the best practices and there are only really two options for this
image.
Either one is going to be you as a personal brand or the face of your business or two.
It's going to be a company logo.
So firstly in terms of a personal brand this is a good example here.
It's a close shot of the face.
It has a very kind of muted background there's no distraction in the background.
And I think it's instantly recognizable as that person.
If we look across here at this profile it could be better if that shot in the face was a lot closer
to the camera because it would be easier to recognize.
And also you can see the pose there it's not as easy to recognize that person.
And also the background is maybe a little bit distracting.
So maybe a closer image of the face there just from it on like this one here would be better.
Also down here make sure if you're uploading an image that it's high quality if you're putting your
business on Pinterest and you want to attract customers.
Well then I think just the high quality image looks more professional and people will take you more
seriously there.
So that is for kind of a personal brand for an actual company really just your simple logo you can do.
If we look at some other examples I can show you some of their examples here.
And these are companies that I think do particularly well.
So if we look at night on Pinterest you can see it's just a very simple black background with the take
instantly recognizable.
And of course consistent across all of their social media profiles.
And let's have a look at one other one.
HubSpot again they always do a good job at this.
Just a simple two color logo.
Very recognizable even when it's very small like it is here.
Now to add the image is very simple.
He can just come to your settings come to your profile change the picture choose the photo and I am
just going to choose from my desktop which is the image that I use across all of my social media profiles.
Now it's in here as well that I also want to optimize a couple of other things about my profile.
The first is the business name.
And what we can do here is start to as you optimize this profile and we do want to be appearing at the
top of the search results.
So keeping that we can do is start to put in some keywords here in our business name.
Now we'll show you if we look at some of these profiles the top influencers and you can have a look
at the top influencers that you have followed.
You can see that they say their name and then they say a couple of keywords for the niche that their
ads.
Pinterest marketing content creator and that helps them appear at the top of the search results when
people are searching for people for those topics.
So while you can see digital marketing and their keyword is kind of in their business name is a marketing
consultant Pinterest expert.
So what I can do is just take that in a little bar and use it on my own profile.
Now what you can do even if you have a business name is say put your business name here and then say
some of the things that you do whatever that is so that could be your business name and then jewelry
e-commerce store or something like that whatever it is.
Now next thing that we can do is just edit our username.
You want to make this look professional.
You may have been given a user name at a random string of numbers like this.
So what you can do is just adjust that slightly.
You could put in the real the official or for personal brand sometimes you can just stick in your middle
initial and that will be available.
Now I'm actually just going to see if if my first and last name is available and if not I can change
that afterwards.
Now next topic we've got the about us about U.S. And once again it's a good idea to look at some top
profiles.
You can see Pinterest marketer again those keywords from the title are repeated in here and you can
see some of the things they're an expert in essentially That's your value proposition.
Why should people be following this it can't.
What are you going to help them to do.
And so there are some of the options there.
So say a little bit about it.
Again bloggers social media enthusiasts etc. you can see a community where marketers and entrepreneurs
come together to to drive traffic increase conversion boost social engagement rates etc. so that's a
good one there because it shows you know why should I join this page or follow them because I'm joining
a community and also a community that wants to achieve these goals.
That's a pretty good bio that I can draw some ideas out of Sudan here more like a personal brand.
You can see top 50 social media marketing influencers so some social proof that's a good idea.
How could I include that into my profile as well here where they're located.
Pinterest for business.
Some of those keywords again and help you scale your blog traffic using Pinterest.
So that's good.
Very focused then on Pinterest and giving it clear value proposition for following this.
We'll look at HubSpot.
Now go ahead and follow these guys.
You can see all in one marketing software that brings your marketing word of mouth together.
We also like to have some fun so little bit of personality coming across there in the BIOS as well.
So when you look at other topics in your niche you can really take the best from those.
Look at some of those ideas and put them together to create your own about you bio.
OK so I feel that my buy me I said to her that is and can be wrong.
So that's something to try and catch their attention a little bit of social proof.
So many students take my digital marketing courses there's my keyword digital marketing follow me for
action tips to grow your business.
That's a call to action.
Follow my Pinterest account.
And then why should you do that.
They get actionable tips to grow their business location then you going to stick this in Dublin Ireland
and then go ahead and click save changes and you might see this saying Oops your username is already
taken.
So you can shorten that then until you find a freezer name or change it around.
Maybe the other way.
So if we come to the profile now we can see that we've got our SEO optimized title we've got our SEO
optimized bio that includes our keywords and we also have a great looking profile image.
So that is how you as you optimize your Pinterest can see you can appear at the top of the search results
and upload a profile image that's going to look professional.
I want people to follow your account.