In this video you're going to learn how to optimize your cure pro Fasi you can get more traffic to your
website and also show you how to identify the best topics for you to focus in on.
So to optimize your profile just click on your profile image in the top right and click on profile and
it's here you'll want the odd headline for yourself and let a little description and include maybe a
link back to your company's Web site or your web site so you can put in something very basic to get
started like your role.
And then in that description you can include a link back to your website or the company's Web site and
maybe include a reason for them to do so or to get curious about it.
So for example I've put in here that 200000 students have taken my courses and that hopefully that creates
some curiosity for people to click through and check it out.
So you don't have to have massive credibility like this.
You can include something that's going to appeal to your target audience and encourage them to maybe
click through.
The key thing to understand here is that I wouldn't worry too much about what this profile says right
now but that you just want to get something down here to get started before you start answering questions
because people will come back clicking to your profile to have a look at this.
After Yvonne's requests see one of deafeningly that link to your company or personal web site and create
some curiosity for people to do that and also just create a title for yourself.
Now an important part of building your profile is to add in the topics that you know about.
You might have a couple in here from when you created your account but we really want to add as many
as possible here and in particular identify those topics which are most popular.
So if you add in another topic that you know about and that you want to attract potential customers
from.
See if I add in Facebook as I can see 110000 followers.
So right all day I know that that is a pretty sizable topic here on Q.
That's tied in something else.
Google Analytics so I can see Eighty thousand people or so already on other Facebook Gad's is more popular
here on core than Google Analytics and eagerly in as many topics as you want.
Course it's going to be different for the type of business that you have.
But you can just keep typing them in and really noticing the amount of followers for each topic because
that'll give you an indication of how popular they are or maybe which is the topic that you should focus
on to get started.
So now it's your turn.
Go ahead into your profile and fill out your headline and description and that in as many topics as
you want so that you can really begin to see the size of them.
And even one when you're out of them you can move your mouse over them to see the number of followers
here and that will give you a sense of which are the most popular topics.
Maybe where you should be focusing your attention.