Congratulations on completing the course.
Now that you are a skilled Facebook advertiser it's time to start thinking about setting up your own
Facebook ads business or working from home.
In this video I'm going to show you three different ways that you can do that firstly by looking at
five or dot.com.
Secondly by looking at up work of freelancing platform and finally how I would set up a digital marketing
agency focus on Facebook ads some of the things that you should think about and really how you would
manage that practically with tools like business manager.
So let's start off with fiber.
Dotcom was spend a couple of minutes on this and the other options as well.
Farver Dotcom is a market place for digital services.
And originally all of the services offered here started at $5 that's how it gets the name fiver or dot
com.
But as you can see now I've typed in Facebook ads and you can see some of the services no longer sort
of $5 but they're starting up $20 $30 and even they can go up and up.
So originally this plus platform was at the very low end of the market small services really bite sized
stuff.
But now it's starting to scale up and grow over the last number of years.
In fact I used to be a top rated seller on fiber and reading on my start online here.
So let's have a look at some of the services that people are offering here in relation to Facebook accounts
and services that you could easily offer as well.
So here's one.
I will design awesome Facebook.
So let's click into this.
Look it's starting at $10 you can move up to $30 and even a $50 service.
I'm just renting up from the Euros here.
So what this guy does is he's designing Facebook ads.
He's not even running Facebook Ads managing them picking the audiences that type of stuff.
Just designing the images for them.
And that's something that you could easily do as well.
Once you understand the 20 percent rule and you understand the dimensions that are needed to fit on
out Facebook and Instagram and even a little bit of design skills you could go ahead and do this is
nothing really stopping you from doing this.
And the interesting thing about this is he has over 847 reviews which if we multiply that by the basic
fee $10 you can see that this guy's probably made over about eight and a half grand doing this and he's
based in Sri Lanka and that's probably pretty decent money there.
So that is just something interesting.
And the point I'm trying to make is you don't have to offer every single step of the face Pickard's
process you could pick out one element become specialized in it and offer it for a very reasonable price
on fiber but make a lot of money through the volume that you build up in terms of sales.
So let's go back and have a look at some other examples.
This is a different one where someone is actually setting up Facebook ads for a business starting at
a higher price point here of around 30 dollars.
So the basic package you can click in here it's seven days.
It's a targeted audience one platform.
One version we can see the standard packet goes up with two platforms.
So that is probably Facebook and Instagram and for versions of some testing done there.
And that's even the premium package $200.
That's basically the month management tracking pixel targeted audiences et cetera.
So $200 per client to continue that management $200 per month per client.
That's not bad if you can rack up 10 clients or make it to around a month and you could probably push
it way beyond that if you have your processes work flow really fine tuned.
But this is a great way that I think you could get started at offering Facebook Ads services on the
fiber platform.
The key advantage of doing it here rather than setting up your own business right from the start is
that five dot com is a marketplace that's really drenched in hungry buyers.
The only reason they're here is to buy services.
It's not like Facebook where they're there to hang out with their friends.
They're just here to buy and that's what makes it so attractive you don't have to do the marketing that
the orders just flooding flooding and you get to work.
So in terms of fiber in general how do you really win on this platform.
Well one of the key things that you can do is to video and none of these services have a video here
certainly Or here's one if I was buying a service if I could see the person's face hear their voice
I probably trust them more and it would be easier for me to put money down behind them.
And that's something easy.
Most people don't do video.
And when I worked on the platform videos were said to have a 200 percent increase in sales if you use
them.
Another thing that is absolutely critical on fiver is their reviews.
You can see the reviews are visible here and it is a big factor that influences the ranking.
So when I type in Facebook it's normally that the highest rated gigs will appear at the top highest
rated services will appear at the top.
So if you are launching a service here you have to make sure that when you put it out there you maybe
get a friend or couple of close associates to buy your gig.
You can start at a very low price like $5.
That's not a big cost to them.
And then you can raise your prices once your reviews have build up and you can really raise the prices
them.
The key thing is getting the reviews initially.
Now as I mentioned I worked on farver before actually a whole course on it.
If you're interested in that you can maybe check that out.
But bottom line is it's a great platform to get started on.
Let's look at some other options you could start working on.
Work dot com and once again I've just typed in Facebook wants to see who's really offering these services
so they're earning at $35 per hour.
So the key difference with this platform is really that people are working on an hourly rate.
They're not defining the exact services that they offer.
Now personally I think it's better to define the service because often the customer doesn't even understand
what they need.
But here in up work it's a little bit more flexible and you really define your work by an error rate
so you can see thirty five dollars per hour in Ukraine that's probably pretty good.
Fifty dollars per hour $640 generic aka air and hundred dollars per hour twenty K earned $60 printer
48.
So there's plenty of people making money and they're making good hourly wages.
Now the key thing here again is the reviews you can see.
Ninety five percent job success.
The percentage of freelancers jobs that resulted in a great client experience.
So once again reviews are absolutely critical.
And one thing you might need to do on a pork.
More than you would on Fiverr is really be clear with the customer exactly what they want to agree on
that.
In real concrete terms before you start the job so that you can meet their expectations because it's
not a defined service and the clients come in from the client side.
You really have to be clear on what you're offering so they're not disappointed.
And the other thing that you can do on work is start to browse for jobs so you can compete on jobs and
a big part of winning business is even to craft together a personalized page for the work.
Most people would just blast out the normal I'll do your job and they have a template that they copy
and paste.
So if you want to weigh in on a book you've got to pitch and make a personalized And so what people
say in the pitches and that'll help you with the work and get those better reviews.
And the third option is to maybe set up your own digital marketing agency and wanted to show you this
example surgical studio.
So what they do is they help plastic surgeons cosmetic dentists and dermatologists get new patients
and grow their business from six to seven figures.
Now if we move down a little bit you can see that they're actually a little bit broader than just Facebook
ads and that may be something you need to do if you really want to go home on a particular needs like
the surgical studio in terms of Plastic Surgeons.
Now this is a good example because number one they've picked a group of people that have a lot of money
plastic surgeons cosmetic dentist dermatologist.
They make a huge amount of money in terms of the services they offer.
Therefore they have a huge amount of money in terms of spending on getting more clients.
So if you want to go to this cruise it's probably best that you try focusing on people who have money.
Lawyers accountants dentists things like that.
People have very small shops and don't even make a big profit themselves probably won't have a lot of
money to give you.
So that's the first thing.
If you want to go down this route try and focus in on a nice night to get started what you could do
is just walk down the road and find a business that needs help getting set up and really just get started
that way.
Testimonials once again like fiber like a cork That's the key thing you need to get your first clients
and maybe you can even start working for free.
So you can walk down into a dentist you could say look a run a Facebook ad for you.
I could even pay for $10 and let's just see the results and take it from there.
Yes you're paying to acquire a comp a customer but that customer if he's paying you a thousand a month
in the long run well then it's going to be worth that so a little bit of investment and you can do a
lot after that.
So those are three different options that you have.
One is five or marketplace.
The other is the work marketplace and three is really to go it alone and maybe start it in your local
area.
Literally getting out and talking to businesses signing them up in all three cases.
The hardest thing to do is get those first clients.
And you should really contact people you know to buy your services or even hook you in and do work for
free.
Start low price build their reviews and work from there.
Now finally in terms of managing this stuff day to day business manager is going to be the absolute
key.
Remember that if we come into business settings here and you want to work on behalf of a client the
key thing that you are going to have to do is come into pages or our accounts here on request access
to their products.
So if we come into our accounts we can add a new ad account and we can request access to their accounts
so that we can re work on it.
And the key advantage of doing this is that they will have their credit card on their account.
So we're not paying for their odds.
We're they're paying for their ads themselves.
And then we have agreed a fee separately which they will pay us maybe at the end of the month.
And your fee could really depend on whatever you've agreed with them that you will run three campaigns
and set up the stuff just like you've seen here.
You could even copy and paste what this guy is offering an offer or something similar.
And there's plenty of agencies that you can look on line to see exactly had a stroke shooting.
Or you could base it on results like get you certain amount of conversions visitors per month.
Whatever way you want to structure it so the opportunities are there.
There's nothing stopping you.
You have the skills the platforms are wide open.
It will take time to build up but it's very easy to work from home and start to face God's business.