So I'm going to share five of the best digital marketing tools to grow a business.
I use them all on a daily basis and they're all absolutely free.
I'm also going to share at the end of the video this list with all of the tools that we'll be looking
at which are start here plus some of my other favorites so hang around to the end and I'll share that
list.
So the first tool is similar Web dot com.
And if you want to get a digital marketing strategy for any business in about five minutes then this
is the tool to use.
All you need to do is go ahead and type in a competitor or a Web site that has a similar audience to
the one that you want to attract and just type it in and similar way boom creates a big marketing report
here really showing you behind the scenes look at how they get web site visitors.
So I've typed in arm brothers here which is just an e-commerce site that send sells men's bracelets
and we can see straight away how much traffic they're getting per month.
What are the countries that the traffic is coming from.
What are the different marketing channels that they are focusing on.
Even the Web sites that are sending them traffic water even the phrases and words that people are typing
into the search engine that are bringing them to their site and also even water to some of the phrases
that they're advertising around.
So with this information I can really figure out you know what is this social media channel they're
focusing on.
I could create content around these terms as well from my own site.
And it's just an incredible look behind the scenes at any business and how they market it.
Now you're not able to get this information and in fact you know Arab brothers probably are not too
happy that all this information is out there but with similar web you can really see how they market
their business see what's successful for them and you can take and apply those strategies for yourself.
You can do it for three or four other competitors and you can get a really clear picture of what marketing
channels they're focusing on even go into say their Facebook see what posts they're making and you don't
have to do a lot of guests guys.
All of the proven strategies tailored specifically to your business are out there.
So check it out on similar web.
You can use it for your own business to get a digital marketing strategy for any client that you come
across.
And also you can research the companies they are interviewing for and really show them in a lot of detail.
I know how you guys market your business and I can help improve x y z.
So that's the first tool similar Web really a key tool for any digital marketer.
Now the second tool is Google Trends and this is incredibly useful tool.
Once again if you want to find sizzling hot topic ideas for blog posts or YouTube videos then there's
no better tool than Google Trends.
And that is because Google Trends really shows you what the world is searching for.
So how I use it if if I'm thinking to create a say video or blog post around something like WordPress
what I'll do is come in and type that into google trends come then and change this filter to the last
30 days.
You can change the country as well if you want to.
Really what I'm looking for here are these break out terms I can see that WordPress 5.0 it's up one
hundred and ten percent over the last 30 days and we're press 5.0 is break at meetings way above you
know even one hundred and fifty percent so as a marketer what does that telling me.
Well it's telling me over the last 30 days.
You know there has been an explosion in interest.
People typing into Google WordPress 5.0.
So if I could create a YouTube video or a blog post explaining what WordPress 5.0 is its features its
benefits its release dates etc. then I'm going to easily be able to get to the top of the search results
or the top youtube video because if it's in the last 30 days you can be guaranteed that not a lot of
other people have created content on this topic and Google Trends and is really looking at these breakout
terms solves a key problem.
If you're a new business how do you really get found when a lot of the big topics are saturated every
good company is made of you know something about Facebook ads say a blog post.
If you were a new company how would you do you want to come look at these breakout terms and that really
gets you to the top of the search results or get huge amount of shares because there is incredible interest
in these new breakout terms.
So that is the second to Google Trends You can use it again for your own business for any clients business
or again come into an interview with some incredibly ideas about content that they could make that would
really suit their audience.
Now the third tool is kinda dot com.
And if you want to save money on stock photos and expensive graphic design software like Photoshop then
you can use COM dot com.
Now as a digital marketer it's really essential that you make know images for your Facebook guides blog
posts youtube tutorials and you want to be able to do that yourself quickly so that you can make changes
and adjustments and can really advise you that they have all these templates.
For example a Facebook post that you can just use you can drag and drop them in here.
You can change the colors you can change the text very easily and so you can really create those eye
catching images and really some basic graphic design skills are really essential as it is digital marketer
now.
So you can add huge value to your business your marketing clients business or again have some extra
skill on your resumé but coming in practicing and getting familiar with can dot.com.
Now the fourth tool is a Chrome extension called vid IQ and this is for YouTube.
Now YouTube is the second biggest Web site in the world and the second biggest search engine in the
world.
So if you want to get traffic and build an audience on the second biggest big biggest Web site in the
world and video IQ is a tool that would really help you do this.
So personally how I use it is if I'm considering making a video on a topic say for example Google Analytics
I just type that into the search bar in YouTube and then video iq.
Once I've got the chrome extension extolled brings up all this extra information at the side here and
I can see for example under the keywords score that this term Google Analytics gets a huge amount of
search volume in YouTube it's not that's up at the top ninety three in the green.
So that's good.
But the most important thing as well is in terms of the competition.
So this is also in the green and this is actually the sweet spot that I can see that overall this keyword
has a score of 81 over 100 meaning that if I was to create a video on this topic I'd have a very good
chance of getting to the top of the search results in YouTube because there's not a lot of competition
but there's a huge amount of search volume and there's a lot of other things you can do it fit IQ but
that's one of my favorite little features that really helps me plan my content in order to get in front
of my audience so that IQ grade too especially if you want to focus then on video marketing and YouTube
marketing.
Now the fifth and final tool we'll look at is the keyword everywhere chrome extension.
So again this is a Chrome extension so you need to be using the Chrome browser for this.
But once you've got it installed what you were gonna be seeing is underneath these search bar in Google
you're going to see this metric here which is key.
The search volume per month so I can see for example you can type in any phrase here.
So online marketing course.
When I was creating my online marketing course I thought I'd name it.
The complete online marketing course and I was like OK well that gets eight times one hundred searches
per month that's pretty good.
But then I was like What about if I change this to digital marketing course.
Are there many more people searching for this compared to online and you can excuse the all caps.
But I saw an ad that's 60000 people per month are searching for that.
So that's just one word in the difference.
But seven times the amount of people are searching for that term.
So what did I do I rename my course to complete digital marketing course I expanded my audience by seven
times.
And so vid are the keyword ever chrome extension is something I use on a daily basis three they test
the name of products blog posts ideas to really make sure that I'm appealing to the broadest audience
possible.
So in terms of content ideas like how to get more views on YouTube I type this in and I was pro twelve
thousand one hundred people per month are searching for that.
Maybe I could create a video on that and you can even star these searches for as well and it adds it
to a list.
So another incredibly useful tool to really validate the demand for your products or the content ideas.
So that wraps up the five best digital marketing tools and how I use them on a daily basis.
I've included them all here in this list which you can access by clicking the link on the description
the five tools we looked at our start here and there are also some of my other favorite ones here as
well you can see this is extremely popular so go ahead and set those tools up for yourself so you can
really use them to grow a business and get incredible results at your digital marketing.