In this video you're going to learn a very quick and simple way that you can reposed other people's
content on Instagram and reposting content like the image that you can see on screen here is not only
a way to really get free content and to publish on Instagram but it's also a way to connect with other
in ceramic cans.
So for example on screen here you can see Dave Ramsey has reposted an image from another catch.
Jenny eats donuts and you know that this is reposted because it's showing it in the bottom left hand
corner of the image and also in the comments below.
Here you can see hash tag he posts.
So Dave Ramsey has added a Commons on top of the original comments which you can see is down here and
it's a great way you can see got 15 times and likes and it's a great way to maybe highlight someone
and your audience is doing very well.
Hit it go like this that you're trying to encourage other people to do.
We're just somebody that senior space or similar kind that's doing something really cool.
You want to share with your audience so just a fantastic way to solve the content problem on Instagram.
What do you post.
And also just make connections as well in scrammed is all about engaging with people.
So if you want to post other people's content like this very easily.
Well then you want to go into your browser and you want to go ahead and download repos for Instagram.
This is a separate app that will allow you to repo's just like that example that I Shoji.
So you can see it's on the left hand corner here and it's got 40000 reviews and it's absolutely free
as well.
And once you've got that downloaded then you just want to open up the repo's stop and you can see that
you can click into Instagram and what you want to do here is really go ahead and look for any posts
that you might want to repose so let's just come into this again.
And maybe let's think about if I wanted to repost this as an example.
I click on the top right hand corner the three dots here I'd copy the link and you can see that link
has been copied to the clipboard inside the reposed free Instagram app.
So what I can do is come back to at the repo's for Instagram.
I can see it's been copied there.
Now I want to go ahead and repost thus us and you can see now that I've got the image with the little
pre-post symbol and the account holders name in the bottom left hand corner of the screen.
So now I can go ahead and click reposte
and it's going to show you how to paste the caption.
So this is great as well.
Saves you typing a the caption that they originally had.
And I'll show had to do this you just literally go down and click paste.
It's actually copied in the clipboard as well as the image really just takes that a couple of great
steps.
Why this app is so cool.
So I got that.
Now I want to share it to in Stroom.
It's going to open up.
I can pick sharing my story on my feet as usual and then like uncropped for if I need to just click
next.
And select a filter for one to click next.
And here is where we write the caption.
So what I can do is hold then my finger and you can see now if I click paste that is going to be the
original comments from Gary V and you can see it even says reposte and it mentions the OP there as well.
So what I can do is go ahead and add in my my own comments
if you wanted to.
And you can put in your comments as well and then you just click OK and then you click share.
And now that has been shared or reposted on my Can't you can see it's coming up under my name.
You can see it's as the kind of the image there re post-cart V and then you can see my commentary if
I'd put in a bigger column it would have appeared there.
And then the original Colman's under me.
So that's a great way that I can share something I think is interesting from other accounts on Instagram
with my audience that's valuable content for them.
Also it takes a couple of minutes you know a lot easier than creating your own content maybe and also
maybe be able to re start to form a conversation or a relationship this big it can't.
Now this particular guy is quite a big account but he can do with maybe smaller cans and make those
connections and start those conversations a lot quicker.
Now if I come back to my profile you can see that that's there on my account as well.
So that is how you repo's on around very quickly and easily.
The key to it all is this re post for Instagram app which is absolutely free and you can go ahead and
then load it really makes the process a lot easier.
So I hope you enjoy that and make good use of it.