In this video you're going to learn how to create your own Linked-In group.
And this is one of the best tactics to build your brand and generate leads to grow your small business.
So we're going to run through the three important steps you need to complete.
And the first step is actually just to go ahead and create the group.
So to do that log into your Linked In profile come across to work and then you'll see the option to
go over to groups.
And then if you come to my groups you can see the option to create a group now in here you can see that
you can give your group a title you can upload a description a logo includes some rules and you probably
want to leave this as the standard groups.
It can be visible in search results so people can find it.
Other members can be invited to it.
So in terms of what should you be putting in the title the logo and the description.
Well really.
You just want to communicate the benefits of people joining this group what is this group about.
Is that a topic like social media marketing and in that description then you know what is the benefit
of this group learn strategies for social learn the latest strategies for social media marketing that
can grow your business better.
You need to get across the benefits there so that is step number one just simply create a group.
And if you're a little bit unsure about this you can always come in and discover some groups to see
the titles that they've put in to see some of the descriptions here that they've put in.
And you can just have a glance through those two to really help you get started setting up the group
who we're having problems with that.
So step number one is just create your own LinkedIn group.
Now step number two is where it starts to get interesting.
This is where we want to find people to join our group and to do that.
Let's go back to living in essentially what we want to do is funnel people who are already active in
similar groups back to our group.
And so to do that let's just say I'm going to search search for Social Media Marketing and we can see
that I'm seeing all these search results here people jobs content companies.
But I really want to filter this tend to groups.
And so what I want to do is go ahead and start to join these groups.
Now I'm a member of this and already see just keep working day and through the live list.
You can see two million people on this group which actually I've requested to join.
So you don't join immediately you need.
You may see a pending and so you can just keep going and through the list and you can become a member
of up to 50 groups.
They may not approve your request to join straightaway but usually it's done with in 24 hours.
So that was Step number two just join up to 50 relevant groups that already contain your audience.
Now Step number three is to come back to the group section again.
And really we want to have a look inside of these groups that we have really joined here.
So let's go to this one looks quite active.
And now what we want to do once we're inside one of the groups and we're approved as a member that we
want to click on the members tab here.
And once we are in the member's tab then we can actually start to message people directly for free.
We don't have to pay to do this and we could send a personalized message invite them to join our group
and paste a link to our group in there as well.
See you can work down through the list if you want and them as you can see there's quite a lot of people
in this group.
So sometimes it's a good strategy to actually come in and maybe look at those smaller groups say this
one here that has a smaller number of members 444 and you can invite them personally or you can just
take the time to go through.
Have a look at their profiles and see are they really a good fit for you on.
That is a great way that you can read just build up a viable pool of your potential customers.
So inside of your group what you can do is just maybe block any from competitors for getting in.
You obviously want to demonstrate your valy demonstrate your expertise don't be overtly spammy or sales.
But it's hugely beneficial to have all of your target audience in one place.
So now that you know how to create a group on LinkedIn consider using this tactic for yourself to build
your brand and generate leads to grow your small business.