In this video I'm going to show you a real quick way to come up at your first five tweets on Twitter.
And what we wanted to do is once again look at the top influencers in our age that we are following
and it's from these top influencers can center Naish that we're really going to get the ideas for our
first five tweets.
I'm going to go ahead and open up the five or six influencer cans I'm following here.
And this is where we're going to get everything that we need in order to come up with the ideas for
our first tweets.
Now to be clear what we are trying to achieve here is just to build some content on our Twitter page.
We don't expect to get any likes or engagement on these tweets because we have no followers.
So the purpose of doing this is to build out really a sample of the type of content and tweets that
we'll be putting out.
And then when we do go to encourage people to follow our account they'll get a clear understanding of
okay what is the what is the content you're putting out and why should I really follow you.
So the best way to come up with that content is just to look at these influencers.
And so what we can do is come in one by one and have a look at these.
So really what we're looking for are tweets that have had a huge amount of engagements on what we can
do if we to like a tweet.
We think it's a good idea it's maybe something we can do we just simply like this.
And then what's going to happen is if we refresh this we should see now in our likes top here any content
that we've liked and this can really be our short list of ideas for content that we can put at.
So I'm going to go through some of these.
Can Pick a side some ideas and then show you how to really make your own posts.
So I think that is a great piece a great some something that we could do or something that we could
retweet and even comment on.
So what we've got here another great post he's sharing an article from a nother Web site in the nation
but he hasn't just shared the article he's added his own comments as well.
And that's something that's interesting and something that we could do as well that is a much better
way to get engagement and engage in the conversation on Twitter not just post a link but give your opinion
or say something about that and add your own little twist on to it.
That's a way to create a post very easily even if you're not creating the actual article that's there.
So let's keep going then.
OK so he has here a link to a blog post that he made.
So he's using Twitter to share blog content.
That's definitely something we could do as well.
OK.
Here he is.
He's been featured in the book not something that we could do probably immediately as Brown you can
but it is something.
Again and he's sharing a blog content sharing your blog content as well.
And here we go some some more kind of comments on different things that we could do useful shortcut.
Maybe that's something we could do is a huge huge useful shortcut.
Quick tip like that and let's move on to another influencer then to get more ideas.
And this is more of a business account.
OK.
A simple way to friends to gift k a video.
This is a video uploaded to Twitter you can see it's got 1500 views so that's maybe something we could
do just record a quick video from our phone posted to our Twitter profile.
Wouldn't even have to look that professional but it gets a good amount of views and something very it's
a different type of content you can see it's very eye catching in the news feed here and even on their
profiles page it is something very attractive and really catches the eye.
So scrolling down a little bit is early retirement realistic dreams so that's a good kind of question.
At the start of sharing a blog there so they've asked a question to kind of hook you in.
And then they posted the the the blog there what investing questions you have for our experts.
OK.
So that's something interesting it's probably something I can do maybe not immediately but definitely
in the future.
And then they've got links off to their blog posts here.
Let's move on to a another example.
You can see just by going through different accounts he can build up ideas quite quickly.
OK.
So Calment What's the worst job you ever had.
They're really sharing at a blog post here.
But again as you can see they're trying to engage people in the conversation rather than just dropping
the link.
So that's pretty easily something we do here they've retweeted a visual image from another account something
Daphne we could do that's not too hard.
Moving on slowly then
sharing an article.
Ok sad news.
Again just read tweeting someone else that has a lot of mentions.
That means that something good that we could do because if we read tweet this something like this and
all of these people will be notified.
And that gets us on their radar.
So let's keep coming down.
Now as you can see it can take you a little bit of time just to go through.
But it's definitely much easier than trying to come up with stuff yourself.
Just come through on like these.
Did you ever use your shop Happy Monday.
True common.
I mean that's not too hard to do.
Or have a great weekend.
Maybe that's even a better thing to do if we've no audience it's maybe just to just say Happy Monday.
That's something we can do.
It's Monday today.
OK I'm going to take a minute just to have a look at some other ideas here.
Here's something interesting interesting I find you know the boom is back.
When you buy a coffee at a train station on the estate agents or advertising on the paper cup so that's
a something that is noticed just out and about.
It's a simple picture.
I mean taken most likely from his mobile phone and then just tweeted out.
And it's commentary on what's happening in the world.
Very simple.
I could definitely do that.
Now coming down we'll look at the final profiles in number six and that's pretty cool.
I mean it's just the team from their business in their Christmas jumpers.
It's around Christmas time now and them.
So anything seasonal is also a great thing that you could tweet out initially.
You wouldn't need to have a huge audience for that and it just looks great.
People get a sense of who you are who your team is and that's something very easy you can do
OK.
So I've collected some ideas for my first tweets from those influencer cants disclose close all these
then so we can focus in them.
And I'm just going to refresh the page sort of 13 like so already there.
I have 13 ideas about what I could do and this is how you can come up with your first five or 10 posts
on Twitter.
Just look at what influencer is doing.
Like any one that you think you could easily replicate and then you can go ahead and do this.
It's very very simple videos.
You've got comments you've got sharing blog posts we've got comments on other articles and we have really
questions that they're asking the audience as well.
So what I'm going to do is go ahead and start doing my first tweet straightaway if you've got any other
tweets there that you just did for practice.
You can go ahead and delete them.
And one tweet I like there that was in our list was happy Monday.
We're almost near Christmas as well.
So what I can do is days.
So you get seven days of Christmas.
What I can do is be Monday.
Seven days
and maybe I can even put in a gif here.
So these are gifts that are actually built into Twitter.
That's putting in Christmas.
You can find free search for these.
So you something like this could be pretty funny just to put in it shows that it's seasonal it shows
that the account is active.
And there we go it's kind of a happy Monday to me.
But also seven days until Christmas and that's going to resonate with anybody who sees our profile right
now because it's timely.
It's something to do this Christmas and it definitely catches attention and something else that I think
I could do straight away.
Is we saw this conversation down here while we can actually do is read tweet tweet but we don't want
to just re read tweeter.
We want to add a bit of our comments as well.
So we want to have some content on our profile that relates to our topic and in this example just setting
up a personal finance type Twitter account.
So the tweet here originally is I think Bitcoin is a ridiculous Bacula But bubble and we can really
outer uncomment in here we can certainly like some heated debates.
In this thread
personally
it's a bubble
What do you think.
So there we've kind of outed our commons.
We've said water opinion as we've also asked a question as well.
So if we come to our profile now we've got something here that really odds are common as well to something
else that has been written about and then really lays the foundation for a contest.
So once again we're not trying to get likes and comments and shares on the streets.
We're just trying to build the base of content on her profile so that people can see when they do come
in when we kind of go after them the followers that they understand what we are actually tweeting about
and why they should follow our Can't.
So to recap in order to find the first 10 or five posts have a look at your influencers that you are
following and any common site you like where any tweets that you think you could do just simply go ahead
and like them that will add them to your life list and then you can use that as a list of ideas for
you to work on.
So go ahead and do that now.
Or put this strategy in your back pocket for pocket for later.