After you have targeted your ad campaign by location and language the next step is to determine your
bids and Budget.
Now by default this would probably show up as manual CPC manual cost per click and over on the right
here we can get an explanation of what this is.
It really allows you to set your own maximum cost per click for your ads so you can say I only want
to pay one dollar for a click.
You can set that up now.
Now this is a manual bidding strategy because you really set that cost per click your self.
But there are also automated bidding strategies.
And I just want to give you a high level overview of these.
But ultimately for this example and for your first campaign I'd recommend you do manual CPC so you can
really keep the costs low and not let things kind of go out of control.
So if we come over to target CPA we can see this law is here to set the bids to get most conversions.
So if you select this option you won't be saying that I want one dollar per click you will be saying
I want to really increase my bids as much as possible to get a cost per acquisition.
So if we click in to that in order to really for AdWords to determine their cost per acquisition they
need to be measuring how many ads there resulting in acquisitions.
And so to do that you need to set a conversion tracking so to use this type of automated bidding strategy
there are a couple of extra set setups steps and that would really require you to put a little piece
of code on your Web site so that words can see which ads are resulting in the most amount of conversions
and those conversions could be email sign ups.
They could be even in sales on the site.
So I won't go into all the details but I just want to briefly run through these other automated bidding
strategies do you have a understanding of what they are and target or OAS target return on ad spend.
So this is a slightly different metric you're not trying to get that cost per acquisition you're really
trying to get a target return on ad spend and once again you would have to set up conversion tracking
and to really get that done.
Next up we have maximum Quick's.
So if you just want to get the maximum amount of clicks on your Web site well then this is the option
that you would select.
Next up with maximum conversions.
So once again it's just getting the maximum amount of conversions.
Not even for a targeted cost per acquisition which is the maximum again that would require conversion
tracking.
Moving on then we have target search page location.
So this is say for example if you wanted to appear in a certain position on the search results then
they will automatically bid as much as they need AdWords will automatically get as much as they need
to get say to the first spot.
So you can imagine that that can get pretty expensive.
So you want to be careful if you're selecting that strategy and target outranking share quite similar
but it's not that you're just getting to say the top spot that you could be ranking a competitor.
So for example if I wanted to always be ranking you da city.
Well then I could select this option and really put in the domain that I want to rank and then I'll
always be ranking them.
Now coming on than I have in hand CPC.
So again we need set up that conversion tracking and this will just allow you to get the it will actually
raise your bids for clicks that seem more likely to lead to a sale or conversion on your Web site.
So that is just a brief overview of those automated bidding strategies.
You can see there is that extra set up process for conversion tracking for a lot of them.
And the dangerous thing I think if you're a beginner is that you will be handing over the the bid to
Google Adwords for them to determine.
So that's why I would recommend you really just stick with manual's CPC to get started.
So you can really understand and control the costs for your first campaign.
Now budget I would recommend you keep it pretty small.
You can just put it in as 20 euros per day to get started.