By now, I'm sure you've had enough of evaluating anti-patterns.
Let's look at a better approach of producing JSON than
string concatenation or formatting, a generator API.
The Jackson generator API is a way of producing JSON where the programmer
explicitly creates JSON for the values you want to encode.
So you call a series of methods saying things like writefields, writearray, etc.
There's no automatic conversion here,
just a simple lightweight API that puts you in full control.
Again, in order to see how this works,
we'll talk through the same loan application to JSON code,
but using a generator API.
In order to create a generator,
we need to begin with by thinking about how do we get a JsonFactory.
We're going to create a JsonFactory.
And this was a factory object that will allow us to
create the generator object itself.
So we're going to create a generator.
A generator needs to wrap some underlying output system.
So we could wrap a writer, wrap an outputStream, you can use a file.
There are different options for what you want to write around.
And here, we're just going to wrap up System.
out and create a generator.
That means whatever method calls we make on the generator
will eventually get delegated to System.
out as the objects being produced.
So let's start here by writing the start of an object.
So when you have a generator API,
you make method calls on the generator itself in
order to produce corresponding JSON.
So we've got things like writeStart of an object,
writeEnd of an object, and then we can.
flush.
If we just run this code,
we see here that we have produced our generator API object.
This here is just the toString of our loan application that we saw earlier,
so we can ignore that for now.
This is where the interesting JSON version of the object will come.
So we need to write a few fields here for the loan application.
We can write different fields by calling these different write methods.
In order to write a field here, you have to write it in a type-specific way.
So you have to say something like writeStringField of the name and the value,
and then we need to write another one here for those two values.
And if we rerun this code, we can see, for example now,
we've got the name of the person and the purposeOfLoan.
Now by default,
our JSON generator will format the value that's output
in the most compact manner possible.
So it won't pretty print it at all.
It will just write it out as fast as possible.
But actually, we have complete control out of that.
So we can say set a pretty printer and we use the DefaultPrettyPrinter.
So the pretty printer is just a way of customizing the formatting of the output,
and we can see now that we have a much better,
a more interesting output that's easier to read by pretty printing it.
So we've got those two basic fields in.
We also need to write out another thing here, which is the loanDetails object.
Create that method.
I'm going to parse this generator down here,
so we're going to take that generator.
Here we need to first of all write the field.
Then we're going to write the field name here for the loanDetails object.
And I need to throw an IOException because potentially
your generator can be delegating to another stream that
could also throw an IOException, so it will throw an IOException.
Then, we need to write to the startObject.
Then we need to write to the end of the object at the end.
And in between those two things, we are going to write a few fields in.
So we need to write a number field here for the amount
of money in the loanDetails object.
And this is one of the interesting things about the generator API is type-safe.
So that writeNumberField object is overloaded.
And in fact, if we look at the overloads here,
we have lots of different overloads with different numeric types.
So you can only.
writeNumberField as a value and that ensures that it gets the right formatting.
So, for example, strings, when you write them out as JSON,
have to be formatted with double quotes around them,
numbers don't.
So this helps you remove one of those classes of errors
that we saw earlier in terms of the typo.
So I'm just going to.
toString that startDate for now, and also, the same thing with the endDate.
If we just see what that code looks like now,
we can see we've got our loanDetails object within there.
Nicely formatted, nicely set up.
And finally, we're going to say toJsonString loanApplication.
getJobs.
And we need to write another method here.
It's going to take a list of jobs as a parameter.
Firstly, again, we need to write the fieldName here.
This is another subfield within our parent object,
and then we're going to write out the array for the
different jobs,. writeStartArray.
Now we saw earlier when we had objects, we have StartObject and EndObject.
Arrays, in JSON, because they start and end with square brackets,
they need to be formatted to start and end appropriately.
So we have a different method call here to start the array and
end the array rather than starting the object.
Now at this point, I want to take each job.
In my jobs array, I want to write some output.
So I want to write the start of an object this time,
write the end of the object, and let's write a stringField for each job title.
And then,
we want to write a number for the annualIncome
because obviously that's a number.
It's an amount of money.
And then finally,
we also want to write a number field for the number of yearsActive.
I think you get the point at this point.
And if we rerun that code, we can see that we've got all our jobs down here,
and the whole correctly formatted JSON approach.
Well the generator API was better than writing JSON serialization code by hand.
It gave us an abstraction.
This meant it was less susceptible to small errors.
We wouldn't, for example, be producing JSON that lacked matching brackets.
It also meant that it was less work to update or maintain the code in question.
When we want to add or remove a field from an object,
we just add or remove a writeField method call rather
than the whole formatting operation.
The generator API though was an improvement on handwritten code,
isn't the peak of humanities endeavors in the JSON sphere.
We can actually simplify this code even more,
or in a way, remove it all together, and that's what the third approach you'll learn about today uses.