A technique that can help you evolve an API in a more reliable
and maintainable manner is to use versioning.
That is to say assign versions to the JSON schema as it evolves.
How does this help?
Let's go back to one of our initial scenarios for using JSON,
which was to exchange information between services.
Each service can produce and consume JSON as part of its protocol.
The JSON is sent and received over the network on top of some other protocol.
Now one of the interesting things and a big advantage of
running different services in production is they can be
deployed independently of each other.
This means that a new version of one service can be deployed
with a new JSON schema and protocol whilst the other version is
still running on the other side.
In order to support the situation,
the newer service may need to be able to produce and consume
requests and responses that the older service can understand
until the older service can be updated.
One way of making this situation easier to manage is to
version the changes to your JSON schema.
It has several advantages.
Firstly, easier debugging.
If you're running different versions of a service
that update their schema production,
the ability to inspect messages and easily identify which
version of the schema is being used for a given interaction can
really help understand what's going on.
Even if you deploy all your services at the same time in lock step,
it can sometimes be the case that one system hasn't
been updated and upgraded properly.
Secondly, compatibility is easier.
An endpoint that cannot support multiple versions of a JSON
schema can more easily do so if it can simply check the version
of a document and act accordingly.
This may include rejecting a request from old clients that it doesn't support.
Finally, schema evolution.
Again,
by simply being able to detect the version of the JSON request or response,
makes it easier to evolve your schema.
You can perform different behaviors and try to be compatible with
different versions if that's a possible and desirable goal,
which it often is because it keeps your software working.
There are a couple of things to bear in mind when we look at versioning.
Firstly, we need to think about when to actually version.
Not every JSON schema needs a version.
If you're always planning on deploying both the
consumer and producer at the same time, then there is no need.
A good example of this is if you're using JSON between a
JavaScript single-page app and a Java server.
If the single-page app gets deployed with the Java server,
so they both get deployed at the same time,
it keeps things simpler if you can do this model.
But you're still best versioning if you want to maintain
independent deployment of those versions.
The second thing is to ensure that you always bump the
version when the JSON schema changes.
It may seem obvious, but such an easy thing to forget when you're making lots of rapid changes.