Alright,
it's time to wrap up this module and really clarify what
you've learned and build on those ideas.
Now, to many people, the binding approach might seem like a no brainer,
but actually,
there are circumstances where you may wish to use the generator API.
It's time to have the great JSON bakeoff and compare the two approaches.
For most programs, the generator API is a lot more effort,
whilst binding is really simple.
With binding,
you don't have to modify your serialization code when you add or remove a field,
and you don't have to write very much code.
It offers a lot higher productivity for most simple cases.
It's definitely the best approach, most of the time.
Generators, however, come into their own in a couple of scenarios.
It's possible to customize the output of binding API,
and we'll look at some examples of that later.
But sometimes,
if you want to do complex customization or perhaps write
complete different views of objects,
it can just be easier to write the code using the generator API than
munging the binding API to do things your way.
The other key scenario where generators win is streaming performance scenarios.
Now,
let's suppose you're writing a program that converts a
CSV file into a large JSON document.
If you're going to use the binding API,
you'd have to read the whole file into memory,
populate a large POJO array with all the values,
and then write them back out as JSON.
With the generator API,
you can just stream the values on the fly and have complete control over the way
that they're producing the JSON objects and not have to create those
intermediate objects or read everything into memory at once.
It's much faster and much less memory is used,
so certainly something worth thinking about.
Now, the key takeaway from this module is please,
please, please, for the love of Douglas Crockford,
the creator of JSON, don't write code that produces JSON by hand,
use a library.
We have two main approaches to producing JSON.
One was a binding API that automatically serializes your POJOs.
This works most of the time, but not always.
If you need customization, performance,
or don't have a POJO in your application domain that
represents the message object being produced, then you can use a generator API instead.