Wow!
If you've come this far,
you've probably learned a lot in terms of the binding style
of API for working with JSON in Java.
Let's wrap up some conclusions and analyze when you would
use binding compared to the other APIs.
I think the best way of looking at these different JSON
consuming APIs is in terms of pros and cons.
Like many questions in life,
the answer to which JSON consuming approach is best is really,
it depends.
On the plus side,
a binding API is a very simple way to consume JSON as it
only involves one or two method calls.
It avoids duplicating the declaration of your object structuring
between the POJO and the Java mapping by just using the structure of
the POJO to understand how to do the mapping.
Finally,
it's usually pretty easy to map different domain objects with
annotations as common patterns are easily supported.
On the downside, it's not the most performant way of mapping JSON.
That's with a SAX-based or streaming API that we'll see in the next section.
It can be a lot faster and less memory hungry.
It's also a bit less flexible.
For example,
if you're deserialization needs actual logic to support
multiple different versions of JSON,
then it's usually better to use the DOM API compared with the binding API.
In conclusion, I love the binding API.
It's really simple, it's commonly used, and it's generally great.
But I do want to caveat that this is not always the best choice.
Sometimes its limitations can become a problem both in terms
of flexibility and in terms of performance.
If optimal performance at the expense of complexity is
your next goal when consuming JSON, then our next module covers the fastest parsing API of all.