So if you've gotten this far in the course and you've finally gotten your listing up congratulations.
If you haven't gotten your listing up it's no big deal maybe you're just peeking ahead to see what we're
going to cover next.
Nevertheless if you have it up that's amazing.
Now you're probably getting excited about what's going to happen when are you going to start getting
your bookings.
When are you going to be your first guest.
This section we're going to start going over one of the strategies that you want to employ at the very
beginning when you actually take your listing live.
What are things you should worry about and what are things that you really don't actually need to worry
about.
I think though that one thing that I really want to get across to everybody who's listening and everybody
is just starting out is that the beginning is crucial.
I mean their first four or five guest they are really make it or break it.
If you have a bad experience with your first say two guests and they both leave bad reviews that could
be a deal breaker that could make it such that you cannot take any more bookings because why would anyone
book at a place that has only two reviews.
And both of them are negative.
So I want you guys to focus really hard on making sure that the first guests have the best experiences
possible.
I know that's kind of hard considering you're starting out but you apply a little bit more effort.
You can have a much better outcome.
Keep in mind once you are actually experienced with your B and B property once you've had say 50 60
gasa or even 20 or 30 guess you'll get to the point where this is very much ordinated.
You just know what to do.
You know what works.
You know how to get your apartments clean.
You know what your guests like you know how to deal with bad guests.
When I run out my space I put about maybe 10 minutes of thought into each guest.
Previously when I first started man I probably put a couple hours in each guest.
I want you guys to think about you know as you're taking this course and you come up with any ideas
of things you think will really help the guest have a good time.
I want you to try to pull out the stops for these first couple of guests in the next section after the
section are and currently we're going to talk about how you maximize the guest experience and I'm going
to walk you through how I make sure that every guest has a good experience.
And Sarah is going to chime in too with her tips and tricks.
We're also going to cover things that I know that anybody can do that will make your reviews considerably
better and make the guest experiences considerably better.
You don't really have much of an excuse to have a say like a bad experience right off the bat because
I'm giving you the warning right now.
Don't blow it.
Try extra hard.
Throw these first one or two or three.
And trust me it gets a lot easier after that.