Tip number two I call this the copy paste.
So I'm sure a lot of you are wondering how can I minimize how much time that I spend on each booking.
I think at the very beginning you probably shouldn't focus on how to maximize your effort when it comes
to the guest experience.
Eventually down the road you're going to get to the point where saving a little bit of time here and
there is really going to make a huge difference in your quality of life and how much you get out of
hosting on air B and B what you can do and this is something that a lot of experience has to realize
is when you're talking on Airbnb to guests they all start to ask the same questions.
In my experience it really kind of boils down to really only four or five things that I get responses
usually it's asking about parking asking whether or not they can fit an additional person asking about
dates asking about price.
That is 90 percent of the interactions that I get.
So what I ended up doing was I started making written responses that I could essentially copy and paste
back to the people that I'm responding to what I would do in the first Suttons is I would answer the
question very succinctly and then I would copy and paste it kind of a tag at the end of it and that
tag was in the paragraph and it all I would say is something along the lines of you guys have any other
questions let me know.
And then I would say I have plenty of recommendations or things that I think can really make your vacation
awesome.
I'd love to have you guys in the space something like that.
And that's going to increase your conversion rate on your.
And how many inquiries you get people are asking about your property.
The more enthusiastic you are the more helpful you are.
That always is going to make them more likely to book in and make them more interested in booking.
How much time does it actually save me.
Not a ton of time but if I had to write it out every single time maybe that's a little bit of a pain.
More importantly though what I started doing was writing very long question and answers for once someone
does book or say they're going to book because a lot of times they'll book and it'll send them information
house rules about the apartment.
Again they all ask the same questions.
I just want to confirm that this is your address.
Or how do I swap out the keys or when can I check in all this is included in the e-mail they get.
But I'd say probably 40 percent of people would ask again and a lot of times you get people who are
coming in and three months yet they want to know everything today and they kind of start freaking out
if they don't hear anything within a week.
I have several folders where I just have responses and I just copy and paste very long answers and every
single time I'd copy and paste an answer and someone asked a question that's not on there I add it to
the master list and then I copy and paste it every time that I have to respond.
It never comes off as robotic because they don't know.
It looks like you did actually write it that way doesn't you know unless you set at the top on copy
and pasting this.
So don't worry about it coming off as genuine.
I think if you explained it to anyone that you ever got found out they would just say yes that makes
sense considering how many people book your apartment and come in and come out.
Does it make sense to type it out every single time.
Also this is something that's going to lower a burnout factor.
You don't want to type out every single response unless you really do enjoy doing that.
Personally I don't like to respond to every single person because it does kind of get to a point where
it will be a little bit of a headache because a very large portion of the people that you're interacting
with are people who just simply didn't read the listing or simply don't you know they'll ask you what
the price is for your apartment when it's displayed very prominently on the page.
Do you have any questions about this is posted in the group discussion.