Tip number five I call this the other hosts I should have probably called this the others.
So when you do become a B and B host there's actually some privileges that come along with this.
And a lot of hoes don't use these privileges.
What do I mean by that.
Hosts on air B and B often travel and when they travel they use Air B and B.
So there's no immediate connection to that right.
What does it matter if a host travels.
There just a host right.
Not really.
Actually when you travel there's a little bit of a red carpet effect when a host message is another
host.
And once you are a host and this point in the course hopefully or harvest what you can do is when you
do go and travel you can tell other hosts that you are actually a hotel or your host.
Now why is this important.
Earlier we talked about your begetting strategy and how the biggest determinant and you raising your
price is going to be how many reviews you have and how positive your reviews are.
What's kind of your track record what's your rating when other host travel this is kind of a hack.
It's I would always make sure if you have an option between hosting another host or hosting someone
else pick the host.
Why.
Because hosts have done this before.
They know the ins and outs of it.
Not only are they to give you fantastic tips.
They're in a really especially if their experience they can really kind of mentor you through it.
They also get fantastic reviews.
You know when you have a normal cast and something goes wrong they can very easily attribute that to
you know oh you know the host is incompetent.
I need to tell everyone about it.
You always run the risk of that happening with a host.
They know how much they hate that they've had that happen to them.
They're much more forgiving.
And what they'll do is actually give you candid feedback about what you're doing right what you're doing
wrong and then they'll give you a good review.
And also what they understand is they have reviews on their wall.
They know what are good reviews and what are bad reviews.
On average they usually end up giving you great reviews.
I always whenever I see a host coming in saying I always make sure that I kind of nicely clear the schedule
but I make sure that I can get them in and I make sure that I'm really accommodating to them because
I know you know this is hosting on easy mode right.
Because they've hosted what cleanliness is.
They know what state they should return the apartment and they know how to not get in your hair not
the pain.
They understand that life sometimes gets in the way and you can't meet them for check and they're the
easiest people in the world House because they've been through this and that's why I say always try
to host them.
Fantastic for your wall your review wall it's great for getting advice.
And also it's probably the easiest rental you can now on the flipside when you're traveling make sure
that you use this as well.
Tell people you're a house because they will reciprocate and this is kind of an informal understanding
that hosts always kind of go out of their way to say OK when I see this person wants to stay.
I know this is going to be super easy.
I should give them extra accommodations to be with them.
I don't need to buy them.
You know the bottle of wine or to pull out the stops because they know what to expect and they can regulate
their own experience.
And in many cases I've gotten rentals other places that were listed that were not listed because I said
I was a host.
I've gotten cleaning fees that were listed before removed because what I just said was Hey I'm a host
I can clean up after myself.
Not going to be there that long.
I did a cleaning for my apartment so I know exactly how to turn it to.
That's always been no problem.
They've been more than willing to take up the cleaning fee and you know if you only staying for two
nights I can actually be a big deal if you're staying around $100 a night and the cleaning the is $60
you going to pay a $6 more than reasonable to ask that question.
So if you have the opportunity to host another host Make sure you actually do that especially at the
very beginning because that could really kind of help you out because previously we talked about how
those first five reviews are absolutely crucial.