Hosting Tip Number Six It's called the review.
When I say in their review hopefully you guys recognize that there's a two way system for use in our
BNP.
You're going to see the reviews that people view but similarly you can leave reviews for other people
who stay at your apartment or your home.
And so what ends up happening people who frequently use Air B and B will actually have a review base
and some of them actually thought their profiles with information and photographs so you can see them
before they come.
Really the temp I'm going to give you on this one is that the review you leave the other guest is completely
worthless.
A lot of times guests will give you a capricious kind of mean spirited review and it's completely unfounded
and they usually make a joke or sponsored You know like a rebuttal to that saying Oh well I can also
leave them for review and that's somehow a deterrent from them leaving you a negative review.
It's simply not a let me explain to you why this is the case if you let your property area be has to
verify your property before it actually gets listed.
They list out what your address is.
So if you get a negative review and you get several negative reviews people will stop saying in your
place and you can't then and go and delete your listing and try to start all over again and starting
another listing because it won't get approved by our BNP.
Now on the flip side or the guest that's not the case if a guest wants to stay at your apartment only
verification they do is automatic and it's I.D. verification and only just goes off of a photo of their
face and it doesn't it's not going to match their name or anything.
So if they get a negative review and they notice that it's stopping them from getting a rent again in
Arabic and B they'll just delete their account and recreate it.
I have seen that several times I've had people who come in a group of three and they use one person's
air being a profile and then when I actually know them a little bit it's because the other person and
the negative are few.
So they just use the other person's.
It's very easy to get around this one previously and this is very new.
The review system we have now is very new.
Previously what would happen is a gas would stay.
And then as soon as they leave they can leave review and you can leave review and there's a period for
which that if they don't leave review their ability to do that expires.
And then if they deliver a view they can added it up to a certain point of time a or b and b responded
to a lot of feedback on this negative feedback from the house saying well this doesn't really make any
sense because I can't give them a honest legitimate review because I'm afraid of them having reprisals
against my property which is much more important than their guest account.
So what they did is now have a new system.
It's like a silent feedback system where you don't get to see their review till you give them a review
or you don't get to see their review until you wait a certain amount of time then it goes public.
So that house helped a little bit in the sense that just can't see that you said something nasty so
they can respond and say something nasty back to you.
But they can still edit the review so it doesn't really fix that problem.
They could after the review period see that you actually said something negative about them then go
back and edit their review.
And I've seen that happen why tip here is that don't worry about your view.
Don't worry what it's going to mean for the other person reviewing you if you want a good review and
I want to make sure you have a good review.
Contact them directly.
Make sure that when they leave you say something to them.
You know you say hope you have a great fly.
Really enjoyed having you whatever.
It's something that is going to make them understand that it's a little bit more personal than not going
to be going to be less inclined to give you a negative review.
You leaving them or view and saying something positive about them.
It used to be the case that that would often warrant them in return saying something nice but now it's
not the case because they don't get to see your review and tell Dave posts that there's And they're
very unlikely to go back and edit it add more nice things.
It's just not really the case that it really matters what you say.
Everybody's feedback system is constantly changing that the moment it's not.
And they know that it's kind of broken and that's how they're taking steps to improve it.
It has improved.
It's not perfect.
The one thing I would say about your review and if you do just have time to add reviews at the end and
this is something I've noticed a lot of posts that we started doing was since we knew that guests would
just delete their account or use a different account or just not use their BND as much if we gave them
blatantly negative reviews started using subtler ways of indicating that the person was crazy or the
person was not worth having in your home.
And so oftentimes you'll find someone who has something like that on their profile.
They have a sentence that says the guest was interesting.
Period.
Now if you are aghast reading that doesn't mean anything to you but me as a host meaning that that means
he's probably bat shit crazy.
So look for those subtle cues that is something that for the last two years I just noticed that we would
do that.
Sarah I mentioned previously that you might hear something like saying oh he's eccentric.
If it's not obviously positive that it's actually probably negative because these reviews are actually
worthless.
There's no point really in doing them unless you just want to feel good about yourself.
It's nice as a host being you'll see that they have reviews but this is the point we're looking for
other hosts to put subtle cues on it saying maybe if you have other options you should go with the other
option.
The eyes of any questions just post in the group discussion will get to them.