Here's another big tip that I think will really help your listing.
I've never seen any host actually take advantage of this.
This pertains to photos.
Earlier we talked about how you know it's a good photo and how you going to angle your photographs what
you're going for or where you want in the photo.
Now here's the question.
How many photos do you put.
That's something that there's really no guidance on early meaning to say more photos or better.
I'm going to take that a step further.
Put as many photographs as you can on my listing.
I have 80 photographs actually I think it's over.
Something like that.
It's an insane amount because they don't limit how many photographs you have.
There is no downside to putting a ton of photographs.
No one's going to look at your listing and say oh there's too much information about this listing when
someone's going to pay a lot of money and go into someone else's space.
There's going to be some apprehension there's going to be some feeling that you know they're feeling
a little bit timid about it.
It is someone else's space.
Maybe they're new to this.
I mean the majority of the people who book with me are new to Air B and B.
One way you can dissuade that kind of anxiety is by putting as much information as you can photographs.
You can't fake that.
People have a healthy amount of skepticism when it comes to descriptions and reviews but photographs
it's what you see is what you get.
So put as many photographs as you can.
Don't make it redundant in the sense that as you spin in a room you take one photo every 10 degrees
air B and B and they take their photographs and they come out there.
They're only gonna give you so many photographs and then it's up to you to take your own photographs
kind of fill in the middle.
And I generally suggest doing as many as you can.
There is a limit to how many photographs you can take inside the house before it does get redundant.
One of my favorite things to do and this is really worked in my listening really worked in other hosts
that have suggested this too is take photos of places outside of your apartment not of your apartment
places the person can go.
Literally just take an afternoon grab your camera and go walk to the spaces that are nearby.
It's one thing to say you live next to a 24 hour grocery store.
But another thing is to take a photograph of it.
It's not going to take a lot of this space away from the other photos at all because your analysis at
the end of the gallery of photos the first say 25 photos are of your apartment or many apartments so
small so it's only 10 photographs.
Then you're going to start listing other things things that are on the periphery.
I take a picture of a dry cleaner across the street took a picture of the Walgreens that's across the
street and I use the subtitle to explain what this is where it is and why this is useful Walgreens.
This is a block and a half away.
It's open late and you can get anything you need like SIM cards like prepaid phones medicine it's a
pharmacy travel kits anything you could possibly need.
And listen out just generally what would be useful to a guest if you went to a Walgreens.
Seems kind of obvious right.
But it's on there.
And then I put all sorts of other things I took photos of bars that were near my apartment not even
particularly interesting ones.
I just wanted people to know visually that there are places they can go to get food and get a drink
and their clothes and I took photos of the points of interest that are closest to me and I've said in
relation to where they are how far away this is and then I just put a statement about enjoy the breeze
at Crissy beach or watch the kite surfers at the Presidio.
You might think that this is not necessary.
And of course it's not necessary but it is something that's very nice.
One of the things that I identified with people who were looking to book is that they would constantly
ask questions about.
Is it near a grocery store or is it near a gym is it near a dry cleaning place.
Or how close am I to this point of interest.
And so you can listen on your scription but the chances are that most people don't read the entire description.
People are going to miss that.
But I think a large portion of people who are bucking finish looking through all of your photos and
sense I have the opportunity to put as many photos as I want.
I will put every single thing you could possibly do in my area whether or not you want to put every
single thing that might be an exaggeration and I've never really tested.
I have the same positive response from 50 photos or 80 photos.
But it's my belief that it cannot possibly can be construed as a negative unless you're taking photos
of say a shady area.
People do shy away from areas that look bad.
So I wouldn't take photos of you know if there's a boarded up house right next to your house don't take
a photo of the Boarded up House stress some common sense when it comes to keeping the integrity of your
photographs intact.
Last thought I think is think about this from a competitive standpoint.
Let's say someone's looking at your property and they're looking at someone else's property that other
property is closer to the main points of interest and your city things that people actually want to
go to.
But you included photographs of them in your listing as if there are very close to you.
Not saying they aren't very close but maybe they're not as close as say another listing you're going
to get the booking and you're going to get the assumption that you're closer to it because you've listed
on your listing you want to be proactive about this and it's a great way of showing everything you could
possibly need is close so close that I've taken photographs of the neighborhood.
And these things that you want to see.