Another tip I call it the rambling taxed.
What does the rambling text I'm talking about.
The description on your listing.
You'll notice this that typically if you write a good listing it's going to be below the fold at least
in the new design of European be it more to see the rest of it.
You don't realize though is that I don't believe that they actually have a character limit on the description.
And if they do it's something that's a very very high.
If any of you have ever read any of those sales the kind of letters were they you know they just keep
going on and on pitching their product in their pages and pages of this long train of thought explaining
you want this product for what it's going to do for you.
How that's going to fix everything for you.
There's something to that and not that you should read something gimmicky or sales.
The reason they make those e-mails or those sales pitches so long is because once it hooks someone and
they're interested they will read it to the end and the longer they read the more and more inclined
they are to purchase the product.
In this case you can use that strategy as well.
No limit to how much you can write.
So you might as well just write as much as you can.
When I did my listing I wrote out every single thing I could think of that could be an additional point.
And I just wrote them all.
I didn't have to think about what to drop.
What's not important what's more important I just listed it all.
I mean I literally went in and said I did the walking distances to every single place of interest that's
from my apartment Nejad on Google Maps that took up a lot of space.
You know I listed out every single feature and amenity and I list it out even though it's already listed
on the airplane listing and it's even less so these sorts of things about San Francisco and the events
that are coming up and what you can see from our apartment.
And I think that's one of the contributing factors to my success was that the more you write the more
information you give the more comfortable guests going to feel booking and feel free to ramble on and
on.
I mean if they don't read it they don't read it.
But there's nothing wrong with more information.
And I think that guests can discern from listening that has great photographs but not a lot of tax description
meaning that the host isn't really putting a lot of effort into describing it.
So if you put a lot it gives off the impression and this is the trend more hosts are now writing more
on their description.
It gives the impression that you are one of those top 10 percent of hosts or top 10 percent property
because they can tell you're putting a lot of effort into it.
In reality you can write this rambling text all in 10 minutes.
If you have something you think is additional That could be something that they could be interested
in list it out put it on your list and keep going don't worry about the length.
No one's going to dock you for that.