One thing that definitely separates great hosts from average host is great hosts.
Over time learn how to maximize what they have going for them and minimize their weaknesses.
I mean this in your listing you will list out things that you have great hosts will recognize the things
that they're missing.
Adam I also recognize that things that they undervalued personally that other people really enjoyed.
For instance if you do have parking you might think that what does it matter if I parking but people
might really enjoy that.
So you should learn to maximize that.
How would you maximize your parking.
Maybe you'll put a description of it in your listing.
Maybe you'll put it higher up to the tops of people see it more.
Neither would it.
I and put it in your title.
Maybe I'll put a photograph of the parking spot and then put it in your photo reel.
These are all legitimate ways of maximizing something you have positive going for you.
I have cable cars running by my apartment.
I thought that would have been incredibly annoying because they're very loud and when they go down the
hill at night they rattle because the guys who are running the cable cars back to the start point.
They just turn off the brakes and they just like write it down eat them.
Like yelling sometimes.
Actually I found out was people really enjoy that.
They think it's so quintessentially San Francisco.
They think it's really cool to look out the window to see these things going by.
It's like they're transported back in time.
I didn't realize that and after my first couple of gusts I realized this is actually a positive and
the rumble at first is kind of jarring but the second time you have it it's actually more relaxing.
It's different for someone who lives there try to assess what it is.
If that's the case something that you think is a negative that other things are a positive and just
see if it's something that you are jaded by because you live there and try to maximize those things
that your guests have highlighted for you and then minimizing your weaknesses these are things that
every guest every host should know are things that aren't fantastically great.
Maybe you don't have a ton of space.
How would you minimize that.
Well you focus on how you take your photographs.
You try to fill your room with things that would make your space look larger.
There are certain colors that make spaces look larger.
You might have to reflect in your price.
You adapt to it.
When I was earning out my living room I didn't have doors attached to it to help minimize my weaknesses
as well we end up doing was installing a curtain rod and putting a curtain over.
And then I put a photograph of the curtain covering it.
People can see there's a hole in the wall and they're like oh there's no door.
I tried to minimize that problem by just putting a curtain over showing that in the photographs.
That's a way that you can minimize your weaknesses.
Every property has a weakness.
These are the things you can't necessarily completely overcome.
But if you recognize them and try to at least say like it's not something that you want to necessarily
list in your listing or you can think of a better way of phrasing it letting people know about it.
It's all about the presentation.
You obviously don't want to go out of your way to say you know I live in a party area.
Typically people will know that what you might want to invest in say anything that might help you with
soundproofing things like that.
Basic additions this is something you will recognize on listings.
I think it's where it's most prominent but you won't identify the things that people really like and
you want to maximize your exposure to those you want to make sure everybody knows about those beforehand
and you want to figure out the things that you think actually kind of crush you or put you in a disadvantage
and you want to make sure that you kind of de-emphasize those things.
You guys have any questions or you want more specific examples to Sabino poster in the group discussion.