Here's a bonus strategy that I thought would be worth outlining and I touched on it a tad bit in the
last lecture talking about pricing strategies.
One way that you can almost guarantee yourself bookings is what I call the hotel strategy go and look
at the hotel space around you.
This is especially true in markets that don't have a lot of air be in BS.
You can do the same exact thing you did with Air B and B and you're scoping out the area.
You can do that with Priceline.com Orbitz or Expedia.
They'll do the map and they show a map of what it cost to say the hotel around you.
And then in general what the price range is don't look for hotels that have Olympic sized swimming pools
or offer large amenities sets.
Look for the standard what a holiday and goes for something in the middle like a Marriott or whatever.
You don't necessarily have to go up to a Motel 6.
It makes more sense to look for something that's mid range.
This almost works without fail.
If you have a one bedroom or even a two bedroom look at the hotel price.
Make the calculation in your head and then just offer roughly the same or more and then list your price
at the same or less.
Typically what happens is when people are coming in there's a large contingent of people and I got this
information base of speaking to a lot of my guests that look for hotels first and when they don't like
the prices look for Airbnb.
Or they at least do both searches before they book on air B and B.
So if they're coming in and they're looking for a hotel they'll see the hotel and say it's $100 a night
and then they look at your space and it's slightly better and it's $80 a night that's kind of an automatic
win unless they're fly by night.
Somebody just came in wanted just find a place to crash and leave because they are being is not typically
great for that.
We'll talk a little bit more about how you should probably use the instant book strategy in general
but the couples with this strategy that if you want to compare yourself to a hotel you probably want
to be doing instant book.
We'll talk about that book later if you don't know what that is.
Don't worry.
We're going to cover it.