One of the things that I think is crucial to enjoying this process and thus getting good at this process
is your ability to remove the maintenance involved with your B and B property.
I mean it's I don't mean specifically how many times you call a plumber to maintain your toilet.
I mean the maintenance in terms of say 30 guests or 30 different bookings booked in the next say five
months whatever.
How much time do you spend on each one.
Are you spending several hours a day.
Are you spending only a couple of minutes a day or only spending maybe an hour each week on your guest
what's going to happen when you get to a point where you're removing a lot of the maintenance involved
with your guests.
It's going to become a much sweeter deal.
They're also going to have a lot more free time to think of ways to improve your listing.
And you're kind of kind of have a lot of access time and you need to be able to invest that in the property.
Because a lot of times what happens is you might be doing a share rental and at first you are just sitting
way too much time yourself.
You're doing the cleanings you're doing the check ins and checking in with them repeatedly you're running
and getting the gifts and the small things we talked about before and you're spending a lot of time
with the guests you might be kind of winded when it comes to check in the next guest and you're thinking
about how I'm going to improve on something or maybe something's broken.
How do I replace it.
So what I suggest overtime is you start to remove yourself from the process.
I talked previously about getting a cleaner.
I say this I absolutely get a cleaner get someone you trust as well.
If you get a cleaner who's smart about this knows that you need has some kind of idea of what you're
doing.
You can use that person and you can expand the sphere of responsibilities.
First thing is they're doing cleaning and then you can start getting the extra things like running to
get flowers running to putting together your gift basket.
You can even have them do check ins you can have them do check ins later and check in with the guest.
You could have them be are kind of on call person.
The more you identify someone else who can do these menial tasks for you and you can make kind of a
win win situation with them the better this experience is going to be for you then you're going to be
a lot happier about it.
So first off getting a cleaner.
It's absolutely crucial.
I think that's something that even if you want to be invested in this and you really want to take a
lot of time with each guest that's still something that's worth doing.
I think the cleaning is the most monotonous part second.
Think about whether or not you want your guests to self check.
The second biggest time suck in this process is the check in process that's a process where you are
talking Airgas showing them the area and making sure they have everything you need and then leaving.
In the case that you're running out your entire apartment if you're doing a space leaving to go to your
room also creates a lot of disruptions that your day has to wait for them because very frequently to
say they're at a certain time and they don't actually end up showing up to a later time.
It might only take 30 minutes.
Check the men but you might also be spending two hours in waiting for them.
And that's not very uncommon.
Think about letting themselves self-check in.
This is something that I started using after about month three.
I think what I found out that a lot of people wanted to check themselves in.
It's a little bit weirder when you have a shared space.
You can let them self check in and then you can meet them later.
It's still a little awkward at first and sometimes people have think it's a little too personal which
is fine.
And when I do have to do this say I'm going out and I'm not going to be there and they check and I'm
perfectly fine with that.
I put a key under the mat and I put little sticky notes all throughout the room showing them what is
what.
That's Minick gotten a kick out of a lot of gas a lot of them really like that.
It's like that little personal touch when they have a self-guided walk through.
So it doesn't feel as robotic when I run out my entire apartment.
I just copy and paste the same thing to them saying here all the rules here's how you get here here's
how you find parking Here's how you find the key.
And then everything goes wrong.
Then I actually message them.
That's something you should consider doing.
I mean if you're running out your entire apartment and you've gotten the space to the point where there's
no major amenities that are completely missing and there's nothing in the experience that's just not
ready or not there consider doing that.
A lot of gas like the fact that they can just check themselves in.
They like the extra privacy of that and they're perfectly capable of doing it.
Some of them are not perfectly capable of doing it but they'll figure out eventually as long as you're
available they need anything.
Third point use the copy and paste that I talked about earlier.
You don't need to handwrite every single message to every single guest and every single instruction
guide to every single person.
Use a guidebook in your space when you have people book with you use a pre-written explanation of where
everything is.
That will save you an enormous amount of time enormous headaches because if you're doing this manually
every time you get to remind them of you know how it is you turn on the heat this is where you find
the extra blankets put the towels used the laundry is.
You're going to forget things over time.
And so you're going to have problems where people keep asking you where things are or they keep bugging
you about things that are missing or things that you forgot to mention.
It's much easier to just write one master list and use that as a template to keep copying to people.
The last thing I'm going to say is you know you can even go as far as getting someone to run your check
ins for you.
And also do things like maintenance if you have someone who lives in the area and they're more than
willing to help you out or they're you know in Sarah's case she was using her parents ideas my friends
and sometimes I've hired people and I just pay them.
You know if they live down the street and they are someone who's presentable who you trust to do basic
tasks like this then consider doing that.
I mean it's not going to break the bank by any means but it's also nicer because then you can have that
person run over.
In the case of they need anything they get locked up the apartment and a person can run over.
Also brings up another point.
It's very helpful if you have someone designated as your key runner meaning you have a spare key to
your house.
Guess I'm Kedia House but also someone in the city has a key to your house.
Several times I put a key under a mat.
It disappears.
Someone in our neighbors accidentally took it once one time.
People kept stepping on the mat and it fell off the side of the patio.
These things happen.
And so if you have a backup plan and someone who's relatively available that's going to save you because
if you don't it's a very very bad situation.
So you want to avoid these types of things because these take the mental strain.
Less headaches means you get a lot more fun with this.
That's going to make it such that whatever you do end up making from this it's going to feel a lot sweeter.