Let's talk real briefly about the amenities checklist that you're going to run into when you're listing
your space on air B and B they want you to check off every box for every amenity that you have in your
space so that anyone who is going through the listing can see kind of immediately what do you have.
It's important from the bookers standpoint to know exactly what you have because a lot of times there
are deal breakers in terms of amenities.
I had guests who are very interested in the space but they find out I don't have a TV and so they don't
want to stay.
Now whether that means that they wanted to watch a sporting event or something on TV or maybe they just
traveling with old parents or something and they don't really want to leave the apartment.
But you can kind of tell very quickly that these are kitchen obviously is very straightforward.
You either have a kitchen or you don't.
It's worth noting that when you list this out everything that you do not have is going to be listed
with a strike out.
So it's not just going to list whatever you have to confusing because then people would know what you're
missing.
It's been a list pretty much everything.
There's Internet and wireless internet.
If you're one of those people that only has wired internet then you need to say Internet and you need
to not say wireless internet.
Then you need to explain that in your listing.
We'll talk a little bit later about trying to be as upfront as possible because the more truthful you
are and the better you set your expectations the less likely to get bad reviews and less likely you're
going to have issues.
If you look at the amenities list a couple of things I wanted to point out that are flexible generally
when you want to fill this out you want to think about casting your net as wide as possible again so
try to incorporate as much as you can and really think about each one whether or not you're comfortable
with it.
If you have a washer and dryer consider letting them use it because then you can say washer and dryer.
That's usually a big plus.
One thing I will mention is if you live near a washer and dryer kind of center you can also check these
you'll need to mention it very quickly in the House Rules or in the description saying like oh it's
a block away or two blocks away.
It's this free parking on premises.
In my case we had two hour parking in front of our street so that technically counts whether you rent
out a garage space and let's say it's.
And then give it to the gas free.
That's something you can do.
That's up to you.
I typically would say you want a list and then mention it in your listing to things that you might be
a little confused about.
Breakfast breakfast is not necessarily mean that you have to serve breakfast.
This is not like a traditional bed and breakfast.
Some people run it like that but that's by far the exception that's being allowed.
That's something that I think you should consider.
It's frequently the case that people bring small animals small dogs small cats if you're OK with that.
I mean I would really kind of look into it because that's something that you know it only happens maybe
three or four percent of the time but that's very much a deal breaker for other listings.
And so if you're capable of allowing small pets in your house it'll give you a decent boost and give
you a little bit of an edge against the people around you.
In my experience you know no one is going to travel with their cat.
It's usually they're traveling with their Chihuahua or small dog a couple times I've had people with
special needs that have like sight dogs they're usually very trained.
And it's just something like for instance in my listing all I would say is if you're bringing animals
let me know because it really depends.
You bring up a very large animal.
They have the potential of scratching up our hardwood floors.
You know when you say let us know the animals this is the opportunity where they will take it upon themselves
to explain why the dog is trained and why it's a well behaving animal and you know that they've taken
in other places they don't kind of help you put your nerves at ease and you can always say no to.
I mean you could just say I don't think this is a good space too small.
I think there might be potential for damage.
Smoking Allowed.
And I know Sarah made a point about this later in the course of her space she is it doesn't even see
the point of listing that because she just doesn't allow it.
I don't allow smoking inside my apartment either.
I illicit smoking out as possible because they can smoke outside.
And that's another thing that I kind of need to point out and I've listed that on the space.
If you're afraid of people saying like oh we can smoke outside but you know the host is going to be
there so we can smoke inside and they won't ever know.
You know you have a deposit.
So I would make sure that you use that deposit.
It's not particularly hard to tell if someone's been smoking even after the fact.
But if it's something you're legitimately weary about then maybe it's something you don't want to do.
In my case you know of a backyard so it's not completely accurate to say that you can't smoke at all
family kid friendly Sarazen to talk about that later how do you tell thier faces child proof or family
proof.
When we talk about the listings and what you can say and things you can add you can always think of
adding small things that would make it more kid friendly and make it something that's more attractive
towards kids.
There are a lot of small subgroups of guests who are looking for very specific things and if you can
accommodate more and more of them you can really put together a block of people who are coming a book
like for instance in my apartment people looking for parking that were in families that want kid friendly
spaces that was a very big market for us.
It's the case that those types of groups are in our group to have more purchasing power.
They end up spending more money.
They're OK with the premium and I get away with charging a little bit more.
So it kind of sweetens the deal.
One other thing I to put in here is the gym and I'll talk later about this as a quick tip about how
you can approach the GM has an amenity.
We live near a gym.
We don't have a gym in our space and they don't.
They leave that kind of open to interpretation so it could be in your space or not in your space and
that you should be checking smoke detector carbon monoxide detector fire extinguisher does it pretty
much just standard in and sees those crossed out those that assume that there is some kind of an error.
He has so many other questions that there is any other kind of technicalities I missed this post some
in the group and I can get back to you.