As promised are now going to talk about your pricing strategy and your position strategy.
Now this is all based on the apartments around you and I want you to keep in mind this is kind of all
in theory because we haven't yet listed your apartment.
This is something that you're going to do and it's part of the section called laying the groundwork
or laying the foundation because it's something you need to decide before you go out there and you start
actually taking bookings and you start actually taking photos and listing your space out.
We've looked at all the properties around you.
So now we have a good idea of what we're dealing with what we're competing against.
And previously I had mentioned that you should take a comparable property something that's physically
close to you.
We're going to take that.
We're going to expand on that.
And this is going to be the anchor point to make our beginning pricing strategy take the property that's
the closest to you and I mean the closest to you and a combination of things physical area it does need
to be close to you because location is probably one of the largest determinants of what you can charge
in our popular property is going to be.
But also look for places that similar amenities or similar offerings or even a look to their space.
A lot of times you might not even have something to compare yourself against and if that's the case
and I'll talk about that later at the end of this lecture what you should do if you can't really find
a space that looks like your space.
I'm operating on the assumption right now that you can find on that some more similar the two things
I want you to pick your order to call it the doppelganger.
You're going to look for some on that just property that looks exactly like you what's your doppelganger.
The two big things that you want to look for are location and the better room setup.
Those are the two biggest things that are going to term in your price if you are on you know in one
area and you're on one street it doesn't necessarily have to be a property on the same street but hopefully
it's near you and not so far away from you that it's a completely different product offering.
It's not something that has a large driving distance between the two.
It should be as close to you as possible and in secondary It needs to have a similar bedroom set up
you should not compare a three bedroom to a one bedroom a one bedroom compared to a one bedroom.
You know if you really can't find something maybe you compared to a studio or something like that or
maybe you can discount it a little bit and your hand gets a little bit harder when you do that.
We'll talk about that again later if you have a two bedroom find a two bedroom hopefully it's near you
pass that.
Everything else is kind of gravy it be nice if they had similar amenities in the sense that maybe you
have a backyard they have a backyard you have parking.
They have parking.
You know what do they offer TV to they have a TV you don't really need to get that much granularity
into it.
But the better the fit the accurate this process will be.
Do you have your doppelganger.
Maybe you're going to try to do this after the lecture maybe you're doing it as I speak.
Find that one that you think is close enough.
And now everyone's going to post in the group discussion saying hey is this close enough for my ganger.
Chances are it probably is.
I mean you have a good judge of what's similar especially if you did the previous lectures and you actually
went through and looked at everything around you.
You get a pretty good idea of what's available to compare yourself against.
I'm going to outline three strategies that I know are effective at starting out.
They're all based off of this anchor property this doppelganger property.
You're not necessarily competing head to head with this property but for the practical reasons of determining
what you can charge or what you will charge.
That's the best tool you can possible use.
I think also that if anyone at this point is wondering yes that's nice it's all relative to someone
else.
But what can I actually get from my property.
Find that one anchor property and look at the prices that they're charging.
Look at what they've actually looked at and congratulations that is the absolute minimum that you can
charge for your property.
They're looking out for $150 a night.
You could book out for $150 a night.
The book it out every single day of the month that's forty five hundred dollars.
There was a booking it out for $500 a night.
Wow.
That's a lot of money.
That probably means you could also book it out for $500 a night if you're identical to them.
You might have some price competition but.
Five hundred dollars a night that's $15000 a month.
That's a lot of money.
Don't pat yourself on the back.
Yes.
What you want to do though is again look at that property.
And here's strategy number one take your doppelganger.
Look at what they are charging.
Look what they are offering.
And you can do this on a Scratchie.
And maybe I'll add this in the resources section of this course.
You want to look at what they offer what they charge.
Now strategy one is to design your space to offer the exact same thing as them but you're going to charge
less.
When I see the exact same thing what are you going to think oh there's a lot of things that I can't
do.
You know I don't have a rooftop bar.
I don't have a swimming pool.
Things like that.
Obviously those two you cannot change.
You would be surprised how much you can close the gap in terms of amenities parking you can find parking
TV.
You can purchase a TV.
These are things that are not completely out of the question for what you can do.
You know even if it's the case that they have laundry and you use a laundromat Why don't you include
a $5 stipend or why don't you just put change on the counter for every gas so they can go to the laundromat
that's closing the gap you want to get as close to them as possible and then you want to offer less.
Why does this make sense and makes sense because when someone searches they see these two properties
you want to edge them out for that kind of mindshare.
They'll see you and chances are if they're a savvy consumer and most of them bookers are pretty savvy
they've used this before.
Or maybe they haven't used it before but it's fairly obvious they're going to look at that too and they're
going to do their due diligence because they're spending lots of money to stay at your place.
They're going to look at two of these properties and go oh OK they're virtually the same thing but this
one's significantly cheaper.
That's obviously a value deal right there.
That's a great deal for them.
They're going to think not only are they going to be happy that they feel like they've saved money they're
also going to be happy because they feel like they got the same experience or you know the best experience
they could without absolutely breaking the bank that's going to make them more enthusiastic about your
listing to if someone was running out a studio apartment for $100 a night and it was a studio apartment
had everything you would assume would be in a studio apartment then someone else left to right next
to it and they list it for $75 or $50 you're going to feel pretty smart that you booked it and that's
going to be reflected in your listing are going to say this is a great deal you're going to get higher
ratings and your value strategy number two obviously is very similar.
You want to take your doppelganger and you want to offer more than them but charge the same price.
It's just jockeying you put them in the loser position and don't think of it like oh that's a never
ending spiral if I lower my prices lower their prices lower price.
It's just not the case it's not that competitive the market reactions or the reactions in the host community
are not that fast.
Maybe they might if you have a really active host which is you know a lot of them are very active but
they're not constantly trolling the other properties to see how they're going to edge everyone out.
It's typically something they do at the beginning to see that at least I have an idea of where I'm going
to be and to be honest most hosts actually don't even do this.
But it's not something that you know if you lower $20 they're going to find the next day that they lower
those thing $20.
It's just rarely the case.
So what you could do and this is obviously limited to what you have available is you can go and try
to beat out their property fine with their listing and offer more.
And it might be the case that your doppelganger is one of those properties that just doesn't offer a
lot.
They didn't take a lot of time to add small things.
And later we're going to talk about going to the actual listing and what are small things you can add
to make yourself better and there's a laundry list of things you can do take little money little effort
and sometimes no money no effort that can edge out your competition.
And these are just things that most the host just don't do.
And that's why I'm very confident in Air B and B is a platform that you can make a lot of money off
of because there's a lot of money being passed around and the vast majority of hosts just do not put
any thought into how to position their apartment how to beat out the other people what to offer.
What are things that their guests would need.
It's not a mystery what your guests need and we'll go over that later.
But there are very small things you can do.
We're talking general strategies right now.
Later we'll get into the nitty gritty of how do you actually beat them out.
If you have a doppelganger that is like I said maybe short on the amenities list or maybe you already
matched them maybe already have the same thing they have you go out and just add something.
Get a parking spot or ask your neighbor his parking spot or maybe you know offer a better experience
maybe you can decorate your space a little bit better.
Maybe you can offer better tips for what to do in the area.
Better host support.
That's a huge difference too and that's something that you can make obvious on the front page of your
listing.
It the take away one thing from this lecture other than the actual identifiable strategies that I know
work and it worked for me and I've worked for other hosts.
If there's one concept you can take away from this it's all about product your apartment.
The space that you create between you and other hosts Now you're going to get a lot of space between
you and the other host not necessarily if someone's listening an apartment a two bedroom for $200 and
the next two bedroom is something that is listed for $400.
And the last isn't that much different maybe their fixtures are nicer maybe their area areas slightly
nicer.
There's a big area between $200 and $400 that's huge.
So what you want to do is you want to own the most space.
It's like the price is right.
Does anyone watch the prices right.
I'm sure you guys have.
Now if I bid $5 and the next person bids $12 What's an effective pricing strategy chances are it's probably
in the middle so you're going to want to bid 5 0 1 or you want to bid eleven ninety nine because that's
going to own the most space if he thought it was over that price and you do 12 to 1 or four ninety nine.
You don't want to say six.
Why do you not want to say six because then if the price is 5:49 the person who bid the low bid it's
going to win out against you and there's no point in you bidding in the middle like that.
Similarly you know if you say it's smack dab right in the center at eight fifty What ends up happening
is you just lower the space you can command.
That's a little bit abstract but it seems like basic pricing logic.
Let's go back to that scenario saying if you a $200 apartment and a $400 apartment you want to bid your
thing at say you know make it better than the lower auction but and comparable to the higher option
in terms of amenities and what you offer.
But go and listed it to 25 or to 10 something like that really you're going to eat the lunch for the
person who's listening in at $400 and you're going to get all these people to look at the other place
that's $200 and say oh for an extra 25 bucks I can get a much better apartment.
It's all about owning that space.
And it's something that you do revaluations with every like year or six months because new properties
get listed typically in the case of Airbnb because these are not professionals listing their property
as many properties will get delisted as get listed.
So like in MySpace every time I kind of go in there I'll notice that two new people have entered but
also three people have left or maybe three have entered and two have left.
It's worth checking this every six months or whenever a year I want you guys to know that throughout
this course we're going to teaching you how to be a rock star kind of host.
And that is going to be your unfair advantage against everyone else if you match someone at $200 you
just Samuelsohn the exact same thing.
If you follow the tips and the rest of this course you'll be better than them.
I can guarantee that unless you have the case where you just have that one host who is insane about
this who runs a bed and breakfast on the side and brings all sorts of expertise to this that you couldn't
match.
And here in that case you're going to give them a run for their money again.
Also it's Air B and B everyone ends up winning because they're going to book that property and then
you're available and chances are you're going to get bookings as well.
It's not a zero sum game.
Everyone kind of wins everyone gets money it's just a question of who gets the lion's share of the bookings.
Like I said you have an unfair advantage.
So operate with that in mind that you're going to beat out pretty much everyone else because you're
going to do the small stuff and you got to focus on the low effort high reward tactics that were going
to go over in the rest of the course.
There's one other strategy that I think is effective but it really is dependent on your market.
It's the strategy of offering what's not available.
And I mean that in the case of if you're in a developing market say or hometown or something like that
and some people have discovered and there's definitely bookings but not mature yet it might be the case
that certain things are just not offered.
And so like for instance if you have a two bedroom apartment and no one is offering a private room that's
cheap you might have an opportunity there and maybe you should try to offer that.
Maybe it's the case that there are no three bedroom apartments.
You know maybe have a limitation in the sense you only a two bedroom apartment.
But again we're going to go over this later there's a tap on later in the course to talk about air bed
strategies and how you can actually turn a two bedroom into a three bedroom or at least kind of ostensibly
at least get the bookings for that obviously gets reflected in your price.
But it's a strategy you can use.
So stick around to the course because there's just going to be a lot of big tips around that and other
tips kind of around how you can make your space and twisted into something that you didn't think it
was you originally had.
The strategy that I wanted to outline that I think is replicable and applicable in most markets most
situations is the strategy of just identifying what's missing in your area.
It's not as simple as it sounds.
You really have to spend a little bit more time.
Previously we're just getting a feel for your area.
Might spend a little bit more time there if nothing immediately jumped out to you.
You might want to go back and look again what's on offer.
Money on a write it out today.
This area has got two bedrooms it's got a wide range of pricing on two bedrooms got three bedrooms got
one bedrooms.
This strategy kind of predicates itself on is that there is something missing in your area.
There are multiple types of people booking on Airbnb and it's very hard that every single area hits
every single possible configuration of a guest type in a guest group.
Our space we really had no one who could haul 10 people.
We really had no one who could fit six or seven in a professional hire in space.
I say professional in the sense that it can actually compete with the hotel with regards to amenities
and the quality of the apartment.
So just look for things that are missing and then try to angle your apartment around offering or filling
that void.
New Markets are some huge voids I mean someone coming to town for a business trip or they're a traveler
and they just want somewhere that's easy to check into easy to get around.
Not necessarily a tourist.
Maybe that's something that you want to offer.
Or maybe it's the case.
You know your area doesn't really having that thing that's suitable to families one needs.
I've noticed that people don't offer parking as often and so you can't make the assumption that every
single Airbnb guest is going to be flying in and not going need to park.
Groups typically are going be more likely to drive in.
And also couples they drive in and maybe that people just have neglected and maybe that's something
you can capitalize on.
I think it's the case that you can always find a space that is available that's not being met.
It just depends on your market.
San Francisco pretty much everything's been met.
There's some smaller kind of nuance spots that I can try to angle for.
But you have to have a belief that that spot is not being served has a lot of demand.
Otherwise you're going to be angling your apartment towards a very very specific type of group.
And while you might have broad appeal you might be losing to the other apartments that try to kind of
cast their net more widely.
Like promise before we can discuss a little bit about if you can't find a doppelganger where you can't
find an apartment that looks like you what you can do in this case and this is one thing I generally
suggest doing is grab a hotel in the area and see what they're charging and figure out roughly what
they're offering that's the standard.
You know there's a way of doing this also as you can look at an Air B and B that's around you that might
be slightly different.
And you can use some deductive logic to figure out roughly where you are in comparison so if you're
comparing say a one bedroom to a two bedroom if you have a two bedroom you can typically charge 75 percent
more at least 50 percent more and then if you go from a two bedroom two or three bedroom it's it's more
like 50 percent more anywhere as low as 30 percent more the premium even charge per extra bedroom tapers
off very quickly.
But that's something you take into consideration if you're comparing yourself and your two bedroom to
a one bedroom deduct 75 percent of or you can add 75 percent to the price of the studio to roughly reflect
what the two bedroom would be if there's a two bedroom that's listed for two hundred dollars and you're
a one bedroom in your listing you can make a pretty good deduction that you could list this thing.
So as a reduction of 50 percent would be a hundred and a reduction of 75 percent would put you at $50.
That's a general range that you're going to be occupying if you're a really nice space.
The other place isn't particularly nice.
You can probably edge up closer to 200 but you're not going to eclipse the two bedroom that is offering
200 and you have a one bedroom you're just not going to go over two hundred and go and leapfrog them
unless you somehow magically added a bedroom or in the case that that host just implodes and they take
that thing off the market or they just have a host of no pun intended of errors.
They just have tons of reviews that are negative and they're not responding to it.
That's enough to kill that property and you can kind of prompt them in that case.
Those are two ways of looking at it.
I'm going to add a bonus section on here a quick tip about another strategy that you can use and I touch
on a slightly about hotels.
So look for that tip later.
So again if you guys have any questions posted in the group discussion again if you want to go over
anything or anything you want me to put an elaboration of section on let me know.
Send me a private message.
The next section I'm going to go over a little bit more of how you can actually drill down against other
hosts and figure out what they're doing wrong and what they're doing right and use that as a guideline
for going forward.
Knowing what you need to do to be successful with the apartment.