Tip number one for creating the best guests experience I call it the guidebook.
Now this is something you'll notice in a lot of hosts do and most the hosts that do this are more experienced
probably make a lot more money than you.
The guidebook is something you probably heard about sometimes you know hosts give preference the guidebook
or maybe you see a picture of a guidebook in a listing what it is is a lot of hosts will go and create
a booklet or maybe it's just a piece of paper or laminated sheet that gives off all the information
about the apartment that the person who is staying needs to know and also includes information about
what to do in the area how to get around how to get to points of interest how to find basic necessities
or what to do in an emergency how to contact the host.
Anything you could possibly think of when you first start listing out your property you might not have
enough information for this.
You might not know everything that the guests want and you might kind of just have a script in your
head that you verbally go over with each guest.
You want to get to the point where you don't have to do this every single time and you want to standardize
the quality that each guess gets.
Think about creating a guidebook I'm going to include as an attachment to this some text where I listed
off some places where you can very cheaply and very quickly create very professional looking guidebooks.
You can get this done for $20 interrupta up you know $100 if you want a professionally bound book.
There are mobile apps that you can download and you can actually make these on your iPhone.
You just pick a background image and then you pick text.
So the background image is the actual image of where you think the person is going or maybe it's a picture
of your apartment or maybe it's just happy clouds it doesn't really matter and you just throw some text
on it.
In my experience this works extremely well and what I have done is I've used my guidebook to not only
crowdsource recommendations but crowdsourced reviews from each of the guests.
I made it kind of like a guest book too.
So at the very end they can write nice things about their stay.
Thank us for allowing them to stay in their apartment.
Thanks for the recommendations and also allow the guest to say this restaurant was great.
This event was great.
Really you should go and do it.
Anybody who's staying in your apartment at least who's coming as a tourist is probably wondering in
their heads what's worth doing and what's not.
Everybody's taste is different.
But it does really help when they can see reviews from guests who have come in the past who can say
this is great.
It is in San Francisco.
Go see Alcatraz.
That's really cool.
And certainly people will put things like.
Alcatraz is not worth seeing and that's something that might help someone who's on the fence who wasn't
sure if they wanted to do it because it is quite kind of expensive to do.
Think of this as something that it's your comprehensive guide to everything about the experience.
It's nice to spend a lot of time on it.
But as you can see in kind of the resource guy that I've attached you can actually do these quite effortlessly.
You can really create these on the fly and they look really good and ship them directly to you.
It's really easy to do.
And I think once you actually have a guidebook and then in the guidebook you can put things like the
rules of the house how to get around how to operate things.
It's really a godsend because you don't have to explain to the ghast every single time they forget how
to do something or if you forget to explain to them how to turn on the heater What's the why fi password
or any of those tiny little minutia that's associated with hosting.
They have this guidebook and as all of it end there it's going to significantly reduce the amount of
conflicts you have or issues you have with guests.
And also it's going to package together everything that you could possibly say for them to do and there's
really no excuse for them to saying like the host didn't help out because they have it right there.
Don't use this as a way to avoid interaction with the guests because the more interaction you have your
guests the more likely they're going to give you a positive review.
I think that guidebook is kind of the cherry on top.
It make sure that you get the same information to everyone and they don't have to call you at 3:00 in
the morning if they need something.