So it sounds like you have your first guest coming to hopefully you don't have any that pre-game anxiety
kind of I'm going to use this lecture as a tool to give you a little bit of a talking through so that
you don't explode in a ball of stress about your first gasp because you think that you know what am
I going to do this is so awkward and I'm thinking I'm going to hockey through a little bit how.
My first guest I want to show you that it's completely normal when you have your first guest.
What are you going to be doing.
You have communicated with him.
You know when they're showing up if you don't know when they're showing up you should probably know
when they're showing up.
Do you have the property ready.
OK.
If you don't and it's going overlap with when they check in make sure you message him as early as possible.
You can say Do you mind checking in later.
Or you can even say Do you mind dropping off your bags doing something else like clean.
There's actually very acceptable things to ask especially if they're coming in during the day because
chances are they might want to drop off their stuff and go somewhere you live near a coffee shop.
You can always say hey I'm going to the coffee shop I'll get you a coffee.
Things like that.
If it is ready don't worry about it.
It's very simple.
They're going to come to your apartment or your place.
You're going to meet them assuming you're checking them in.
I would suggest checking in you're the first people you have.
Sending them a message saying how to check themselves are not usually fantastic key handoffs are a little
bit tricky unless you have some a system for that.
So I'd say check them in for the first ones.
I've met them and introduced myself what do I do now.
Simple.
You show them their space first thing off.
Take them right to their space show you want to drop their stuff and then you're going to spend time
showing them your place.
Show them how to work the heat work the air conditioner.
Show them where they go to the bathroom.
Is it a low flow toilet.
You can show them how to use that.
Show them the kitchen and show them where all the amenities are possibly interested in or gauge your
guest as well.
They look like they're not interested in something skip over it.
Make sure that you show them everything you can honestly since your first gas you're going to forget
to mention a lot of things.
Don't worry about it you don't need to memorize a script.
You can tell them you're my first guest.
They will forgive you and make sure that they communicate with you if they need anything.
That's the most important thing I'm going to say.
But your first guest even if you forget to show them an entire room of your place.
Just ask and give them your cell phone number that the community they text you call you if you need
anything.
Also I think it's always a good idea that after they check in maybe the next day maybe even 12 hours
later you just send them a quick text message saying Hey is there anything else you need.
Very simple like that.
A lot of times they'll think to themselves oh man i wish i had a blowdryer but I don't want to ask because
it's so minor.
Once you ask them that will ask you that's going to give them a much better experience.
This whole process is not particularly weird after you know your first three or four ghast you're kind
of start memorizing the speech that you give them and you're going to start inserting canned humor and
you're going to start noticing where people tend to snooze off at and where people seem to wake up and
you're going to get a general idea of how long this process should take.
I've done check ins that take five minutes I've done check ins that took an hour.
The reason why it takes an hour is because it took 20 minutes showing them the myspace and I spent 40
minutes talking to them make sure that you enjoy this process.
Sarah talked about how it's important that you like people the more you like people the more you're
going to get out of this.
You don't necessarily have to be a gushing huge extrovert gregarious kind of people person to get anything
out of this but it does help if you're at least somewhat interested in meeting new people even if it's
for a short period of time.
Your Enthusiasm will rub off on them.
Sometimes it's really helpful because you have guests who reciprocate and they show that they're really
happy and excited and that kind of cool will rub off on you.
Make sure you don't stress about it.
Make sure that you show them everything in your space so that they are acquainted.
Make sure you have their contact information.
I usually don't like to say like when checkout is.
You can always text them that later or even you know send them an email or something like that.
My first guest when I first got his booking he was coming in for the night news coming in late and he's
only saying one night he booked because he ended up staying in San Francisco an extra night and he was
going to stay at a hotel and he saw the prices of the hotels and the like that's crazy.
So he booked with me.
Never use air B and B before.
Ended up being a really cool guy.
Really interesting.
We had a fun time talking I mean I only spent maybe 30 45 minutes with them but I did enough spending
way more time than I usually was and I was way too anxious about it and I forgot everything that I was
supposed to tell him.
I totally forgot to tell him how to use the dishwasher and then use basic things that he would need
or where the parking spot was and things like that so don't worry about it you're always have these
problems and if you're worried about not being able to connect with someone who's coming from another
country just really just don't worry about it.
You don't need to brush up on your Japanese for your first Japanese gas.
It's not something that's a big deal.
Irving these community is much stronger than the group of people usually see at hotels.
Certainly at the beginning your price is going to be lower.
You going to have people that are much more relaxed so take a deep breath have fun with it and make
sure that you create a way that they can relay feedback to you and if they need something because you're
going to forget they can contact you easily.