Tip number four this is called towels and linens when you do end up taking in gas and running out your
space.
You do realize hopefully by this point in the course that you need to offer your guests linens you know
previously the hosing.
I don't even know what linens were.
I thought it was some kind of a fabric or something.
But what it means is the bedding that goes on your bed.
It also means that you know and then when I say towels towels or for your gas when I shower you're going
to want to present them towels that are specifically theirs unless they have a private bathroom in which
case you can put their towels in their bathroom what you need to know about towels and one ends and
Sarah talked about this a little bit earlier does that white always looks better.
That always looks more professional.
The second thing I'm going to say is try not to go completely cheap on your towels and linens.
You might think oh I need to save money but that doesn't particularly make sense especially considering
how much money you could potentially charge for your space.
It's going to wash away all of the maintenance costs.
And what I mean by that is say you have a choice between getting really cheap fixtures really cheap
amenities and maybe it only cost you five to $10 per guest.
The difference between a very very good post and a mediocre post could be several hundred dollars a
night.
I don't think you're ever going to spend more than $20 agast per reservation.
So it's not a wide range of money they're going to be spending 10 to 20 dollars but the difference is
if you go for higher quality you're going to have better reviews and better experiences and eventually
are going to be to charge more.
So it actually ends up being that the costs are very negligible sorrow's saying White does look a lot
more professional It does look a lot cleaner too when you just see why you kind of assume everything's
clean.
The flip side of why is that it's harder to keep clean.
And so this is something that's worked pretty well for me is that I just plan on doing that I'm going
to have what I called towel attrition meaning that over time since air white towels and white linens
people are going to put their makeup on them people are going to stain them in some way they're going
to get ripped especially because you going to be doing a lot of white load's bleach and you can put
it on high heat because you want it to dry out.
And so over time it's actually the tick take cheap towels they will end up ripping.
So I just kind of plan on knowing that a lot of my stuff over time isn't going to make it.
And so I just plan on picking towels.
I know we're going to last the longest.
Per how much I'm spending on them and I don't want to go for the cheap towels because I fall apart very
quickly and they don't really look as nice.
Plan on your towels and your linens just being destroyed.
And so always keep extras.
I had three beds to Bath.
I just had a set packet of towels that I would buy every month or every say like 15 reservations and
that package you know is only 25 bucks 30 bucks or something and gave me an extra three towels.
Sorry like you know three or four towels.
But if you just plan on it.
Figure out how you can do this very easily and might be the case.
You can use Amazon Prime and you can order towels and order linens repeatedly but just plan on them
getting ruined.
And this is going to prevent you from having kind of an a like an oh moment when you know guests are
coming and that you did not realize the last second to the last guests actually ruined someone ends
and you don't have anything to cover.
The third better the second better whatever.
Always have these as backup.
And so just buy a lot of them and can keep purchasing them in regular intervals knowing that they're
going to get ruined linens.
Sarah did mention this at the end of the day they are paying for a good night's sleep and Lenins can
make a huge difference and that if you spend more it's going to feel a lot better.
As one of the things I put a lot of focus on.
I knew that over time certain things might break down or it might not look as nice or you know maybe
my check in process was not fantastic that I can always make up for it with a comfortable bed.
And so I put a lot of effort into that.
And Sarah saying that if you purchased linens that have very high thread counts then people kind of
associate that with high class expensive hotels.
They want to kind of put it in the same category.
You know what you're trying to charge them for and that's ideally what we want to get to we're going
to get to the point where you're are charging a lot of money because that's where it really starts to
get sweet.
And that's something that's kind of the limit if you take cheap linens.
I come from kind of a cost angle in the sense that you can spend hundreds of dollars in bed sheets and
you can also go as low as $20.
The problem is that you know if you spend $20 in bedsheets you're going to change them every single
time because they're just not going to last.
And at the end of the day you know you spend a lot more than that.
Plus how much time and effort you spend having to swap them out because you didn't realize that they
got ruined.