Let's talk about the feature called Instant book if anyone's noticed this when you're filling out your
listing there's an option where you can turn on instant book and then you can set different parameters
for which you can accept instant booking when you're searching on air being me.
For those of you who don't know what this is you can see on the thumbnails.
A lightning bolt if there's a lightning bolt that means the host has enabled instant booking.
If they don't have the lightning ball that means that in order to book that property you would have
to send a message to the host and have the host pre-approve your dates and then book with them.
If you don't have instant book it requires that the guests message you telling you why they're coming
maybe a little bit of information about themselves and they give you the dates beforehand and the amount
of guests and then you get to choose whether or not you approve them.
Now you'll notice this when you're searching on air B and B in most big urban centers most of the properties
are going to have the lightening bolt logo meaning that they have instant book turned on.
I would imagine in smaller markets it's probably the case that a lot of them don't have instant book
turned on but it's probably 50 percent.
If you walk in San Francisco and just take a quick search that's roughly about probably 75 percent have
this turned on in sin book allows the host to say I can take gas to whenever and I don't need to pre-qualify
them beforehand.
And it also allows you to basically say I'm OK with what Air B and B does in their pre-fall qualification
system.
I'm ok with E-Verify.
I'm OK with the phone and e-mail verify and that's it.
The rest of the way that goes kind of mitigate any type of risk in that case is just using a security
deposit.
Since this is under the section of the setting out and starting out at first the reason why I bring
this up is because it's something that you might be tempted to do.
Arab and B does push people towards using instant booking in the actual administration panel you're
setting up your listing.
They usually list something out saying consider Ansun book you'll get an extra 20 percent bookings.
In my experience and experience in the house I've talked to you this is absolutely true.
It is true that you get a lot more bookings with instant book.
However you have to consider the fact that at first he put on instant book that means anyone can book
you know and it is at a time when you're not completely used to the system.
So you need to think about it.
Typically with instant book is it something that experienced host to use and it's something that I strongly
suggest you don't use at first.
Now at first it might hurt you in the sense that if you see two properties one has Ansen book and one
doesn't.
You might have the case where someone just goes with the Ansin book.
They don't have to deal with the process of messaging the host waiting for the host to respond.
Waiting then to send preapproval then to book.
And that might be the case that they'll get more bookings but at first I don't think it's worth it.
And if you listen to the previous lecture we talked about how important it is that you're first say
four or five ghast have a positive experience and positive reviews you'll get why I say that instant
booking is risky.
It means that you have a space that's always available.
Say you have a space and it's empty to night.
That means that someone could literally go to the page book it for tonight and they could book it at
7:00 p.m. which means that by 8:00 p.m. or 9:00 p.m. when they show up it needs to be clean and it needs
to be ready for someone to move en.
And that might not be conducive with your schedule at first and it's usually something that over time
once you've hosted say 10 15 people you get used to it and then you know how to handle this whole system.
If you turn on and in a book it's also going to require that you are closer to your phone or closing
your computer more often because you really want to know at the exact moment when someone books.
And the reason why is because they can do these last second bookings.
They can also do bookings on weekends that you haven't necessarily thought out yet.
And then I can give an example in my apartment I haven't seen book set up because I've done this enough
times and I'm comfortable with people booking without messaging me and introducing themselves.
But what ends up happening is because I don't update my calendar every single time that something changes
or anything in my schedule updates say something happens that I know is a week and three months from
now that I can host I don't immediately take that down.
Now there's a small chance that someone can get on and book that weekend.
And then what ends up happening is you have to have a really awkward conversation with the guests saying
oh sorry I can't actually host you then and you have to end up usually canceling and what that does
it posts on your listing saying that you cancel on the ghast.
That's something you never want to have happen.
Inevitably if you have instant book on it's a possibility.
Now if you're listening and listening and you have say like a shared room inside of a full apartment
that could create problems as well because what happens if you have instant book on both of them.
You go to bed you have two people book say they're in Europe because they're you know six to nine hours
ahead of us said a book the private room and then the full apartment gets also booked by someone as
well right afterwards.
You can't possibly fulfill both of those bookings.
So you have to end up canceling one of them and having an awkward kind of exchange.
So usually when you do instant book you kind of have to be comfortable in the system you've created.
You need to really be like a hawk on the schedule especially if you're doing multiple properties then
it's very easy for you to forget and not notice when there's an instant book and then all of a sudden
say the weekend's coming up and oh wow you have to find a cleaner to clean it right now.
So I think at the very beginning it's not worth doing but after you get comfortable and you get used
to have a routine going down then it's something I definitely think you should look into and eventually
start using because it's going to get to a point where even if you're in a small market as more people
start hosting and more and more people start staying on Airbnb it's going to become normal that people
start instant booking and offering instant booking if you're the one person who isn't offering.
It's going be a significant downer for how many inquiries you get and how many bookings you get you
guys have any questions is posted in the group discussion.
If you have any questions about.
I've hosted five guests six guests I think I'm pretty confident and ready to do instant book.
You can post it also if he goes on experiences with instant book.
You can post it.
Typically I call it a pro feature it's something that you should hold off on until you're much much
better and more experience with this whole process.