Welcome to the cause on introduction to neuro networks in this course.
Let me walk through the guideline and the outline with you.
This cause we will cover the introduction to the foundations of deep learning and in preparation for
more advanced courses such as computer vision recurring neural network our team and the likes.
Now at the end of this course the learners the students will have a really firm understanding of the
basic concepts of neural networks such as what a neuron is the architecture of neural networks are the
nomenclature such as layers nodes feed forward networks back propagation and dropout and many many more
I really wanted this cause to actually help you to set the foundation so that when you actually embark
on more advanced neural network architecture you will be able to understand it.
But this is why this course lies is the foundation to help you to understand really as an entry level
to the world of neural networks.
Now we will provide many examples from really simple artificial neural networks to topics that was covered
in the classical machine learning.
I'll highlight them so that you can compare in terms of the performance.
These classical machine learning is self-contained is provided within this course as well so that you
can actually compare and contrast the performance of the two different approaches.
Now some of the networks some of the topics that we are covering will be topics such as neural network
architectures the actual architecture of the neural network itself the feed forward networks paper location
dropout and also comparing and contrasting artificial neural networks vs. classical machine learning
within.
I'm going to stop here.
Thank you for listening to this introduction.
I'm really excited to get started with the first topic which is what exactly is deep learning.
I look forward to seeing you in class next.