Greetings Welcome to the complete machine learning course with Python.
I'd like to thank you for purchasing this cost.
I'm also so glad that you have just embark on this truly exciting journey.
My name is Anthony Ng and I've been a senior lecturer in Singapore for the past ten years.
My background is financial engineering by trade.
I also hold a double degree an MBA as well as financial engineering plus a degree in I.T. and finance
to begin with I like to share with you this little secret.
Please get your hands dirty to learn this course properly.
You do need to code along come into this cause with an attitude of curiosity and to explore hunger to
learn and apply what you've learned here to solve real world problems.
Now I'm sure you know by now in the past decades machine learning has really given us self-driving cars
speech recognition Google Translate effective web search house price predictions Netflix as well as
Amazon recommendations.
And guess what.
There really only is just the tip of the iceberg of what's possible.
And this cause you are going to learn how to be a powerful machine learning model to solve any problems
you will go from a beginner completely novice to extremely high level competency and your instructor
will build each algorithm with you step by step.
By the time you've finished his course you will have trained machine learning and deep learning algorithm
to do the following classify flowers predict house prices identify hen writings or digits sentiment
analysis computer vision identify staff that's most likely to leave prematurely other things such as
conduct medical diagnosis such as detecting cancerous cells segment your customers and.
And identify those underserved profitable clients and of course much much more for this caused no prior
machine learning experience is required or the data says the source codes are available for download.
You'll get friendly support and a Q and A area.
I like to equip you with the skill sets to be able to solve business problems.
So let's get started.
Start learning and start applying everything you've learned.
I look forward to seeing you in class.