Welcome back everyone.
We are still in the building blocks of deep learning.
So one of the key concept of new our network and how it learns.
Let me just come back here under the optimizer is that uses what's called gradient base optimization.
And.
And another word for gradient really is actually slope for every layer deep learning neural network
layer every layer ends with what's core and next by evasion function.
Now this activation function comes in different a few times.
You have the sigmoid.
You have solved Max and you have really.
Again I'm not explaining this.
Sorry.
Yeah yeah.
I'm not explaining this for now.
I will cover that and separate lesson.
I just want to highlight that the the actual activation function is to actually squash the data so that
it actually provide a specific output.
Right.
Let's walk through these one by one where W is the actual weights.
We've seen that before.
There's the weights for every note of the layer.
B is the buyer's term.
Now if you think of linear regression or why is gram x plus C the B here is actually the bias term which
is to intercept.
And then the initial weights when you actually training your neural network initially the weights are
set randomly.
Now of course that's not the best place to start but for now we will take that and add enough to that
of course when you actually said a random.
It's not going to have a really accurate prediction or a very accurate neural network that is able to
predict everything accurately so the training part has to come in.
Now we didn't need to make gradual not gradual graduate as gradual adjustment and it just gradual
we need to make gradual adjustment.
Or rather we need to gradually adjust and update to do the weight to reduce the error.
So which is this portion here.
So we need to actually continual adjust this so that the lost function gets smaller and smaller.
Our prediction get closer and closer to Y.
Here's an example of our definition of neural network.
How you define your network in carriers whereby you have the input from models to sequential and also
four layers we import dense and activation.
So we have two dense layer here with 32 neurons and 10 neurons an input should be specified in the activation
function is value here and self makes here.
So these are somewhat the basic concepts.
I will cover this grid in base optimization in a future lesson I'd want to actually touch on this for
now and so that you are aware that this exist.
That's the first thing and and you need to understand that this is the actual so core layout the other
way to look at this.
Let me just touch on this for those who are a little bit more mathematically inclined you can think
of this portion here the inside part here the DOT w multiplied by input plus b you can actually write
it as W x plus B.
This is going to look very similar two ways to emacs plus see where this is the intercept him also call
the bias term X is our input data M is our slope.
You'll notice that they actually look very similar except that this is in the vector Rice format.
This is usually not in their vector Rice format and of course with this it comes out in the terms of
some sort of value and we have a sigmoid function that's being applied to F X after the value has been
calculated.
Okay.
And will refrain from explaining what a signal more is or cover that in future lesson.
But for now I just understand that through this formula okay is how the whole neural network gets trained.
Okay book cover artist and let me walk through the training loops so that you can understand at least
conceptually how it's done before we actually implement the actual training itself.
Right you draw a batch of training samples.
X and the corresponding targets y and you train the neural network on X to obtain prediction of Y recall
you draw a batch of data X and Y corresponding y you train it to get it or obtain a prediction of y.
Okay so we are up to this point.
Step number two then you compute the laws or the errors of the neural network on the bench meaning your
prediction y prediction.
How far is it from the actual y.
Step four then you compute the gradient of the loss with respect to the neural network parameters and
that's what's called a backward pass.
Again if you don't understand is that OK all right.
That's not bad at all.
We will actually cover that in the numerical example so that you can actually cross it a bit better.
So with this this is partial portion here you are actually computing the gradient of the lost meaning
you are calculating the slope with respect to the lost with respect to the neural net neural network
parameters OK meaning the parameters here is X and also y.
Okay.
So that we are freezing X and Y and we actually
changing w okay we're changing W which is the gradient here until we actually get the optimal output.
So let me come back here.
I've removed that.
So let me help you recall what we did to adjust now is this.
I draw this.
Y is good too w x plus C or bias or if X is a W X Y spies.
So let me just change the color a little bit.
Black we are freezing this we are freezing this so what's left is this.
This is our projection and then we have a actual y.
So I can call this religious call this I have an actual effects which are actual value or sometimes
you also call y and I have an effect set of Y head here because this is this is fixed.
This is fix.
These two parameters are fixed.
Okay so what's left now is to actually change w so that our y prediction is closer and closer in value
to Y.
So that's really what this steps number four is.
And finally step 5 is once we actually calculated the gradient we move our parliament is little in the
opposite direction from the gradient.
If it's a positive slope we'll put a minus mark so that it moves closer.
If there's a negative slope we change to sign to positive so that it moves towards the right direction
faster because it will move the parent is little in the opposite direction from the gradient taking
one small step to reduce the loss on the bench.
The step here
where's my pen.
Okay.
The step here has another name core lending rate we've calculated the gradient from earlier so the the
point now is that we actually take put a minus with a small Smalls lending rate in the direction of
the gradient.
Okay.
The minus here meaning opposite that the tip of the direction of the gradient so that we move closer
and closer our y prediction moves closer and closer to Y.
Well I thought conceptually this is the training loop.
This is how neural networks learn.
I know that right now you're not convinced in terms of how this x2 can work out.
For that I need to actually show you an example.
But before we do that let me just explain one more concept which is to stochastic gradient descent and
it is an optimizer which is along the line of but we looked at earlier
it's not here.
Can we have look at our immense prop this is another alternative which is called Stochastic gradient
descent.
Right.
So a couple again some terminologies.
The first one is a study which is the stochastic gradient descent.
With this we actually draw one sample at a time and it is a mini batch stochastic gradient descent.
We draw a batch of data or a sample sample set off the data shouldn't really be sample a sample set
of the data.
The common batch size is 1 2 8 5 1 2.
And also another terminology is called batch as you did.
This is all the data.
So at the one extreme the stochastic gradient basically to run one forward past with one sample and
then update the gradient at the other extreme is it get trained with all the data then it update the
gradient.
All right update degrading and the weight essentially mini batch is somewhere in the middle whereby
it only draw a sample sample set or batch of data which is why the 1 2 or 2 5 6 5 1 2 all whatever you
specify.
So at the one extreme you have every time you have one data and then you actually update the weight
which is computationally very expensive.
The other end is all the data which means the update is quite slow so you have something in between
which is the many big badge as G.D. which is something that's a lot more popular.
There are the more sophisticated techniques to deal with momentum at a grid iron man's prop but will
cover this in the left relevant lectures in the different segment of the advanced neural network models
for now or you know need to know is that these exist and we will cover these in future lessons for now
sufficient to know that we are looking at stochastic gradient descent or bench mini batch of SGI D.
All right with that I hope that has been useful.
Thank you once again for watching.