Welcome back everyone.
In this session we're going to look at getting started with neural network.
For a start I just want to revise some basic principles which is the anatomy of a neural network and
the elements that you will typically see is number one you have an input data which is x here and then
you have a target levels which are labeled as actual and then you have the layers which is this and
also this.
In this case we have two layers.
So while when you combine them they are core network neural network and then you need to measure the
accuracy of your prediction which is here and the actual measurement that we use is called a lost function.
The output of the function calculation is core a last call it informs you how far away is your prediction
from the actual scores and because obviously in the beginning the weights is actually origin just randomized.
No.
We did an optimizer of salt to actually continuously tune our neural network until the weights are accurate
or able to allow our neural network to predict accurately optimizes some example this stochastic gradient
descent.
We discussed a few of last time and the picture below really is an example of what a neural network
may look like.
You have two inputs you have layer 1 layer 2 These are the two hidden layers and then this is the output
a single output layer.
All right.
So it's time to actually have a look at some of the really popular Deep Learning libraries.
I've only highlighted three here.
There are actually a lot more piano.
I guess you can call that the grandfather of Deep Learning libraries.
It's no longer commercially supported but it's still hugely popular.
Before any of these previous libraries to or is really more or less the first and the most popular Deep
Learning libraries that it's been used ever since tens before was launched in 2015.
It basically took off.
It's now the most popular.
This is obviously supported by Google and carers is supported by chocolate and quite a few of the engineers
from Google as well.
Interestingly carers was actually launched in March 2015 whereas intensive flow was launched late 2015
around November.
If I remember correctly pine torch is actually supported by Facebook and but these three are really
the most popular of all the different various Deep Learning libraries as you can see from the are from
various metrics.
One that I've shown here is just google search.
Right.
Finally in terms of the workflow that I just want to discuss with you before we go into looking at some
examples.
Chris intensive law is what we are using this course.
We are using carrots because it's really probably one of the easiest to grasp in terms of the concept
rather than get down to the nitty gritty of it.
You can actually visualize it from previously I've shown you how it's done.
We're gonna go into a few more examples this time.
Looking at the workflow typically you will need to define your training data.
You have your input x and your target y.
So you need to take your input and also the the so-called result that you or you want the neural network
to learn and the next thing you need to do is define your network architecture from the complexity of
the task you are.
You have to make choices in terms of how deep your layer is and how many neurons to learn and the next
thing is do you need to select the appropriate lost function optimizer as well as performance matrix
in order to actually measure the performance of your neural network and you repeat this task until you
finally preset for specified performance is reached.
Those are the basic workflow and that comes with a neural network and with that I'm going to stop here
and I'm going to go into example and the next video.
Thank you once again.