Welcome back everyone.
In the next few lessons we're going to look at some of the mechanics of machine learning some of the
key part that we need to cover in terms of wrapping up this course is how do you evaluate the machine
learning the performance of it.
Of course we're going to touch on a little bit of the different categories of machine learning or those
already gone through that extensively in another course.
We're going to talk about how do you split your data.
What used to be your data and to attain validation and test said.
We'll also cover a data processing feature engineering and how to spot of an under fitting.
And that's pretty much some of the key ideas that we're going to cover.
And before we finish we're going to touch on regularization and dropout and finally workflow.
So let's dig into it the first one that I want to cover with something that is hopefully a review for
you.
Nevertheless I do want to cover it for those who have not seen it before.
There are really four different categories of machine learning.
There is this supervised which is your typical classification and regression problem.
It could include also sequence generation object detection and image segmentation by and large.
This class is called supervised because you provide the actual target that no one else and also the
input data so that the neural network learn the the expected output there is also the unsupervised which
is.
Well there's basically no Target here.
The machine learning algorithm needs to distinguish the underlying pattern clusters the similar patterns
together or reduced the dimension of the actual underlying pattern itself.
And also you have self supervised.
These are auto encoders whereby again these so core target is not provided it learns to categorize by
itself using auto encoders as hen's core self supervise.
This is a new class on his own is it's it's a real fairly new invention only really a couple of years
old and it really deserve a class on its own because it is quite unique and quite different altogether.
And the final one wonder has quite a lot.
Whether receival or headline attention is reinforcement learning ever since the Alpha ego that beat
the world champion.
So those are the real basic four different categories of machine learning.
And I just want to revise this once again in terms of machine learning performance evaluation.
We've seen this many times before within this course.
You have your input data there's multiple layers of For Your neural network but does the prediction
and the comparing against the actual why you use lost function to measure the difference and generate
a law score of course to improve your you know your neural network you use an optimizer that's that's
based on the problem that you're faced with and finally continue to tune the weights which is really
the memory of your neural network as well.
So the goal of machine learning is that your mettle your model is able to generalize to problems that
are Data's it has not seen before.
And what exactly is the last function we've covered this really is is to Mr. function to calculate how
far this your prediction deviates away from the actual and the lost functions depends on the problem
that you face it could be binary multi class or regression problem.
OK.
So just want to touch on a little bit of train validate and test.
This is really important concepts I did talk about this a little earlier.
So just go straight to the key nodes here tests data set is meant for you to be used only once ones
only and only at the end of the model building.
So this is necessary because you want to prevent information like this is the only way that you can
tell whether your model can actually perform well in the real world situation or not.
So test is really the only way that you can actually tell.
Hence you cannot touch it to be your model.
That's the key point here.
You cannot use the test to build your model your model building must be done using training data set
of course you still need to check how good your model is this where the validation dataset comes in
so for your model your neural net what model it would have seen these data sets the training data says
many many times in order to learn the weight.
But there's no way for you to tell if it all fit and they can generalize to unseen data.
Hence we use validation a dataset to evaluate your model performance.
With respect to various hyper power meters.
OK.
So this is an example of what's called a single holdout test set whereby you have a training set and
then you have a test set.
I'm going to show you this is the simplest of them all.
I'm going to show you a difference a few variation of this.
And the best practice as well so this is a single holdout set in.
And this is useful but that does suffer from some flaws in that up to you train your data.
There's no way for you to tell whether it's all fit or under fit.
And and that's not good.
So which is why this was developed.
You have a single holdout validation and test set.
What I mean by a single holdout here is actually we use a pen.
Is this this portion here.
So there's only one of these.
So this why is core single.
Earlier the previous slide the example was this one.
Okay.
Now instead of that week the training data we're split into maybe this is just 10 percent of your training
data.
The remaining 90 percent is used to train your data.
And this is much better because now you have some way to validate to see if your data has indeed.
Well your neural network model has indeed over learned of a fit.
Your training data.
So that's where the validation comes in.
But one of the more common breast best practice is to do this is called K for validation whereby you
have one fall to actually test your data.
So there's a 10 4 Here.
This is common in in the shadow machine learning for neural network.
This is sufficient just one single holdout validation and also a test that is sufficient to to validate
your neural network.
All right I hope that there has been use for this just one more key point so a few key points that I
want to actually highlight before we move on this.
This slide on traps here please be mindful of them the data representativeness is important.
You must have all the so-called target as well as features represented in your training data otherwise
your neural network never get to seen an example.
So it will never would.
It would never would have learned and for time series data Don Chapel because the sequence in the order
of how the data comes or comes true is important.
You have to ensure that all your test data are posterior meaning in the future to the data in the training
set.
So to use simple English posterior here basically means future
data redundancy.
Also make sure that the same data is not repeated in both the train and test data.
This is a mistake that I wish I demonstrated to you when we were looking at the binary classification
1.
We did some training on on the validation set before we actually created the validation set.
So that's basically noticed that the arrow was significantly lower.
You can try that out but the problem when you actually do that is that while your validation is no longer
useful as a validation dataset because you have allowed your neural network model to see it
and the other example is you have the same picture of the same CAD exactly the same picture in both
your training as well as your validation as well as your tests either war.
This is an A and a real war analogy.
This is basically cheating.
It's like a teacher giving the student sample exam question and then testing the same questions in the
exam.
All right so that's really what's the the traps that.
You do need to be mindful of and it's critical to pay attention to that.
Then I'm gonna stopped and the next video we're gonna go into a data pre processing.