Good day everyone in this lesson we're gonna go on to a non-linear relationships once we get to this
point whereby the underlying data is clearly not really really nonlinear.
Now we have two weeks to start moving away from the simple ordinarily square or linear regression or
the polynomial as best as we can.
We tried to make use of those as well even as the baseline but once you actually stopped looking at
data there's substantially more complex and a lot more interesting features.
I suppose you can say it then we have to start looking at models.
There are a lot more complicated and a lot more rich to describe and tried to model use use those to
model our underlying data.
The usual drill here is importing the libraries that we need for the purpose of our lesson.
Loading the data have a preview of the data and just basically read our data.
Okay.
That is running in the background the first regress.
Then we're going to make use of this court decision tree.
This may not be very common knowledge to a lot of people decision trees aren't just purely for classification
based machine learning.
It can be used for regression base.
A quick differentiation between regression versus classification really is that classification is often
binary in nature or things are boxed into different classes apples orange dogs cats.
Those are distinct classes on their own zero and one is obviously another example.
Whereas if you're talking about regression it's the numbers that you're dealing with are continuous
in nature.
But the example we've been looking at so far is house price projection or the median value that we're
looking at.
Modeling.
And with that you can see that the value is continuous.
There isn't a distinct category to it.
So that's the basic idea here is the psychic and the psychic then there's a decision tree library that's
built in.
And yes you can use decision tree except that you do need to import the decision tree regress.
And we are looking specifically is just one of the feature in this case our state.
I just want to use this as an illustration lesson for instructional purpose rather than for on model
building.
For now we need to understand what is it that we are working with the actual features and the star lies.
Characteristics of Decision Tree regress rather than full on modelling of the underlying data.
What are the so-called parameters that we need to specify is how deep or how big we want to build our
tree.
In this case we specify a maximum depth of five.
We have no way of knowing whether that's too deep or not.
We have to iterate this process until we develop some intuition of that underlying data.
So let's try that and then fit it.
Okay.
These are the output.
There are a lot of parameters that you can actually tune out for now.
We just really want to make use of just one which is max depth and the next thing is just plot it.
The blue dots are the underlying data and the black line is our predicted prediction using the decision
tree.
That's where the prediction part comes in here.
No this function here is just really X is it comes in an array.
What we wanted to do is just flatten it so that it becomes a while.
Originally when it can come in in the form of vector we want to just flatten it so this is just a continuous.
It's just an array and then next we want to do is actually just sorted from the lowest to the largest.
Otherwise it gets a bit problematic when it comes to the plotting.
So that's really the basic idea there.
And as we actually performing the prediction this is the x value and this is the y value.
And as you can see here is if you plot a linear regression it would have been like this and this is
not what you will.
Normally core normal model and you can see that is all over the place at this is what we call a telltale
sign of the model of fitting we might have given it far too many degrees of freedom and is not fitting
this way.
And one other way to actually reduce that is just to change it to just say two.
And you can see that is substantially better.
But what might we have.
What what what we might have done in doing that exercises that we might have restricted it so much.
Kind of like a regular Rick.
The regularize adjustment technique that we talked about earlier having is a bit tongue tied today.
Just too restricted from being able to model the data too much.
And three years seems OK but I just want to go back to five.
Just to illustrate to you as you can see this is quite a lengthy process and one that you need to iterate
through just so that you actually know underlie understand the model that you've built.
So we've look at two we looked at three and looked at five and since those three is probably one of
the best.
And we also highlight this whole exercise here using two
Decision Tree is one we can also look at another which is call random forest.
We're going to make use of this model to begin with I'm splitting the data into train and test.
I'll explain that in a minute and keeping 30 percent as our test and we input the random forest regress.
This is an ensemble.
It's a different type of model random forest technically is combinations of decision trees.
It's not just one tree but many of them.
And COBOL criterion is that we need to provide for now don't need to worry about these essentially just
I'm saying look estimated 500 times using means great errors.
The worry about the random state I just want to fix it so that I get the same output and also use all
the all the threads my computer cores to.
She does the computation because if you were working with lots of data and a forest is actually computationally
quite intensive fit the data predict perform the prediction for training data and it perform the prediction
for test data and look at the main square error kind of hard to tell whether that's good or bad.
If you look at the ask where is ninety seven point eighty seven for the training and then in the whole
of the sample the test is eighty seven percent.
And if you look at the misery error in sample is one point eighty seven.
And test is substantially worse.
So that tells you as you know our models do not stay in our grade.
There seem to be something else that's actually at play here.
But ask where does tell you that it is an improvement or slightly somewhat better.
And the next model that want to look at is score and a boost.
Also an ensemble method.
So let's run this and look at the direct comparison between the miss gray area as well so ask.
You notice that the Atavus did not perform as well as the random forest.
So in this case we may revert to random for us quite often in real life.
You will still continue to run that at a boost on the side ESA check especially if it is useful to help
you to evaluate random furrows especially if both models are deteriorating concurrently it tells you
that something is changing the underlying data brought with it.
I'm gonna stop and just to summarize the lesson here When we're dealing with non related non-linear
relationships we may deviate from the normal linear regressions or polynomial regression model.
When we start looking at Decision Trees random forests as well as a edibles and down more but that ultimately
this is just to show you these models that you can estimate use Office for regression as well.