Welcome back everyone.
Good to see you here again.
In this portion we're going to look at over fitting as well as under fitting for your neuro networks.
Then there is always a tradeoff between the fitting and the fitting.
The goal of training your neural network is so that it can learn from the pattern of the data it is
under fitting.
It's a waste of the data.
So we tend to continue to fit the data.
The only problem is that it can over fit your training data and is not able to generalize.
So that part is important.
Now the fitting process there's another term for it was mentioned here is core optimization.
Your model will always start off with being under fitted.
Now as you continuously expose your data your model to the training data many times it will continue
to improve but there will come a tipping point whereby your model will over learn and or over learn
from the training data and wasn't able to generalize.
And at that point is actually you should and ought to have stopped the training.
Now the fitting is when your model has not learned fully from the training data in this situation both
the training and test loss will be falling on each epoch.
So we demonstrated that in some of our examples in fact all of the examples that we've talked about
that this is for the lost score.
Now in order to improve both your training and test score you can increase the number of times your
model epoxy the data e.g. pull it sees all the data.
This process is also a core optimization all fitting is when the law score in the training and test
start to diverge.
The training law score continue to fall while the test scores start to rise.
So rising is bad.
OK.
So that means the error errors is going up.
So in this situation the bottle is starting to over fit your training data and unable to generalize
it will not perform well with data.
It has not seen before the data that hasn't been seen before is also called test score.
How do you overcome a fitting.
There's a few ways you can get more data.
You can also perform one score regularization meaning forcing your weights to be within a range.
Okay.
So that is sexually constrained.
So regularization reduced.
There's a few ways.
There's.
Reduce your network size.
Meaning don't have too many neurons or don't have too many layers.
Weight regularization is pertaining to the weight meaning constrain it to within a range.
Drop out is something that we will look at essentially as we are running our training from one level
to another level.
We dropped some of the nodes or the neuron data and Don pass it on but it's randomly dropped doing so
improve the model's ability to generalize OK.
So when these are the key a few key points reducing the network size I cover before I the managed to
number of layers or managed a number of notes players.
These are also core learnable parameters.
This dictates the capacity of the model.
Now this part is more art than science.
Hans is a good idea to have a GP you or use or use cloud based computer to improve that with this part.
I'm going to show you three examples or two examples I should say when the model is undersized and the
model is too big.
And using benchmark as a reference and for weight regularization you forced to wait to be restricted
to within the range or constrain to within the range.
This is done by applying a costume to the last function.
What is this costume.
There are two types of costume.
There is the L1 regularization and the other one's called out to regularization.
The difference between the two is the L1 is the absolute value L2 is the squared value.
So let's look at L1 regularization.
The costume is proportional to the absolute value of the weight coefficient meaning it is constraining
it based on the absolute value whereby the second one is relative to the squared value but Dropout is
the more common and and much more popular method.
This is created by Hinton again.
It's also called the godfather of AA and he's the one person that is persistent been persistent and
pursuing his goal.
I guess you can call him dogged as well but without him we will not have a two day drop out is the most
commonly used applied to a layer.
Basically you're randomly dropping meaning zero setting meaning setting the weight to zero a number
of output features of the layer during training.
Sorry not weights.
It's in the output not the weight.
The weight is retained but the output from layer to leave is not passed on meaning zero before I move
on to the next layer.
Now according to Charlotte dropout rate usually is set between zero point two and zero point five during
the test time however no drop out is applied
all right.
Look at some examples here of of the so-called validation lost that I have extracted for you and let's
look at this.
What do you see.
You have the plus blue plus is the original model when you look at the blue plus is consistently low
and you notice that the smaller model is consistently higher meaning it has a larger validation lost.
What that is saying is that the smaller model smaller neural network is not able to learn the the features
or the richness of the features.
In the data itself handset there is always a gap.
It wasn't able to learn.
Not only was it able not to learn from the training data in the validation data it wasn't able to actually
generalize as well.
It just wasn't able to to provide a better prediction.
So that therein lies as hens I'm using validation laws rather than the training loss let's have a look
an example of a bigger model.
If you look at this bigger model this is zooming in it's the same original model that we're looking
at except the scale is a bit different now.
If you look at this what you can see is that the larger models start all with a better validation loss
because the initial few epochs and it's able to actually well from if you look at this right you can
see is that.
Let me just use a pen so that you can follow along my argument.
Let me just change the color to black because we have
because we have let's use black right.
This is the original model and this is the larger model.
OK so the larger model is started off with a better value validation lost and then we have the crossover
here where the original model goes down the validation lost for the larger model goes up and that's
when the larger model start to all the fit the the the training data and then wasn't able to actually
predict as well.
And data that is not seen but that's not the key point of this light.
What are the key slide that I wanted to actually highlight is that the larger model is able to learn
the features better hence it actually has better lost up to around let's just call it a PoC.
OK.
So that's the benefit of having a bigger model is that it is able to learn the data better and also
able to predict the better.
So therein lies the contrast between the smaller model the original model as well as the larger model.
Now if we look at the original was this the larger model training lost you'll notice that they are continuously
falling it's continued to adapt and learn from the actual training data itself from here you cannot
tell that it is actually over fitting.
We know from this previous slide from the number 9 onwards epoch 9 onwards the larger model is already
all fitting and hence you always have a validation data to inform you of that.
OK.
I also want to show you how you can actually perform weight regularization as well ignore those commented
code.
If you look at the data or rather the line of code.
This is an out to regularization and how you actually apply the regularization is that you have this
line here.
Core kernel underscore regularly the equals to regularize is dot L2.
This is L2.
Okay so that's out too.
And the the value that you use is zero point zero zero one.
So this is l to zero point zero zero one.
Okay.
And the rest are exactly the same.
Notice that this is obviously a larger model with 2048 note.
Basically it means that you know in your neural network so you say you have tree input and you have
to layer and then you have legislate 3 output and what you have here is it's basically two thousand
neural network neural nodes.
Okay neurons here.
So religious from 1 all the way to 2048.
So that's how many there is here now.
So that's an example out to what about L1.
This is an L1 and the actual difference between the both line and this is just that for this you have
l 1 but you have to write it as it's lower cap again.
Upper cap when you're actually writing the code.
I'm just changing into upper case so that you can actually see that easily.
So that's basically for L1 and for L1 and L2.
This is what you do L1 on this go out to and L 1 is equal to zero point zero zero one.
So basically you're actually providing the L1 the value that you want to regularize it for.
So that's pretty much it.
And you do apply regularize us for each of the layer as well.
And apart from that the rest are exactly the same.
I hope that as it's clear.
Let's have a look at the application of weight regularization on the larger model.
And if you look at this carefully this is validation lost.
You have the L2 regularize model here and you notice that it.
Well it's it's basically being forced constrain.
So hopes.
Sorry.
This is the we'll just bring on the pen.
So this is the L to regularize model and this hasn't actually overfed the data.
In contrast to the larger model which is our own here and it jumps.
It has of a fit but in this situation what happened is that because the regularization does apply here
as constrain the model so much is that it did not perform as well as either the original or the regularized
model.
And.
And this is the part whereby you need to tune the the regularization here is what's called a hyper parameter.
It's not part of the neural network parameters hence is called hyper primitives.
So if I look at dropout as as an alternative to applying weight regularization what do we see.
Right.
So we have a couple models once again some images bring out my pen.
You have the green one is your larger model.
You have to drop out let's look at the larger model there.
This is the strict stop plus is your larger model.
Okay let's just change color.
OK so let's just draw this.
This is our larger model unconstrained without any regularization or dropout applied.
So let me just change to paint color and this time this use yellow.
This is our dropout models started off didn't perform as well.
Okay.
And then the validation is better then the larger model.
And around here is do better as was is better better.
And notice that it continues to do better even as we allow the data the more data is being applied in
fact when you look carefully and actually perform as well as the original model.
And it seems to be stable of course you can continue to run this but this require a fair bit of tuning
a fair bit of of you know playing around with it until you actually get a at an ideal or optimal neural
network.
That part takes time and I hope that this portion on dropout wait regularization has been useful and
I hope that you've gained much all of this on how to manage and understood also what is all the fitting
and under fitting and how to actually and what to do with it when you actually do come across this situation.
Thank you once again for watching.
I look forward to seeing you in the next video.