In our previous lesson we talked about decision tree.
Well really there's actually a very brief introduction to Decision Tree random for us as far as a boost
as an added benefit of using those two models.
Let me take a step back.
Remember when we were looking into Boston housing there were a lot of features and see if I actually
did provide.
Yeah there are a lot of features you have no idea which is the important feature.
I did talk about adding one by one by one and observe using ask where to tell if the actual data.
Sorry the feature itself is important and provide any significant value add in the machine learning
models prediction.
There's a shortcut or walk around to get to those answer really really quickly.
That's where this random forest as well as that of both comes in really handy.
So this is the part whereby we want to revisit the feature importance which we did earlier.
The answer the questions that we won the one to ask is that we have 13 features for the Boston Housing.
Are they all equally important.
Which features are more important.
In Kentucky Lynn help us with this exercise rather than going through the process of elimination one
by one.
Well if we use the edibles we already perform the modeling earlier edibles to have this special feature
or you can call it method call feature underscore importance is and generate this so values.
And if I look at the columns of our underlying data I just need to well combine the two and view them
concurrently which is why I'm using Panda's data frame here and label the column as feature and sort
them in ascending order
descending order because I said it to force then you can see that Alstead has the highest value followed
by room number and all the way down to CHP errors.
So this is the ranking order the importance or the feature importance.
It can also plot them to see in terms of the value absolute of value relative to the rest and you can
see that the first tree although this is not in percentage format provide subsidies or amount of the
explanatory power towards the so-called medium value of the house.
If we look at random forest it doesn't have the same feature importance and as we plotted it pretty
much state the least same state R.M. and this is far although in slightly different.
So core scale but there's still picked the first this tree is the most important.
After that there's some shuffling and slightly defined in terms of order.
Okay.
So a bit of exercise for you looking at Decision Tree regress.
And just to compare now what we did earlier is that we did the random forest and we also did edibles
and what we did is that we spread the data to train and test it but we didn't do is to calculate that
mean square error as well as ask where.
What I'd like to do is actually do that exercise using decision tree regression and see what the actual
outcomes are.
I will provide the code for you to to you to view as a comparison bearing in mind there's one more thing
that we cover in these two lessons is also the so-called feature importance.
I'd like you to actually try that exercise you see the decision tree to help you with the you know to
to not just watch me go through the whole process but also you actually get your hands dirty as well
so let's walk through this exercise.
We perform the prediction of course we create an instance of the model perform the prediction followed
by running diminished area and then to ask where it performed far worse than both the random for us
as well as to add a boost.
And finally when you look at the feature importance it by the order is slightly different but they asked
you the same three variable to arm and this state are in this okay with that I'm going to stop right
now hopefully you've got the same result.
Feel free to dig in a little bit more just to understand the whole exercise.