Welcome back.
And the last Listen we talk about the difference between classical programming and machine learning.
And we talked about the fact that the machine has this portion which it learns from the data without
rules being provided to it.
So in this lesson we're going to go into how does the machine learning algorithm actually learn how
does it do the learning itself.
So there are three basic ingredients that's that are needed.
The first one is that you do provide you do need to provide training data.
Now copious amount of data lots.
In other words and you also have targeted or examples of expected output.
I mentioned previously cards it could be dogs it could be pandas.
Basically the idea here is really it has something to learn towards so-called goal that is actually
blending towards a look go based learning so you provide the answer and you provide the raw data it
learn a representation of it and in it's different from human from the machine learning algorithm point
of view is Justice's statistical representation zero.
And one's in other words the third ingredient is that is needed or you need to provide is what's called
a performance measurement a book a way of measuring to check the accuracy of the model.
Now this performance measurement or The Matrix provides the feedback to make the adjustment.
Another word for the adjustment part really is actually the learning part.
So you can think of it this way it's a little bit like a while like adults but most of the time we think
of it as a young child learn is that you give them a picture of one and you ask them what this picture
represent.
If they say one they got it right.
Okay.
If they say two then they've got it wrong then you correct them and say the answer to that actually
is one they'll learn to actually correct themselves.
So what have you done.
What you have done is that you provide some training data.
Of course you initially trained them on the examples of digits 1 to 10 and then you give them the answer
as you were teaching them 1 2 3 or the way to 10 and after that a way to measure the performance of
course and the measure of performance is slightly different in the machine learning well is that it
uses specific algorithm to tell and formed the software or the script that it is correct or incorrect
but in the human world the parents or the teacher inform the child whether it is correct or incorrect
based on the understanding and the knowledge of the teacher.
So this feedback loops allow the learner to continue to learn and that's the key part of the ingredients
that's needed to provide to him that any machine learning algorithm to learn from the data.
Now this is from Charlotte Chollet is actually a Google researcher.
He's the creator of a deep learning library called Kerry's hugely popular second most popular after
tens of flow tens of law is provided or open source by Google and his employer and terrorists is another
deep learning architecture.
Or you can call it library if you like or to kid for you to actually write the algorithm to conduct
deep learning now this is what a state machine learning model transforms its input data into meaningful
outputs a process that is learned from exposure to known examples of inputs and outputs.
Therefore the central problem in machine learning and deep learning is to meaningfully transform data.
Another was to learn useful representations of the input data at hand representations that get us closer
to the expected output.
So the idea really is that you are learning from the data input and also the output and continuously
learn from the mistakes and you can generalize with examples that you have not seen before.
Let me give you some example of what it looks like to look at representations.
I'm going to give you two example.
One example is one of regression and another example is one of classification regression for some of
you.
You would have been exposed to it in either high school or a level or university's undergraduate courses.
It is populates frequently
covered in graduate courses and when you're working with regression you are basically working with numerical
data whereas if you are dealing with classical classification problems you are dealing with categorical.
It could be binary 0 and 1 yes or no or categorical it could be in the forms or different country names
UK you as China Japan.
That's categorical it's not continuous in the form of a real no other example or categorical.
It could be the letters A B C D or the way to disease or death situation.
You have 26 categories.
So let's look at the example of regression now if you just ignore that line for now if you are given
a data that looks like there's many basically a whole bunch of dots.
You are asked to use x to predict Y.
The question is how would you do that.
Now if you look at it without that line there you probably will have a general heuristic understanding
or an appreciation that as the value X goes up the value Y goes up.
Now where by in the situation of regression the line of best fit which is that solid blue line data
is drawn to represent the underlying relationship between X and Y.
Now it's not going to be perfect.
The reason is not gonna be perfect is because number one there's a lot of noise.
So that's why there is actually a line there.
This is what script let's call linear regression.
And if you remove all the dots if you are given any number or sample of angst it could be also a new
data then it will be able to predict what y is with some certain level of confidence fairly accurate
because that line is the line of best fit.
It is learned by using what's called sums of squares of errors.
For now we don't need to dwell too into that.
The basic idea is that it's trying to minimize the errors so you can just quickly very quickly appreciate
and understand that that line is line of best fit it is drawn there because it minimize the errors relative
to all the other lines that you can draw.
Right.
So this really an example of representations.
This is in this case this is a linear regression.
So what about an example of classification.
Now this is an example of deep learning CNN has standards for convolution or neural network which is
a really fancy term.
In the real world an element is actually computer vision.
How computer sees the world.
Now specifically this picture it's a layer of five.
Okay I know that we haven't talk about what layers are for now.
Just take my word for it.
This is how the computers see the world in layer 5 of the deep learning neural network or deep neural
network you can see that is just patterns you can't exactly decipher what it is but that's basically
how the computer designed for the world and how to decipher the actual imagery is that is actually presented
to it to learn.
You can just imagine that if there are many layers involved here it's basically learning layer upon
layer years different representation of the world the first layer could be just straight lines corners
the next could be diagonals lines and the third layer could be circle the 4th and 5th and on and on
start to actually decipher and learn more complex structures and patterns such as waves as you can see
here there are a whole lot of.
There are no words to describe this pattern some of them looks like feathers some of them look like
the picture of the ocean some of them just looks like petty few.
So there's really a lot of representation there's no way to tell what these are but this is an example
of the features that they extracted and a representation of the world.
So for now I'm going to stop here.
So in this lesson what you've learned really is how this computer sees the world is an example of learning
representations from data.
Not that we're going to be able to understand it from a human perspective but this is how it helps the
computer to actually make sense of the world.
Whereas the picture before is for regression for the.
For this computer vision it's little bit more complicated but the purpose ultimately at the end of the
day is for us from the perspective of this lesson is to understand that computer sees it from its statistical
representation patterns.
OK.
With that I'm going to stop the next lesson.
We're going to go into what is deep learning and look at a little bit of the structure of.
What does it mean by deep learning thank you once again.