Welcome back.
In this segment we're going to look at a motivational example.
Now this is from the other causes Markle Foundation or neural network or introduction to neural network.
So what I have is the example of one an example too is this one here.
Okay.
All right.
Did let me just walk through these codes just to refresh your memory and then we're going to go into
a comparison between the neural network and artificial neural network vs. CNN and compare them in terms
of performance.
Right.
So these text processes but as usual you input the data or rather you input num pi you import tariffs
and from carers we are using the MNC data set and then we split our data sets into training set and
also the test set.
This is the basic usual data exploration.
There are sixty thousand rows of data and each of them are 28 by 28 28 rows and 28 columns and they
are all in the NUM pi array.
And this is what it looks like.
It doesn't make any sense hence what we do is that we usually convert it to an image format that looks
like this to make some sense out of it.
So looking at the the training why train privacies X train.
This is the white train which is a target variable the shape is also sixty thousand.
We're looking at the second which is the third item to remember the pattern start counting from zero.
So we're looking at for the actual target.
Yeah or the label was four and if you look at the corresponding X train two is the image looks that
this is a four is a handwritten digit.
Right.
And then if you look at the X tests and that y test there are ten thousand rows of data that we're using
to actually test the accuracy of the neural networks in terms of the architecture we're using Kerry's
here and the actual model is the sequential model and there are two dense layer.
There are 512 neurons so you can see that this is quite a quite a massive new network is is very wide
but it's not very deep so a breath Y is it's fine and twelve.
But depth wise is only one two because we have ten classes or ten digits.
So that's why we actually have 10 dense core outcome here.
And we're using the self mixed and cell predictor rather than sigmoid sigmoid for binary soft mixes
for multi class.
So those are the basic steps out the previous portion is really just reshaping our data in such a way
that the sixty thousand row we're combining reshaping rather than 28 by 28 in terms of the 2D we come
with community into
one vector and we convert the data normalized it into between 0 and 1 hence we divide it by 2 5 5 because
the numbers here is between 0 and 2 5 5 and we're using an optimizer which is armaments prop the more
advanced version instead of stock that is stochastic gradient descent.
All right Judy.
And we're using categorical across in entropy rather than binary because we're at 10 digits here and
the training shows that in terms of the performance accuracy starts from 91 percent and reached a peak
of ninety nine point six percent and in terms of the prediction is ninety eight point one five.
Right.
So that's really a really quick tool revision of what we looked at.
If we go over to the motivational example the first portion here is exactly the same.
OK well I'm just combining all the codes into one and insulting.
Instead of calling it model I call it an.
And if you look at the performance that is exactly is exactly the same 98 and in terms of the prediction
is ninety eight point 0 1 percent because see that architecture should look familiar to you it's fine
until off in terms of the number of neurons or breadth and the depth there's only two rows one densely
connected in two and another one.
So there's actually two of them.
Now let's have a look at CNN convolution all neural networks.
You if you look at these first cell here they are exactly the same.
If you are looking at the eye put a note here.
This is without padding.
Just take note of that.
That's not important for now.
Reward should cover the actual details of the architect a bit later on.
Right.
So in terms of the architecture of the CNN we have a convolution or layer followed by Mexico.
Another convolution there might be followed by Mexico convolution there followed by a flatten and then
another to densely connected there.
And it's that that's all that we have.
So we have one two three convolution there two makes poorly and then flatten it so that the these core
soft Max the classifier can actually make prediction.
All love it that there is this is an important process or step that they actually need to flatten it.
Otherwise these soft mix would not be able to perform is what it needs to do.
So the rest is exactly the same we are we need to compile it we need to fit it and then followed by
prediction.
So if you look at the training score this is the highest is ninety nine point eight 0 7 radians to outperform
against the end and this is 98 percent and this is the actual print of the architecture itself you can
see convolution next convolution Max convolution flatten to dance layer and if you look at the prediction
is ninety nine point one six.
It's far outperform the ninety eight point 0 1 offer and then.
And that's the basic idea of CNN you can see that this is really an exciting space this is where you
can see that the CNN outperform the and then in terms of the prediction and it actually able to learn
not just because the actual prediction is more accurate but much what's more important is that it is
actually you can see that it actually learn to distinguish the key features that they end and when able
to learn before and then lies the problem with fully connected layer is that it just learn the universal
features but it doesn't actually learn the intricacy of some of the key difference in terms of the shapes
of the of the underlying pictures that we feed fit through.
OK.
So that's really to motivate you to understand why we actually embark on the journey to learn CNN which
is the state of the art architecture of two for object detection and image recognition.
And now when we come back we're going to start to get some another perspective or intuition of how CNN
actually view images this time around.
A lot more visual rather than code and I look forward to seeing you then.