Welcome back.
Previously what we've done is import couple libraries for the purpose of data analysis.
The number pi depends is the seaborne as far as the map.
Look we have them fully utilized and yet work we have done though is that we didn't make use of panders
to read the ARIAs dataset into memory.
So right now having done all of that renaming the columns hey we're going to compare the same dataset
which is provided for within C bond itself.
Now bearing in mind that I mentioned before the name Pi which is let's come back here a little bit the
version that we use num pi is version 1.
So it's no longer in beta both pandas as far as C bond are still in beta.
OK so zero point two five and zero point nine.
So they can the actual API core they're using like reads yes we can change.
OK.
Which is why I just know the minus one threw out an error and the last lesson.
But those are things to keep in mind.
But again usually the error message provide sufficient information for you to actually make correction
or deal with the problem or to them to be.
I did show you how to actually go to Google just search the error message and then you see some kind.
So has already asked a question in the stack overflow to how to do with it right.
This is to show you and the C bond which we use as an S to denote that that you can actually load the
data set.
There are some toy data sets that you are deep in preloaded and c bone for you to make use of.
So let's run that so load data said we are looking for the iris and storing into the variable core Iris
and let's have a look at the first five records with data and show enough as you can see here the the
data already is straight from seaborne look similar but also different at the same time.
You notice that the column name is a bit different is the that they use the underscore to connect the
two terms separately.
Length instead of what we use is actually just space and the other one is that when it comes to the
class we call it class that species and they've stripped off the iris dash and leave it.
I think then the other two but inspecting the raw data it looks roughly similar.
I don't think they're exactly the same.
There will be some variation but that's ok at least from the surface of it.
You can tell that they are the same data more or less to a large extent that's useful for that purpose.
And you can see here that once somebody has 60 kinda loaded the data set it makes it a lot easier for
you to utilize it.
So let's make use of data frame that describe which is a method is provided for within the pandas itself.
So if you look at this described to you that the number count or conversely tell us how many rolls of
data that you have is 150 or so and gives you some basic information several length for point eight
with history on all five pedal lengths three point seven five panel with this one line nine so that
these are descriptive stats.
Okay.
This is probably why it's called this describe.
You have to mean you have.
STV means towards the end deviation of the minimum 25 percentile fiftieth percentile seventy fifth percentile
and maximum.
If you're not familiar with what I just said there like means standard deviation minimum and maximum
and the percentile you probably want to refreshed at slightly beyond the scope.
I assume that prerequisites of the foundation that you already have those basic foundation of knowledge.
Otherwise this costs we're just going to be run too long.
But don't be too concerned with that just google it.
Most information already online somewhere that you can actually quickly refer to it just to refresh
yourself but is useful to know that.
OK.
So this is the dev from what we had before which is this DNA here.
All right.
So if we look at the iris which is from the dataset is from si bon let's have a look at the describe.
And just to compare.
Are they vastly different.
So looking at it broadly they look almost the same.
Almost I say almost because yes they have hundred and fifty rows of data.
But I do notice that the sample with mean is a bit different OK.
And this.
Yep the.
Likewise the pedal length is a bit different.
The pedal with is a bit different.
And some of these are probably because of the treatment of the data.
Then once you actually go down the track of learning machine learning and data science you will very
very quickly come to an appreciation that the data are usually very very dirty yes dirty.
Okay.
There are a lot of manipulation cleaning sorting managing that you have to do to actually get it to
a steady state whereby you can see properly analyze it.
No I just wanted to highlight to you that despite the fact that they are two same data set there are
some variation OK there the DNA of which the data frame which we store imported from hundreds of cells
using pendants to imported the raw data set is directly from the UCI in machine learning repository
and Iris which is of course from seaborne and likewise spawning state extract this Dalek directly from
UCI as well because they're all from the same source file which is Robert.
What's his name again.
Robert Fisher is all from the same source but somehow along the way something change.
So that's really to actually give you a rough idea and just the appreciation that these things can and
do happen.
So moving on from there I just want to you illustrate to you that you can actually use this method call
in full and I'm going to print it to the screen that gives you some really quick summary information.
How many rows of data the type of data you have the length with in the form of float 64 and species
is in the form of an object.
OK so keep that in mind.
You have four objects four floats right or float 64 and one object and and I'm using slightly more bonds.
Panda features which is grouping them I'm saying the data frame call Iris grouped them by the column
core species and using a chain method size to tell me the number of observations for those respective
species that it's in the data.
So so looking at this we have three different classes or three different species that those of us in
color Virginia occur each of them have a size of 50 count of 50.
So that's the one part to keep in mind then you can see that there are balance.
OK.
Fifty each which is useful for the purpose of our exercise.
So for that I hope that you've found that useful just a clue a quick summary.
What have we done so far with the previous lessons we extract the data directly from the UCI machine
learning already provided to you in the form of CSP in the data directory and you read it using independence
reads yes we method.
OK.
That one there and this lesson we cover.
How do you load the same toy data set directly from bond itself.
And we make use of some basic descriptive statistics methodology or methods as provided for in pandas
in the follow describe which allows you to see information very quickly in the math in the ways of Count
the Ways and Means standard deviation and the percentiles plus the minimal maximum as well.