Welcome back everyone.
And the session we're going to start digging into understanding convolution and also its neural network
structure.
This lesson we're going to look at a couple properties of CNN and also how to work with images.
So let's get started.
One of the key characteristics of CNN is that its core local in variance.
Now once did CNN have learned the pattern.
It can recognize it anywhere.
And it's also called a transitional or translational invariant.
And also the other second feature is it is composed of senility and learns spatial hierarchy causal
patterns.
Now this use an example does fancy words.
The first layer may learn simple patterns such as vertical and horizontal edges.
As we looked at the last lesson the secondly it may learn more complex patterns that are made up of
features from the first layer.
This ensure that the CNN then efficiently and doesn't duplicate what was learned before.
So each layer actually picks up different features.
Those are the two key properties of CNN and others is that it operates with what's called three dimensional
tenses are also images.
If you look at it and how it works is that it has height.
The first column or rather the first input is called height followed by the width and channels channels.
Depends on the input pictures that you provide.
If it's a black and white picture then it's the channel will be equal to one if it's a red green and
blue images.
So G.B. then the channel will be three in the example that we looked at which is the MLS example it's
really only black and white.
The example there is 28 height 28 and with also core 28 by 28.
The channel is only one because there's no color for that is only one scale or 8 bit which is starts
which starts from zero and max out at 255 and followed by the actual filter that's being applied to
it is the three by three future also Coke.
Coke colonel in the previous lesson that we looked at the number of futures that was applied to it was
thirty two.
So as a result of that what comes up idea the end is that it's twenty six by twenty six followed by
thirty two channels and that's how a few to actually work because there are 32 futures being applied
to the same image the output then must then be 32 futures.
So what you have now is that the depth has gone from one to now thirty two stick together again I'll
show you a picture later so that you can see visually how what it looks like the question then is why
is it that the output feature is only 26.
The reason lies with the future in this situation because we didn't had any numbers around the edges
what happened now is that the filter is only three it can go hanging out at the edge so as a result
of that you've lost two columns and also two rows.
Again I'll show that to you in the picture format so that you can visualize it but if you can actually
just walk through that in your mind it's a future of three by three you will that you will always lose
the the the core height or the high for example with and you actually lose all of it minus one The same
goes with the road.
Now when you're working with pictures this is a slightly repeat of the previous slide is that there
are few things to be able to bear in mind.
The amnesty mentioned us now was really small is 28 pixels by 28 pixels and there's only one channel
because it is grayscale.
So when you actually multiply 28 by 28 the sixty seven hundred eighty four values that you're looking
at in each of those values range from 0 to 255 because it is grayscale.
However if you're working with color images typically they are substantially larger and a simple image
a video image kind of like pixel size a 640 by four a four eighty.
Well not quite is actually a hundred by six hours or this is slightly SPG 640 by 480 in part by three
channels and then suddenly you find that this is nine hundred twenty one thousand six hundred values
here and that substantially in multitudes of scale larger than the seven eighty four values and 640
by forty is not even high at all.
That's not what we call a high resolution picture.
And if you converted it usually the neural network you have fully connect that layer at the end and
if you have to fully connect that layer once you have is 640 by 40 by three to the power of two and
you have that guest s astronomical number Kestrel comical astronomical number.
And that's why the computational strain on our place on your laptop or your P.C. is really high when
you actually start playing around with pictures let alone videos.
And what I have shown here is that this is an example black and white scale and below here's an example
of a colour scale colour image right.
So when we come back we're going to look at the different layer types and this deconstruct them and
look into them a little bit more details to help you to understand CNN altogether.
Thank you again ones for watching.
I look forward to seeing you in the next video.