Welcome back everyone.
And this section of the video we're going to go in to deal different later times of the convolution
all neural network.
So there are a few types of listed them here for your reference.
It starts from convolution all and carries its called Con D.
And then you have your activation layer sometimes the activation function used is rare Lou.
They are also a few other types as well.
We'll look into that.
There is the pulling layer the common pulling layers used is either Max pulling or average pulling and
you have your fully connected layer.
These are typically two wants to end before the so-called output.
They are two are the layered types.
Technically these are not really lay at times they are more computational that operation that has been
conducted.
So they're not typically counted as layers but nevertheless I put it there so that as you come across
them you won't be surprise.
These are batch normalization and also drop out.
Right.
So let's look at an example of a CNN architecture.
If you look at this you have your typical input followed by convolution or layer 2D and then makes porting
layer followed by another convolution 2D layer and then another Max pulling layer followed by another
convolution to the plus two layers of fully connected layer.
And finally the output.
Let's dive into these one by one we will start with input.
Now this is a typical example of an image.
This is a little bit contrived.
It's 10 by 10 pixel with a depth of one.
So this is the example of a grayscale or black and white picture but with grayscale the grayscale range
from 0 2 to 5 5 in Python.
In other words 256 value to it.
Now the high care is 10 pixels the width is 10 pixels the numbers there designate the so-called intensity
of the grayscale.
Let me just illustrate as an example.
We looked at this and in our previous lesson let me zoom in.
You will notice that there are numbers that comes with each of these cell here.
As you move along
let me zoom over.
OK.
As you move your mouse along some reason is not following.
As you move along you notice that adequately checks the number each of these is a pixel each pixel has
a number.
That number designate or represent the actual value determines the actual the intensity of the grayscale
of the picture.
So this is a black and white or grayscale picture.
Why here as you can see is a small number Black is actually images some reason there is actually a delay
here.
OK let's refresh that zoom out OK.
There you go.
Seems that when you zoom in it doesn't work so well.
Black is a small number.
Client is 60.
Closer and closer to 255.
So the larger number the closer it is to highlight the darker it is the lower the number the closer
it is to black.
Right.
So that's really what I wanted to highlight to you.
If you can imagine this is a little bit like the features on the machine learning.
So these are what we actually feed into the neural network every picture you feed into the neural network
and the neural network will actually start to decipher these so-called characteristics distinctive edges
and the characteristics of each of these input image.
Now this is an example of a picture that has color.
It consists of three channels to R G and B channel.
And if you look at this this one two three that is also represented as depth.
Again this is to a 10 by 10 pixels picture except the difference now is that you have three channels.
Now each channel represent each of the R G or B and the value determines the intensity of the red the
green and blue.
And when you combine them it gives you a different color.
So that's really how the three layers or three channel actually work.
So you can pay attention to this picture here you can see is ten by 10 followed by three three layers
deep.
So this is a typical example of an image color image.
Let's move into Max pulling.
So I convolution to these operations so we're looking at convolution to the operation now.
And now what we will do is that I think it's best that we cover this we will move into convolution to
these layers in the next video.
Thank you for watching.