Welcome back.
In this portion we're going to go into what exactly is a tensor.
We need to make Steve walk through this because this is fundamentals to what we do need to know we're
going to look at a few key concepts and build some foundations before we proceed further.
We've looked at what the neural network the training of it looks like.
Nonetheless last question as well as in previous lessons let's build some foundation before we we start
running.
So what exactly is tensor.
I've given you some examples here.
These are all tenses.
OK now some describe it as a container for data.
Some describe it as basically a form of representing data the other way to think of it.
Is that it is a form of data type much like integer is a data type array is a data type tensor is actually
a container or a data type that actually by and large most of the time is actually just numerical data.
You may be familiar with matrix would such as a two by two matrix that is actually a tensor.
So let me walk through some example of the different various type of tenses a tensor with 0 0 dimension
tensor is actually called a scalar in the math mathematical world scalar basically is one number.
Here is an example.
Three is a scalar which is also zero dimension tensor.
And if we look talking about vectors it's a one dimension tensor and here's an example of a tensor 3
6.
So that's actually tensor as well.
Except there is one dimension in mathematics we call this a vector.
What about matrix and the wolf matrix.
It could be two by two could be three by three.
It could be three by five.
And that would be what's core.
Two dimensional tenses and this shapes has the first column its core number of samples followed by the
features and the next one it's the time series data as an example.
This will be a 3D or three dimensional tensor doesn't really have a mathematical name to go with it.
We just call it 3D.
And with this the samples there's timestamps followed by features and for four dimensional tenses it
can come in to form and these are typically images it can come in usually the first one is always samples
followed by height with and channels.
Occasionally however it can be channels height and width we'll get to that a little bit more when we're
talking about convolution or neural network.
For now just understand that does exist and the 5 D tenses will be a video.
An example would be a video whereby you have the number of samples followed by the frames.
Okay.
The individual frames itself followed by either high with channel or channel height with.
So that's pretty much the example of what's called a tensor.
And basically really as I mentioned is actually a data container.
And by and large most of the time is actually numerical data.
Right.
So that's really what I wanted to cover when we come back.
I'm going to start illustrating some of these in a notebook so that you can actually relate how relate
this to what it looks like when you are working at in Python.