Welcome back everyone.
In this segment we can start looking at a few more distinguished and unique characteristics of several
types of layers.
This is towards the end of the different type of layers.
In this segment we're going to look at putting layer the fully connected and the flatten just to wrap
it up so let's start with pulling layer.
This is an example of Max pulling down to common times average pulling or Max pulling.
The idea here applies to each activation map independently.
The purpose of pulling is to reduce the size or spatial size or the representation.
It is speeds up the computation layer so that there's not so many calculation that needs to be done.
And it helps over control of the fitting as well.
Now if you think about what is the purpose of Max.
Max pulling the basic idea is that you take the maximum value in.
In this case in two by two matrix.
What that is doing is that you are actually just taking the mole most outstanding value and take that
as the representation of that small four pixels or two by two matrix.
Looking at the pictures that we have here there are two outputs the top one with the stride of to the
bottom one with the strata one.
So let's look at the one with the stride of two and you do need to follow along with the color and the
color represent the origin or origin of the maximum value.
So if we take this portion here this is the first application of the max pulling within this two by
two matrix.
You can see that value is chaff as the high is hands you have that because the stride is too you skip
this and you come over here and again you look at this two by two matrix and tech the highest value
which is five and now you have because the stride is too you skip this row and you come to this raw
you're looking at this then you notice that the maximum value here is twenty two followed by thirty
two.
So this basically makes pulling with two by two filter with the stride of two what happen if this stride
is actually one.
So you will the first one will be the same but you move along to twelve and you know looking at this
matrix here.
OK.
This matrix the highest value is twelve hands is off and you move along by one the highest value is
five hence you have five and you moved down here within this two by two matrix the highest value is
twenty two and is twenty two and then let me just move along one more.
Just basically finished this row and you look at this two by two the highest value is twelve hence is
two of and if you look at this two by two the highest values ten then you move down by one pixel looking
at this the highest values twenty two so looking at a stride one you get a lot more overlaps that's
why when you look at the so-called output the future of this being repeated there there's few twenty
two there's a few thirty two.
These are all repetition if you really want to reduce the size then you choose a larger stride like
the one on top whereby or the highest value is represented those are the so called high intensity I
suppose you can call it from a slightly different angle but the idea here is that it picks up the key
features so that's basically what I want to cover in regards to pulling.
Let's move to the next one which is flatten the basic idea of flatten.
Is that the classifier that we will apply next.
Which could be a sigmoid could be a linear regression logistic regression or soft Max and the likes
this allowed the classifier to to to convert it into a class.
Otherwise if you have a matrix structure then these functions can handle it.
So hence we actually convert it into a one dimensional format.
So where you have logistic this and Z a two by two which is char 5 and then followed by another row
20 to 30 to become 520 232 one long string of numbers and you apply the sigmoid or the soft Max depending
on your depending on your intention or whether there is actually multiple classes or only binary classification.
OK so that's pretty much for the flatten layer.
And we have the fully connected layer which is very common right through our artificial neural network
in then.
And if you look at this fully connected layer it's also called dense layer whereby every neuron from
previous layer is connected to every neuron in the current layer and the next layer and on and on it
goes.
If you look at this you can see that is extremely busy in terms of the picture.
So this connects to all the neuron.
Likewise this connects to all four neurons.
If you have fifty two neurons you can see what it means or why did they actually used to call this dense
layer.
And also the rationale of calling it fully connected because they are connected to every single one
of them normally in the modern day architecture of CNN you usually observe these at the end of the neural
network right.
So we come to the end of all the different layers.
There is this convolution neural network but this one is written in Java Script by cup of tea cup of
the was the professor in Stanford.
Two pops in every now and then I believe but now he's if I follow along correctly as it's in 2018 he
is in Tesla working on the self-driving autonomous cars.
So this is what he created when he was actually teaching in Stanford.
This is based on the CFR 10 which is 10 classes data sets it's all pictures.
And at this Scripps here are the java scripts demonstrate to you how CNN actually work.
It's quite a good visualization technique allows you to see end to end how it works.
A You can let me just zoom in here in terms of the loss functions this year.
You can choose the lending rate.
You can also choose the actual momentum which we haven't talked about.
So instead of stochastic gradient descent that applies momentum we've trained to it.
And then you can choose to bench size.
You can also change the way decay.
This is to actually allow the so-called fine and green training as well.
This is training from grown up meaning starting from zero.
You can also load pre train networks just by clicking this and wait for a while.
It would just refresh and start again and the preacher network has accuracy of approximate 80 percent.
This is what the so-called layer looked like neural network architecture.
Look like you have the input you have the convolution layer pulling layer convolution pulling convolution
pulling and then soft Max finally in terms of visualization you have the input.
Okay.
And this is what the activation function or pictures looks like.
And you notice that these are the different futures and these are the gradient.
These are the weights.
And this again that Renu again activation gradient gradient.
And this is the max pulling.
This is convolution and on and on it goes it actually highlight all the multiple layers and what it
looks like.
And to help you to actually see that.
And these are the so-called example prediction.
OK.
Got the truck correct the DOT correct.
There's a dot.
Yes.
This is the ship and also shows you how confident it is something like this is not very confident.
This is a horse.
Notice they got it wrong.
This is a frog.
What it takes to call it a ship.
Yeah.
So it tells you the first three classifications the top three classification whether they're right or
wrong.
Green means is actually correct.
That's the correct class of his top.
That means it takes to classify that correctly.
Yeah.
So there are a whole lot of intuition that you can develop out of playing around with this.
I highly highly encourage you.
I mean it's not very complicated architecture.
CNN architecture but it definitely will help you in terms of developing your intuition with it.
So it's really screaming.
My my my Mac is screaming now because he's actually using my CPO to actually do the calculation.
So one two three convolution that pulling in between
and the activation function.
All right.
So one convolution one value and then you have a pulling convolution to pulling convolution really pulling
and then fully connected layer and solve Max.
Right.
With that let me just close it off because it's really heating up my my end mic and them.
Yeah.
So this is basically what we've covered right throughout this whole series of lessons in terms of the
different layers.
Let me go back to the architecture that we looked at.
We covered the employer which is the image that is made out pixels of its gray scale.
There is only one layer if its color then you have to be three layers or three channels.
We talked about convolution We talked about pulling layer.
We talked about the flatten the purpose of flatten.
And we also talked about the densely connected layer.
And yeah that's pretty much everything that we cover.
I hope you have found that extremely useful.
These are all the different layers we covered.
Thank you once again for watching.
I look forward to seeing you in the next lesson.