Welcome to this module,
so let's dive right into it and let's get started with the basics of CSS. To be precise in this module,
you will learn how you can add CSS to HTML, to really ensure that your page looks good and which
different options you have when it comes to that.
We'll then dive into how you may set up CSS rules,
so after you learned how to add CSS, how you actually write CSS code to change something on your
page.
We'll then dive deeper into selectors, properties and values because these things turn out to be important
when it comes to writing CSS rules
and finally, besides a couple of other things that are related to the previous topics, we'll also have
a look at how we can actually resolve conflicting styles.
So a lot to cover,
let's get started.