Welcome to this optional video.
This video is meant for everybody who just joined this expert track,
so in case you will followed along the course so far and watch the previous module,
you can skip this video. In case you just joined,
let me guide you quickly through the current projects that you use and what we achieved so far.
Now before we dive into the page, you can of course find the project code attached to this video to get
started quickly.
However, as you can see right here, we created uHost so far, this is our hosting provider website and
we basically build this starting page right here,
we added a background image for example, we have a navigation bar and down here, we have our different plans.
Then we also got some features down here and we have a footer, the footer and the navigation bar is the
same on all pages.
So we also have a packages page which gives you an overview of the different hosting plans we have available
on our fictional site and down here, we have our footer again.
And we also have a customers page we have some nice images and some testimonials
in the end and down here, we again have the footer and we also added a form right here if we click onto
this start hosting button.
The important thing is that our site focuses on to CSS of course,
therefore we did not create any back-end and we won't create any back-end because the focus of this course
is to learn how to use CSS but we already implemented a mobile design.
So if we click right here in the developer tools, we can see, if I increase the zoom a bit like that, that
our page also works in a mobile view,
we can for example change or switch to different pages,
this is the packages page again,
you can see it works quite nice in the mobile view also
and if we click on to our icon right here, we are coming back to our starting page, also in a nice mobile
design.
So this is what our website looks like at the moment,
let's now also have a quick look at the code we wrote so far because right there, we have a main index.html
file which contains of course the navigation bar and the footer and also the content of this starting
page,
for example our different plans right here,
choose your plan,
we saw that right here, this part.
Then we have a corresponding CSS file which refers to this index.html
file.
Then we have a shared.css file which contains the CSS styles for our header and for the footer,
so basically for the elements which are displayed on every website. We also have some shared.js file here,
so some Javascript which is required to make sure that our 'Choose Plan' button right here,
this one works and which opens that modal right here
and for the other pages, we have our customers file right here,
so this is for this customers page we can see with the corresponding CSS and HTML files. The same thing is
true for packages and for start hosting
and then we got this image folder which basically contains the customer images, our background image
of the starting page and the background image of our plans right here, on this page
and of course also our uHost icon right there and that's it actually.
This is what we achieved so far
and with that, we can now dive into flexbox together.