Now that we understand how we should write our code to work in as many browsers as possible and to be
understandable and easy to maintain,
there is another question that could come up. Once you dive deeper into CSS world,
you'll find out that so-called CSS frameworks exist, things like Bootstrap.
Now what are they and when should you use them?
Let's do a quick comparison.
We have vanilla CSS of course, with that I mean CSS code we write with the base features. We write
all our styles and layouts on our own
if we don't use an extra package, with extra packages, I mean things like component frameworks, for example
Foundation or Bootstrap 4.
These are simply third-party CSS packages,
often they also come with Javascript portion for some interactive elements but in general, they are packages
of code which give you prestyled components and utility classes.
So in the end, they expose a bunch of CSS classes which you can start using
and if you apply one of their class to one element, it immediately looks in a certain way because they
did the styling.
There also are utility frameworks like Tailwind CSS which are also giving you some help,
they offer you some styles in which you can build up on, they give you some utility classes but they
don't give you prestyled components,
they don't do all the work for you.
Now let's take a look.
Obviously, our project is written with vanilla CSS all from scratch, all by ourselves,
now I'm on getbootstrap.com which is the site of the Bootstrap package. The Bootstrap package is
a CSS framework which you can simply install by putting that link here into your HTML file,
this will download the Bootstrap styles and then you can start using their layout utilities, like their
own grid which is not based on CSS grid but which actually uses the flexbox behind the scenes
and allows you to use these helper classes
you see here to build a grid or you use one of the many components they offer you, like these beautifully
styled alerts or like buttons or things like their prestyled form elements.
These are all normal HTML elements but by attaching the classes they offer to you,
they immediately look the way they look here.
Obviously, this has some great advantages,
you save a lot of time writing these styles on your own
but I'll come back to a detailed comparison in a second.
Let's also
have a look at Tailwind CSS first, this is kind of an alternative to Bootstrap but it follows a
different approach.
This does not offer with a bunch of components, you'll find no single component here,
instead it offers a bunch of utility features.
It also offers some layouting system which makes it easier for you to position elements and it does so
by also exposing utility CSS classes which you can add to your code and these classes allow you to
quickly achieve certain looks and styles and behaviors.
Here, you've got more control over the final outcome and the look of that outcome
but you still can build up on some of the utility classes without writing everything from scratch on
your own.
So which one should you use then?
Well, let's have a look at some advantages and disadvantages.
Vanilla CSS of course has the advantage did you have full control.
You saw that in this course, we wrote everything from scratch on our own,
therefore everything works and looks exactly the way we want it to be.
You also have no or at least very little unnecessary code,
at least if you write clean code and remove code you don't need anymore.
You only have selectors and classes and rules which you need,
you don't have any code lying around which doesn't do anything on your page.
You're also free to name classes as you like and whilst you should follow some best practices when it
comes to this,
this of course has the advantage that you and hopefully your entire team has an easier time understanding
which class does what.
Of course, there are disadvantages too. You have to build everything from scratch,
this is a lot of work and it also means that you have the full responsibility of your code.
If you write bad code that doesn't run on some browser you need to support, that screws something up,
that simply is too complex,
well then this is your fault and you'll have to fix it on your own,
you might not even recognize it for quite some time.
Still overall, if you need full control and want to write highly optimized code, you'll of course have to
put in the effort to do so
but then vanilla CSS gives you everything you need for that. Component frameworks, like Bootstrap allow for
very rapid development,
you can build webpages in no time because all the components are already there,
you just start dropping some classes on your HTML code. They also typically already follow some
best practices, so the code which gets used behind the scenes should support many browsers and should
all run relatively fast.
And of course a big advantage is you don't have to be a CSS expert to use these frameworks,
you can theoretically just dive into their documentation and start using their classes,
having some CSS knowledge certainly helps but you can build nice webpages without being an expert
at all.
The downside obviously is, you get no or very little control,
you can't really adjust the code. Well in some frameworks, you can do that by using SASS and so on but it's
harder and some things just might not be really changeable.
Keep in mind, you can always overwrite rules set up by them by simply abusing cascading and specificity
but therefore you need to know what their rules are named like
and you might break other things while doing so.
So this is possible but should be used with care. Another disadvantage of component frameworks is that
you might import unnecessary overhead code.
If the framework gives you access to prestyled buttons, forms, alerts and modals and you only use the
forms, you still import to the code for the other features without using it,
that's unnecessary code your users have to download,
so maybe also something you want to avoid.
Now that being said, some modern frameworks like Bootstrap also allow you to only download parts of their
feature sets,
still it is something to be aware of. Finally, all websites tend to look the same, if you use Bootstrap
with their default theme, your page is going to look just like that other page which uses Bootstrap with their
default theme.
Now there are different themes and there are ways to adjust the theme but in general, a common look can't
be avoided
and once you are more experienced with web development, you can see that in the web, some pages look deceivingly
equal even though they use different colors.
Now what about utility frameworks then? Utility frameworks allow for faster development,
it's not as rapid as with component frameworks because you still have to write the styles on your own,
you have to write your components so to say on your own but you can build up on some utility classes,
so this definitely speeds up the development flow.
They also should follow best practices,
so you have to worry about that less
but on the other hand since you build up on their code, you still have to write a lot of code on your
own and there, you can mess things up again
but still, you need no expert knowledge.
Now that being said, you certainly need more knowledge than with component frameworks because here you
still build a lot on your own but you don't start from scratch,
so some knowledge is required but you probably still don't need to be an expert.
You've certainly got more control than with component frameworks but you still don't have full control
but a little bit at least. You still might have the problem of unnecessary overhead
code here though, you still might import utility classes you just don't use but at least you avoid
the problem of all websites looking the same.
There certainly are some elements which are re-occurring but since you generally write your styles
on components on your own, it's definitely less than you have with the component framework approach.
Now with that, these were a lot of arguments, which one should you choose?
Well, you have to make that decision for yourself.
Here are the pros and cons and there is no wrong choice here,
it really depends on what you're building, your time horizon and what your goal is in the end.