Now that we have to look at the basics of animations, let's create one for another part of our page. On
the customers page,
let's make sure we can actually flip a customer if we hover over him. For that,
I'll go to my customers.css
file
and first of all, I'll create the keyframes for the animation, just as we learned it,
that's always the first step.
So we use @keyframes to create our keyframes set and I'll name it FlipCustomer or whichever name
you want to assign to that animation.
Then here, I want to use three keyframes
and of course you can tweak this just as you desire.
I want to use transform again, as you saw, you often use transform when you play around with animations
or transitions simply because transitions and animations often are about moving things
and here, I want to rotate the customer on the y-axis but start at zero.
Now I will also add a second keyframe and transform my rotation again
but now I want to transform to let's say 160 degrees,
so I want to completely flip the customer and this is almost at the point where we flip it half. With
180 degree, we would see the back side of the customer perfectly
but I want to play this a little bit slower,
so at 50% of the animation, we didn't entirely complete half the flip yet
but then at 100%, I of course want to complete the flip and I do so by adding transform rotateY here,
360 degrees.
Now with that, we get the keyframe set and
now of course we just need to add it somewhere and to add it somewhere, I'll go up to my customers and
I'll actually create a new selector.
Our customers have an ID,
customer one has an ID of customer-1.
So I'll use that ID selector here,
maybe here, doesn't matter,
customer 1 and listen to a hover or use that hover pseudo selector
but then I actually want to animate a nested element,
I want to animate the image container, I want to flip the image, not the entire customer. So there I'll
target testimonial image container.
So whenever I hover over the customer block, then I want to adjust the style for the image container
and here I want to play my animation,
FlipCustomer,
that's the keyframe set
we just added, over one second let's say, maybe with an ease out timing function and I want to keep the
ending state with forwards.
Now if we save that and we reload the page, you can already see it, if we hover over the customer, it flips
but the skewness is messed up as you can see.
So this is something we can fix by going down to our keyframes again and now by animating more than one
property,
I also want to animate the skewness and since this also is a transform value,
I'll simply add the skew function here and now it's 20 degrees by which I skewed the container.
This now stays constant in all my keyframes because I never want to change the skewness, though if you
want to create a really fancy effect, play around with that too and you will probably get a crazy animation.
Now with that, let's go back and let's reload the page
and now actually the skewness is kept when we rotate that image, only of customer 1 by the way because
we only added the effect there.
Now on a mobile device by the way, you don't see this,
you have to click on it to trigger that and then click somewhere else because there is no hovering on
mobile devices of course.
This is working the way I want it to work
and it shows that of course you can animate more than one property value-pair. Here we're animating
two
and we're even keeping one constant to ensure that we don't mess up our skewness
in this case.