So what about these font formats right here,
this ttf that we use so far? By the way,
we can also add the format after that, like this, with the quotation marks
and this would be the so-called true type format, like that.
This is an optional information we can add,
this simply gives the browser additional information regarding our font format right here.
So as I said, not required but to make sure our code is as complete as possible,
we can actually add this right here and right there also,
so for both of our imports right here for the font face. However, we only use this true type format so far
and the thing is that we have other file types available for our font formats
and now I could dive into all these formats step-by-step and talk about this but I think the better approach
is really if we just go back to caniuse.com and I show you some of the formats and especially
the browser compatibility
because as we know so far, we're going to make sure that as many visitors as possible can access the
fonts on our website, so the browser compatibility is definitely an important factor.
Now let's start with our ttf,
this is the true type font or the open type font also available right here, As we can see right here,
the general support in the browsers is quite good,
the only browser that's really not supporting it perfectly is Opera Mini,
yes but also the IE which only has a partial support but generally, the font format we use seems
to be not the worst one.
Another one we could use is woff, this one. As you can see, the web open font format right here
and if you read the description right there, this is a compressed true type or open type font
and the first thing that's really good about that is, well if it's a compressed format, it's smaller and
therefore it makes our website faster because we will later see when we talk about the font display
property that fonts can become quite big, so the file size of font families can become quite big.
This is maybe unexpected and therefore, the compression and loading times and maybe impacting these loading
times is important when using our font faces right here, our customized font faces.
As I said, more about that later
at the end of this module. However we can see that the woff format is compressed, which is great and that the
browser support is also quite awesome.
So if we compare it with our first format, the ttf format, then we can say that ttf is really good because
it's really well-known and well used format by font builders actually, by font face builders but the browser
support is not perfect as we saw with the IE. For the woff format,
we have a better compression and a better browser support. In addition to the woff format,
we also have woff two right here. As you can see, this provides an even better compression but we can see
that browsers support for the IE is not there at all
and also Safari support is limited.
So to summarize what we saw, we have the ttf format as a basic, which is widespread and well-known but you
have the problem with the IE. We then have woff which has a better compression and is faster and has
a better browser support in general
and then we have woff two which is the fastest one with the best compression but with some limitations
regarding browser compatibility.
Therefore, what we could do now is we could simply add all three formats to our source for the font family.
The problem is of course that we only have our custom font in this ttf format and in this course, we also want
to create the other files
now. But in theory, if you have these files, what you could simply do is you could simply copy the URL
right here, like that,
maybe like this. Important, get rid of the semi-colon right here and change it to a comma,
also right here and then add it a third time,
now with the semi-colon again and then you could start with woff two right here, the format for woff
two is also woff two.
Then we have woff as a second choice,
this one and that one, not woff two, woff only
and then the ttf, our true type as the third format that we have. As I said, in our case, we don't have all
these formats, so we only need ttf so we can delete these
but I just wanted to show you how this would work in general
and with these formats, you're actually quite safe when it comes to your custom fonts.
There are also other formats to be honest
but the reason I'm not diving deeper into these is if I go back to caniuse.com and for example
enter eot, like that, the embedded open type font,
well you can see what I mean.
We don't have any browser support at all,
the only browser that supports it is the IE
and we saw that woff is also perfectly supporting the IE,
so I don't think it is required to dive deeper into the other formats that we have right here for our fonts.
So with that, we understood these different fonts formats and we can now dive deeper into different
font properties that we can use for our fonts in the next lecture.