So with the core logic being set, it's now time to get our hands dirty and dive into the responsive design
on our website.
Now before we do that though, we have two issues;
the first issue is that we should get rid of that second media query right here.
We can apply that, it's not a problem but for our project, I will like to stick to this 40rem limit
right here for all our media queries, just to keep things simple.
However, there is an additional problem and the problem is this background image because right here, we can
see that our woman right here
kind of gets her head stuck in the nav bar and I don't think that's a good look.
So let's quickly improve that by simply changing our left 10% and bottom 10% to center,
that's the simplest solution for that.
Max already told you about the details, how to format your background images,
so with that if we reload the page, you can see that the head is now going not into the nav bar
because the image is always centered and I think this looks quite nice actually now.
So with that, we can now continue with the responsive design of our plans because what I would like to
achieve is that as soon as we are below our 640 pixels,
so right here, this 40rem, the plans should be displayed below each other,
so they should just simply be three containers basically displaying all the information.
For that, we need to work on the plans ID maybe and especially inside this ID, we have the plan list
class right here and then the plan, the highlighted plan and the premium plan, so free, highlighted, premium.
So we might have to work on these classes,
therefore if we go back to our code, we can start our work right here maybe with the plan class because
the first thing I want to change is, I want to change this display style right here because I don't
want to have inline block elements which then kind of show the behavior we have right here,
I would like to have simple block elements.
Therefore what we can do
and keep in mind, this is the mobile first design,
we can simply delete display inline block. What will happen then is
if I reload the page, you can see the plans are now displayed below each other.
Why is this happening?
Well because as you can see it right here,
each plan now again is a simple div
and we talked about the general behavior of a div, a div is a block level element and therefore, occupies the
entire space of where it is positioned.
Now with that, we did our first step. By the way, of course the desktop design is now less but we work
on that in our media query of course
but for now, let's stick to our mobile design right here.
So the general order is fine,
we have a different way to display our plans but the width should be different.
For that, we can go back and get rid of that empty line maybe and now simply change the width right here
to 100%, like that.
Let's see what happens
now if we do that, yes it looks better,
now the plans are basically occupying
almost 100%.
Let's see why this is not working.
Well, this should be due to the plan list class right here,
yes.
Well as we can see, the plan list class right here has a margin to the left and to the right
and we can also see why this is happening because we have a width of 80% only and this margin
auto.
So if we just change that to 100% and then actually get rid of the margin
auto
because there should not be any margin left,
let's se,
yes,
then we can see that we have our elements now displayed below each other still and we got rid of the
margin,
so that's getting closer to the look that I would like to have.
What we can also see is that our website is not really formatted perfectly yet, you can see this little gap
right here between the image and the right border
and we can also go to the left and to the right of our plans
and if we inspect the plan, we can see that we have a margin around it,
we can see this down here.
So let's maybe get rid of the left and right margin,
so I'm in the plan selector class selector again and the margin top and bottom is fine but I think
to the left and to the right, we should have a zero margin.
If I reload the page now, we should see that yes, now it works fine.
Now we don't have this gap between the image and the right limit of the developer tools of the website
right here and we can see that we can scroll perfectly through our different plans and we don't have
any margins to the left and to the right,
so this looks nice actually.
We can then also clean our code a bit and actually get rid of the vertical alignment now because we
should actually be able,
yes as you can see, as the elements are basically using the entire space, the vertical alignment is not
required anymore.
So we also made sure our code is a bit leaner now.
I will also comment out the plan list right here for the moment because we don't need that wrapping
container,
so this container right here, for the mobile view,
this is working totally fine without it but it might be the case that we need it later,
so I will keep it like that,
let's see if we have to add it in our media query.
Another thing that I would like to change is that we should get rid of this shadow we have around our
recommended plan right here because the highlighted plan, this one as you can see has this box shadow around
it and although it looks great in the desktop version, I don't think it's nice right here because it
looks kind of like an error,
so we should also get rid of the box shadow right here.
Let me also comment this out for the moment because we might need it later in the media query
because there, the shadow looked actually quite nice.
So with that, we also improve the look again and yes it looks better as I think.
And with that, we are actually, well at least for the moment, done with the responsive design of our plans.