So with our box shadow removed, our website looks actually quite nice in the mobile view right here.
So now it's time to add a media query because we want to make sure that the page doesn't look
like that on the desktop devices because I don't think that's a good look.
So let's go back to the code
and as we learned it in the last lecture, we will add the media query right here below our actual part of
the website.
That's not the way we should do it in the end or we will do it in the end,
as I said, we will add all the media queries below the code at the end of this course
but for now, let's add the media query, we will use the same width we had before, so our 40rem and let's
now start with our plan right here,
so the plan class and let's see what we have to change right here.
As we said for the mobile view, we now defined these rules and while these rules in general are fine,
there is one really important thing that we have to change.
That's of course we need to change the way our elements are displayed because right now, we have changed
them to block level elements
but we want to make sure that these are displayed as inline block elements again.
So let's let display inline block right here,
like that and with that if we reload the page, you can see
nothing changes.
What's the reason for that?
Well if we go back to our code and go back to the plan, we can see that we applied a width of 100%
and that's of course not what we want for the desktop view. For the desktop view, we should go back to
our initial value which was at 30% width,
so let's add width 30% right here like that and with that change in place, we can see that our
plans look better again.
We still have some issues but we will fix these in the next minutes.
A first fix would be to again apply the vertical align because we got rid of that
but for the desktop version, this should definitely be right here and improve the look already,
let's see what happens.
Yes as we can see, now these two plans are more in line with the recommended plan again,
so that was definitely an improvement that was required.
What we need though is we need to add back our plan list code right here, this one and we can actually
take the entire code because we don't get it up here but we need the code in our media query.
So let's maybe add it at the beginning directly, like that and with that, we have our wrapping container
added back,
so this container should take place in case the media query is applied
and if we are reload that, we can see that our text or our boxes are central again because remember, we
just added this container back, so the code for this container here
and because of that, we basically got our style back that we had before in our desktop version and the
cool thing now is of course that once we are below our 640 pixels right here, we can see some issues
though, as you can see right here, the box is too small,
we'll fix that. Then you can see the website jumps from the mobile to desktop version
and that's pretty cool actually as I think. Now let's go back to the code and let's see if we have to
add some more properties to our media query.
Do you remember one thing we deleted?
Because if we scroll up, we also commented out our highlighted plan,
so the box shadow for our highlighted plan
and while we didn't want to have it right here in the mobile version, I think it makes sense to add it
back in the desktop version.
So let's add our plan highlighted class right here,
plan highlighted, this one and let's add this declaration back in, like that
and if we now go back and reload the page, we can see that the box shadow is visible in the desktop
view
but in the mobile view, it's of course not there because always keep in mind, these declarations or
these rules will only be applied if we have this media query applied and this is only true if this if condition
is met,
so if the min width is equal or larger than this 40rem. With that, there is only one issue that I just
saw, that we should also fix because if I decrease the size, we can see that the box is a bit too small,
so the recommended is outside of the box and if I increase the width again, well the boxes get bigger
and bigger and I don't think that this is a nice look
and if you remember back the units module, we learned that we have these min width and max width properties.
Now wouldn't it be a good idea to apply these right here and to specify a min width for our plans right
here, maybe round about here for example
and also a max width so that we can say we don't want our plans or the boxes for our plans to become
wider than a specific width that we define.
So what would be a minimum width that we want to have for our plans right here?
Well let's maybe have a look at our highlighted plan for example and if we now go to computed, we know
that already
and scroll down, then we can find the width right here.
If we now decrease the width right there,
now the formatting changed, so now we can find it down here.
So we have 300, increase that, we have 336 pixels
and if we decrease it, yes maybe it shouldn't get smaller than this, maybe a bit, maybe like that,
something like that.
So round about 210, 205 pixels,
so let's maybe use a min width then, right here for our plan,
the min width which should be equal to 13rem.
So 13rem, 13 times 16 is 208,
so this is fine,
let's add a space right here.
If we do that and reload the page, we can now see that our box,
can you see it, doesn't become smaller than these 208 pixels that we defined
and if we decrease it further, it looks nice all the time
actually. There is a certain point, so below 200 pixels where it still doesn't look perfect
but to be honest, if you remember back when we had a look at the different device widths that we have,
having a smartphone with width below 200 pixels is pretty uncommon,
so therefore I think we can live with that for the moment,
this is fine.
What we need to add though is also a max width because as you can see right here, the plans keep increasing.
So let's also do this and for the max width,
let's also have a look at the recommended plan and the highlighted plan and let's see what we computed right here,
496 pixels,
I think that's way too big.
I think around about here,
what's that now?
Yes maybe round about 400 pixels which would be 25rem.
So let's maybe add a max width right here
of 25rem like that
and if we reload the page again, we should see that the boxes don't become bigger than the 25rem we defined
and that's pretty amazing already right,
because now we have two really significantly different designs implemented on our website; the mobile design,
right here and our desktop design which keeps increasing up to certain screen widths
but then is limited
once we hit a certain maximum width that we just defined. So with the plans being responsive, it's time to
continue with the next area of our starting page.