So that's it,
that was the module on how you can approach the styling of form elements.
In the end it's not that different from the way you style other things in your app.
You learned that for styling inputs, you have to watch out that many input elements have default browser
styles which you want to overwrite or overwrite them with the inherit special value, to inherit the values
you define anywhere else in your web app or a website.
You learned about special pseudos selectors, like focus, to provide a good user feedback or checked for the
checkbox for example and you learned about the difference between outline and border again.
We also had a look at validation and you learned that you can give the user feedback with the valid and invalid
pseudo selectors or with manual validation done by adding some invalid class or whatever you want to
name it, to the elements you currently consider to be invalid.
And we also had a look at buttons and especially, how we can style the disabled state with the help of
the disabled attribute selector and that's it.
This is hopefully something which helps you in your next projects.
Now in the next module, Manuel will take over again and will walk you through how you can style text in
different ways in your application.
So let's move on to this module together now.