So that's it,
that was it for this module.
You learned about the transform property.
You learned that you can use translate to move the element around on the different axis.
You learn about scale, rotate and skew and that these functions can be applied as values on the transform
property to change the look of your element just as you need it.
You learned that 3D transformations are possible via the z-axis or for the rotate
actually via the
x and y-axis due to the way elements rotate around axis
and that you can use transform origin and transform style to change how your elements actually transform.
You also learned about perspective,
very useful for 3D animations and that this allows you to define the perspective or the distance from
the object of the viewer.
You also learned about perspective origin which allows you to manipulate the origin of the viewer, which
means the angle at which you're looking at a transformation
and these are the key things you need to know about the transform property which can help you build
really powerful visual effects.