So let's dive into some font properties now that we have applied them and see which impact they have onto
our fonts. For that,
I will now go to the customers page maybe, right here, so that we can see the font on a different page
now and let's have a look at this class right here,
so the testimonial text class.
Let's find this class also in our customers file right here
and let's now scroll down a bit, right here and let me know show you some of the font properties
I just talked about. The first one is of course font size,
I think I don't have to talk about the details regarding the units,
we had an entire module about that, so we could for example say we use 40 pixels right here
and if I reload the page, you can see that the font size increases.
I think that's pretty clear for you now.
Another property that has a direct impact onto the way our text is displayed
is this one, font variant.
If I use this one, this small caps value, then the following will happen, if we reload the page,
you can see that basically the height of our font did not change but all our small characters that
we had before were now changed to capital ones.
So that's also just a property that basically impacts the style or the look of the font we have right
here.
Another property we have is font stretch, this one right here.
There you can see that you can select different stretch levels, so which define the way our font is
displayed
and if I would now apply ultra condensed for example right here and reload our page, you can see that
the font looks exactly the same way it looked before.
The problem with that font stretch property is that it is supported by browsers nowadays, so that's not
the problem
but each stretching level has to be part of a separate font face
and as this is not true for a lot of fonts, at least at the time when I'm recording this video,
I will not dive deeper into this property, in case you want to find out more about it,
just have a look at the MDN for example right here, here
you can also see what it would impact
and you can find all the values you have
and as I said, what would happen if you have a font where it can be applied.
But as I said, the browser support is good as we can see it also also down here
but the problem is that the font availability is not the best.
Therefore, I will not dive deeper into font stretch right now.
So these are the properties that basically affect the general style of the letters you have
but there are also other properties which have an impact onto the letter spacing for example and on
to the line height,
what that is, how they work and what they do,
let's find out that in the next lecture.