So let's have a look at some other properties.
For that, I will delete our font stretch and now add the letter spacing property, this one. For the letter
spacing property,
we have to use lengths as a value, so this can be either pixels or rem, I will use pixels now because
I think it's easier to see like that,
so let's say we use 5 pixels as letter spacing.
If we do that and we load, we can see that the space between our letters, between each letter increased
or we could set it also to 10 pixels
if you really want to have a big space between your letters. And as you can see, this is basically what
letter spacing does,
as the name already indicates, it increases the space between each of the letters that you have in your
text right here but
we don't need that so we can delete it right here.
A more interesting property is the next one,
this is whitespace,
this one right here. For whitespace, we have no lengths but we have properties like normal, like that.
If we apply normal,
well as you can imagine, this will show us the text in its initial status but with this whitespace,
we can now impact the way whitespace is treated inside our element and if we think about the whitespace
we have right here for our testimonial text class right here,
so this one, uHost helped me right,
then we can see that you of course have whitespaces in here. So this is a whitespace,
this is the whitespace and so on.
So at the moment, if we go back to our customers.css file, we have this whitespace normal,
we see the behavior that we can observe right here, as soon as the element has enough space,
the whitespace will jump up a bit and always start a new line where we have the whitespaces and where it doesn't
fit into the element.
Now if we change this from normal to no wrap, like that, then we can see as the name already indicates, that
no wrapping takes place.
This means the entire text in our element will be displayed in one line and the width of our window
doesn't have any impact on that, as the name says,
this is no wrap.
If we change this to pre, like that, then we cannot see a difference right here
but if we go back to our code, to the index.html file
and now let's say we add a new paragraph but not with the p
but just by hitting it like that on the keyboard, after project,
keep that in mind. If we now go back and reload the page,
you can see that after project, we have this paragraph and we see this indention that we have right here.
This is all automatically created by that value,
we also have another one which would be pre-wrap, this one right here.
If we use this one and we load the page, then you can see that we have a line break right here but that's
simply due to the reason that the space is not enough right here
but as soon as we increase the size again, we can see that we have our project in one line and after
our project where we added a paragraph, we start in a new line and then the next break of course is right
here because these words right here don't fit into one line.
The last value would have is pre-line,
let's have a look at what happens right then.
If we use pre-line right here, like this and we load the page,
now you can see that the lines are filled whenever possible because before, we saw that this line right
here was empty
but now we keep our line break right here because you said that after project, there should be a line
break, so it has to put project into a separate line
but then we have the next one starting and all the lines are filled whenever possible.
So that's what you can do basically with whitespace.
I think this is a nice property because it can help you really changing the way your text is displayed.
However, we can now go back right here
and put that new line back up again to avoid that whitespace,
I think it's better like that.
So back to our customers file now, to the CSS
file and back to another property, the line height property.
Let's have a look at this one in the next lecture.