So we saw how relative positioning works and we also saw that we can move our element out of the parent.
Now to avoid this behavior,
we can simply go to our parent element with the class parent right here and now add overflow hidden because this
will exactly do what the property already indicates,
it will hide the element once it's outside of our parent, like this
as you can see it. If we would reuse the top distance now, maybe 2, I'm not sure,
this is like trial and error or maybe 80, something like that,
let's see,
yes we can see it already,
as soon as the element moves out of the parent element, it's invisible.
This can be a behavior you want or not but at least it allows you to make sure that you don't place
elements anywhere on your website.
Now there is one problem though,
I mentioned that in the last video. If I remove the overflow
hidden property right here
and also remove position relative
and actually all the code we have for our child, like that,
let's now say that our parent is now a relatively positioned element, like that and also pushed down
from the top by maybe 200 pixels.
What happens now is that if I reload the page, you could guess that, is that element is now outside
of the parent, so the parent of our parent right here is the body element.
We can see this right here,
we have the div class parent inside the body,
so body is the parent
and now you could say well I can solve this easily,
the only thing I have to do is I have to go to the body selector right here and add overflow
hidden like that.
Let's see if this works,
as you can imagine by my voice, it probably won't work because if I unselect the inspect tool and reload the
page, you can see I can reload it as often as I want,
nothing changes
and why is this happening?
Well this is due to a default behavior of CSS. If you apply the overflow
hidden declaration to the body element,
this will simply be passed onto the HTML element right here,
so in our case to the HTML selector and the consequence of that is, well you don't have the overflow hidden declaration
on your body element,
so the code you basically have is this one.
You can cut this out, add it right here,
save the file,
so you have overflow hidden on the HTML element but not on the body element
and if we have a look at our page now, this is the consequence,
you don't have any impact of this declaration at all.
This is just a default behavior of CSS
as I said, so we cannot change that
unfortunately. What we can do though is we can simply take the chance and also add overflow
hidden to our body element right here.
If we do that and reload the page, we can see that the overflow property is working again because right
now, the overflow hidden declaration is not passed onto the HTML element because it already has such
a declaration,
why would it need it twice,
doesn't make sense
and because of that, this is working.
It would also work if you add overflow auto by the way here, as you can see, same behavior,
the element cannot be displayed outside the parent which is the body element in our case.
This is just some quick tip that I wanted to show you in case you have a situation like that. If your
parent is not the body element,
this is not a problem at all
but if this is the case, then you can solve this issue with this little fix right here.
With that, we now understood the relative positioning,
so there is only one value left that we should have a look at, sticky positioning.
Let's see how this works in the next video.