You saw the linear gradient in the last lecture,
let's comment it out and let's add another background image, this time with the radial gradient function.
The radial gradient function as the name suggests allows you to define a radial gradient,
so not one that starts at one edge and goes to another one but one that starts at a certain shape and then
transitions to all the areas around it.
Let's start with a simple gradient again, red blue because we can clearly see that. If we reload,
this is our default radial gradient, positioned in the middle by default and the shape is an ellipse,
it's not a circle, it's an ellipse
and you see it starts with the first color and then transitions to the second color which is all around
it.
Of course here too,
you can define multiple colors like green and the shape will simply be kept
and now we have a red ellipse going to a blue ellipse going to a green ellipse,
this is how that works.
Now of course you can also change the shape,
for example you can add a first argument that can be circle,
that's the alternative, the only alternative you have to the ellipse,
you can set it to be a circle instead of an ellipse. If you now reload and watch closely, you see it now indeed
is a perfect circle, no longer an ellipse.
Now of course you can also change the position, where it should start.
Right now, it was always centered but maybe you don't want that, you can add @ attribute here and say @top
for example, if you do that and you reload,
now you see the center of the circle is right in the middle of the top,
you can also say @top left to put it to the top left.
Now the center of the circle is in the top left and then the radial gradient starts from there.
You can also enter custom values here,
you could say 20%, 50%, if you do that you actually see it's moved 20% from the left,
so the circle of the innermost shape is 20% from the left and 50% from the top.
So this is basically how you know it, first value is the x-axis,
second value is the y-axis,
of course you can also use pixels here.
Now with that, we got the shape and we got the position,
now what's missing?
The missing piece of course is the size,
you can define the size by for example adding 20 pixels after a circle.
If you do that and you reload,
now you see the circle is very tiny because now and that's important,
the entire circle, without the outermost part,
so in this case the red and the blue area, have a total of combined diameter of 20 pixels,
so that's basically the width of the shape.
Now this only works for the circle, for the ellipse,
if you use that which would be the default, this actually doesn't work because what would the 20 pixels
be referring to? Of course you could add two values here and reload,
now you again create a circle though,
so you could add different values to turn this back to a non-circle.
So with two values, you can also style the ellipse, give it a certain width and height like that, first
value is width, second value is height
but there also are some keywords in case you don't want to do it like that.
You can also add something like farthest side.
Now what does this do?
Watch the current value and then reload.
Now what this actually means and you can barely see it, that the ending shape and that simply means until
it transitions to the outermost color,
so in case of two colors after the first color or in case after three colors as we have it here, after
the second color, that the ending shape and you can barely see it,
the outer rings of the blue color touch the farthest side,
so the side furthest away from the center, from the position of the element, this barely touches this
side and on the other hand, you would have closest side to reduce the size,
now the outermost circle of the blue color
and again that's hard to see but you can see there is still some non-perfect green part here,
this touches the closest side and it also concerns top and bottom by the way
and you can also not use the sides but the corners. Closest corner for example ensures that the outermost
ring touches the closest corner
and on the other hand, farthest corner allows you to control that it touches the farthest corner.
So these are some great defaults you can use to control the size of your radial gradient and that's
actually all there's to it. What you can still do is you can define color stops like blue after 70%,
you can do that to change
where it should transition to green and so on
but besides that, it behaves like the linear gradient,
you can define multiple colors, you can use hex codes, you can use color functions and so on and that is
how you can use a radial gradient.
Now just as linear gradients, they are added as background images and they can be stacked.
Now let's dive into that stacking part in the next lecture.