So over the last modules, we built this page.
It's not finished yet,
we can improve the look of that background image, we can center it and so on, we can maybe position that
text differently,
we can in general work with units a bit more, use better units than pixels, we'll do that.
We can add images here and the positioning with inline block has some issues, that hacky approach we used
in the navigation bar where we had to calculate the width of our navigation here by deducting an estimated
amount
basically, we can improve that.
The fact that here, these boxes on the left and right don't align,
these are all things we will fix especially once we dive into flex box, a cool way of layouting elements
you could say, of positioning elements but the general look is great and you learned many basics with
that and you practiced many basics now.
The next step still in this same module will be to add a second page, the packages page. We'll add the
same navigation and footer to the page and then we'll add some HTML code to that page and I will show
you and explain what it should look like in the end
and then it's your turn to practice that and try to style it with tools you learned so that you achieve
that style
I want to see at the end.
So these are the next step,
adding that new page, setting the header and the bottom, the footer there and then adding content to it which
you can style.