With partials and better import out of the way, let's move on to advanced media.
Now what is that about,
what does this mean?
We obviously have media queries
in normal CSS too and we got one at the bottom of our file here,
it just changes some sizes here.
Now, media queries can still be used like this,
nothing wrong with that.
Now of course you can also use SASS features, like variables or nested selectors in here if you wanted
to do that,
this is all normal SASS code
in the end but you can also write your media queries a bit differently if you want.
You can take that media query code here,
let's say for the HTML element and go up to the HTML element and actually nest the media query now.
Now what you can do is you can get rid of that selector, since you already nested the media query in
that selector
and of the first curly brace and just keep the closing curly brace of the media query and now if you
save that, what this will do is, it will still generate a separate media query, so valid CSS code
which nests this HTML rule
but you as a developer have this convenient way of keeping your media queries close to the elements
which they affect. You don't have to use it,
you can still use the other approach of collecting all your elements that should go into a single media
query but this is a way you might like because it's keeping your code closer to where you use it.
So if I also do that for sass-introduction here, I'll cut the entire media query, go to my sass-introduction
and add it here,
get rid of the HTML part, get rid of the selectors here and reformat this and now I can also copy that over
to details where I also wanted to use that.
Now I got this restructured and maybe a bit more readable to us as a developer because the media query
is always sitting on the element which it affects and again behind the scenes,
this compiled to code like this. If we go back to our running application and we reload it,
we shouldn't see a difference because it still leads to the same code,
it just is a bit more readable to us.
Again this is only an option,
you don't have to use it but you can use it if you want to.