So what is the line height property?
Well for that, we will first delete the whitespace right here because we understood how it works and
we don't need it anymore
and then go to our packages page
back again right here and then to the package info
class. So I'm again right here on this page and right here in this package info, specifically I will
focus onto this class right here because it only consists of one line and this is what we need to understand
the line height.
Now let's add this line height property then, so line height
and let's start with a value of 1 and
let's see what that means.
So let's save that and reload the page and if we now inspect it right here, we can see down there that
we now have line height of 18.8 pixels.
OK,
let's keep in mind our font size because the font size we actually have is this one, 19.2 pixels,
you remember 1.2rem and that's pretty close to that value actually.
Now let's see if we can get closer.
The first thing we should do is we should reduce our zoom level because I again zoomed into the page to
make sure you can see everything
but as we can see, have a look at the height right here of our content box,
the height decreases and now we are at 19 pixels already which is pretty close to the 19.2 pixels
and the reason for that is that the line height calculation simply does not consider the decimals.
Therefore, it will just stick to the 19, not the 19.2
but with that, you already saw what the line height actually is. The line height lets us define the top
and the bottom, so the space between the top and the bottom
of our content box
and with that, we have 19 pixels now
and if we follow our calculation right here, if we change that to two, then there should be 38.
And if we scroll down again, then we can see it is indeed 38 because we take our actual font size which
is the 19.2 pixels calculated based on the 1.2rem and 19.2 pixels times the two we added
right here is 38.4
and then the decimals are not considered,
therefore we have 38 pixels of line height right here.
So this is one way how to define the line height,
I will keep it zoomed out like that because it makes it easier to follow this pattern
right now. This line height can of course also apply to other font families,
let's for example use our Monserrat font that we used throughout this course.
If I use this one and I reload, you can see that if we inspect it right here, that the line height is again
38 pixels but there is one interesting thing. If I change the line height from two to normal
which is the default value, then you will see that right now, we have a line height of 24 pixels for our
Monserrat font but if I change it back to AnonymousPro,
so our custom font,
this one right here,
keep in mind we had 24 for Monserrat,
then you can already see it actually we only have 19 pixels of line height right now.
So that's important to keep in mind.
By default, the line height depends on the font family we are using.
If we change that behavior and add the line property with a value of two for example, then this will
always refer to the font size and as the font size,
in our case at least, is the same for all font families,
we have the same line height no matter which font family we are using. Now of course we are not only
limited to using this number, we can also use pixels like 32 pixels for example and if I now reload
the page, as you can imagine,
now we have a line height of 32 pixels. What's of course
also possible is using percentages for example,
so if we use 200% like that, then we would simply apply a value of,
if we scroll down again, you can see, 38, so 200% of the initial font size.
So that's basically how it works with percentages.
However, I would always recommend not using percentages like here but simply using the numbers like we
did it before because percentages sometimes lead to an unexpected behavior when it comes to inheritance
because sometimes the calculation basis for the percentage is not the font size of the element itself
but of an inherited font size of a parent
and then this can,
as I said, lead to unexpected results. By using the number right here,
we always make sure that the line height is calculated based on the actual font size of the element
we apply this line height to and that's probably the approach we can follow to ensure that our site exactly
behaves the way it should behave.
However, we don't need the line height actually right here, so we can simply get rid of that and that's actually
the basic concept of the line height,
so you basically define the height of your content right here. Attached to this video,
you can also find an article which will give you additional information about the line height property.
So in case you want to dive deeper,
feel free to have a look at this article.
So with that, we understood the line height.
Let's now have to look at text decoration and text shadow in the next lecture.