Now we're already at the point where you probably will be dreaming about the grid tonight,
so time to dive even deeper. Thus far when we wanted to position elements, like element two and three where
we overwrote the default positioning,
we did this by going to the child and giving it a start and end row and column to tell it where
it should sit.
Now this is perfectly fine and this is an approach you will probably use a lot, however you can also
kind of reverse the process.
You can divide your grid into areas which you assign names to and now I'm talking about the cells, not
the lines
and then tell the elements which areas they should occupy.
Sounds strange?
Let me show you how it works
and for that, let's pick a different layout now.
Let's say element three should take the entire first row
and we want to position it differently, so not with grid area here but instead with this named area I
was referring to.
For this, we first of all remove our value for grid area and we give it a name, any name of your choice,
maybe header.
Now here important, no square brackets, just the name.
Now of course if I reload, this leads to nothing,
now the green element is somewhere here at the bottom,
so essentially our grid is just broken.
How we would it know what the header area is?
Obviously it can't. We defined these areas in our container now,
so where we set the display grid. There we can add a special property, grid template areas. We get columns
and rows, grid template columns and grid template rows,
now with the area's property, we can give ourselves in the grid a name which we can then use on our elements
to position them in these marked cells. Here
you pass a string as a value,
so you need quotation marks, double or single quotation marks, doesn't matter,
opening and closing and now the syntax is both easy and strange at the same time.
It's easy because it's very close to how we humans think
and it's strange because it's not very close to how computers normally work.
You simply create your grid here with name values, with labels.
So what do I mean with that?
Our grid has four columns and it has three rows, right?
It has one row, 5rem,
second row with a dynamic value and a third row.
So our grid has four times three cells, four columns and then three rows.
Now we could normally clarify this here on our grid preview and we can do so if I comment out grid area
header on element three so that it doesn't get broken.
Now we can verify that we get four columns and three rows,
so we get 12 cells.
We now simply create a pattern of these columns and rows here in the string and we give each element
or each cell a name, so like header and important, this is the name we then use below.
So header and then we've got four columns, so we add header, header, header and now we have a new line
and you simply create a new line by adding a new string,
so outside of the first string, you add a second string and you can also put this into a new line here,
just to really make it look more like a table
and there, we could
name this side side main main
and add another row
so to say with another string where we have the footer, footer, footer, footer.
So important, you need to end up with as many rows and columns as you have,
so here we got four columns and three rows.
If I now save this and reload,
nothing changes but now actually, we defined areas, the first row is the header area, the second row has
two areas, the side and main and the last row has a footer area
and now we can use these names with the grid area property.
So now I can use header here because we've got header up here too
and with that, if you reload, element three actually takes to full header. So this is really cool because
now, you don't have to go to the element and tell it where to start and end, you define names and labels for
your grid up there.
And if there is some element which you don't want to give a label or what you want to leave empty, you
add a dot instead,
so I replaced the two side labels with two dots and now, they won't have names.
Now we can position element two and we can position it by commenting out our row and colors shorthands
and let's say this should go into the main area,
so now we can simply add grid area here, main. Again no square brackets or anything like that,
now it goes into the main area and the other elements fill up the remaining space.
Important here by the way, you see that element four also is positioned prior to element two because with the
grid area setting here, the DOM order actually is not respected anymore.
So this is some trivia, something important to recognize at this point.
If we give element four its own place of course by setting this grid area to footer for example, then
it will jump down there
and this cell will remain empty.
So working with grid areas is a really powerful tool which makes it very easy or much easier for us
to define where in the grid what should be positioned and this syntax can look really strange at the
beginning but especially when you write it like this, you can think of this as a table;
you got three rows and each row has four columns. Just important,
don't omit any values here,
you have to end up with as many words or dots as you have cells in the final grid.