So what can we do with text decoration and text shadow?
Let's start with the decoration first.
For that, I'm again right here in our package info class and now I will add the text decoration property
right here.
For this element right here, we didn't apply any text decoration by default
but what we could do is for example, we could apply a value of underline. If we do that and reload the
page, we can see that,
well as expected probably, the text is underlined.
If we have underline, we probably also have overline right here. If we change the value and have a look
at the result,
we can see that now we have an overline for our text right here. So we have an underline, an overline,
well we can probably also line through our text right here.
Let's see if this also works,
if I reload that, like that, yes.
So that's what we can do,
we can add an underline, an overline or a line through. We can of course also more specify the line
we want to have, we could add dotted right here for example to create a dotted line, like this.
So you can see, now we have the dotted line,
this can of course also be applied to all the other values we had,
for example the underline again, so that we can see it better and you could also choose a color of your
choice, for example red right here. If we do that and reload the page, we have a dotted underline with
that red color.
Another really nice line type is also
this one here,
so if we change dotted for wavy. If we do that and we load our page, you can see that we have this
wavy line below our text right here.
Looks kind of like an error, so maybe not the line type you always want to use but I just wanted to
show you this one,
of course it's also available for overline and for line through,
so this will be the overline style for this one, like that
and that's actually the main purpose of this text decoration property.
We don't need it right here of course, so we can again get rid of it
but one important thing we should also keep in mind when using text decoration is that if we go to
our shared.css file right here and then go down to our anchor tag selector,
so this one, there you could see that we used text decoration already. If I quickly comment that out now,
like this and like that and reload the page, then you can see that this default text decoration for links
is back in again.
So don't forget to use text decoration for both, to add such a decoration of course but also to remove a
default decoration, like we did it right here.
Let's comment it in again because we want to make sure that our text decoration for the links is not visible.
Another property in connection with the text is the text
shadow,
so let's go back to our packages file right here and add such a shadow right now.
So the property we need is text shadow,
this one right here and now we have to specify an offset to the x-axis, so 5 pixels maybe
and to the y-axis, also 5 pixels.
So with that, let's see what this looks like
if I reload the page, yes this looks interesting but probably not as we intend it to look.
I think we need two additional things; we need a blur radius or a blur at least to blur the
actual text because it should be a shadow and not a copy of the text
and then we need maybe a different color also.
Let's see if we can add these two things and to add the blur,
we simply have to add a third value right here
and let's say we use a blur of maybe 2 pixels, something like that and the color of grre, like this,
maybe we can also use a lighter grey, something like that. With that
if we go back and reload the page, we can see that our shadow looks a lot better,
it's probably a bit too far to the right and to the bottom and still too sharp, so let's reduce the offset
to the x-axis and to the y-axis and increase the blur to maybe 7 pixels.
Let's see what this looks like, like this,
yes I think now it looks quite cool because now we have a really slight text shadow behind our text.
And of course we can play around with that a lot,
we can also increase the blue more, we can for example add a color to the text shadow and make a blur of 20
pixels, something like that,
just as you prefer.
So as you can see, this would create this look.
You could also set an offset of 0 if you want to, like this and like that,
right,
would also not be a problem,
if I reload, you can see that's what it will look like then.
So feel free to play around with these values right here.
Again for our project, I don't think we need the text shadow, so we unfortunately have to delete it once
again
and with that, bring back our initial cleaner look
as I would call it. And with that, we already saw all the core properties that are font related.
Therefore in the next video, I think it's time to show you the font shorthand, which kind of combines all
these properties if you want to but which also has one alternative functionality.
So let's have a look at this
shorthand in the next lecture.