That was a lot of work
but I think now we are able to work with the position property.
Let me summarize what we learn throughout this module because the first thing we learned is that we have
this position property. The position property has a default value which is applied to all elements on
our website
and this is the static value but we can also apply values on our own.
These values are fixed, absolute, relative and sticky. Sticky is this more recent value though which
is not perfect supported by all browsers yet but still it's something to keep in mind for the future.
We also saw that we have a so-called document flow,
this basically describes the default positioning behavior of our HTML elements. We can change this
default document flow by adding the position property and depending on the value we applied, we can see
it in the first box, so fixed, absolute and so on,
the elements are either part of the document flow, for example by adding relative to it or will be executed
from this document
flow, for example by adding the fixed value to our position property. We also saw that we can move our
elements after we added this position property, there we can use the top, bottom, left and right properties
in combination with values like pixels or percentages
for example. In connection with that, we also saw that the positioning context is a really important concept
to understand why our elements actually move where they are moving because this positioning context defines
the anchor point for the actual position changed and depending on the value applied for the position
property, the positioning context changes. For fixed values, the viewport is the positioning context, for
absolute,
another element is the positioning context,
this can either be the HTML element or if we have any ancestors which have the position property applied,
this closest ancestor will be positioning context.
We also have the element itself as a positioning context,
this is the case whenever we apply the relative value for the position property and we have the viewport in
combination with another element
if we apply sticky, this rather new value as a value for the position property. We also saw that we have a
z-index which allows us to also change the position of elements along the z-axis because so far, we
only move the elements along the x or y-axis. With the z-index,
we can change the default element positioning along the z-axis.
The default value is auto which is basically equal to a number of 0 and we can change the z-index
whenever we applied the position property to an element.
What we also have to keep in mind is that larger values will position our elements on top of other elements,
lowwe values will position it below them,
so an element with a z-index of five will be positioned above an element with a value of -1
for example.
However this is not always true and this is also something we just saw in the assignment because we also
have to keep in mind the stacking context. The stacking context or a new stacking context is created
when we apply the fixed or sticky value or if we apply the absolute or relative value in combination
with a z-index which is specified by us, we saw that just in the assignment. And the stacking context simply
defines the stacking behavior of child elements
and because of that, it can be the case that a child of a specific parent has a z-index of 10 but
a neighbor element of our parent has a z-index of one only
but still the neighbor is positioned above our children of the actual element
and this is everything we learned throughout this module. With that, we are now ready to dive deeper into
CSS and because of that, I will hand over to Max again which will now show you how you can work on
background image shows and images in general
in CSS.