So what is the font display property
and how does it impact the loading performance of our fonts?
And that's important, by our fonts,
I'm referring to our custom fonts that we imported by using @font-face.
Keep that in mind, font display only works in connection with that.
However, font display is a property as you can imagine
and for this property, we can apply different values which impact the loading behavior of our custom
fonts. The values we can have are swap, block, fallback, optional or if we don't set anything, then it will
be set to a value of auto by default. Auto simply means that the browser our visitor is using will automatically
choose a value of his choice.
So what do these values mean now?
Well, let's have a look.
We basically have two different situations
while the loading process of the font takes place. This is the so-called block period,
this one right here and the swap period, that one.
Now what do these mean and how are they different for the different values that we can apply? For the
swap value,
we don't have any kind of block period.
Now what does this mean, block period
and why don't we have a block period right here for this swap value?
Well to understand the block period, imagine the following situation: our user is visiting our website
so the content has to load,
now as the fonts are not displayed immediately, we could have such a block period. In this block period,
the space where our text would be displayed would be reserved with an invisible fallback font face
and that's important.
The font face will not be visible at the moment but the space for it would be reserved,
this would be a block period,
so we basically would have the styling or the general structure of all our websites visible,
so a box which would contain text already has almost the correct height and is visible but no text would
be displayed because the font is an invisible fallback, that will be a block period.
Now if we don't have such a block period which is the case for the swap, the fallback right here would
be immediately visible,
this means once our users browses our website, boom, the fallback will be there.
After that, we have a swap period and the swap period as the name already indicates, simply is the period where
the browser has the ability to change or to swap the fallback font style that was loaded with the actual
fonts style that we have, for the swap value,
this period is infinite.
This simply means no matter how long it takes, if our browser manages to load our custom font that we
want to display,
it will swap it with the fallback, if it cannot change it,
the fallback will just stay there.
So that's the first value, that's swap,
now what about block now?
Well for block, we have a short block period,
this means this invisible font is loaded, so there is no text displayed but we have a placeholder that is
reserving the space
and after that, the behavior actually follows the swap value. We load the fallback
and once we can load it, the browser will change the fallback with the custom font that we created. The
third value is the fallback, the fallback case a very short block period,
so we have this invisible font family displayed but only for a really minimum amount of time,
then we have the fallback and then now it gets interesting,
we only have a short swap period. So there is only a short window of time where the browser has the chance
to load our custom font right here and to change it with our fallback. If the browser is able to do
that within this swap period, this short swap period, he can change it with the custom font otherwise, the fallback
will be displayed as long as our site is displayed for the visitor.
So that's the difference.
For the fallback, there was only a short opportunity to change the fallback with the custom font, for swap and block,
the loading of the custom font or attempt to load the custom font lasts forever basically, as long as
the user is on our website. Now optional is the last value that we have, for optional,
we also have a very short block period and then this thing right here, then we don't have a swap period because
the optional value simply allows the browser to choose
what you should do and this basically depends on the internet connection speed. If the browser decides
that our connection is good,
he might decide to immediately load the custom font.
If we have a worse connection which is not fast enough, the browser might decide to use the fallback
and therefore, not load our custom font.
This decision cannot be reversed, of course if we reload the page, it can but as soon we stay on the
website as a user, we will only see the fallback for example if the internet connection is not good enough.
Now the last value, auto, lets the browser make the entire decision. At the moment,
most browsers choose block then,
so if you don't set a font display, auto be applied and then it will use block, the one we saw right here
as a second option. Now the problem with this font display and this performance topic is that the fonts
we are using right here load really fast,
so to be honest, I cannot show you this in a real life example now.
What I can show you though if we go back to our code right here is how you could add or implement the font
display property.
Well important, not right here in our actual selector, so in the actual element but we have to add it
up here in our font face import,
for example if we use our first import here, we would simply add font display like that.
As I said, I cannot show you how it works because the loading time is simply too fast but basically, you
would simply add the property up here and then simply apply the values like swap or block or fallback
or the last one, we also saw this, optional, like that.
That's how you could do it.
However as I said, I cannot show it to you, so we can delete that actually once again. What we should
have a look at now though is the browser compatibility because as you might imagine, it's not the best
unfortunately.
If we go to caniuse.com once again and enter font-display right here,
you can see what I mean.
We have support for the latest versions of Safari, Chrome and Firefox but for example, the IE or Edge
don't support the font display property at all
and that also kind of summarizes the difficulties you could have when you use your own created fonts
with @font-face, with the font
import. The import itself can mean a lot of work as we have to import all the different font faces
and then if we want to optimize our loading behavior, we also have to ensure that browser compatibility
is OK for the users we want to address
and as you normally also want to address IE or Edge users, well this can become a problem.
However of course, you're totally free to do this as you prefer.
Now with that, we are almost done with this module,
there is actually only one thing that I would like to change right here
snd this is our font shorthand because we actually don't need the AnonymousPro font family here
because I would like to stick to Monserrat as we had it in the beginning and I also don't want to have
this bold style.
And additionally, now very important, as we only have one value left right here,
the font size, we cannot use the font shorthand.
We talked about that,
we at least need the font size and the font family,
otherwise this shorthand won't work.
I can also prove this to you
if I now go back to our page here, to the packages page and then inspect for example the class right here,
you can see that the font was not applied because we use the shorthand incorrectly.
Now if I add font size right here like that and reload the page, you can see that the font size was overtaken
correctly based on the definition that we made.
And with that, I think our code is cleaned up and looks fine, so we learned a lot I
think about fonts and text now and before I wrap up this module,
let's quickly have a look if all pages still look fine, as we can see right here,
this looks pretty decent, so the font style
is correct and the font families.
The packages page also looks nice,
same thing hopefully for the customers page,
yes I think also still good and start hosting also works perfectly.
Now with that, we finish this text and fonts module, now let me wrap up what we learned in the next lecture.