So now that we are real text and font experts, let me quickly summarize what we have to keep in mind.
The first thing we have to keep in mind is that we have generic and font families. A generic family
is actually a fallback in case a font family is not available and a font family allows us to define the
exact font that we want to use.
We saw it at the beginning of this module when we had a look at the syntax for example, where we had the
font family first and then the generic family as a fallback where the specific font family will then be
chosen by the settings in the browser.
We also had a look at the way how to import font families onto our website or into our code.
The important thing is that we need to make sure that we have the font families that we use for our
website in the code also available for our website users.
If we rely on to locally installed font families which could be installed on our computer but maybe
not on the machine of our website user, this can cause problems. We can avoid these problems by using
embedded font families with
@font-face,
we talked a lot about that, also about the disadvantages this approach might come with or we can import
font families from third-party providers like Google with Google fonts,
this is the approach we will follow throughout this course. Another thing we had a look at are the font
properties.
I will not dive into each property again but we saw all of that,
we saw the font size, the font style which allowed us to create an Italian style for example.
We had a look at the weight and about the importance of adding different font faces for our weight.
We saw font stretch which is very well-supported by browsers but not that perfect from a font family
availability perspective
and we saw font variant which allowed us to add this small character style to our website.
We also saw letter spacing, whitespace and the line height which allowed us to define the height of our
content box basically.
And we worked with text decoration and text shadow to add underlines or overlines to our text or
to also add some nice shadow behind it.
Then we had to look at font display,
this defines the loading behavior of our customly created fonts with @font-face and we saw that we
have different values available which can be distinguished by their block period and their so-called
swap period. The default value is auto which simply means that the browser will choose a value of his
choice which is usually block.
And to summarize kind of what we learned, the font shorthand takes into account a lot of the properties
we talked about
but it cannot only be used as a shorthand,
it also allows us to refer to system font families, so font families applied for different parts on our
operating system,
for example for message boxes and therefore, also has these two purposes which we had a look at. And with
that, we actually finished all the core concepts of
CSS with this module because in the next module, it's time to dive into a more advanced concept.
We will have a look at flexbox,
so we will see how we can use this tool or this concept to change the way our elements behave really
easily.
So really looking forward to this module, let's have a look at flexbox then as the next step in this course.