So how can we easily center our elements?
Well to be honest, we already applied this value
I want to show you right now,
that's why it's just a quick tip
but I want to make sure that we also saw this as part of this unit's module. The value I'm talking about
is the one we for example used here in our plan list because as you can see, the elements are centered
and the reason why this works is that if we go to our main.css file and then go down to plan list,
it's this one right here,
margin
auto
because if I would comment that out now just for testing purposes, like that and reload the page, you can
see that the items are obviously not centered.
Now you could play around and define a margin left right of X percent and with that, center your element
but with margin auto, this is automatically done by the browser basically
and as we can see with that, we easily can center our elements perfectly and make our lives a bit easier.
Now margin auto is not always the perfect solution of course but I just want you to keep that in mind in
case you have issues like that.
So we now also got this in our minds,
so in the next lecture, it's time to have a last look at our code in this module and see if we have to
clean up our code a bit and maybe adjust some values to one of the units
we just learned about.