We're making good progress, our links do look better
but wouldn't it be nice if they changed their style if we hover over them or if we keep clicking on
them, so if we hold the mouse button which is like a touch event on a mobile phone? That would be great
and of course we can style that too with CSS, we use so-called pseudo classes for that.
Now how does this work?
Let me show you what it is and then I'll explain how it works.
We again add our selector, main-nav__item a just as before but now we add a pseudo class to the anchor
tag selector.
We do this by adding a colon directly after it,
so there is no whitespace in between because that would just be another descendant combinator and
would select elements over which we hover which are nested inside an anchor tag,
we want to fetch to hover on the anchor tag. The colon alone doesn't listen to hover though but colon
hover is just one of many pseudo classes we can attach,
another one would be the active one,
so let's quickly copy that and create a second rule and assign the active pseudo class here.
Now we can assign our rules
and for example, we could say that upon hovering, we want to have a white color and we want to have the
same style for the active click,
so once we hold the mouse pressed. If we save that and reload, we can hover over these
and now the color changes and it also keeps changing or keeps changed
if I hold my mouse button.
So this is how we can use such a pseudo class, now which other psuedo classes do exist
and what exactly does this pseudo thing mean?