So what's the next property we can use in connection with the flex items?
Well this property is close to a property we already used so far on the flex container,
now let me show you the property. For that,
I will now add it right here to our third item,
so this is basically this orange box right here,
this one. If we now add align but not align content or align items but align self,
this one right here,
then we can again use values we already know,
for example flex start. If we do that, go back and relod the page, you can see that the element is, that's
important, positioned in relation to the cross axis.
So the cross axis, right here we have flex direction row and by the way, that's also the reason why
I repeat telling you the main axis and cross axis topics because as you can see, it's really important
to understand and to work with both the flex container and the flex items.
However, we have flex direction row right here,
so our cross axis starts in the upper left corner and goes to the lower left corner, therefore flex start
will pin the item right here. If we will change align self to flex end, not like that, maybe written
correctly like this and reload the page again,
it will be at the end.
The important thing though and the difference in contrast to align items is that align items of course
referred to all elements,
that's the difference but align self allows us to define the position of a single element which is part
of a flex container
of course. As always, I will not dive into all values we have for this align self property just because
again, I think that understanding the core concept is more important than trying out all the values
but if you have a look at the MDN right here, you can see which values we can apply.
We for example tried flex start and flex end now, we talked about baseline already when we had a look
at the flex container.
So feel free to play around right here
but basically this is how align self works for elements which are flex items inside our flex container.
So these were the first two properties I wanted to show you,
so we have order and we have align self which always aligns a single flex item along the cross axis
and now we have three more properties left.
Now let me show you the first property, flex grow, in the next lecture.