So we have generic families and we have font families,
what's the difference?
Well a generic family is something like this, serif or sans-serif.
Well as you can imagine, the difference is that serif has a font style which is including serifs and
sans-serif,
well it doesn't have sans-serifs but we have more of these generic families,
we also have cursive.
Well I think the name tells you already what that could stand for or why it's called cursive.
We also have Monospace and we have Fantasy,
I made Fantasy a bit gray because it's not the most usual generic family you could use, we'll still have
a look at it though
but the thing is that these generic families are a kind of a headline which therefore define a specific
attribute of the fonts that are inside this generic family.
For example, the cursive generic family includes fonts which are cursive and by saying include,
this brings us to the font families because that's actually more specific
and these are actually the different fonts we have inside our generic family. For serif for example, this
could be Times New Roman or Georgia,
so both are part of this generic family,
the serif family
and as you can see in the different font families, Times New Roman and Georgia both have these serifs
in them but they look different though.
We also have other font families which are part of the sans-serif generic family,
this could be Helvetica
or Verdana, these are of course all just examples,
we have a lot more font families for all our generic families.
The thing is that for these fonts, both don't have any serifs.
Again as the generic family indicates and that's this general attribute or characteristic these font
families which are part of a specific generic family are sharing. For cursive, as we can imagine,
we have this cursive style,
well probably not the most beautiful one but still, this is for example Brush Script and Mistral
and we have Monospace, so we have Courier New and Lucida Bright and for Fantasy,
I didn't get any font families, as I said, it's a pretty uncommon generic family as I would say.
Nevertheless, we'll also cover that throughout this module.
So that's the general theoretical background that we need.
We have generic families which kind of define a specific core attribute and inside these generic families,
we have multiple font families which share this common attribute of course but nevertheless, look different.
So that's the first theoretical introduction,
let's now go to our browser and see if we can find such generic families and font families in there.