So to get started, attached to this video, you'll find the following files,
the index.html file and the favicon.png file.
Now the favicon is only there so that we have it,
it's not related to CSS, the index.html file is the important one,
it's the first piece of the course project we're going to build.
If you open it with your favorite editor or IDE, I am using Visual Studio Code here,
then you can see that we get a normal HTML5 skeleton inside of that file.
We've got a doctype, we've got the HTML opening and closing tag,
then we get a head section where we set some meta tags as well as a title
and since we're building a fictional web hosting company or the website of this company, we named it
uHost and you have the body tag.
Now the body tag of course holds the content of our web page
and right now this really is just a main tag,
a section tag and in there, this hi tag. So not too exciting but we'll add more and more throughout
this course
of course. This is already some great code with which we can get started though, which is the reason why
it's there. Now
all these things here are different HTML selectors
and now if we open that web page, if we double-click on that index.html file and we open in the browser
therefore, we should see something like this.
The exact thing you see here might differ depending on which browser you use,
I'm using Chrome,
I strongly recommend using Chrome because of its developer tools which we'll also use later but this
is what you should roughly see, just some text which has actually some styling,
it's a bit bigger than the default text would be,
it is fat but it doesn't look super great and there certainly is more we can do with it.
So this is our starting set up and our goal is to turn this into this.
So as you can see, what we have here is some background color of the surrounding element as it looks
like and the text is then inside of that background and looks a bit differently.
This is achieved via CSS, not via HTML because HTML leads to what we see here,
it's about the content and the structure of our page in the end and we get all of that.
We got the content there, we can read it, this page although it doesn't have that many features right
now, is fully usable,
this is super important to understand, it's fully usable.
So what we can now do is we can make it more beautiful
and for that we can use CSS. Now in the next video, we'll dive into using CSS and I will show you three
different ways of adding CSS code to this page.