Let's start with transitions. Transitions are a kind of built-in animation you could say. Transitions are
added by adding one property, transition and specifying which other property,
like the opacity or the position
of an element should be watched and should be animated
if it changes.
So here's an example; we got a box and we actually want to move that towards us with transform and translate
set let's say, then we could animate that change. We tell the transition property, and we'll apply it in
practice in a second,
which properties to change, if there should be a delay,
how should animate it, so
over which time and how fast it should move through that time.
So should we start fast and end slow, start slow and end fast,
these are all things we can define.
Now that's of course just the theory,
let's dive into this in a concrete example.
In our main.css file, we got that modal selector,
now this is obviously responsible for that modal we got on our page.
Right now, we're always using display none to not show it,
let's actually change this and let's make sure we don't show it by adding opacity zero instead, opacity
zero simply makes it invisible, the difference is
it's now still part of the document flow and opacity,
unlike display, is a property we can watch with a so-called transition, a list with properties you can
watch can be found in the last lecture of this module by the way.
So opacity zero is how I now want to hide the modal,
let's also add a transformation and let's use translateY to move it on the y-axis with -3rem
as a value,
so this will move the element up by 3rem.
Now you might ask, why am I doing this,
we're not seeing it anyways?
Well you'll see why
and of course you could always move the element up with top but transform is what you should use if
you plan on animating that movement
because it is watchable with transition and it's hard where accelerated,
it's awesome for animations or for transitions to be precise,
so let's add these two properties to modal.
Now the idea is that we change these two properties with Javascript.
You remember, earlier in this course, we added code to show the modal when we click on select a plan
by simply adding that open class.
Now in that open class if we have a look at this again, we can find it in the shared.css file,
we set display block to important.
Now this doesn't really matter anymore because right now for the modal at least, we don't use the display
value anymore but we can also still leave it.
More importantly, what I want to do here is, I want to set the opacity to one here and use transform
with translateY and set it to zero.
Now this simply sets it back to its original position as defined in the document flow.
So when we open the modal, it should be moved to that place.
Now just as with block, we need to add important to all of these to overwrite the defaults though.
So let's save all of that,
let's go back to our project and reload and now if I click choose plan, we see the modal again. Just as before,
there is no animation or anything like that at all
but now, we can set up a so-called transition.
For this, we go to the main.css file and we add a new property, anywhere in that list of properties
as always, which is named transition. Now the transition property is able to take a couple of values, to
be precise,
you can define up to four values here, a list of four values.
The first one is absolutely required and that is, which property do you want to watch?
You can watch all with the all keyword,
then the transition will be played whenever a transitionable property changes
but here, I could also enter opacity and transform as values, so two values separated with a comma
in this case,
if you have more than one value, you need to separate them with a comma. You then also define the duration
over which you want to play an animation when one of these properties changes or when a property changes
and you define that duration directly after the property you're watching,
so let's say .5 seconds after opacity. By the way, instead of .5s for seconds,
you could also write 500ms,
this is all supported.
So you can use s for seconds or ms for milliseconds
and let's also transform this over let's say 500ms too, maybe it becomes visible faster though,
maybe 200ms.
So please note that you set different durations for the different properties you're transitioning over.
Of course if you just want to animate one, you would just animate one by simply removing the second one,
if you animate more than one, you need to separate the lists with commas though.
So this is now defining what we animate and over which time we want to animate or transition to that
new value and CSS will automatically interpolate the value you're coming from,
so opacity zero translate -3rem to the value you're going to,
so opacity 1, translateY is 0.
With that, we can already save this and now reload our page and now if I click 'choose plan',
you actually see there's some nice animation and there also is the animation if I close it because it
automatically reverses this or plays it in the other directions so to say. In the end, what it does is it simply
transitions smoothly from your starting value to your end value
and this is a very easy way of adding a nice looking animation.
Now you can add more than just a what and over which duration,
you can also add a timing function which allows you how fast it should go through that duration.
It'll always take 200ms but you can tell it to start fast and end slow with ease out,
now it will become slower towards the end
or with ease in for example, it'll start faster.
I'll dive deeper into timing functions in a second by the way. So let's use ease out here for the opacity
and also for the transformation, so for translate in the end, though this will animate anything you transforme
by the way, you can't really filter for just translations here.
So now with that, if we reload and I choose plan, not sure if you see it but actually it's now ending slower
than it starts. Now last one but not least, you can also set a delay,
you simply add a fourth value like one second,
this would mean it will start one second before it starts with that transition.
So now if I click the button,
nothing happens for one second
and then it plays this animation, for some use cases,
this can also be helpful, in this case
here, it isn't
so let's get rid of it.
This is how you use transitions, you define what you want to watch, over which duration you want to animate
to that new value and how that duration should be used.