More on CSS classes. We used CSS class selectors quite a bit,
they're very useful,
we can define reuseable rules with them and apply them to any element which should receive the rule
and here are two additional things I want to bring to your attention. In this HTML snippet here, we
see that we got two elements and the first one actually got more than one class applied to it,
it got class 1 and class 2 and the two classes are simply separated by a whitespace between them and
the second element is a normal link which has just one class but we'll select it in a special way.
So for the first element, important, you can use multiple classes on one element,
that is something I want to emphasize. So the two rules we have
here on the left would both be applied independently to that element because that element has the
same class. Now important,
if you got two classes applied to the same element and they both happened to set a certain style on
the element, then the normal specificity and order rules will apply, the order in this class list here
is not important regarding this.
Now for the second element, the anchor tag,
I also get a nice style, here
we actually use a combinator, it's not officially a combinator but we still use a combined selector here
somehow.
We got a tag collector and then our class selector
and if you look closely, there's no whitespace between the two selectors, also no plus or anything else.
So they're written as one word you could say and that simply means this targets an element which is
an anchor tag and which has the active CSS class and to such an element, the following styles will
get applied.
This can of course target more than one element because you could have more than one anchor tag with
the active class
and this also is not limited to tag class selector combinations,
you could have two classes, you could have an ID in a class or a tag as with a class is here or a tag with
two classes.
You can simply chain selectors into one selector to be more specific about what you want to select.
The difference to a combinator here is that we're not selecting an element with the active class that's
nested in an element which is an anchor tag
but we want to select an anchor tag that has the active class and we didn't encounter a combinator that
would allow us to do that yet because there is none, this is the way to achieve this.
Now let's see this in practice. Attached to this video,
you'll find a little starting code snippet, in the HTML code,
I just got some dummy elements, navigation with the links and then two sections with IDs and classes
and in the main.css file,
some basic styles are set up.
Nothing we haven't seen before,
just a bunch of tag collectors and one class selector, we're setting height, border, padding and some colors,
so really nothing fancy.
Please note that I'm using shorthands all the time except for margin bottom because I really just
want to set the margin bottom here and it leads to this layout
if we load this page.
Now let's see or check that case where we got the two classes on one element.
We don't have such a case in th HTML code right now, so let's create one,
let's maybe add a second class to that first section, maybe highlighted.
So now, this first section has two CSS classes applied to it and they're totally independent from each
other,
they just sit on the same section but we could reuse any of the classes anywhere else in our document.
Important, they're separated by a whitespace, so no comma, no semi-colon, just a whitespace and important,
if both classes happen to define a style for the same property, the normal specificity and order rules
apply and therefore the class which is defined later in the file would win.
Well let's actually see that. We got our main section class down here and as you can see, it sets a border.
Now let's create this highlighted class which we just added to the same element and there, let's
say we want to have a border of 2 pixels, solid and in this orange color here.
Now if we add this and we reload the page, we can see that style getting applied to that first section
and if we open the developer tools, we can see that if we inspect that first element, both classes are
obviously applied there too
and if we have a look at the styles which are having an effect, we see that both the main section and
the highlighted class are doing their job and the highlighted class wins regarding the border simply
because it's defined later in the file.
If we switch the order in the file here and we reload, then it doesn't win,
so the order in the class definition here is not important.
So let's go back and revert the order again because I want to have that orange border and with that,
this is really all that's to it,
this is the case that we apply two or more classes to the same element,
you can add as many as you want.
Now let's have a look at that combined selector,
for example this first anchor tag is not just an anchor tag,
it also has the active class,
the second one doesn't have that class.
Now let's say we want to give that first anchor tag a special style,
here's our normal anchor tag rule,
now let's create a new selector, a new rule here and there I'll directly add the active class.
Now if I were to put a whitespace between the anchor tag and the active class selector here, then this
would actually target elements that have the active class, that have a direct or indirect parent which
is an anchor tag.
Now this would not match any elements on our page because we got no such case,
there is no nested HTML element in any of our anchor tags, leave alone that it would have this class,
we just got an anchor tag which directly has the class and to target that, we need to remove the
whitespace
and now we're saying apply whatever styles we're defining here to an anchor tag which has the active
class applied to itself.
By the way, you can of course also combine this with an ID,
this would target all anchor tags that have some ID, which should at most be one on our page,
it's none
but back to the active class, so we can combine selectors like this and there, we could say this should
actually have some purple color, let's say.
So here I am defining a purple color, hex code #521751
and now with that if we reload the page,
this first link looks different. So that is really important to understand and to know, you can work with
selectors like this,
you can combine them.
It's not an official combinator but it's still useful to target elements more precisely.