So what is the CSS grid? Let's consider a normal web page like this one, where we have a couple of different
elements or areas. We may have a header, sidebar,
the main content with some elements and a footer let's say. Now if we look close, we could divide this
up into a grid of rows and columns, so like this
and of course we have more than one row and one column. We could think of this page being structured
along this grid and actually, this is how you work in many design tools like sketch and so on where
you can also use a grid to position elements or when you work with CSS frameworks like Bootstrap,
they also always ship with a grid which makes the positioning of elements easier because positioning
elements on the page in the place where you want them to have is one of the most difficult or complex features
you have in CSS and the CSS grid is another tool which aims to help you with that.
It allows you to define such a grid of rows and columns and to then specify which element should be
positioned where and it's really flexible about all of that as you will learn,
so let's dive into it and let's start creating a simple grid.