No matter if you just joined at this stage of the project or if you followed along, this is the status
we will start with, you can of course find the code attached to this video
and we actually achieved a lot so far.
We created this navigation bar right here on top of our starting page,
we have this background image with this slogan, get the freedom you deserve,
we also created and styled the different plans, so the free plan, the recommended plan and the premium
plan,
we also have the reasons why uHost is a really important hosting provider and we created that photo
right here.
Additionally, we build the second page, this packages page and by saying we build, actually you
build it, right?
So on this page, we can find more information about the different plans we have
and of course we also have our photo down here. Now where could we add the position property now?
As I said, a property that allows us to change the position of some elements.
Well actually we could change the position of our navigation bar right here.
Now you might say what's wrong with it,
it's a fine navigation bar and I would agree partially
but if we scroll down, we see that the navigation bar disappears.
So I don't think that's the best user experience because if you want to change to the packages page now,
the navigation bar is kind of gone.
So adding a fixed navigation bar definitely is something we should change or we should add right here.
Additionally, the background image
or more specifically, the slogan right here
is not presented the best way.
Generally, we should change the position inside this image.
That's what I want to change on the starting page,
if we go to the packages page now, I would like to change the fact that we don't have a background image,
this is also something we will add using the position property
and finally I'm not happy with our plus plan because the plus plan is our recommended plan and therefore
the most important plan actually
and so far, this doesn't really become clear as I think.
So why don't we just add a badge maybe right here in the right upper part of this plan to really ensure
that our users see that this is the recommended plan.
So this is what we want to achieve in this module
and before we can apply that in practice and we will do that, no worries, I think it's theory time now.