I'm liking the shape of our application, we're really making good progress.
What I'd also like is a little bit of a different style if we hover over these links.
It would be nice if they by default, not only if we hover over them, would be bold, well that's easy to
achieve of course but if they also had like a border at the bottom. We could re-add text decoration but
that underlining was very close to the text,
I'd like a real border with some padding in between.
Now let's start with the bold part, that's easy,
we can simply add font weight
bold to our nav item.
If we go back and reload, it's bold unsurprisingly.
Now regarding the underlining, that is something I want to do with a border. Now for that, we can add
border-bottom,
this is another shorthand which only styles the bottom border and there we can for example set this
to 5 pixels solid and white.
If we save that and we reload the page, we always got that,
I of course only want it if I hover over it,
so let's copy it to that style,
excuse me,
so only to the hover and active style.
If we now reload,
we got it if I hover over it but it's still very close,
I want to have some padding in between.
So let's go back and let's add a padding to the anchor tag,
not only when we're hovering over it but always
otherwise we'll see some ugly jumping.
So here, we can add a padding into all directions or just top and bottom, whatever you want,
let's say top and bottom of three pixels,
so zero to left and right.
If we now go back, that did work just fine.
Now the last thing I want to add for this navigation, this start hosting button here or link should actually
look a bit different,
it should be our call to action link,
so it should really stand out from the rest and have a different styling. Now let's style that in the next lecture.