Let's have a look at how we use the CSS grids together with media queries. For that,
back in the code, I'll remove justify and align content because I want to have the grid in the top
left corner essentially
and I will also set element two back to take that stretch mode again.
So now this is the grid again.
Now of course, we could translate this kind of to having a header, a footer, a side bar and a main area,
kind of what we had in assignments earlier.
Now this is one possible layout but maybe in mobile mode,
so once you decrease the size of the page, you want to set this to behave differently.
Now first of all, what I need to do is I need to get rid of that hardcoded width, it should again be flexible
regarding this but still, the issue I have here is it becomes very narrow and there is a certain breakpoint
where you probably want to ensure that element two, let's say takes the entire second row and that there
is a third row before the footer where the yellow element, element one can then go to. This would be a typical
requirement for a grid based webpage, where you want to have different positioning and maybe a different
amount of rows even for different layouts. On a desktop
device, three rows is fine, on a mobile device,
we probably need four. Now of course, we can implement this with the help of media queries and I will add the media
queries directly after the element
they are used on, just to keep this easier to see.
So let's add a media query right after the container because we'll need to add a third row.
So here I'll this to max width actually,
so this is not mobile first here,
excuse me, but I find it was easier to focus on the grid on a bigger screen,
so now we'll engineer a solution for that smaller screens with max width and let's say the max width
we want to have a look at is 40rem, so for screens up to 40rem,
I want to have a different grid and that different grid needs an additional row, a row for the yellow
element.
Now we can simply copy grid template areas and grid template rows, not into the media query like this
though
but into the container selector in there. Let's get rid of that comment and grid gap and now we need
to add an additional row by overwriting grid template rows and by simply adding an additional row then.
We got a third row with 100 pixels,
now let's say we want to have 150 maybe there and I then want to add a fourth row,
so I'll name this row four start here maybe
and then add my 100 pixel row there, row four end thereafter.
So this is now the updated row set up with an extra row.
Now in the template area, so I also want to add it and I want to say main actually takes the entire third
row on mobile devices
and as I just said, we have a new row below that, above the footer which would be our, let's name it side
bar
so to say, now pushed into its own row occupying the full row let's say. Of course, you could also add
some dots if you don't want this to be the case.
Now with this, we added a new row and we change the positioning with the help of template areas
and the cool thing is since we are referencing these areas on our elements, at least for most of them,
we don't even need to change them. Now we need to change element one because here I'm still using that
line-based approach and easiest way to make this really flexible is to also use grid area there and assign
a name of side
and let's also add this instead of the dots here.
First one should stay a dot but let's say on our desktop layout and now we never need to touch the elements
because they always refer to the same name,
we just restructure our amount and positioning of cells with grid template rows and grid template areas
and if we were to need it, with grid template columns of course. And now we can save this and reload and
we get the same layout as before
but if I shrink the screen,
it then goes into that mobile mode and that's the cool thing about media queries and the grid.
It's really easy to build highly flexible and responsive layouts with media queries just as you learned
it
but by taking advantage of features like this, named areas and the advantage that you never have to change
your elements again, you just change the general layout you defined on the grid container.
This is something I want you to take with you, that you think about the grid like this,
that you take it as a chance to really configure everything on the container, adjust it with media queries
as required and then save a lot of work because you don't need to reposition anything else
and of course you're free to overwrite whatever needs to be overwritten on the container.
So if you also want to change the items and positioning, you could overwrite justify items and so on
here too.