So my idea is to turn this last list item into a call to action button,
so this should really stand out from the other links, should be clearly visible. To ensure that we can style
it that way,
I'll add an extra class and that's important,
you can add more than one class to an element.
So here, I'll simply add a whitespace after the first class and then add my second class, here
I'll name the class main-nav__item and then --cta, that name might look
very ugly and strange,
it's again following this BEM way of naming classes, we have main-nav__item still but it has a special
state
so to say and you, per the BEM specification, separate this with two dashes and then the state name
which of course is set by you, here CTA for call to action.
So now with that extra class added, I can target either of them to style this link and we do use the first
one of course, we always did over the last lectures but now this second class can be used to also style
this and since it only is applied to this list item, the other links won't be affected by it. So I'll
go back to the main.css file and I'll add a new rule, main-nav__item--cta, to be precise,
I want to target the anchor tag inside of there just as we did it for the normal main-nav__item. I'll now have
to overwrite anything that I want to have different than before.
Now here, the order does matter,
they have the same specificity because they both have descendant combinator,
they both target the anchor tag,
they both have a class at the beginning,
so for this and this rule, it's now really just the order in the file that's important.
So now we can overwrite the parts that we want to change for that call to action button.
What I want to change is I want to set the text color to white because I'll add a background color of
this the red color we used, this reddish color.
I also want to change the padding,
I want to use 8 pixels top and bottom and 16 pixels left and right and I also will give this a border
radius of 8 pixels.
Now border radius is new, this will round the corners,
if we save this, you can see it, save both files including the HTML file.
If you now reload it,
this is our call to action button which looks really strange with that white border bottom hover effect
here but this is now our button clearly standing out from the other
links and I would agree that with that color below there,
that doesn't look that great,
we'll replace it with an image soon.
So now we got that button, the hover effect also needs to change now to make sure it this looks good.
So I'll add another main-nav__item--cta a hover and for active, so main-nav__item --cta a active
and here, I'll set the color of the text to the red color and I'll set the background color to white, so
I'll swap that essentially
and I also will remove that border assignment which we have for normal link hover effects so that
we don't get that border bottom because again, order matters here, specificity would be the same,
so this one resolves the conflict and it simply overwrites all border settings that were made earlier.
With that if we reload again,
now we have a different style and hovering over that
and now we added that CTA button and that's it for now with the navigation.
Now we'll revisit this of course later, a couple of times actually, to make it responsive and to also
style it differently or position the elements differently. The next and last thing I want to do is I
want to add an image here so that we got less of a harsh contrast.
Let's do this in the next lecture.