Before we conclude this section and dive into the next module, I promised you that list of properties
which are worth remembering.
Now keep in mind, properties are the part in front of the colon and you might of course be wondering which ones
you should use.
You saw that long reference of properties but here's a list of properties we already used and what you
will see over and over again.
The color property to change a text color, the background color property to change the background of
a box, display to change the way it's positioned or how it behaves from block to inline to inline block
to none, the padding to add some distance between the content and the border, the border itself to add a
border, margin to add some spacing around the box, the width to
set the width and the height to set the height.
There are more important properties of course which we'll see from time to time and there are way more
which you see or which you use very rarely,
these are core properties which you already saw and which are definitely worth to remember.
Now we will see way more,
we already did see more than just these few but you can learn them and you will learn them by heart
by simply using them.
Don't go to a reference and learn them just by reading them,
use them and that helps you really memorizing what they do and when to use them.