To build a simple grid, attached to this video, you'll find this very simple starting project.
Now why am I not working in our main course project?
We will work on that later in this module again
but the CSS grid has so many different properties and features, it would really be forced to put
it all into the context of the course project and we would have many distracting side effects.
That is why we will work with this simple layout here, where we have a wrapping div and then some child
elements which we can use to learn about all the features the grid offers
and then again, we will apply some of these concepts to our course project
so that you also see it in action. Now in that main.css file which we're importing, I right now only
define a margin on the container to put it a little bit further into the page and have it not sit directly
on the edges of the page
and each element, each child element has a distinct background color, so that we can quickly tell them
apart. If we have a look at this page,
this is what it looks like
and here I actually opened it in Firefox because Firefox has a very decent CSS grid debugging utilities
which make it easier for me to explain it and to show some concepts.
So you can of course also use it in Chrome, Chrome supports the CSS grid but Firefox makes learning it and
diving into what happens behind the scenes a bit easier.
Now that I mention it, Chrome supports the grid,
let's check the general grid support. If we check
caniuse.com, we see that modern browsers support the grid pretty well.
We do have problems in the Internet Explorer, especially in older version
and that's something you have to keep in mind, if you work with the CSS grid, you can't support
older Internet Explorer versions.
So if that is something your page needs to support, the CSS grid might not be your first choice, if you
support more modern browsers,
you're definitely free to use it though.
With that out of the way, let's dive into our demo project here and let's start turning this into a grid
and then I'll also show you how we can debug it with these
Firefox developer tools.