Let's actually start with the title here
before we dive into the different inputs and for the title, if we go to the start hosting folder and there
into the index.html file, we see that here we get that signup title class assigned to it.
So let's now add a start-hosting.css file in the start hosting folder and make sure you
are importing it,
it should be there,
the import should already be there though because we added it to the code you copied into that page and
in that start-hosting.css file, we can select that signup title class element and there for example,
align the text in the center, give it let's say a font size of 1.8rem so that it's looking good
and a bit bigger than normal text and maybe also add a color which could be #ff5454, that's
a reddish color.
Now if we reload, this looks better.
Now maybe some distance would be nice,
so let's add a class to the selector for the main element and there, let's add a padding top of
2rem,
also as we did it on the other pages, we have different paddings, maybe 2rem is too much, let's add
1rem
but just so that we have some space between our content and the header.
Now with that, we worked on the title,
now obviously we are here to work on the form and the input elements.
Now for that, let's go back to the index.html file and let's have a look at what we got here.
We have a form element, here with the class signup-form
and in there, we always have combinations of labels and then input elements, like this, select element
or a bunch of normal inputs or also our terms and conditions and
there, we have some special setup where the label actually wraps our link here to the terms and conditions
but is then also positioned next to a checkbox input,
the difference to the other labels is that it's coming after the input because we want to have that look of
having the label after the checkbox instead of in front of it.
That's a general look we have here. Now there is no single correct way of styling form inputs and elements,
you can find dozens of solutions, for example one thing you see in some solutions is that you wrap your
labels and inputs into divs, so you would put each pair of label and input into a div and then you
could also give that div some class, like input group or form group or whatever you want and give that
some style where you essentially maybe set a margin to the bottom or margin to the next element that's
coming after it.
This is one way of styling this, you could absolutely do that, here
I will follow a different approach though and I will not style it like this,
instead I will target labels and the different inputs individually because I need to do this anyway
as I also plan on applying different stylings to these elements.
Let's start with some basic stylings.
In the start-hosting.css file,
let's start by selecting our labels, inputs and select elements,
so basically all types of elements we have in our form except for the button
and let's turn them into block level elements.
Now why do I want to do that?
Because normally, they're all inline elements, as you can clearly see here,
they're all in one line.
This is actually something you might want,
maybe you want to position some of them next to each other
but here, I want to position them below each other and therefore I need to change their default behavior
and turn them to block level elements.
For that, we could simply select label, input and select elements with their tag selectors,
however I will combine that with the signup-form class and use the descendant combinator,
so signup-form and then some whitespace, just to ensure that only elements which are inside of
that form receive that style.
Now on our page, this is technically not required but if we would have some scenario where we get some
other input on the page, let's say a search bar in the header for example, then we might not want to style it
in the same way as we style our form,
hence the combinator approach here. The style I want to apply here is that I want to set display to block,
as I said and then I also want to add a margin top of let's say 1rem, to add some distance between all
these elements.
If we do that and we reload, we can already see a difference,
now all the elements are beneath each other.
Now it's not looking perfect,
we'll work on that but it's better.
We can also see one thing though, even though they're all block level elements and we can inspect them
here, to see that they indeed do take up the full width,
we see that the majority of the available width is occupied with nothing, with a margin. For form inputs,
like select or input,
we actually also need to set the width to 100 to force them to expand over the full available width.
Now clearly, this is not looking super beautiful here but we'll work on that and we'll change the
width of the overall form soon enough.
Now this is the first step
I wanted to take, now one problem we have is the styling of the checkbox. This actually, if we inspect
our HTML code, is also a normal input element, here
but in this case, I don't want to set it to block,
it should stay an inline element because I actually want to ensure that this checkbox is positioned
next to its label and therefore, this current approach of just setting it to be a block level element
does not work, we'll have to change that
and actually we will change this and learn about attributes selectors and use them in the next lecture.