We had a look at that box model in theory,
let's now work with it and let's work with it by going to our product overview selector here,
the ID selector where we have the background and let's add a padding of 20 pixels for example.
So pixels is a unit you can use in CSS,
there are other units like percentages and font related units too
but for now let's stick to pixels since they're very easy to understand.
So if we add this and save that file, we can reload the page
and now we see that there is some spacing around the text.
If we now inspect that section again, we can already see it on the left if we hover over it, that there
are different boxes now
and if we now scroll down, we indeed see there is a padding and this time, the padding is even around
the margin of the h1 tag which can look strange at first since this wasn't considered previously,
it's just that if you add a padding, then the content of the element is to be considered the content
plus any margins it might have because padding and margins shouldn't overlap hence the padding is added
after the margin of child elements.
So here, we got our padding added, we can hover over it in the box model to see highlighted in the top
left
and of course we can also add a border now.
So let's add a border, let's add five pixels black and solid.
Now this value might look strange at first, this way of writing a value, we have more than one value,
this is called a shorthand,
I'll also dive into this in a second.
This is just a shorter way of writing
border style solid, border color black, border width 5 pixels but you could use this notation too. If you
add this and reload the page, you'll see a black border around the element
and if you again scroll down to your box model, you'll see the 5 pixels here
and if we hover over it, the border gets highlighted in the top left,
so in the loaded page
too. Now finally, let's add a margin to complete the box model,
if we add a margin here, let's say 20 pixels and we save that and then we reload the page one more time,
again if we scroll down, we can see that margin here
and if we hover over it, we see that orange margin around our box.
We still see some whitespace to the left and right and that is something I'll revisit very soon too
but with that, we see all layers of the box model in action.
Now there are a couple of special things you also got to know about the box model and default styles of the
webpage.
So let's dive into these things step-by-step
over the next lectures.