So what's the difference,
what are these different pixel types?
Well so far, we played around right here in the dev tools and decreased our width right here and we saw that
the page partially reacts, not perfect yet but we have kind of a reaction,
so basically our browser understands that we have less width available.
The problem at the moment though is that our browser does not really understand the difference between
a desktop device and a mobile device.
How can I prove this to you?
Well, if we go to our dev tools and now click onto this symbol right here, like that, then we can see that
we have a mobile device right here, I'll dive into that in a few seconds,
just some information about this menu right here before, here we can choose different simulated devices.
So we have the iPhone 8 selected right here,
you can use an iPhone 7 or a Nexus or a Galaxy S5 just as you prefer, I'll
stick to the iPhone 8.
You can also change the zoom level,
I will use 150 maybe so that you can see everything
and if you increase the width a bit more maybe, you can find options to define if your device is online, offline
or with a lost connection,
not something we'll dive into now.
You can change the mode between landscape and portrait, like that, we'll stick to portrait though for the
moment and you have these three dots right here which allow you for example to hide the device frame or
to show the device frame. I'll show it to you because I think it looks a little bit better.
However, the important thing that you might have noticed is that although we had this partially responsive
design on a smaller screen in the desktop version,
so if I click right here and decrease the screen width, this reaction right here,
well this is not happening in our mobile design because although we only have a mobile device which
should actually be smaller than our desktop device if we decrease the width, the browser basically squeezes
the entire website onto our mobile phone
and with that, there is no responsive design at all available at the moment.
Now what's the reason for that?
Well first, have a look at this thing right here, at these pixels.
We can see that in this simulator, in this mobile phone simulator in the dev tools,
a width of 375 pixels right here is assumed and the height of 667 pixels.
Let's focus onto these 375 pixels right here because if we inspect our background
image which basically occupies the entire width right here and if we now increase that a bit here and
scroll down, this is our menu we had before right here,
so our computed menu, this one right here, as we have more space for the dev tools now, this is now
directly available right here.
And if we scroll down, we can see that we have a width of 980 pixels, which is quite big actually
especially if we take into account that the Chrome developer tools actually assume a width of
375 pixels for this iPhone 8.
Now as you can see, there is something not working correctly at the moment
and to understand this, we can go to this page right here.
This is w3.org, a link to this website
can of course be found attached to this video
and on this page, you can see how absolute lengths are translated into pixels or vice versa
in CSS and right here, you can see that 1 inch right here is equal to 69 pixels.
Now in case you're not familiar with inch, one inch are 2.54 centimeters, so 1 inch is 69
pixels
and we had 980 pixels for the width of our background image right here,
this one, this is 980 pixels.
So if we translate that into inches, we have more than 10 inches right here for our device width
and although an iPhone 8 is a big smartphone, I don't think it's more than 10 inches and this shows you
exactly where the problem is coming from we have at the moment. The browser is of course able to identify
the height of our pixels, so the pixel this iPhone has by default but it will just translate these pixels
based on this logic right here.
So here we'll say OK, I have a specific amount of pixels, so I assume that with each 96 pixels I have, the
device has a width of 1 inch
and while this works perfect for monitors or desktop devices, for a mobile phone,
this leads to a website being displayed like this which is of course way too small.
And what causes this problem of course in the end is that modern mobile phones have a really high pixel
density and this high pixel density,
so a lot of pixels in a really little amount of space lead to the problem that these, as I would call
them, traditional ways of translating pixels into inches and by that, specify the amount of information
that is displayed on the device is not working anymore.
So if pixels are translated into inches and we have the problem that we have too many pixels and not
enough space available or a too-small device, then we can either increase the size of the device which
is difficult because our mobile phones have the size they have or decrease the amount of pixels because
if we have less pixels available, then less information would be displayed at the same time on our display
and with that, we would have a bigger font size and a bigger size of the entire content of the
website actually.
And if you now go to this page right here, mydevice.io and click on to compare devices, we can find the
solution for that problem because here we have our iPhone 8 for example and we can see the physical width
and the physical height,
so these are the hardware pixels I'm referring to
and right here, you can now see the CSS width and the CSS height.
And we saw these numbers already
because if we go back to our website, we can see that this is exactly the width and height that the
Chrome developer tools show us as the device height and width for this iPhone 8
and this basically is due to the fact that we have a so-called pixel ratio.
In the case of the iPhone 8, we have a pixel ratio of two.
This basically means that we take the physical height divided by two, as you can see it,
and with that, we have the height that is now assumed by CSS
for our mobile phone
and with this pixel ratio, CSS would only assume a height of 676 pixels for our iPhone
and if we think back about our calculation right here, that 96 pixels are 1 inch, then we would only have
let's say round about 6 inches of height that the browser understands
for our iPhone and with that, we have a height that is a lot closer to the real one
when comparing it to the initial one which led to this strange way of displaying the website right
here
and with that, we would be able to display our website in a better scaled way.
The question now is, how can we achieve that goal?
How can we tell the browser that it should apply this pixel ratio to make sure that it translates the
actual hardware pixels, so 751334 into 375667.
Well the answer is we simply have to add this viewport meta tag.
For that, we can go back to our website and actually switch back to our code
and as we are on the starting page, we can go to the main index.html file right here and now add the meta tag
right here as the third meta tag and we simply add meta.
Now we add name which should be viewport like that and now we add a second attribute, the content. For the
content, we will add width equals the device width, I'll dive into these attributes in the next lectures in a bit
more detail
but generally, this simply means that the width of the viewport should be equal to the device width
and with that, we can recognize the device width of our device,
that's the important thing
we didn't have so far.
So we should add device width and then we can also add initial scale which equals 1.0.
As I said, I will dive into that in one of the next lectures in a bit more detail. If we now go back to our
website and reload it, you can see that the style totally changed because now our browser is able
to identify the actual device
width we have right here on our smartphone.
This means he does not consider the actual hardware pixels
but considers the CSS, the software pixels,
so this 375 times 667 and for a width of 375 pixels, this is the way our website is displayed.
And if we now go back to our desktop version and also decrease the size to this 375 pixels, right
here,
well then you can see if we switch back and increased the size a bit, that this is pretty identical now
and with that, we applied a first very important core concept to be able to apply a responsive design
to our website.
Now before we dive deeper into this viewport meta tag and also into media queries, let me show you a
quick comparison between the viewport meta tag and the media queries in the next lecture.