So which tools do we have to add a responsive design?
Well, we just saw that we have this viewport meta tag,
this is created or added in HTML
and we have media queries. We'll dive into these later in this module and media queries are of course
created in CSS because that is what this course is all about, right? Now let me show you the differences
between these two concepts and especially why we need both to create our responsive website. The viewport
meta tag is required to be able to adjust our site to the device viewport,
we just saw that. If we only take into account the actual pixels,
we will not be able to display our websites correctly or in a convenient and appropriate way on mobile
devices.
Therefore in addition to the actual pixels, we need to take into account the device width
and with that, automatically apply a specific pixel ratio which will then allow us to translate the hardware
pixels into these software, the CSS pixels,
we just did that.
The important thing is though that we cannot apply any design changes,
so in case you want to say if I am in a mobile version, I would like to change the entire structure of
my website,
I would like to add some things or maybe make some things disappear,
this is not possible.
The only thing it does, it translates the pixels according to the pixel ratio and therefore adjust the
way our website is displayed. In contrast to that, we have the media queries. The media queries allow us to
change the design depending on the actual size and that's the important difference,
media queries really allow us to specify the way our website is displayed depending on the size and
size doesn't mean a single size, we are able to define specific rules based on the width for example
where specific properties of our website should change
and I'm referring to properties.
So I'm not only talking about the width of our elements, you could change basically anything you want with
such media queries,
you could also change colors for example, so we will dive into these options
and as you will see, media queries are really cool and allow you to really adjust the look of your website
depending on different device sizes.
The important thing with that is of course that these changes are defined by us. With the viewport, the
impact we have is limited because the viewport will just translate the pixels
as I said and that's it
but with the media queries, we can really dive into the design and specify a unique design for the different
devices
we have. Now as this still sounds kind of abstract probably,
we will now dive deeper into the first concept, the viewport and after that, have a closer look at media
queries.