So let's start turning this into a grid.
If we go back to the HTML file real quick, we see we got this wrapping container and this container
holds all the other divs.
Now we can turn this container into a grid by setting the display property to grid.
Now you learned that we can set it to inline block none, inline block flex, grid is just another option
and with that, the container element becomes a CSS grid and the elements inside of it,
so these four divs are then positioned within the grid and with no further settings as we have it here, some
default settings will kick in.
Let's have a look.
If I now reload the page, nothing changes, the elements look exactly the way it did it before.
However if we inspect this here in the developer tools, this div, we can see display grid is taking
effect,
it even gives us this grid
icon and if we click that icon, we also see something, it maybe a bit hard to see here but if you do
it in your browser, you should see that by clicking on that,
some helpful lines are added.
We've got purple lines around the block, dotted lines to the right and bottom and between the different
elements and solid lines on the left and top
and if you click on the layout ribbon here, you can customize this,
you can click on that color
icon here for example and set this to a different color which you maybe can see a bit easier, whatever
your requirements are
and you can also check these items here on the right to see more information, like the line numbers,
something I'll come back to,
area names where we don't see in effect right now but I'll also come back to that
and this feature which is really useful to extend lines infinitely. If you check it, then the lines don't
end after the grid container but they continue thereafter
which makes it easier to see them especially when you have elements with a solid background as in our case
here.
You also see in the developer tools, this demo grid here where you can also highlight the different, let's
call it cells and on the left, you then see that it's highlighted there too if I hover over them here on the
right.
Now that is really useful because this already shows us that a grid was created
and right now it has one column, only one column but four rows, one row for each element and that's just
because the default behavior for an element with display grid is no settings are set, then it will create
only one column and as many rows as we have child elements. And if one of these divs had a nested child
element, then only the wrapping div,
so el2 let's say gets its own row, the nested elements inside of el2 or any other div would not be part
of the grid,
so only direct children are part of the grid so to say or are considered by the row generation mechanism.
So this is our demo grid,
our first simple grid.
Now in the next lecture, we'll dive a bit deeper into this and see what else we can do with that.