So back on our more beautiful website and let's now make sure that our navigation up here also becomes
a fixed navigation bar which is always visible.
Therefore, we have to go back to the code and we only need the main index.html file and the shared.css
file. We need the index.html file because I want to show you that we have to work on the header
right here because in this header we have our navigation and specifically, we have to work on the class
main header because this class includes our brand name, uHost and of course also the classes with
the packages, the customers and the start hosting button.
Now as I said we need to go to the shared.css file because the navigation bar will be displayed on
all pages on our website and in the shared.css file,
we now have to go to the main header class.
Well, we have a width of 100% applied already which is totally fine,
we saw that in the theoretical example,
we will need that,
so let's keep it
but now we have to add the position property with the value of fixed.
And before we change anything else, let's see what it looks like
by just adding this declaration and that's really interesting, right?
It actually looks quite fine
immediately, we have the problem that the image and the slogan are partially hidden below this navigation
bar,
we'll fix that in one of the next videos
but generally, the navigation bar is fixed and seems to work fine
and this might raise a question in your case because in the previous video, I added the top zero and
left zero declarations to make sure that the navigation bar is stick to the left top of the viewport.
Now the reason for that was that we had a margin in our HTML element, if I add a HTML selector right
here like that and add a margin of for example 10 pixels or maybe make 30, so that it becomes really clear
like that
and if I now reload the page, you can see that now the element is not positioned correctly.
That's what you always have to keep in mind, as soon as you add a margin to the HTML element or the body
element or basically any parent element of your header, then you have to add the top zero and left
zero declarations in case you want to stick this navigation bar to the left top of
your page,
sorry for that.
Now with that, we can see that although we edit this margin to our HTML element, the navigation bar
is now displayed correctly,
however we don't need that margin so we can delete it again, like that to make sure we have a clean code
and as we can see, now it looks really fine,
the only thing that's not looking fine of course is the image and the slogan. As I said, we'll fix that
soon but fixing that will only work if we learn about more values,
the absolute and relative values for the position property
but if we go to the packages page, then I can see something which we can already change because like
for the uHost page right here, I would like to have a background image
also on this page. The difference should be that this background image should not be only in parts or
on parts of our website, like here,
it should be the background image of the entire website and it also should move,
so it should be kind of a fixed background image. As we want to have such a fixed background image, using
the fixed value might not be the worst idea.