So time to write our first SASS code and for that, I'll create a new file and I'll name it main.sass
and now in this file, we can surprisingly write SASS code.
Now let's start simple and let's not even use a SASS feature, let's just try to replicate our CSS code with
SASS and for that, I'll copy all the code from the main.css file and put it into that SASS file
and now you see a bunch of errors,
all the semi-colons are marked as red and all the curly braces.
The reason for this is that SASS actually works without semi-colons and without braces, instead indentation
is used to determine to which selector a certain property belongs.
So if we were to convert this code to valid SASS code, we would remove all these semi-colons and
we would remove all the curly braces here, like that.
This is a valid SASS code now
and if we would remove the indentation, this would be invalid because the indentation here really now
decides to which selector this property belongs, if it's indented one level, it belongs to the selector
above this level so to say.
So this is how we would convert our code.
Now you might like this or you may not like this,
this is really something which differs from person to person.
Most people find SCSS a bit easier though, it uses the same features as SASS does but it actually keeps
the CSS syntax with the semi-colons and the curly braces.
So I will revert my deletions here and add all the semi-colons and curly braces back in and I'll rename
that file here to .scss at the end,
not SASS.
Now we can actually keep our code as it was before, just need to add a semi-colon after the import here and now
we can continue working here.
So this is the syntax I will use
and this now looks like CSS and actually normal CSS also is valid SCSS, so we could leave it like
this
but now we can add more features to that file.
Now let's already add one feature, so that I can also show you how this compilation step works and that
one feature I want to add is nesting.
So if we scrolled down a bit, we see that for example for documentation links, we nest a list item,
we nest documentation link and we nest documentation link hover and active.
So what we can do is, we can go to documentation links and simply add another selector nested into this selector,
so next to the other properties. With normal CSS, this would not be possible
but now, this will actually be converted to this syntax here.
So I will now grab the code I had in there and put it into this nested li
and now we can nest this even more.
So I will grab this code for the documentation link and add it next to the li.
Actually it could also added inside of the li,
since as you can see on the index.html file, documentation link is a class on an element nested in
the li
but both will work here of course because documentation link is also nested in documentation links,
even though it's no direct child but that also doesn't have to be the case,
this really is just the translation of this syntax here.
And that of course means you can also grab the hover and active links and copy that into our code, so we
can go up and add that selector here,
get rid of that documentation links, so that now we got this nested code.
Now I can get rid of documentation links
li and this and this,
so all the code we just nested and you can already see how this makes the code a bit more readable
because here, we're now containing all the styles related to my documentation links in one big selector
so to say.
Now how do we turn this into normal CSS though because this would not run. We need the command line,
the terminal for that
and here I will open the terminal which is integrated into Visual Studio Code but you can also use the
normal Mac or Windows terminal we used before,
just make sure that you navigate into this project folder.
Then you can use the SASS command which is available since we installed SASS with the gem command earlier
and now you can run SASS main.scss, so you target the file which holds your SASS code and then you
define a file name for the file you want to generate and here I will use main.css,
hence I will overwrite the original .css file. If I hit enter,
this will now generate the main.css file,
it also gives us a map file which is a source map file which makes it easier for the browser to map
our code to the original source code
but we don't have to worry about that right now.
In the new main.css file though,
you can see that instead, it automatically created these nestings
we had in there before.
So we get the same code as before but now generated automatically by the SASS command
and if you don't want to rerun this command whenever you make a change in your .scss file, then you
can also enter sass--watch main.scss, so the file you want to watch for changes and
then colon and then immediately without a whitespace, main.css.
Now this will enter watch mode
and as you see, this is now an ongoing process which you can quit with control c
and now whenever we change something in that file and save that file, it will automatically recompile.
So if I quickly set the background here to black for example, just to see a difference and I save this,
you'll see it detected a change and recreated the file
and if we go back and reload, we see that new style.
Now I will switch this back but this is now really useful to ensure that we don't have to manually compile
all the time.
So with that, we see how we can use SASS and we already learned about the first feature, the nesting of
selectors.
Now let's see what else we can do with SASS.