So how does this percentage unit work, what does it refer to?
For that, I prepared for three rules to remember and we will have a look at each of these rules separately
and also have a look at our project to see how these rules apply in practice.
Now let's dive into it right now
and the starting point of course is an element.
So this is the element we applied a percentage unit to, for example to the width property.
Now the important thing is that this is a special element.
Why is it special?
Because it has this declaration also applied, position fixed and by the way, that's also how you can see
how things tie together in this course because although we will not position our elements in this module,
the position property definitely has an impact on the way the percentage unit behaves.
Now how does this impact work?
Well the reference point for such an element with a percentage unit is called the containing block, this containing
block is simply for example an element, a parent element for example which has a width of let's say 100
pixels applied.
If this parent is the containing block and we will find out in this in the next videos how we can identify
the containing block, well then our child, so our element right here, would have a width of let's say 10 pixels
if we applied a width of 10% to it, so 10% width of a child would be 10 pixels if the
containing block has a width of 100 pixels.
Now the issue is that the containing block depends on the position property applied to our element right here
and in case the position property or the value for this property that we applied is fixed, then the
containing block is not an element, it's the viewport
and that's actually quite nice because if you remember back the position module, then we also had that
relationship between a fixed positioned element and the viewport.
However as I said, this time it's not about positioning,
so let's go back onto our website and see how this behaves in practice.
So I'm back on the customers page but I'm actually more interested into our nav bar right here because this
nav bar if we inspect it, as we can see it has the position fixed declaration applied
and as we just saw because of that, this width of 100% should refer to the viewport.
A good indication is that if we change the size of the viewport like that, we can also see that the
nav part changes
but let's play around a bit with the width to really make sure that this is the case. For that,
let's remember that we now have a width of 882 pixels.
This means if I go back to code and not to the customers.css file but to the shared.css file
because that's where our header is located or the selector of our header
and right here we need this class selector named header.
Right here, we have the 100%
and if I now reduce it to 50% let's say and go back and reload the page, we can see that the nav
bar decreased its size to only 50%,
so this should be as we can see it
441 pixels,
before we had 882,
so 50% now.
And more interestingly if I increase the size of the viewport right here by increasing it, we can see
that the nav bar also increases and decreases,
so basically we can change it back to 100% like that and reload the page because with that, we understood
that whenever we have an element which has the position fixed declaration applied and a percentage unit,
well the containing block is the viewport.
This was the first rule to remember.