So let's work on these bullet points together now. For that,
I'll again go back to my HTML file and there on the unordered list, for each plan now, not just for
the highlighted one, I'll add a class to the unordered list and call it
plan__features. Of course that name as always is totally up to you.
Now I will grab that class attribute and add it to all unordered lists, so that we style them all and
not just one of them and then I'll go back
to the main.css file
and in there, I'll add my plan__features class selector and now the idea here
is to simply set the list style to none.
You saw this earlier in the course, list style none removes the bullet points,
additionally I want to get rid of all the margin and padding introduced by the unordered list.
And with that if we save this and we reload,
this looks much nicer in my opinion.
We can still clearly see that these are different features but now they don't look like a boring
bullet point list. One thing I want to do though is, I want to have a little bit more space between
the items, top and bottom I mean not left and right,
that's fine but they should have some space to the item sitting below them.
Well this can be achieved by simply going to the plan features, so each list item and changing the margin
of it.
Now you could of course simply say plan features li to select the list item in the plan features
class and set a margin of let's say 8 pixels top and bottom and 0 left and right
and if you save that, we get the desired style, looks good to me. An alternative which I will use
is that you assign a class to each of these list items, to basically stay in line with the rest of your
code where you also use a lot of classes.
We could name this plan__feature and of course this class assignment should now
be added to every single list item.
Again, this is kind of optional,
you can of course use the combinator I just showed you, using a class probably is a bit cleaner or
more in line with your other code but ultimately, it's up to you. If you do use a class though, you simply
set it to plan feature like this, of course just using the plan feature class selector.
Once you save that and save the HTML file too, you can again reload the page and see the same look
as before.
So this is the list styled differently,
now the button is another thing we have to work on and I also want to change a style of my title
and my price.
So these are the things coming up in the next lecture.