So let's have a closer look at this
viewport meta tag and see what we added there and what else we might be able to add there. For that,
I'll go back to our index.html file, the main index.html
file and let's now have a look at it step-by-step.
The first attribute we added was this viewport attribute,
this simply allows us to tell this meta tag that it should target the viewport,
so actually the area on our device inside our browser that should display our website.
The second attribute we added was this content attribute, with that, we are now able to set the width of
our page that we have, so the page on the viewport, the visible part of it
basically, this should be equal to the width of the screen of our device and that's the important thing
we talked about in the previous lectures. With that, we were able to tell our browser that our device
is a smaller device, a mobile device and therefore, it should apply this pixel ratio conversion because
otherwise, we would have the problem that we had initially, that our browser simply has a look at the
amount of hardware pixels it has and therefore is not aware of the fact that we have a smaller device
and with that, simply displays the entire website squeezed into our mobile device screen.
Then we have this initial scale information right here,
the initial scale simply defines the zoom level that we have. 1.0 simply means that we have the default
value,
this means no zoom is applied.
If you would change that to 1.5 for example like that and go back to our website, reload it, it's not working
that's a little Chrome developer tools bug
but if we simply go back to the desktop mode and go back to the mobile mode, you can see that the website
as expected is now zoomed in. What is also interesting is that we can also zoom in more if we want to,
basically without any limitation as you can see, quite far and we can also zoom out a bit as you can
see. Now zooming in and zooming out are the next types of information that we can specify in this meta tag
because for example, we could say that our user, let's simply add it right here, user scalable like that,
this can be either yes which is the default value or the default behavior,
so as you can see, that's what we have,
we have our initial scale with this slide
zoom in now and the user can zoom out or zoom in, as you can see zooming out is basically the same
zoom level we had before,
so no zoom applied basically. In case you say you don't want your visitors to be able to zoom, which
I will not recommend because normally, we would like to give our users as much freedom as possible so
that they can view our website in the most convenient way
but let's say you want to restrict the zoom and not allow your users to zoom right here,
then you can simply set user scalable to no
and if we do that, reload and go back right here, then I'm not able to zoom in or out anymore.
I can scroll around of course, that's not the problem
but zooming is not possible anymore
but as I said, this is probably not the behavior you would like to have,
so you could either set this to yes then or as yes is the default value, you could simply delete that
entirely.
Now there are two more interesting types of information that we can add to our content attribute right
here;
the first one is the maximum scale, right here.
If you think about the initial scale which set the default zoom level when the user enters our website,
the maximum scale simply restricts the maximum zoom level that is available.
So let's set this to 2.0 for example
and if we do that and go back like this, we can see that this is the default value,
we can zoom out, that's not a problem but zooming in is now restricted.
Without that maximum scale, let me quickly cut it out right here,
reload the page and go back, we can see that zooming out is not a problem but zooming in was possible a lot more
up to this level.
Now if we put it back in, as you can see it, this allows us to limit that zoom level that's possible like
this and like that.
Now the last thing we could add is we have a maximum scale,
we can also add a minimum scale of course. The minimum scale simply restricts the amount of zooming out
level that our user is allowed to apply.
So let's set this to 1.2 for example, like that
and if we now go back and reload the page once again and do our little trick right here, then you can
see that now I'm not able to zoom out entirely like we had it before.
If I set this to 1.0 which would be able to the value of not having a zoom at all, then we can again
reload it, go back
and as you can see, now we have the website back in the initial form where we didn't apply any kind
of zoom
and these are actually the main functionalities of this viewport
meta tag that we should know right here.
The important thing that you have to keep in mind is that without adding this meta tag, we are not
really able to implement a mobile design to our website but this also means that in case you didn't
create a mobile first website, we'll dive into that in the next lectures
and by that, maybe you don't have a mobile design at all,
not adding the meta tag might also be an option because imagine, this is your final website and you only
have this desktop website which looks actually quite nice but you don't create this mobile site for
whatever reason, then you don't want to show your user the website
in this version, then the better but definitely not recommended approach would be to leave out this meta
tag and by that, present your website like this.
But we of course want to create a responsive website and also a website which looks awesome on mobile
devices, so we need this meta tag
and with that, we will now get rid of the scaling options because we don't need this to be honest,
we only need 1.0 as initial scale,
so no zoom at all, as you can see, this looks fine like that, not fine, we'll improve it but this looks okay like
that
and I already mentioned this mobile first approach
a few seconds ago.
Now let's dive into media queries and this mobile first design in the next lectures.