So we created our grid with eight cells and right now, every child element of the container takes one
cell.
Now it would be nice if we could overwrite that default positioning and let's say element three should
actually take the last two cells in the first row,
so it should take the cell where element four is in too.
We can overwrite this by going to the child selector now,
so el3 selects the element three here and there, we can define where it should be positioned.
We do this with the help of the grid column start property for example.
Do you remember that setting in the developer tools I showed you earlier, display line numbers? CSS
grid
actually things in lines. The grid is constructed by automatically adding a couple of lines before
and after our columns and rows.
So the first horizontal line here marks the beginning of the first row,
the second one marks the end of the first row and the third one marks the end of the last row and the
same for the columns.
Now if we want to tell element three to start at line number three, well then we can simply set grid
column start to three.
This is line number three and the developer tools of Firefox help us identifying this number.
Now we of course want to also tell it where to end and this is the interesting part now because by default,
this is set to simply span one cell,
now we can set this to end at line number five, so column line number five, which we simply do by typing
a 5 here.
If we now save that and reload, we see something interesting, element number four jumps into a new row
because its old place is taken, taken by element number three which we clearly define to go into these
two cells.
Now due to the helper lines and our preview at the bottom, you can still see that actually, we've got
two cells here but because of grid column start and end, we each define that this element should take
them both,
we also see that if we hover over it here, it takes both. The same can be said for the rows, we can set grid
row start to the row number it should start in,
in our example this would be one,
so let's set it to one.
Now we want to force the green element, element three, to go all the way to the bottom here,
so to the end of row number two, then we have to set a grid row and property of three because the last
line here in the row categories, so the last row line is line number three. With that if we save that and
we reload the page,
now element three takes this full block of four cells, simply due to the way we configured it
and this is how you can explicitly position elements in the grid.
Now as you can see at element one, two and four, the grid automatically positions all child elements and it starts
filling the grid at the top left and then goes to the right and to the bottom, though it will respect
the browser reading settings,
so if you're watching this on right-to-left device, it would actually start in the top right corner.
It automatically fills that but you can overwrite that behavior by explicitly stating a position with the
help of these properties just as you need it. This is something super important to understand, how you interact
between your grid elements with the positioning and the grid container where you define the layout.
This is happening in two different places,
you defined the layout in the container, you defined the position on the child element.