So our navigation works fine,
also on the packages page but now we want to add a background image to this page right here.
For that, we have to go back to our code and open two files.
We have to go to the packages folder and open this index.html
file right here and the packages.css file,
so both files that are inside this folder basically.
Now as we want to add a background image right here, we first need an element that contains this actual
background image.
Next we'll dive deeper into background images in the next video,
so I will keep it rather short in this video because the focus really is on the position property,
so in case some things might be unclear, don't worry, we'll dive into that in the next module.
However, we could add this containing element maybe right here,
basically above the header, this could be a simple div without any content
but with the class background, like that.
Now with this class being added, we might also need a background image. To add this,
we need a new folder or we can use a new folder,
it's not necessarily required to save these images in new folders but to keep things structured,
I think it makes sense to do it like this and we shouldn't create that images folder in the packages
folder though,
we should create it right here, like this, so it should be on the same level as the packages folder and
now attached to this video,
you can find an image which you can use for that,
this is the plans-background.jpg which you can then simply drag and drop into the folder.
If you do that, you will see that this image right here with the MacBook and the coffee is added to our
folder right here.
So this is nice but now we need to add this image to our background and for that, we have to go to the
packages.css
file and now we have to add the background selector first. So we created that class, so let's create
a background right here
and the first thing we have to do is we have to add the background property.
What we then need is a URL which refers to our image and for that, we need to make sure to add these quotation
marks,
now we have to move one level up because remember, we are in the packages folder,
so we have to go onto the same level as the images folder, then add a slash, then go to the images folder
and then refer to plans-background, this file right here,
.jpg,
plans-background.jpg, like that
and don't forget about the semi-colon.
If we now go back and reload the page, we can see that not a lot changed apparently.
So let's go back and let's maybe add a width
of 100% and also a height of also 100%. If we do that, maybe this helps,
let's see,
then we see that this is also not working.
Let's maybe try pixels then, as you can see without the position property,
this is not really a nice thing to do.
So let's maybe add a width of 500 pixels and also a height of 500 pixels,
so let's see what happens then. If we do that, yes we can see that we now at least got an image
but as we can see, we have issues with the percentage values and the image is of course not being displayed
completely because of pixels we added
and more importantly, we can see why the position fixed declaration might be helpful right here because
the image on the starting page was part of the actual document flow,
it was positioned above the other elements right here.
But on the packages page, the image should be positioned behind our actual content on the website,
therefore doing it like this will not make us happy.
Therefore let's go back and let's now add the position property with the fixed value right here.
If we do that and now reload the page, yes then we can see as expected hopefully that it kind of works
because as we learned already, with this value, we take the image or the element out of the actual
document flow and therefore it doesn't exist for the other elements
and because of that, it is positioned, well at the moment, above the other elements,
we will fix that soon
but generally we're coming closer to where we want to be.
Now we can go back and also change the height and width to 100% right here, like this and like that,
let's see if it works now
and as we can see, the image indeed covers the entire viewport,
so that's basically working now
but if I now increased the width,
well we can also see that the image is not correctly sized. At the moment the image is just displayed
in its original size
and as the viewport is smaller, well the image could actually also be a bit smaller.
However we will dive deeper into background sizing in the next module,
therefore for the moment we will keep that solution and continue our work.
The important thing for the moment though is that we added this background image but it's called a background
image but somehow, it is displayed in front of the other images and that's actually not the way it should
be displayed.
Therefore in the next video, we will have a look at the z-index and at the stacking context. Now what
are these, how it works and how it is connected to the fact that the background image is now displayed
in front of the other images,
let's find that out in the next video.