So let's have a look at this first method now,
at this first source for our font families, the font family which is saved locally on our user's computer.
Because you might say that so far throughout this module, we didn't have a problem with the font families at
all because basically, our browsers supported all of the font families we used besides the unknown ones
which I used to show you with the syntax in general.
But the problem or it's not a problem
but the thing we have at the moment is that in Chrome right here, we have a lot of default font families
which are supported
and that's awesome
but what's not so awesome is that we cannot control the browser
our website visitors are using. Therefore, in case your website visitor doesn't use Chrome, with the approaches
we use so far except for the web font of course but with the general approach of simply adding a font
family to our code, chances are that not all our users will be able to receive the font and therefore,
the fallback will be applied because the problem is, if you google for CSS font stack right here
and then click onto this link, then you can see that the so-called website fonts only include a limited
amount of font families because these are the generic families right here and the corresponding font
families that are installed locally on your machine.
So just by using a Windows machine, chances are quite high that Arial Black is installed on your computer
by default,
the same thing is true if you're using a Mac and if you go down right here for example to serif, you
can see that Bodoni, this one right here is not installed at all on the Mac.
Vice-versa,
we see for this Didot,
I don't know how it's pronounced to be honest, that this font family is not installed at all
on Windows machines but on many Macs and this is what you have to keep in mind.
In the end, just by adding font family, so our code that we added right here in the shared file, so just by
adding this font family property without adding a web font like we did right here,
so if we would delete that and just add the font family like that, the only two things we would rely
on is that either our user has this font family installed on his machine,
maybe by default or afterwards or that our browser knows this font family.
The problem with these approaches is of course, again we cannot control
neither of that two factors because we cannot force our users to install a font family and we cannot
force our users to use a specific browser.
So one option you always have of course
if you want to make sure that you will reach a large audience with your font family is to go to
cssfontstack.com and check for the font families available right here
because with that, you can of course make sure that a lot of your users should have this font family installed
on their machines and therefore, should be able to see your website the way you intend it to look like.
But of course that's not the best approach because we don't want to be limited by the default font families
installed on the machine.
Therefore, we used this web font right here which we imported from Google fonts and although we
did that already, I will like to take a closer look at that and show you what we did, how we can do it
and why using this is probably a better approach than just relying onto the fact that our users have installed
our font family by default on the machines.