Now what is the third rule to remember when it comes to the positioning units?
Well, no surprise right here, we have an element,
again we apply the percentage unit to it
and this time we have,
well what do we have?
We have positioned static or position relative applied right here.
If that is the case, then the containing block again is an ancestor, like we had it before but this time,
it's only the content of the ancestor,
so not content and padding like we had it before when our element had the position absolute declaration
applied but with position static or relative,
it's only the content.
Now how do we now identify the containing block,
so which is the ancestor we refer to?
Well the answer is there is simply the closest ancestor which is a block level element
and with that, we can now finish this slide actually and jump back to our project and see if we can also
find an example for our third rule to remember in our project.
So what we need is basically an element which has a percentage unit applied already maybe and which
is either not positioned at all,
so position static or relatively positioned.
Now if we go to our customers page right here, then I think that our image container might be a good
example for that.
So if we go into our main element right here, then we can see that we have our div, this name div right here, this wrapping
div, then we have the testimonial class
and inside this testimonial class, we have this image container right here.
If we scroll down, we can see we apply the width of 65%,
I showed you that in the beginning of this module also but we don't have any position property applied.
From a code perspective, we can find that if we go to the customers folder and to this index.html
file and right here, you can see the testimonial class and here, the testimonial image container.
So these are the classes we will probably work with now.
So let's now open the customer.css file
and here we need the testimonial image container class right here
because what we will do now is, we will now increase the width of this container from 65% to 100%,
like that.
If I do that and reload the page, you can see that the image increased dramatically.
Now why is this happening?
Well, because our element right here,
so this one, this testimonial class now takes the closest ancestor which is a block level element, which
is the case for this div right here with the testimonial class as the containing block.
And if we inspect that right here and go down there, we can see that this div has a width of 912
pixels and with that, our testimonial image container now also has this width applied because
that's the width of 100%. If I would reduce that width now, right here, to 50% for example,
like that and go back and reload the page, the image would decrease again because let's see, the containing
block still has a width of 912 pixels, you can see it right here
but the div inside of it,
so our element with the percentage unit now only has half of it.
That's also really important, it refers to 50% of the actual content, as we can see right
here,
912 is the actual content.
This means if I go to our testimonial right here and now add a padding of let's say zero top and bottom
and 10 pixels left right and reload the page, we can see that we have some movement here and maybe
also slight movement of the image,
I told you it wouldn't change, let's
see why it changed.
Well this is the container,
the container now has a width of 892 pixels only and 10 padding or 20 padding.
You remember why, right?
Because we added box sizing border box to our project,
therefore if I add a padding to our element right here, well then the padding will be added and this
will decrease the width of our content.
The interesting thing though is that if everything work correctly,
our image now or our image container, sorry for that, should have a width of 50% of 892 which
should be 446.
The interesting thing now is if I go back and change the position of our image container right here
to relative because you remember this third rule applies to both, position static and relative,
right here, if you remember the relative positioning,
we know that this should actually not have an impact on to our image right now or onto the positioning
of the image.
Let's see if this works,
if I reload the page, it looks still fine
and as we can see, the container of course still has 892 of width and the image still has 446 of
width.
So this is working for both static and relative positioning
but what happens now
if I turn our container into an inline element? This will probably break the entire website
but let's see if the relation is fine.
So I will add display inline now,
see how this works because as I said, this third rule only applies if our element with the percentage unit
is static or relative and then it looks for the closest ancestor which is a block level element,
so by turning this div into an inline element, this should not be true anymore.
So let's reload the page, as we can see the page is a bit messed up but it's still working generally.
So if I now look for our testimonial class right here, you can see it only has a width of 744 pixels
now, why is this the case?
Because it's set to auto which makes sense as we have now an inline element
but what happened to our image container right here?
This still has a width of 456 pixels,
let me see,
we still have the width of 50% applied.
Now let's have a look at the index.html
file and see what the next ancestor could be, which is a block level element.
We can see this first ancestor, the testimonial class
is not working anymore because it's an inline element but this div now here, this wrapping div, this should
be the ancestor we need and if we inspect that div right here, then we can see that this div has a
width of 912 pixels
and with that, we found the answer to this question.
Now that this div is not a block level element anymore, the closest ancestor is this wrapping
div and with that, we changed the containing block from the testimonial class to this wrapping div.
So let's change this back again
otherwise we will kind of mess up our website right here and also remove the padding and change the
width of the image container back to 65% because this is where we have been and also remove the
position relative declaration down here, like that.
So if we reload the page now, everything looks the way it did before.
We now understand why this 65% value right here is referring to our testimonial class right there
because this is the closest ancestor which is a block level element
and with that, we also understood this third rule to remember.
However, there is one important thing that I would like to show you because whenever you work with the
height and a percentage unit in cases like that, then the containing block could lead to a behavior which
you would not expect.
Let's have a look at that behavior and how we can quickly fix it in the next video.