We had a detailed look at CSS transitions, which make it very easy to animate the transition of a
CSS property from one value to another,
now let's have a look at CSS animations. We can think of them as CSS Transitions++,
so it's still about animating things but with way more control over the animation.
So if we have a block and we want to move to a bigger block, maybe with a different color, we
can of course use a transition
but if we want more control, like some in-between step, CSS animations are really what we're looking for.
In CSS animations,
we define so-called keyframes and we got full control what the style of an element is at a given point
of time,
now let's see how that works.
For this, I'm back in our project and I want to animate that start hosting call to action button in
the top right corner here.
Now that button's style is defined in the shared.css file, we can search for CTA here to find our main
nav CTA link here
and I want to play an animation on that button, right when the page loads,
I want it to wiggle around, so to rotate a bit up and rotate a bit down. Now with a transition, that's hard
to do because it should
wiggle, it should move in both directions and it should also stop after a given time
but until this it should just iterate between moving up moving down.
Transition is not really what we're looking for in this case, an
animation is what we need
and an animation always starts with you defining some keyframes,
these are the steps of the animation you want to go through.
You define keyframes in a CSS file by using @keyframes,
so just as you used @media and so on before, @keyframes is a special expression. You define a set
of keyframes here, which you can later use in a CSS animation and you have to give that set a name,
the name is totally up to you, can be wiggle for example. Now you then add curly braces and in there,
the most basic animation simply has a from value,
so you add the from keyword and then curly braces and then the two keyword. This essentially allows you
to define two keyframes, the starting state and the ending state. We'll later dive into how you can add
more keyframes.
Now I want this to rotate, so let's add a transform property here and then maybe rotate set zero,
this is where I want to start,
so I want to start with the rotation it has initially, which is not rotated at all.
Please note that there is no CSS selector in here, just the CSS property,
this property will later be applied to any element which receives that set of keyframes as an animation.
The target state maybe is that
we have a transformation of let's say rotate set of 10 degrees,
so moved up a little bit.
Now important, you can of course use any CSS property here, not just transforme,
you can also change the text color with color or the background or whatever you want to do,
not every property is animatable but you can still change it,
it might just jump to the next value immediately because what happens behind the scenes is that for
a CSS animation, CSS will still automatically generate smooth transitions between your starting
and target value,
you just have more control about the different in-between states, something I'll come back to
and of course it's way easier to define like five different properties that should be animated
than it is with transitions, here
you simply add them one after each other.
So here we get a simple animation though, just one property which we change and just two states; starting
and end state.
Now with that keyframes set defined, let's use it as an animation
and please note that we say nothing about the duration of the animation here, just where we want to start
and end.
So let's move up then and let's find our navigation items, here we got the call to action button,
now I'll add a new selector and for main nav item CTA,
so only in the main navigation for the call to action button,
I want to add that animation by adding the animation property.
First of all, we then reference the name of the keyframes we want to play, wiggle
in our case, so the name we defined for the keyframe set and then we define the duration, like
200ms.
We can also add a delay
and since this will actually play right from the time we load the page, a delay of three seconds might
not be too bad, to give the user some time to orientate himself.
Of course you can also use Javascript to dynamically add an animation so that it only plays when a certain
event happens. One other useful value you can specify here are the
animation iterations,
maybe eight,
this means it will play the animation eight times after it starts.
You also can then specify the direction, which simply means after one iteration, does it snap back to the
starting state and start the next iteration or does it actually alternate and move back to the starting
state?
So we can specify alternate here in this case. With that if we save that, we can reload our page
and now after three seconds, we actually see that our button starts wiggling here.
Now this didn't look like eight times because the alternate swing actually also counts as an iteration,
so we got four iterations in each direction. Besides alternate, you got also got reverse,
let's see what this does. If we now reload, here after three seconds, we can see now it's way more bumpy
because now what it actually does is it plays the keyframes in reverse,
so it starts with the end state and then moves back and you also got alternate reverse, I think alternate
looks the best here though. One interesting other value you can set for animations is filled state.
Now the fill states simply defines, should the properties set during the animation,
so in our case the transformed property and its value, should that be kept when the animation is finished
or not?
The default is that it's not keeping that,
you can also decide that you'd want to keep the starting state which can differ from your normal elements
state by the way. Here it's the same but of course, you can have an element where you add an animation
and the starting state is for example that it has a blue background color,
so it immediately starts the animation with that but by default, the element could have a green background
color,
so then the starting state of the animation would differ from the default state of the element. Anyways
you can tell the animation or CSS which values to keep with the fill state which is added as another
value to that animation shorthand here and that can be forwards to tell it to keep the final result,
let me show you what this means.
Now if I reload,
you will see that the animation plays and it actually finishes with nothing because we alternate
but if we remove alternate, you will see that it actually will finish in a rotated state
because now it has this bumpy look but it actually finishes rotated because we specified forwards
which tells it 'please keep the final property and values you have in the last keyframe here.'
If you use backwards, it'll keep the set up of the starting state,
now let me show you what I mean.
If we set the starting set to -10 degrees, then it's actually a different state than the default
state of the element which of course is no rotation.
So if I now set this to backwards and we reload, you'll see it starts in this state already and then
it starts wiggling and it ends in the final normal state.
You can also use both, in which case it will start with that first keyframe already and then will end
with the value of the last keyframe.
Now the most common use case is forwards actually because often you have animations where you want to
ensure that you finish in a certain state and that you then keep that state.
So now with forward set, we start in the normal state, then we start wiggling around
and then we have our end state.
Now here for the call to action button,
I actually want to have none,
so we can set none here,
we don't have to do that though, none is the default value.
So that's a basic animation.
Thus far, we only use two keyframes,
the cool thing about animations is that we can use more than two though,
so let's do that in the next lecture.