We get our basic transformations set up,
let's now change the perspective from which we're looking at this. To change the perspective,
we've got a special function we can use on transform, perspective.
There you enter a value in pixels or rem, like for example 100 pixels.
If I enter 100 pixels and reload, now you see this looks as if we're sitting next to the element
and the reason for this is, the smaller perspective is,
so for example one pixel, the closer you are to the element.
So for one pixel, we're right inside of the elements so to say. If we increase this to 1000 pixels, then we're
really far away but still closer too than we were before.
So now we can actually see this effect a bit better because it now goes outside of its surrounding
box and therefore it creates a 3D look.
Instead of using the perspective function, you can also use the perspective property by the way. You can
set perspective here, with the perspective property
and if you now reload, you don't see an effect, do you?
The reason for this is that the perspective property actually has to be applied to the parent element,
the advantage then is that you get the same perspective on all child elements. If you use perspective function,
then each element where you apply it has its own perspective,
even if they sit next to each other, this can leads to strange effects.
So on the container if we now reload, we're back to where we were.
Now we're looking at all child elements of the container, of which we only have one
but if it were more, it would affect all, we're looking at all elements from the same perspective.
Now you can also change the angle with perspective origin.
Here you by default have center but you can also enter
right
for example, if you enter right here and you reload,
now it looks as if it rotated a bit more
but actually our perspective just moved to the right,
so we're looking at this from a right angle now and on the other hand if we enter left here and we reload,
now we're further on the left.
You can also enter other values, like 100 pixels here,
this moves the perspective center to the right by 100 pixels.
So if you now reload, you're further to the right and if you enter an even bigger value, like 500 pixels
here and you then reload,
now you're even more on the right.
So this can be really useful to make sure that you look at the rotated element from the right perspective.
And with that said, it now also becomes easier to see both rotateX and y in action at the same time.
If we now rotate x by 30 degrees for example and we keep our perspective on the container element, now
we can reload
and now we actually see both transformations in effect
again, it's rotating around the y-axis and around the x-axis at the same time.
We can now also introduce rotateZ to complete it and enter 30 degrees here
and now it's also rotating around that.
Now it can be hard to see which rotation has which effect but in the end, you can always tweak and play
around with the settings until you got your desired effect.
Important to understand is simply that you can control both the rotation of the element on three axis,
as well as the perspective from which you're looking at this, both regarding the distance as well
as the angle.