Now that we get these basics set, let me remove all rotations but the Y rotation so that we're back to
an easier to understand 3D transformation,
now we're just rotating around the y-axis
and let me add a second box.
I'll simply duplicate that box and make sure it also is inside of the container and I'll give it a label
of animate two, the first one receives animate one
and here, I will name this box two and I'll change the selector, the class of the first one to box one.
In the CSS file, I'll
change that selector to box one,
then I'll duplicate the code and enter box two here.
Let's give that a blue background,
let's keep the width and height and I'll remove transform on box two for now.
Now if I save that and we reload the page,
we actually see this result.
Now the blue box is not inside of the container box, simply because we restrict the size of the container
box
and there already is one element with width 100%, height 100% in there.
Let's quickly fix that by giving this a position of relative,
so the container has this position and both boxes will now receive a position of absolute,
now if we reload, both are inside of that box.
Now let's also transform the blue box here by re-adding a transforme property to it
and let's give it a transform property of translateX 1rem for now. If we now save that and we then reload,
it simply moved to the right a bit,
just as we saw it before.
Now let's apply translateZ
then to also see that in effect. We use translateY and X thus far, translateZ is now the 3D transformation
for moving the element.
Now it can be confusing, since for rotating, we used Y and X
but if you keep the axis set up in mind, it makes sense that translating the element,
so moving the element on the z-axis, which is the axis coming out of the screen so to say, that moving
the element on that axis actually is the one that creates a 3D effect.
Now let's move it by let's say 10rem there, let's save that and let's reload and now you see it moved
towards us,
it became bigger because due to our perspective, moving an element towards us makes it bigger. On the
other hand, if we enter -10rem here and we then reload,
now it's moving back into that box, further away.
Now if we enter a way bigger value, like 100rem, -100rem and we then reload,
it's really small and it looks like it's outside of the box here
but actually even if I remove translateX, it stays inside of the box.
You can just think of that box as extending as a 3D space into
that 3D area behind it,
so it's actually moved further into the box so to say
and since we have a perspective coming from the right, we look at this from the right side.
This should become clearer if I reset my perspective origin to center for now,
if I then reload the page, now you can see it's still in the box, just moved further into the back.
It doesn't actually go behind our red box simply because the Z-index still applies when it comes to
how these elements stack,
they don't actually intersect.
Now, let me change that perspective back to 500pixel again and let me now show you something interesting
in the next lecture.
What happens if we also transform the container?