In the last lectures, we worked a lot with background images
and for a good reason because positioning background images really gives you a lot of flexibility.
It's actually harder to style normal images as you will see,
so let's dive into that because it's harder but of course not impossible.
Let's start with a logo for our page.
Right now, we only have text here,
why don't we use an image instead?
For that, I'll go to my index.html file
first of all and here where I have uHost in my anchor tag, I'll actually add an image element. Now
we can enter any alt text we want, doesn't really matter for our styling here,
so I'll name it
uHost, your favorite hosting company
and now for the source, we need an image. Now attached to this video,
you'll find the uHost icon which I'll put into the images folder here and I will also move my freedom
image in there by the way
and with that added, I first of all will quickly adjust the link here to freedom, to images/freedom
but more importantly in the index.html file,
I'll now also link to my newly added icon here, so I'll add
images/uhost icon.png. If we save all files and we reload,
yes it's a relatively big icon I'd say, at least we can clearly see it but it might be a little bit
too big for our page here.
So we definitely need to style that
and that's exactly what I want to do in this video. I'll style it in the shared.css file because it's
part of our shared header and now there, we can have a look at our brand styling.
If we scroll through our existing styles,
here is the main header, brand.
Now we set a text color, a text decoration and also font weight and size.
Now actually, we can leave that in case the alt text is shown but I want to change the way my image
is displayed.
Now one thing you could think is that we simply want to give it a let's say a height of 22 pixels to
be inline with our font size,
if we do that and we reload our page, yes didn't have too much effect, did it? The reason is and that's
important that by setting a height on a container and keep in mind, main header brand is just the container,
not the image element itself.
By setting a height on the container, the image will not be affected because the default behavior and
that's really important now,
the default behavior is if you enter an image tag and you point to an image, then the default height
and width of the original image will be used and will be entered into your document, no matter which
width and height you set for the surrounding element.
So in our case here if we have a look at our image, you'll see it it has dimensions of 186 x 190.
If we hover over the anchor tag, we actually can see on the left that the blue area is much smaller
than that but the image doesn't care. To make the image care,
we can of course follow two routes.
First of all, we need to select it,
that's always the case.
So let's use our main header brand class here
and then let's select the image.
You could of course also add a class to the image, here
I will simply use the descendant selector to select any images in main header brand,
now in there, we could of course also set a height of 22 pixels.
If we do that and we reload,
now we see the image is much smaller.
Now besides doing that, what we could do is of course set 100%, this would mean it should take the
height of the surrounding container, which happens to be our brand that sets the height of 22 pixels.
However, this does not work.
Height
100% on the image will again lead it to use its original height, not the height defined by the container,
that's
important to understand,
so we should really set the final value we want to have on the image here.
Now let's find out if that's also the case for the width, in case we're not setting the height
but let's say we're setting a width of 20 pixels on the surrounding container.
If we set nothing on the image, nothing changes,
if we go to the image and we set width to 100% and then we reload, also nothing changes.
So percentage values on the image don't help us here because they don't respect the surrounding container.
Now actually the reason for that simply is that our surrounding container is an inline element itself,
it's just an anchor tag.
If we set it to inline block instead and now we reload,
now the image does respect this container style,
so it was not the image but the fact that the anchor tag was not a block or inline block element.
As soon as it is, we can use 100%
and of course not just on the width but also on the height.
So this is important to understand, with using images it depends on whether you use it nested in an
inline element, in which case 100% will simply use the default dimension, the default or height
of the image
or if you use it inside a block level element where it will use the container width or height.
So now with that back, we now can set 100% as a height and it will use the height of our
container here.
So with that, we style the image and this is about all we can do regarding styling already. All the fancy
things we could do for background images, with the different positioning modes and sizing modes, with cover
and so on, are not really possible with normal images.
You can always find some hacky solutions with negative paddings or margins to position an image in
a certain way,
for example here, we could go to our image here and give it a margin top of let's say -5 pixels
and if we do that, then you see it was actually moved up a tiny bit but that really is about it
and it's as I said, also a bit hacky.
Now therefore if you want to do some more complex styling on an image, I recommend using background
image.
The downside of background image just is as it's not part of your normal document flow,
it doesn't have its own HTML elements that clearly signals that it's an image,
it's worse for accessibility.
So background images should really just be used as such,
backgrounds. If you got an image in your normal document flow, you should go with the normal image but
then you often don't have to set more than the width or the height.
Of course you can still set anything else like borders and so on,
I'm just talking about the positioning and sizing where you are limited, regarding all the other things,
you can of course set everything you want.
So that was just a tiny exercise though, that was just our brand
icon. We got that customers page and there, I actually want to have bigger images. So let's add this page
in the next lecture.