So when we click on a button, we get this blue outline, another browser default. You can inspect it
in the developer tools by selecting the button and then clicking on this pseudo selector hov thing here.
If you click on it, you can toggle different states because otherwise, it's not really possible to inspect
the active state for example. Here you can check active and now you see what the button will look like if it's
active.
You can also see this is the style we assign for it
but this does not have the blue color, for that,
you need the focus pseudo selector. The focus pseudo selector is available for input fields,
so both text input fields as well as buttons which also handle user input
and it basically is applied or becomes active whenever a user has this focused, which of course is the
case if the the user clicks it
but also if the user circles around with tab, so there you can also set the focus state. So focus has
this outline property as you can see here.
Now the outline is comparable to a border but it's not part of the box model,
keep in mind the border is part of the box model,
the outline actually is not. The outline is just some additional border-like thing which actually is
applied outside of the box,
so before the margin but after the border and it's therefore like a lighter version of the border. You can
style it with the outline property.
Now as you learned we need to use the focus pseudo selector for that and we can simply set outline to none
here because I don't want to have any look for when this button is focused.
Of course you can get a different style,
you can set outline to a different look or assign a normal border or change any other property. You can of
course do that for the focus pseudo selector
just as for any other pseudo selector. With that,
now if we reload and click that button, we don't have that blue outline and that is a look I like much
more.