In the last lecture, we added a basic animation and I hope these values are all clear,
let's now add another keyframe though and for that, I'll generally change the notation. Instead of
from and to,
we can also use percentage values here.
We have 0% and 100% then, that's the same as from and to
but now we can add as many in-between steps as we want
simply by adding another block, for example with 50% but you can also use 10, 15, whatever you
need
and now you can define which state your animation should have when it's halfway done.
So this is now where I will set transform to rotate set -10 degree.
So now I'll actually start at zero,
then halfway through the animation, we'll be at 50%
and by the end, we'll be at 100%.
Now we got three keyframes and therefore way more control over our animation.
Now if we go back to our animation property, where we add it to an element, we still have wiggle,
we still maybe have that duration, maybe we increased it a bit so that we can see that animation
a bit better,
we still have the delay and the iteration count maybe.
So let's now save this and look what that yields,
now you'll see we have a way better wiggle effect because now we have that in-between step which actually
looks way better than using that alternate mode.
We can still use alternate here of course, we can still add alternate as a value but this will actually
lead to a strange look here because we're already controlling the full animation perfectly.
So now here, it will actually play this strange thing because it moves through the entire animation and then plays
it back which looks ugly in our case.
One thing that's good to know is that you can still add a timing function though, you can still add ease
out and by the way, the order of these values here doesn't really matter
except for duration and delay,
since both use seconds or milliseconds, here the duration should come first.
But back to the timing function,
isn't it strange to specify ease out or any other timing function
if you have perfect control over the way the animation plays? Well the timing function simply is there
to decide how the movement between the keyframes should be animated because if you go from transform
rotate set zero to transform rotate set -10 degree,
this change of course has to be animated
and actually, this works exactly as the transition did.
So here, it will simply transition from zero to -10 degree and that transition happens over
half the time of your animation
but that time there, between these two keyframes, this is now affected by the timing function.
You can specify linear or any other function you want, like ease out
in our case here.
So with that if we reload, we might not even see a big difference here because that's really hard to
spot
but now this is actually animating with an ease out timing function between our keyframes steps.