Time for a quick tip because we already talked about the fact that we can change the font size in the
browser settings, right here if I change it to very large, that and go back to my website, we can see that
all the font sizes which were not specified by us, like this text right here where we defined the font
size of 20 pixels, all the other font sizes changed because of that browser settings.
That's the normal behavior, probably
there's no reason to change that.
There can be cases though
where you say that you want to change the font size for the entire HTML element from the beginning, depending
on the browser settings.
You can do this if you go to our shared.css file for example, add an HTML selector like this and now say
font size should be not 100%.
You could do that but this doesn't add a lot of value because it will simply overtake the browser
settings which is the behavior we already have
but you could say you would like to change the font size to 75% of the browser settings by default.
If you do that, you can see that the font size for this navigation items decreases to 75% of the default value
and with that, you have a direct impact onto the default settings by default.
Nevertheless, we will not follow this approach because we will define the font size specifically for
the different parts on our website.
I just wanted to show you that this is possible
and by the way, we can also change back the font size to medium, I think this looks better.
So as I said, I just wanted to show you that this is possible, that you can do that
and if you have a specific case where you want to do it, you can do it like this with the percentage
value
but normally you can keep it like that
and with that, we can now continue with the next video where we will have a look at the percentage value
once again,
one last time actually
and also see how we can use it in combination with the min and max width property.
Let's find out how this works in the next lecture.