So the last option we have is adding our own fonts to our website.
Well, this course is not about creating fonts,
therefore I will use another approach to show you how this works.
For that, I'm back on Google fonts and let's now maybe select a Monospace font because we had sans-serif
a lot,
so let's see, what could we use,
I think this one, AnonymousPro,
this looks actually quite nice.
If we look at this option right here, we talked about that where we have the font weights and the font style
right here defined, we can see that we have four different so-called font faces right here.
So let's now select the regular 400,
so the default font face right here and again, press onto the plus as we did it before.
Now right here, we can now get rid of the Roboto font, we don't need that and we could of course import it
again as we learned it but this is our own font, right?
Well, at least that's what we pretend now,
so we want to find another way how to embed it onto our website
and for that, we can simply download this font by clicking right here.
Once you finished the download and unzip the file, you can see these four ttf files right here.
I'll talk about the file names and which files we have right here in the next lecture,
so let's stick to this ttf for the moment and as we can see, we have four different files.
Each file represents a font face,
so we have the bold font face, the bold-italic font face, the regular-italic font face and the regular font
face.
So we want to add this regular font face to our page,
so let's focus onto this one now.
Now to import this onto our website, we simply have to go to our CSS file. As I will only use it
in our packages.css file,
I will add it right here on top of the page.
So what we need to do is, we need to write @font-face like that and of course add the curly braces and
now we need to specify a name for our font family.
Well, the font family was anonymous so let's maybe call it AnonymousPro, like that and we will
again put it into quotation marks,
you could also use single quotation marks if you want to but I will stick to the normal quotation marks
right here.
So that's what we have,
we now said that we have a font family that we want to import,
that's basically what this code right here tells us.
The problem is that we also need the files which contain the information,
so we need to add a source right here, like that and this should be a URL.
The problem is that we don't have a URL at the moment because we didn't add the file
we want to use to our code right here,
so I will simply drag and drop this file right here into our packages folder because we only want
to use it right there,
so that's the AnonymousPro
regular.ttf,
that's the file I just dragged right there.
So we now have the URL which is simply
AnonymousPro.ttf, that's our file name, so not pro, including regular,
sorry for that,
we have to add this too
and that's it.
With that, we imported our own font face, our custom font face. As you can see, not a lot different to
the way we did it right here with our @import but this time, we simply added our file directly to our
folder where our code is located
and with that, if we would assume that we have our code for the website hosted on our server, we would
also host our code for the font families right there
and with that, we would again ensure that each visitor of our website can access this font.
However, we have to add this font of course here in our packages info class
and let's get rid of these properties for now
and let's change Roboto with AnonymousPro now, like that and if we now go back to our website,
we can actually minimize right here
and reload the page, you can see that we now use our imported custom font that we used.
And this is really cool actually
and now you could say, well that's easy,
why don't we always do it like that?
Well the issue is the following; if we now have another look at Google fonts right here and think back
about the different font faces, we have this regular one and this bold 700 one for example and let's say
that we want to have this bold, this 700 font weight,
then we could add this of course right here, like that, the font weight of 700
but the problem is if we now reload the page, like that, this bold style is not applied because again, keep
that in mind, we only imported the regular font family,
so this one right here, the Regular.ttf and therefore our code and our browser have no idea what a bold
AnonymousPro font face would look like.
So what we have to do right here is we have to import this specific font face.
For that, we simply copy this, first font face right here and now important, don't change the font family
because we of course want to refer to the same font family,
we only want to be able to apply a bolder font way to it. Therefore we first have to add our bold file
to our folder,
so this one right here, like that,
that's the AnonymousProBold,
so we have to name it accordingly,
AnonymousProBold,
like that
and if we save that and keep in mind, we still left the font weight of 700 right here and reload the page, then
you can see that the bold style was applied.
The problem is that the code we wrote right now is not correct because look back at our syntax. If we
scroll up again right here, we can see that there is no difference in the font
in general, the source is different,
yes but how should our browser or the code be able to differentiate between these two imports we have?
So for example if I now change the font weight to 400 here, which would be the normal font weight and
reload the page, nothing would change, even if I change it to normal for example, like that.
Because the problem is that based on the code we wrote right now,
well we will simply apply this last font face import, the first one won't be imported.
Now we can simply change this
and by the way, I forgot the semi-colons right here and right there,
please excuse that and make sure to add this. So we can change this by adding a font weight right here
of 700 because that's the import that we did,
that's the font weight that we have for our bold font style right here.
With that, if we now scroll down again and keep this to normal
and now reload, you can see that we now have the thinner font style
and if we change it back to 700, then if we did it correctly, we should have our bold font style back
again.
So that's the crucial thing right here,
if you import multiple font faces up here, then make sure to add the font weight which is the differentiation
criteria between our different font faces,
otherwise you will always use the last code.
Another thing we could change right here by the way is the starting letter right here,
this should actually be a small letter, not a capital letter.
This is not crucial though but this can cause problems with the Internet Explorer,
so make sure to make these letters right here small ones
and then of course, accordingly change this file right here
and the second one also to these small letters, like that.
That's just a small cosmetic change but we want to write our code as good as possible, therefore
definitely makes sense to change that.
With that, we saw how we can import our fonts with font face and how we can use our custom fonts with
all the pros and cons that we have
but so far we only used this ttf file format right here.
Now let's have a look at that in more detail and see if we have other file formats available for our
font faces.