Thus far we transformed the elements in our container,
let's now transform the container itself. Let's transform it by rotating it, by rotating it around the
y-axis
let's say. Let's rotate it by 45 degrees,
let's save that,
so I'm on the container now.
Now if I reload, you see the elements moved a bit because the parent container also rotates.
If I rotate the container by 90 degrees, so we shouldn't see the container and I reload the page,
everything is hidden.
Now of course, logically this doesn't make a lot of sense because even if the container is rotated by
90 degrees, since we also rotate the red box and move the blue box a little bit to the back, we should
definitely see these two elements still
because they actually have their own 3D space inside of the container.
The default behavior however flattens this 3D space
and you can change this behavior with another property which you add to the container,
it's called transform style.
The default value is flat, which means the container rotates and the elements move with the container
but they're actually in a flat 3D space in there,
so the overall container is seen as one flat object.
However, you can change that value to preserve-3D. With this value,
the 3D position of the child elements is preserved.
So now if you reload, you can actually still see the red box,
now the blue box is something we can't see because since we only translate but don't rotate it, it has the
same angle as the parent element, which right now is rotated by 90 degree and therefore is perfectly
invisible.
If we change this to 95 again and we reload, then we can see the border of our container again, we don't
see the blue box.
The reason for this is that keep in mind, the blue element is in front of the red element
and since we're flipping everything here, in front now actually means in the back. Yes it can be tricky
to wrap your head around that
but the easiest way to get into this really is just to build a simple demo like this and play around
with it to see how elements move around and change their look or how the visual effect changes.
If we increase this to 130 degree, we flip this element further, then we'll soon reach the point where
we can see the blue box again.
Of course one way to see it right now would be to give the red box a z-index of one so that it sits
in front of the blue box
and with that if we reload
and we also decrease that translateY
value, translateZ value of the blue box let's say -10,
then we can see it. With a higher translateZ value, we couldn't see it because that actually also
moved it out of the screen because again, we're flipping this,
so a negative translateZ value
now actually leads to this element moving towards us or towards us and out of the screen to the left
to be precise and therefore a smaller distance moves it closer to the container, closer to the red box and
the red box is behind the blue box
even though it has a z-index because we're flipping everything as you can see by the reversed text
here.
So 3D transformations can really mess with your head but also allow you to create really powerful visual
effects on your page.