So in this module, we learned a lot about how we can change styles with the style property or by adding
classes or manipulating classes,
now let me console dir element, like the backdrop for example again and let's dive into the style property
for a second
again. If we reload and go to the console, here we see the backdrop.
Now let's go down to style and you might have noticed it before,
if you watch closely, we didn't recognize it for display because it's only one word
but for other things like background image and a lot of other multi-word properties, they are written
in a different way than you use it when writing CSS code in CSS files or in HTML files.
You don't have a dash between background and image and image then starts with a capital I,
the reason for this is that property names, you can call these variables and object so to say, are invalid
if they contain a dash, that is why the notation differs slightly.
Essentially, whenever you have a CSS property that consists of multiple words, like border radius
and you want to change this directly from within Javascript, you would change it to one word where the dash
is omitted and the word after the dash starts with a capital character,
so borderRadius in this case here. This is simply something you have to keep in mind,
you have to change the syntax without a dash but with a capital character after the dash. You've got
an alternative though, in the shared.js file,
if I access style background image I just showed you, this will work,
if we reload,
we just see nothing because no value is assigned
but you do see an empty line so it did execute.
You can also access it in a different notation by using square brackets right after style,
no dot in between and then passing a string to the square brackets and in there, you now use the normal CSS
property name, like background-image. Here
since it's a string, the dash is allowed
and if you want to use the normal names as you know them, this is an alternative syntax you can use.
If you now save this and you reload,
you again see an empty line and no error which means it worked.
So that's important,
by default use that so-called camel case notation without a dash but with a capital character for the
separate words or use this way of accessing the property names. If you're attaching and removing classes
as we do here, you of course don't change the way you style or write your styles in your CSS file, that's
not affected by Javascript at all,
this is really just needed if you directly access a style property from within your Javascript code.
So that's something important which I wanted to highlight,
now with that, let's wrap up this module.