Now we saw how we can use grid column start end and grid row start and end to target different line numbers
and are accurate to define where the elements should go.
Now working with the line numbers of course is an option but not the only one we got,
it would also be nice to give our columns and rows names or to give our column and row lines names to
be precise and we can do that.
Let's start with the rows because we repeat the columns and there is something special about that,
I'll come back to that,
so let's start with the rows.
If we want to name line number one,
so this first horizontal line, then we have to add the name in front of the value for the first row, so
of the height of the first row
and we add the name in square brackets, that's important,
this is required
and then any name of your choice, you're totally free.
You shouldn't take span though because it's a reserved word
but other than that, you're totally free.
So for example here, we could name this row-1-start,
however again, the name is up to you,
so row-1-start. After this first row,
we name the line that comes thereafter,
so line number two, the second horizontal line. We add square brackets again
and now we can name this row-1-end. You could argue that it maybe also should be named row-2-start
though because the second the line here actually is both the ending of the first row and the start of
the second one.
Good thing is if you want,
you can assign multiple names, simply by staying in the square brackets, adding a whitespace and adding
the second name which of course is totally up to you.
This is not required,
you can do that,
you can of course also use one name. This will refer to the same line, that's important,
so you can use the two names interchangeably now.
And now we can simply add another name after this additional row here,
so maybe we can name this row-2-end and we could also name it row-3-start if we wanted to,
so we could add row-3-start as a second name and then we can name the last line number which is
row-3-end
for example. If you save that and you reload,
you don't see the names here
in the inspector, that's not displayed. We can just check if it works because we can now reference
these names instead.
So in places where we refer to the row numbers, like here grid row start, we refer to line number
two,
now a name for line number two is either row-1-end or row-2-start.
Let's maybe pick 2-start
because here we are defining something which should start there,
so we set this to row-2-start, without square brackets.
Now grid row end doesn't take a line number here because here we use the span syntax but for example
down there on element three, we get a grid row end of three,
now line number three has that row-2-end
name for example, we could also use row-3-start.
But let's take a row-2-end and let's replace grid row end, the value three to be precise with
row-2-end, again without square brackets here and grid row
start of course could be row-1-start as a name, like that. With all that added, if we save everything and
we reload,
we shouldn't see any changes which is a good sign because that means it works because we target the
same lines as before but this time, with our named lines here.