Let's wrap up by doing a final review of the case for Docker and why
we want to use this in our development environment.
So we talked about that Docker brings many development
benefits to our different team members, and even if you're just a team of one,
there's a lot of benefits,
because you could bring servers and databases and many of the things up very
quickly, and then get rid of those if you're done with them.
So we talked about how we can bring up web servers and
databases and caching servers and more,
and bring those up in a very consistent way across team members,
even in distributed locations if we needed to,
and then how we can even move those up into the cloud if we'd like.
And so there's the benefits of the consistency and the fact that how it runs in
development is how it's going to run if you move those containers and images
into your staging and your production environments.
Now, we talked about that the heart and soul of Docker is,
of course,
Docker images, and that Docker images are used to create our containers.
So some of the key tools that we talked about were Docker Client,
and this is, of course, how we can work with our images and containers.
We talked about Docker Machine, and how we can use
that to interact with a virtual box.
And then Docker Compose, one of my personal favorite tools, is especially
helpful as we need to work with multiple containers and get those all up and
running and talking between each other. And then,
if you don't want to work with the command line, we
also talked about Docker Kitematic,
and it does provide a really nice and simple way to get started with
Docker if you really just want to jump in quickly and not have to
learn all the commands that we talked about for Docker Client,
Docker Compose, and others. Now,
we also talked about linking our source code from a running container to a
local folder that you might have on your development machine.
And this is a really, really important part for us as web developers,
because we obviously need a way to quickly and easily make changes
to code, get that code running up in a container,
such as a Node.js or ASP.NET or PHP or whatever it may be container
that is running the actual server. And we talked about how we can do
that with Docker Volumes, and how a volume can point to a folder that
we set up, and that makes it very easy to link our source code into a
running container.
Now,
when it comes to containers, while we can pull many of the
containers out there from Docker Hub,
we can also create our custom Docker images.
And we talked about how we can do Docker files and create Docker files
that can be based on an image that's in Docker Hub, and then we can
add our custom functionality into that.
Now, as mentioned,
one of my favorite things covered in the entire course was Docker Compose,
and we also talked about the Compose YAML file.
And this YAML file is just a great way, I think,
to get your development environment up and running very quickly. You
could have 10 different services, if you wanted, and not have to bring
those up individually using Docker Client.
We could get this YAML file in place,
and we'd be off to the races and up and running.
So that's a wrap on the Docker for Web Developers course,
and I hope that you have a really solid feel now for the role that
Docker can play in your development environment.
I appreciate you taking the time to listen to the course,
and hope you're able to apply this new knowledge into your Web development efforts.