Developers are quite used to writing instructions in a code file,
running those through a compiler,
and then outputting some type of binary or other file.
Well in the Docker world,
we have a very similar type of process that we can follow to
create an image and then a running container,
and that's to create something called a Dockerfile.
Now, a Dockerfile is nothing more than a text file that has instructions in it.
Now these instructions, of course, are unique to Docker,
and they're defined up in the Docker documentation,
but it's a very,
very similar process to, if you're writing Java or
C# or another compiled language, you'll write some instructions in a file,
and then in the developer world we'd run those through a compiler.
Well in the Docker world, we'll run them through the Docker client
and it has a build command we can run,
and then that build command can read through those instructions,
generate a layered file system, as we've talked about earlier in the course,
and then we have a Docker image that comes out of this that we can then use,
and we can make a container from that.
Dockerfile itself, as mentioned, is really just a text file.
There's really nothing fancy about it, in fact,
it's normally called Dockerfile and oftentimes doesn't even have an extension,
but you can name it whatever you want.
It's just a text file that we want to feed into the Docker build process.
And so it contains some build instructions,
which we're going to be looking at,
and these build instructions will do things like work with
environment variables or copy source code into the image,
and more.
Now,
the instructions that we're going to be doing oftentimes
create intermediate images, and these images are kind of
behind the scenes images that are cached,
and that way if you maybe change an instruction,
need to rebuild the image, it won't have to do everything from scratch.
Now, there are ways you can override that and not cache anything,
but then it'll make your build process take a little bit longer.
And, as mentioned,
we're going to be using a docker build command to actually
convert the text file into an image.
Now here's some of the key Dockerfile instructions,
and this certainly is not all of them, it's just a few,
and I'm going to talk through the high‑level look at what do these do.
So normally what you'll do is you'll start off by saying I would
like to create an image from another image.
Now you can create it from scratch, from kind of nothing,
but normally you'll create one based on,
for instance, a Node.js image or a MongoDB image or PostgreSQL,
or something like that.
You'll use that as your baseline,
and then you'll build on top of that using this layered file system.
There's also a way you can define who maintains it,
that's a very simple instruction, but you could say your name,
and then there's a run command.
Now the run command's really important because you can actually have different
things defined that are going to be run, and these would be,
I want to go out to the internet and grab something,
I want to run npm install, dnu restore,
those types of things could be actually run using this run instruction.
Another really important one is copy.
When you're ready to go to production,
we learned about earlier in the course you can use volumes for source code,
but when you go to production we want to copy that source
code into the container oftentimes.
There's multiple ways to do it, but that's pretty common,
and so we can use the copy instruction to do that.
You can also set what is the main entry point for this container.
In other words, when you have an exe, or something like that on a system,
you can normally double‑click it and it has a main
entry point that kicks everything off.
Very similar here, what is the initial entry point that kicks off the container,
for instance?
You can also define what the working directory is.
This sets the context for where that container is going to run as,
for instance, the entry point is run.
So I could say what folder has my package.json, and I can do an npm run.
You can also expose a port,
and this will be the default port that the container
would then run internally with, define environment variables,
these environment variables can be used then in that container,
and then we can even define volumes.
And we've already looked at volumes in the course,
but you can now define the actual volume and control how it
stores that on the host system for that container,
as we've already talked about with volumes.
Now let's take a look at what a Dockerfile actually looks like then.
That's a few of the commands, but it kind of helps to see them in action.
So, first off you could say from,
and this will always be the very first instruction that
you're going to put at the top of your Dockerfile, and I'm
going to say FROM node build an image.
And this will grab Node as the base file system and then
add additional layers on top of that.
Now I could say the maintainer, in this case I obviously put me,
but this is where you could put yourself,
you could put your email, things like that.
Then we can say I'd like to copy my source code from my
current folder I'm building from, in this case dot,
and I'm telling Docker in this case that when you build the image,
copy that source code into the var/www folder,
which is just one I of course made up.
What that will do now is this layered file system will have a layer
in it that's going to be just for our source code,
and that will be the copy command or instruction.
We can then set the var/www as our work directory because we might want to run
some different commands like npm install if it was Node,
we can define the port we'd like to expose that the
container actually runs with, and we can also define an entry point.
In this case I'm saying that the node command and
server.js is my initial entry point into this,
but of course that could be whatever you want for your chosen technology.
So that's a quick look at some of the different instructions,
and as mentioned,
there are more, but we're focusing on the ones that you really need
to know to get started with as a developer. But what we're going to
do now is take a look at building custom Dockerfiles from scratch with some different technologies.