Let's start things off by answering the question, what is Docker?
Docker does have some different terms.
So we're going to clarify what those are,
we're going to clarify where it can run,
and how this all kind of works.
So Docker itself is just a lightweight, open, secure platform.
This is kind of the official party line, if you will.
And the first time I heard that it didn't make maybe a
whole lot of sense because I could think of several things
that might fit a lightweight, open, secure platform definition.
But really what Docker is is a way to simplify the
process of building applications, shipping them,
and then running them in different environments.
Now, when I say environments, of course,
I'm talking about development, staging, production,
and others that you may have at work.
Now, what actually ships with Docker then?
Well, we're going to be talking about things called images and containers,
and containers are really, really important.
You'll see over at the left the Docker logo,
and you can think of the whale there as kind of like a ship that has containers.
And back in the old days,
there was no standardized way to ship things on the old‑school ships.
So it was a lot more time intensive and not very productive
to get stuff on the ship and off the ship.
Whereas nowadays, the major shipping companies,
of course, have very standardized sized,
standard height standard width, shipping containers.
So as the crane goes over when the ship docks,
it's very quick and efficient,
very productive to get those containers on and off these ships.
Well, Docker is very similar.
If you think of the old days with ships that had no
standards for shipping products around,
that's kind of where development has been for many years.
Everybody does it their own way.
Well,
Docker provides a consistent way to ship our code
around to different environments,
and so it's going to provide a lot of benefits that we'll be talking about in
this particular section of the module for us as developers.
Now it runs natively on Linux or Windows,
and when I say Windows, Windows Server 2016 or higher now supports it.
We'll talk more about that coming up.
And as a developer, if you're on a Windows box or a Mac box or a Linux box,
you can use Docker in your development workflow,
and it's very easy to get up and running.
Now if you're on Mac or Windows, you will need a virtual machine,
because by default it's going to expect a Windows server or a Linux server.
Now finally,
the key buzzwords that are typically thrown around with
Docker are images and containers.
Let's clarify what exactly is an image and what is a
container and how do they relate to each other?
So when it comes to the role of images and containers,
an image is something that's used to build a container.
Now an image will have the necessary files to run something on
an operating system like Ubuntu or Windows,
and then you'll have your application framework or your
database and then the files that support that.
So if you're doing Node.js or ASP.NET or PHP or Python,
then you'd have that framework built into the image
as well as your application code, typically.
Now the image itself is not overly useful because it just is the definition.
Think of it as the blueprint that's used to actually
get a running container going.
So if you go back to the shipping analogy,
think of some person who does some CAD drawings of what's
going to go in the shipping container,
maybe even how they're going to arrange it in the shipping container,
but the blueprints aren't very useful on their own,
but you can use those to create an actual instance of that container.
Well, that's the same process in Docker.
We'll have images that can be used to create a running instance of a container.
Now containers are actually where the live application runs,
or the database or caching server or whatever it may be that you need to
actually run on a Linux or a Windows Server machine.
Now let's dive into the definitions of each of these just a little bit more.
So an image is a read‑only template.
And what it's composed of, and we'll be building these throughout the course,
is a layered file system.
So you'll have some files, for instance,
specific to your Linux operating system or your Windows operating system,
and then you'll have your files for your framework,
ASP.NET, or Node.js, or whatever it may be,
and then they are all put together to make this image.
Now once you have an image, you can use that to build this isolated container.
And again if you go back to ships,
every container is very isolated from the other containers.
It makes it so you don't necessarily know what's going on in another container.
Now there are some gotchas there that we can talk about later,
but in a nutshell,
the image is used to create an instance of the running container.
And then you can start the container, you can stop it,
you can move it, you can delete it, and it starts and stops really,
really fast.
And that's what's so cool about this technology is,
it's very quick and easy to get a container on the ship and off the ship.
And the ship, in our case, would be the development environment,
the staging environment, the production environment.
Now where does Docker run then?
Well, as I've already mentioned, Docker can run on Linux or Windows servers.
And so if you're going to be running on a development machine,
you have to have a virtual machine, which we'll talk about.
Now the exception would be if you're developing directly on a Linux machine,
then you could just run Docker containers natively.
But Docker ships with what's called a Docker client,
and Docker client can then integrate with these different operating systems,
such as Linux, and it integrates with a Docker Engine,
a daemon that you'll see here.
Now Docker itself has its roots in Linux.
That's actually where it came out of.
The Docker, the company, built on top of some LXC support,
it's called Linux Container Support,
that's already built in to the Linux operating system.
Now likewise, Windows Server 2016 or higher also has Docker support built in,
and so the Docker client there could be used to
integrate with the Docker Engine,
which can start and stop and delete and do all those things with our containers.
So think of the Docker client as kind of the commands that are given to the
people that load the ship or remove things off the ship,
whereas the Docker Engine could be the cranes and the people running those that
actually get the container on the ship and up and running.
Now what's the difference between Docker containers then in virtual machines?
Because this is one of those things that,
the first time I learned about this, it didn't make a lot of sense to me.
So virtual machines always run on top of a host operating system.
So of course you could have a host running Linux or Windows,
and then you can run a guest OS on top of something called a hypervisor.
And so on the left, you might have, App 1 might be a PHP app,
for instance, with its binaries, libraries,
whatever it may be, or ASP.NET or Node, or whatever you have.
And then App 2 might be running on a different guest OS.
So let's say the guest OS on the left is maybe Windows,
and the guest OS on the right could be Linux.
The bottom line is you have a copy of the operating
system for every virtual machine.
And so, depending on the type of hard drive and things like that,
it can be a little bit expensive to start up and stop a virtual machine.
They run well, but they're pretty big.
The images for a virtual machine to get it up and running
are generally multiple gigabytes in size.
Well, let's compare and contrast that with Docker containers.
Now they do sit still on top of a host operating system,
Linux and now, most recently, Windows server 2016 or higher.
And then we have this Docker Engine,
which can integrate the containers with the host operating system.
And so now, as we get a container up and running,
you can think of the host operating system as the ship and
then the container for App 1 has everything App 1 needs
for that particular feature, so Node.js with all the application code,
for instance.
Now App 2 might have a completely different container,
and then typically applications will have multiple containers.
You might have a container for your database,
a container for a caching piece,
a container for your application code and the framework,
those type of things.
But the bottom line is they sit right on top of the native operating system.
So when I ship these around, I'm shipping a smaller image.
It's very small compared to a guest OS virtual machine.
They also start containers also start very,
very fast, and we'll be seeing that throughout the course.
They're great.
They just come up in a matter of seconds.
The difference here is very, very big.
Containers sit on top of the host,
whereas guest OSs and VMs sit on top of the actual host,
but they're their own copy of all the files.
Everything is a copy as you make a new VM.
So that's an example of what Docker is.
We've now talked about images and containers,
and we'll be delving much, much more into those throughout the course.
And then we've also done a comparison between Docker
containers and virtual machines.
So now that we've done that, let's start talking about,
all right, this is great and all, but how does this actually help me as a web developer?