Up to this point,
you've learned about the layered file system and how
it's used with images and containers,
and we've also learned about the basics of volumes.
But let's go a little more in depth into volumes and how we can
actually use these to store some source code.
So earlier,
we looked at containers and saw that we can define a volume in a container.
Now, we haven't quite seen the syntax to do that,
but I'm going to show you that here.
And I mentioned that when you write to a volume,
if you set that up,
that it's actually going to write to some special
area that's on your Docker host.
And by default, Docker takes care of that.
It takes care of creating this area where it mounts this folder.
And so I like to think of the var/www/volume that's in the container
here as really being an alias that points over to the Docker host
and this mounted folder type of area,
and that's where you can put your log files and that type of stuff.
Now to do this,
we normally run a command like the following to start
up an image and make a container.
So we can say Docker run, give it our port,
and we have the external and the internal container port,
and in this case, I'm going to run the Node image.
Well, if we actually want to have a special area,
a data volume, where that Node app could write to,
then we can change it to look like this.
So I can put ‑v, and that stands for volume,
and in this case, say, /var/www and then put the image name.
Now the var/www, or www, however you like to say it, that would be the volume.
And then the area that it writes to would be in the Docker host,
and so it would kind of look like this.
We create a volume, this is the container volume alias,
but it actually is going to right to the host area,
and Docker again will automatically create that.
Now, where does it store it?
How would you know?
Let's say that, for instance,
your Node application writes a log file out to this var/www
folder; how does it know where that's going to be?
Well, what's going to happen is,
Docker kind of magically makes that mounted folder.
And the way you can find where it is is by running docker
inspect and then the name of your container.
And so we could come in and do that,
and if you scroll through the information it gives you,
you'll see a Mounts area.
You can see that over here.
And the Mounts area has a name, and it's going to be a really long,
unique identifier, and then a source path,
and it's also a fairly long path.
You'll notice it's in this Mount, mnt, folder,
and that's going to be on your host, your Docker host.
The destination that the container actually writes
to is going to be this var/www.
And so we have the host location defined there in the source,
and then we have the volume location that's in the container
defined by the destination property that you can see.
And so, in this case,
Docker is automatically taking care of where that data gets written to.
But you now have to know if you ever wanted to go
get it outside of the container, have to know how to get to this path,
which can be a little bit long.
And it works great in scenarios where you don't want to control it.
You just want to set up a container volume,
write to it,
and then have Docker take care of storing that
somewhere and persisting that data.
And this is the default way it will do it.
Now, the other option is, we can actually customize our volumes.
Because in this case, Docker is determining the mount location,
the folder, where the var/www is actually going to write to.
So let's look at how we could actually customize this.
So instead of actually having Docker set up the
folder that it writes to on the host,
we could come in and give it our own folder path.
And in this case, I'm just saying /source, but it could be a variety of paths.
And this could be in your source code, could be where you want your log files,
your database files, or whatever it may be.
So this gives us an option to work with,
for instance, source code in this example,
store that in a certain folder, maybe on your Mac or your Windows machine,
and then have the volume actually read and write to that specific area,
which in this case, would be our /source.
So what does the Docker client command like like to make this possible?
Well, again, if we start out with the following where we just run the node image,
we could change it to this type of pattern.
We could say ‑v, and that again creates a volume.
This $(pwd) basically says, hey,
go from the current working directory and use that as the host mount.
In other words, use that as the folder where I want to put my source code.
Now the actual container volume, though,
would be this /var/www, and then, of course,
we have the name of the image, in this case node.
So what this will do is create a volume in the container,
which is going to be var/www,
but when you write to that or when source code's read from that
as the Node container's actually running,
that's it's actually going to look in the host location,
which would be the current working directory.
So if you set up a /source folder and that was where
you ran the command prompt from,
then that would be your current working directory.
If you were in your user folder,
then that would be the current working directory.
Just depends on where you are.
Now, if you do an inspect on this, things change a little bit,
and so we'll run docker inspect on the name of your container,
and here's what we'll see in the Mounts area.
So again, we'll always have a name, which is a unique identifier,
but you'll notice now that the source on the host location is what we wanted,
in this case, /source.
Now, if you're on Mac or Windows,
Docker's smart enough to allow you to work with source code
directly on your Mac or your Windows machine,
have that talk through VirtualBox and up to the container,
and it kind of does some magic there to make all that happen.
So that's really nice for us as developers because now I can
work with my source code right on my Mac,
Windows,
or Linux machine but have my container be loaded up and then reading the
source code or writing to that area using this volume support.
Now the destination, or the volume in the container,
the destination as far as the container is concerned,
is now going to be var/www again, so that part doesn't really change.
But again, that's kind of like an alias,
is how I like to think of it,
and that's actually going to read and write up to this /source.
And again,
anytime you're working with this ‑v syntax as you run a
particular image and make a container,
whatever you write to that volume gets persisted.
So even if you delete the container, that's going to stick around,
and in this case, that's a good thing.
Obviously, if we delete a container, we don't want it to delete our source code.
So that's an example of how we can get started using the Docker
client with setting up a volume that could either automatically
generate a folder using Docker on the host or how we can control
it by using our own syntax.
So now that I've shown you the basics there,
let's look at some examples of how we can actually hook source code into different types of containers.