We've talked about the fundamentals of Kubernetes,
how to get it running locally on your machine,
as well as some of the key concepts such as deployments and services.
So now it's time to actually take a Docker Compose file and
either run it directly in Kubernetes or convert it into some of
the files Kubernetes normally works with.
So there's several options when it comes to migrating
from Docker Compose to Kubernetes.
One is just to use Docker Desktop directly.
It has an open‑source project built into it called Compose on Kubernetes,
and I'll show you this in just a moment,
a very easy way to get started.
Now there's another project called Kompose that you could also use.
This doesn't run directly in Docker Desktop.
It's a separate open‑source project,
but it will directly translate from a Docker Compose
file to the different deployment, service,
and other files that Kubernetes normally needs.
And this is a good way to go because, as mentioned in a previous section,
if you're working with a DevOps team and you're just trying to get Kubernetes
running locally just to make sure your app runs as expected,
but then you want to be able to hand them off some
of the work you've already done, if they work with Kubernetes,
they're probably going to want the different Kubernetes files.
So let's take a quick look at both of these and how
we would get started with them.
I'm going to start with Compose on Kubernetes.
So I've gone to the GitHub site that Docker maintains for this.
And as mentioned, this is actually part of Docker Desktop now.
So you have this already if you're running Docker Desktop.
Now if we scroll on down,
they'll give us an idea about what we're going to be doing,
and they call it deploying a stack.
When it comes to clustering and having multiple VMs or nodes out there,
Docker has their own solution called Docker Swarm.
Now they also directly support Kubernetes,
of course, as we've already seen,
but they have a docker stack command that's been in there for quite a
while now if you want to get a swarm or a cluster setup.
Now what they've done is made it so their normal docker stack
command can actually be used to deploy, but using a Docker Compose file.
It's actually very simple.
So, assuming you had a Compose file like you see here,
we can run a docker stack command.
We could deploy it using the Kubernetes orchestrator,
and then give the Compose file, which is docker‑compose.yml,
and then give the stack of name.
Now earlier I mentioned when you come into the Preferences
on Docker Desktop and go into Kubernetes,
there's this checkbox, Deploy Docker Stacks to Kubernetes by default.
Now, if you enable that, then when you run these docker stack commands,
you won't have to set the orchestrator.
It'll just automatically do that for you.
So that's an option if you'd like to go that route.
Now if you don't want to work with Docker Compose for Kubernetes
and instead just want to go 100% Kubernetes,
then we can go to the Kompose project.
Now Kompose actually translates and converts your Docker
Compose files into the deployments, and services,
and persistent volumes,
and other types of files that you can have to work with Kubernetes.
To get started is really easy.
You come on into the Installation, and you can see for Linux and Mac,
they have some curl commands, and for Windows they have some instructions.
You can download a binary, and then add it to your path.
Now I've already installed Kompose on my Mac and run these steps here,
so it's ready to go, and I'm going to show you how we can use it.
But let's go to the get started guide.
So if we scroll on down a little bit,
you're going to see a kompose convert command.
And what it will do is take that docker‑compose.yml file that you'd
have wherever you run this command and automatically generate the
different service and deployment files for each of the services that
are in your Docker Compose file.
So if you add four services,
then by default you're going to get four service Kubernetes
files and four deployment Kubernetes files.
And you can see that kind of here.
Now just like Docker Compose, there's even a kompose up you can run,
and that will allow you to actually run directly without really
having to worry about the different files.
I personally like to have the files because oftentimes
I need to tweak them a little bit.
But this gives you a good starting point with a convert command to do that.
So let me show you that real quick.
So if we come back into a project,
I've opened up the CodeWithDanDockerServices project that
you've seen several times up to this point.
And if I come on in and type kompose convert,
if I were to hit Enter,
that would take this Docker Compose file and convert it into
the deployment and service files I mentioned.
Now I've actually already done that for the project.
You're going to find a Kubernetes folder.
K8s is an abbreviation for that, by the way.
And then here's what it generated based on what it
found in this Docker Compose file.
So I had a mongo‑service.
It did all those deployments and services,
nginx, node, and redis because that's what we had in here.
Now in order to get this going, if you want to run it on your own,
there's a README me at the route of this project that'll help you out there.
But you do need to run this in production mode,
which means exporting or setting if you're on Windows,
the app environment to production, set in your DOCKER_ACCT,
removing a node volume, and you'll see that right down here in my node service.
And then after that, you'd be ready to go.
You can do a docker‑compose build to get your images.
Now we could come in and do our kompose convert,
or if you just want to have one file instead of many,
you could say ‑‑out, and I'll just say test.yml,
and I'll show you the output here.
So now if we go to the route, it just generated this file.
And you'll notice that we have a lot of different YAML code in here.
In fact, it's pretty large, actually, with everything that we want.
Now I normally like to work with the individual files,
as I mentioned,
so let's talk through these just really quickly and see what a
deployment and what a service actually looks like.
So if we go to the mongo‑deployment, if we come on in,
it'll say how many replicas we need.
Well, we just want one of these database items in this case, one container.
It's going to say some environment variables here,
some key value pairs, and if we come on down,
you'll notice image: danwahlin/mongo or whatever you called your image,
in this case.
Now, if I go into the mongo‑service, the important part is the ports down here.
Now as we talked about earlier,
a service provides an IP and abstracts the consumer from one
or more pods running behind that service.
In this case, there's just one.
It would be for mongo.
But this will define how to communicate to that pod through this port.
We have an external and internal port.
Now the same goes for nginx.. It has a deployment.
It also has the image.
It has a service that has our two ports in this case.
And if I go down to node and the redis, you'd see the same types of things.
The deployments define the image to run for the container,
and then the service defines the ports and can have other information.
Now that's a really quick look at what we can do because with services,
there's different types of services and ways you can use them.
But this will be enough to help us move from our
docker‑compose file here to actually Kubernetes files.
So now that those files are generated using the Compose open‑source tool,
let's take a look at how we can get Kubernetes going and get our containers in Kubernetes.