Now let's take a look at how we can work with
volumes in an ASP.NET Core container.
So I've already created an MVC project using the dotnet new command.
And I'll show you that real quick in case you're new to it.
But this is just and out‑of‑the‑box project.
It's an MVC project,
and what we're going to do is get this running inside of a container.
So the first thing I'm going to do is run off to the command line.
So let's come on back to the command with Open in Terminal.
And then inside of here, what I'd like to do first off is get a container going.
Now before I show you that, if you're new to .NET Core at all,
you'd have to go to dot.net, and then you can download the SDK it's called,
and I have that installed on this machine.
And then I could do this, dotnet new, and then we can give it the project type.
I did MVC.
That actually generated the project that you see right here.
What we're going to do, though, is we're going to get this code running,
but not locally.
We're going to get it running in a container running on my machine.
And it's going to be a Linux container.
So to do that,
the first thing we need is the actual image that we want to work with.
And in this case,
Microsoft publishes an image that we can actually use
to work with this type of thing.
So I'm going to go ahead and pull this image onto my machine.
I actually already have it, but I'll show you the command.
So we could say docker pull, and instead of going to Docker Hub,
we're going to go to the Microsoft Container Registry,
mcr.microsoft.com.
So that's the domain of the registry.
Now we're going to give it a path to what we want from an image standpoint,
and we want the dotnet/core/sdk image.
And if I hit Enter, this will now pull it down.
Now the first time it pulls, you'll get the different layers.
It will probably take you a minute or two to get
those depending on your bandwidth.
And we've already seen how it pulls layers and kind of shows you that output.
So now that we have the image, the next thing I want to do is I want to run this,
but I want to link it through a volume back to this source code here.
So what we're going to do is kind of an interesting
take on running the container,
link it back to this source code on the left here that's on my local machine.
But then I'm going to interact with the running container
right through this command prompt here.
And the way we're going to do that is with a ‑it command.
This is an interactive, and it stands for TTY,
kind of an older term, but, in essence, it's going to allow my terminal window,
my terminal shell, to link into the container.
And I'll show you that in just a moment.
Now the next thing I'm going to do is we're going to say the volume
that we want is to our current working directory,
print working directory (pwd).
Now the next thing I'm going to do is put the name of the folder.
I'm going to call it /app.
But I could call this anything.
It could be foo, foe, fum, whatever your folder is.
But we'll just do app in this case.
And then I'm going to make that the working directory,
the startup directory, so that when the container starts up,
it jumps right to the app folder.
Then we're going to say the name of the image,
and we, again, do dotnet/core/sdk.
But then I'm going to say, Hey,
I'm going to shell into a bash shell in this container.
Now one thing I want to point out really quick here
is what port should we run on?
Okay, we haven't defined that yet.
And also that pwd syntax.
So let's briefly talk about that really quickly before we move on.
So I kind of purposely left out the port because we do need that.
We can put it anywhere in here.
I'll put it right after this, let's say.
And what do we want to run this on?
Well, let's say externally that we're good with 8080,
but what's the internal port?
Well, it depends on your project actually.
We have a launchSettings.json file that they included by default,
and this will become the two ports that we look for.
Now we're not going to have a Development certificate, though, available.
We could do that but not in this particular demo.
So I'm going to take out the HTTPS one,
and then I don't necessarily just want localhost to work.
I want any IP address, so we're going to put a + right there.
Now there are many ways you can override the default port where your code
runs in the container or even on your local machine.
You could update this launchSettings, you could set environment variables,
or you could even go to the Program.cs,
and there's some syntax you could use there.
But this is kind of the easier way based on what they give us.
Okay, so now that we know that, we can do 5000 right there.
Okay, so that looks good.
Now what about this syntax right here though?
Well, this is only going to work on Mac or Linux.
Okay, so let me show you just real quick.
If you had PowerShell, then it would look like this.
And that'd be kind of PowerShell.
If you are on, let's say, just regular DOS, then you could do this, %cd.
So the syntax that you put right here really depends on what
command shell or command window you're using.
Because I'm on Mac in this demo, I'm going to put the Mac or Linux‑type syntax.
They're both the same in this case.
But be aware that you need to kind of look into that,
and you can see from the link down below here,
there's a blog post you can go to to learn more about that different syntax
across the different operating system command line prompts.
Okay, so now we've done that, we have docker run in interactive mode.
We know the external and internal ports.
We're going to have the volume link from a folder in the container called
app back to the code that is in our working directory.
That's our DEMOS.
You'll see right up top here.
The startup directory's app, that's our working directory.
We have our image,
and then we're going to fire up an interactive, kind of bash terminal modes.
So let's hit Enter. And there we go.
So now we are in the container actually,
and I can actually do things like ls, and you see how it
linked back to my local source code.
This code was never in Microsoft's image.
How would they know to obviously put this code? They wouldn't.
So, instead, that volume linked the app folder,
which is our working directory, back to this local source code.
So just think of it as you have a container kind of like in a bubble.
Somebody poked a hole in the bubble and put a hose in there,
and that hose kind of flows back to the directory on your machine.
Now we can kind of talk between the two.
So now I can do dotnet run, dotnet build. In fact, let's just do a build
real quick. Dotnet restore, all those type of commands.
There we do.
I could do dotnet run, or I can even do dotnet watch run.
Let's do a watch run if you're not familiar with that. That
will make it so if any files change over here,
it will automatically restart the server that's running in the container.
Super cool! So let's hit Enter.
All right, we'll let this fire up, and then we'll run off to the browser.
So notice it's listening on any IP 5000.
Okay, and then we just saw we did 8080 to 5000, so we're good there.
So let's go ahead and go to the browser.
Okay, so let me go from localhost to localhost 8080, and notice it works.
This is now running the server,
though, in the container even though our source code is local. Now here's
what's kind of cool about that. Let me go back to VS Code.
Let's go to our index, our home. Instead of just Welcome, let's say
Welcome to Docker Volumes or something like that. And let's save. Now
watch down below. See how File changed, Index.cshtml.
Now it's doing the rebuild, and it restarted the
Kestrel server in the container.
Pretty cool.
So let's go back to the browser. And there we go, Welcome to Docker Volumes.
Now, are you going to develop this way?
Probably not because, normally, if you already have the .NET tools local,
you'll just run dotnet run local.
But what this shows is how you literally could link this
container or any container to local code.
And if you didn't want to install something for whatever reason,
you literally wouldn't have to.
You could run the container that has your framework,
your server, whatever it is, and just have it link back just like we did here.
Now coming on back, let's clear.
We'll exit. Let's do docker ps ‑a, and there we go.
We have an exited container, you'll notice, f5b, so let's do docker
rm f5b. Now I could do this to remove volumes,
but because we created the volume, it wasn't a Docker kind of allocated volume.
We did it.
We said pwd, for example.
Then this ‑v won't have any effect because we created the volume, not Docker.
I'll talk about this a little bit later as well. But in this case,
I'll just do f5b.
There we go.
Let's run docker ps ‑a again, and it's gone.
And so imagine that I didn't actually create this code.
I checked it out from somewhere,
but I don't have the SDK installed on my machine.
I could just get this image going and literally do live
development against it without ever installing it.
Now, again,
that's not what I'd do in the real world because I already have
.NET and the tools installed on my machine.
But there are a lot of powerful techniques here that
you can use in various scenarios.
Keep in mind,
volumes could also be just to store log files the server writes out. There are all kinds of reasons you might use volumes.