In this module,
we learned about different options for getting Docker
running on different operating systems.
We started off by talking about a legacy version
that's available called Docker Toolbox,
and that would be one you might choose if you're on Windows
7 or 8 or even on Windows 10 Home Edition because that
won't have support for Hyper‑V.
Therefore, you're going to have to go with VirtualBox.
Now if you do have Windows 10 Pro or higher or you're on a Mac,
then it's highly recommended, you run Docker Desktop.
If you're on Linux,
you can install the Docker engine that I mentioned to paint on
the version of Linux that you're running.
Docker Desktop, as we saw though,
gives you not only direct integration with Docker,
but also a dashboard.
You can customize different preferences and settings.
So you can set, for instance,
the CPUs that are going to be used, memory, swap, size of the virtual machine,
all that type of information.
Not only is it very easy to get going,
but it also makes it very easy to interact with. And so
we'll be focusing on Docker Desktop a lot as we move
throughout the rest of the course.
We also took a look at Docker Kitematic,
and although I personally don't use it on real‑life projects,
it does provide a really,
really nice starting point if you're brand new to Docker.
Maybe you've seen nothing about it.
This is the first time you've learned about images and containers,
and you just want to get something going quickly and easily,
then you could use Docker Kitematic to do that.
And as you saw,
it provides a nice visual way to integrate with downloading the image
from Docker Hub and actually running the container,
seeing what ports are being used on that container, and more.
So now that we've talked about how to get Docker and the
various tools going on our systems,
let's go ahead and move on and dive a little bit deeper into more Docker features.