Although you can always build a custom image using the
docker build command anywhere you'd like,
you may want an easy way to deploy this and pull it down so you
don't have to build it every single time.
And we can do that by publishing an image up to Docker Hub.
And that's what we're going to take a look at here.
So the command you'll use is really,
really simple. Number one, you will have to go to
hub.docker.com and create an account,
and we talked about that earlier actually in the course. Very simple to
do, very quick. And then you'll have to run a logging command, and I'm
going to be showing that in just a moment.
But once you're logged in, it's very, very simple to push your image.
All you have to do is say docker push,
give it the username and the name of the image, in this case, node, and then
that's going to go ahead and push it up to the Docker Registry.
So let's take a look at how we can do that with the node image and
the ASP.NET Core image that we generated earlier.
Now,
before we can run a docker push, we will have to log in. So
we'll do docker login. Just hit Enter, and then you can put
your username and your password. And then it's going to ask for
the email you used as well.
All right, once it's done that, from here we can go ahead and try to push,
and you'll notice it's kind of saved some of our credential information locally.
So now I could come in, and let's do docker images again, and we'll do
docker push danwahlin/aspnetcore, and then this is actually going to
prepare the image and then push it up into Docker Hub.
I'll go ahead and let it do that,
and we're going to come on over as well to the Mac side,
and I have the node image that was created.
Now I've already logged in on this machine, so we can again do
docker push, my username, and the image tag,
and that will go ahead and prepare that.
And after a little bit of time after it's done pushing this up,
we'll be able to log into the site, and you can actually see
your image up there. Now, right now this is going to go ahead
and put it into a public repository, and I'll show you that as soon as it's done.
It looks like the image is now pushed up to Docker Hub.
So we'll go to hub.docker.com, and let me go ahead and log in here.
All right, and there we go.
So there's my node one that was pushed up, and there's the aspnetcore
you can see. So we could click on this, and there won't be much in here
because I don't have any descriptions yet,
but you could see how somebody could easily pull this and then use that image.
And we're going to do that in just a moment.
Now, likewise over here on this side, on the Mac side,
we've pushed up the Node.js image that was created, and
you'll see that's all ready to go.
So what I'm going to do is let's go ahead and try to run
this now directly from Docker Hub.
So we're going to say docker remove image, and we'll give it this f4 image here.
All right,
so that should be gone. Now we can say docker pull if we'd
like, or even docker run if we want to run it.
Well, we've already seen that, and now we could put the name of the image.
So let's go ahead on this machine and we'll grab the node one, and
this is going to pull down the latest version.
So you can see some of the layers already exist because they were cached.
So you can see how fast that was. Now, I could go in and clear
everything out or do kind of a no cache scenario,
but you can see that worked. Now, likewise on the same machine, if I wanted
to come in and do a docker pull on the aspnetcore one that was also shown in
this module, then we can grab that as well.
Now this one won't be cached,
so it's going to have to pull down everything because I've never
run this image on this particular machine.
All right, so that will take a moment to run.
And then we could, of course,
do the same thing over on my Windows box over here as well. It would
be the same exact command. We could do docker pull. And since I've
already done the aspnetcore one here,
let's go ahead and I'll show you how fast this should be. And it should be
pretty quick because a lot of the layers are already there.
You can see that was extremely quick.
Basically what it did is it looked at the IDs for each of those layers and said,
hey, I already have these.
There's really no need to recreate these because they
haven't changed. And that makes it really,
really fast as you work with multiple containers and
images. So it'll start caching those.
So you can see this one's still going; it's going to take a
little bit longer. And we're all done.
So now I can say docker images, and there we go.
We now have the node, the aspnetcore, and then the base node that I had.
So that's how easy it is to actually take an image once it's built, push
that up to Docker Hub, and now I can pull that from anywhere. Team members
can pull it. Even other people out there, since these are public images
right now, could pull it as well.
So it's a really, really powerful technology because now it makes it very,
very easy to share my exact environment, and we still have a
lot more to cover. So that will get us started with custom
Docker files, how we can do builds,
run containers, and even push images up to Docker Hub. But we're
going to start diving into more about linking containers and more as we move along in the course.