Throughout this module,
we've taken a look at how we can move from Docker Compose to Kubernetes and saw
how Kubernetes provides a robust solution for deployments,
scaling, and overall management of our containers.
By using some of the constructs built into Kubernetes,
we can provide a way to move to the desired state,
and we could do that using YAML or even JSON files to represent
that desired state and that's done through our deployment
services and other options available.
We also talked about how nodes and pods play a
really central role in Kubernetes.
Now nodes were the VMS,
whereas pods act as a way to group one or more containers together.
We looked at a container running in a pod and saw how we can
even do port forwarding to get to that,
at least while we're on our local machine for testing purposes.
And we looked at several different kubectl commands that could be used to
do things such as run a particular container in a pod,
apply different deployment services and other options available,
delete, and much more. So while Kubernetes is a very big topic and I would
highly encourage you to check out some of the other courses on it on
Pluralsight to get the full breadth of what it offers, I hope this modules
provided a nice starting point for you to get you started moving from Docker Compose to Kubernetes.