So let's review some basic symmetric encryption principles.
Let's say we have some data, and we want to make it
indecipherable to anyone else.
Well, we could lock that data up with an encryption key,
and in order to get that data,
you would then need to use the same key in order to decrypt it.
Now, in this visualization,
we'll just use the lock here to signify that something is encrypted.
Now, if we wanted to have some encrypted value inside of our code,
we could do this, but if we needed it decrypted for any reason,
maybe to show it to a user or to actually allow it
to be acted upon by some process, we would need to decrypt it.
So in this case,
we might need to actually use the key within our code to
decrypt the value and then to get access to it.
But this is kind of a bad practice because it might be a bad idea if we have an
attacker that wants to get at this data. Take this example.
Let's say we're trying to encrypt keys in basically the same way,
and we have our encryption key and the encryption, which we'll
use this lock to signify again, and we have a bunch of twitter
API keys, or maybe these are access keys to some other system
that we're trying to protect.
If we encrypt these keys with a green encryption key, and then we wanna have our
code written here and put these keys in sight of that code,
we'd also need to include the green encryption key to decrypt them.
Now, if an attacker comes along and they access our system somehow,
maybe the code is pushed into GitHub and inadvertently it gets made public,
which has happened many times in the past and is likely to
happen in the future, the attacker would then see the encrypted
value and the key and would basically know how to get the keys
back out from that value.
Then they could take those keys and gallivant through our
systems doing basically whatever they wanted with them. So
how do we avoid issues like this?
Well,
we'll be using Parameter Store and KMS. Specifically, we'll be taking
our keys and putting them into Parameter Store.
Now you're noticing here that I'm locking these up with the
red lock here, and that's because for all the keys that we're
adding inside of Parameter Store,
we'll also be locking them with a key that's managed
by the Key Management Service, KMS.
And I'll explain how that comes in in just a moment.
But let's say we have our Lambda code over here, and we want this Lambda
code to be able to get the decrypted values of those keys.
So we're going to give it an IAM role, and this IAM role will be checked
against the Identity and Access Management system.
When we make a request over to the Parameter Store,
it'll basically then allow us to do that if we have the correct permissions,
so we'll need to make sure we give it permissions to go and
fetch these keys from the Parameter Store.
Then the Lambda code can make that call,
and in the background, the Parameter Store will go and ask KMS,
the Key Management Service from AWS, to give us the decrypted value of
that green key because KMS is managing the red key,
which is locking it up.
So KMS goes and allows that value to be decrypted by Parameter
Store, and then that's returned to our Lambda code.
Now this will be returned while our Lambda code is actually running,
and the key itself isn't stored anywhere inside our Lambda code, so this helps
us avoid issues of having keys and source code or having them in unsecured
places that might end up being a liability later on.
We do still need to make sure our AWS account itself is secure
and that the permissions granted to access the Parameter Store
keys are heavily scoped down.
But this gives us a better way to manage all of our access keys and secrets, and that's why we're doing it inside of this demo.