In this video,
we'll look at a few different methods of storing our twitter API
keys inside of the Systems Manager Parameter Store.
First, we'll be using the AWS.
console.
I'll be navigating to the Systems Manager Parameter
Store by clicking on this icon here,
but you can also go to the Services drop‑down to search for it.
Now, underneath the Systems Manager, there's a lot of different services,
but we're going to be taking advantage only of one, the Parameter Store here,
underneath the Application Management.
Now, inside of the Parameter Store,
make sure that you're in the correct a region that you were using
before in earlier sections. Again, for this course,
I'm using Northern Virginia, or us‑east‑1.
But just make sure you're consistent throughout your using the demos in this
course so that you can get the parameters from the correct region when you're
running your code and working with your functions.
So when I'm in the correct region, I can go here and create a parameter,
and in this parameter, I'll need to start by giving it a name.
Now, for this first parameter,
we'll start by giving it a name of CONSUMER_KEY. This will be one of the
values that we got from Twitter in the previous video.
For Description,
I can just type out Twitter Consumer Key, and this will give
us all the details we need. And then below,
I'll need to pick between a tier for the Parameter
Store of Standard or Advanced.
I'm going to stick with the Standard tier right now because it won't cost
me anything to put parameters with the Standard tier.
But be sure to review the pricing documentation for parameters and
parameter tiers before you go through with adding these.
After you've selected the Standard tier,
you can then pick the type of parameter you'll be using.
We could use an unencrypted string,
but in this case, I want to use a secure string.
An alternative would be a string list where we'd have
multiple strings separated by commas.
But with this secure string,
I can use KMS to encrypt the values of this string
and make it a bit more secure.
I can also choose if I want to use the KMS key inside of my current account,
and by default, this will be a KMS key ID that is associated
with the Systems Manager Parameter Store.
You can see the ID for that key below with the alias/aws.ssm value down
there, or I could choose a key from another AWS account,
but they I'd have to provide some more configuration to do that.
So I'm going to stick with my current account and the key associated with SSM.
Now, if I had other KMS keys,
I could use those in this application, but I'm going to stick with the
free KMS key that's associated with this alias here.
Next, I'm going to need to enter in the value for this parameter.
Now,
I'm going to copy and paste the consumer key value from the
credentials that I copied down earlier, and then I'm going to
scroll down and create this parameter.
I could also add tags, but I'm not going to do that for right now.
So now we have this consumer key even though the UI is a little bit wonky
here, so I can close this out and see it a little better.
And this consumer key will be storing an encrypted value of
the consumer key that we got from Twitter.
Now, when our application runs,
it's going to make a call to the Parameter Store to get
back the decrypted version of that key.
So if you want to,
you could add all of the Twitter credentials in this way, or
you could wait a little bit longer and learn how to do it with boto3, the AWS SDK for Python.