With our dependencies installed, let's open up the Python interpreter.
I could enter into Python 3 from this virtual environment,
either by typing python or python3, and that's because we're referencing the
Python installation inside of venv whenever we activate it.
So now that I'm in the Python 3 interpreter, let's try testing stuff out here.
I'm going to copy the first few lines of this file, and let's paste them into
the interpreter. That'll get our dependencies all set up here.
Next, let's create the Twitter client.
If we wanted to make sure that our secrets were here, we could copy one
of these lines from get_secrets to make sure that process was working,
and we'll see that they're returned here.
So this should be working with our SSM Parameter Store, and I can
go back in here and hit Enter one more time,
and this should create our Twitter client.
If we wanted to test if this worked, we could always type this out again,
and you'll see this is the same consumer key that we were setting earlier.
So, great for us.
Let's scroll down a little further. Next, let's go ahead and copy the
potential tweets here to make sure that we'll be able to randomly select
one from this list and use it with the handler.
So I'm going to hit Enter there, and we've defined
this new potential_tweets variable, which,
if I paste it in there,
should contain three different strings that we could send out to Twitter.
So now I have this next function, send_tweet,
so let's copy that too. Let's paste that in there and hit Enter a few times.
So now that we've pasted that in, why don't we test this out?
Let's run send_tweet.
Let's do an open parenthesis, and let's say "Hello pet
owners!" because maybe this is what our first tweet will be
for our Globomantics Pet Care business.
Then I'm going to go back to my browser here and open up
the Globomantics Pet Care home page.
Now, I've had a chance to spruce up our profile with a few
pictures just by using the Twitter UI, but I haven't tweeted
anything out yet, as you can see.
So let's refresh the page and see if that action worked from earlier.
Once the page is refreshed,
you should notice that we have a new tweet here. It says Hello pet owners! So
that means that just a few seconds ago, when we ran this,
it worked properly to send out this tweet.
Nice work.
Next, let's see how we could use it to send a random tweet out.
So I'm going to copy this handler here, and let's paste it in
here. Now, because we're not actually using the event or the
context inside of our handler function, and they don't appear in
our code in there at all,
other than in the definition which is required when we're working with Lambda,
I could actually just go type in here,
event = and then put an empty string, context = and then put
another empty string, and this will allow us to call our handler
with some empty values, because they don't matter, and test out
the functionality of send_ tweet.
So let's do that.
Let's go ahead and do handler, open, and let's pass it in an event and
context that we just defined there, and let's hit Enter.
So now that we ran that, we should see a random value from the
potential_tweets that we defined earlier.
So let's go back up to those, and let's scroll back over here and refresh the
page one more time to see if we see a new random tweet.
Now it looks like we did successfully use this to send out a random tweet.
So let's go back to our code and see what else we could do with this bot.
So now that we've tested it, this should all be good to
go to package up and send out to Lambda and configure it
to run on an event schedule.
But if we wanted to play around with more of the functionality of the Twitter
client we created from Twython, I've also included some code that you could
use below the handler and include in your bot.
Now, some of these examples use the
create_friendship method of the Twitter client,
which is used to follow a person on Twitter if you're familiar
with that convention more, essentially to see what their statuses
are and get more information from them.
Now if we scroll down a little further,
I've also included the create_favorite method here,
which allows you to like a Twitter status using the tweet ID of the
tweet, which essentially is a long number that appears whenever
you're loading the status inside of Twitter.
Let's go ahead and copy all of these different functions
here and paste them into our interpreter.
Now, if I wanted to try using any of these,
I could scroll back up and just see how we define them up here.
So let's try using the follow_someone function.
I'm going to copy the title of that right there, and it looks like
we just use this screen name to follow someone.
So let's go ahead and do follow_someone, open
parenthesis, and we'll pass in a string.
And I'm going to try and follow myself using this command. So I'm
going to do fmc_sea, which is my twitter handle, and then I'm going
to close out this function and hit Enter.
Now let's go back over to our Globomantics Pet Care here,
and you can see that we're not following anyone right now,
and we have no followers.
But if I refresh the page,
we should now see that there's one person that we're following.
And If I go over here and click on it, looks like
it's me with my Twitter handle.
So feel free to play around with the other examples that I've included here.
And if you'd like to learn more about Twython and using the
Twitter client that you just created,
go ahead and look for the Twython documentation,
which will have a lot of other opportunities for you to use it.
Now, keep in mind that when you created your Twitter API credentials,
you got a limited set of use related to them.
Now,
probably there's going to be some methods that you're not going to be
allowed to use by Twitter, simply because they haven't approved your
API keys to do those different methods.
Those might involve getting data from Twitter that they want to make
sure is restricted to respect people's privacy.
So nice work, and in the next video, we'll learn how to put all of this into AWS Lambda inside of a function package.