Welcome to this module of my AWS Developer course, An
Introduction to AWS Lambda. In this module, we'll be taking a
closer look at Modern Serverless Development.
Now to start, we'll look at serverless development,
including manual development versus frameworks and how
those two different options differ.
We'll look at a few different frameworks that we could use,
and we'll spend some time focusing on the Serverless Framework,
including a limited overview, as well as the
installation process for the framework.
We'll use it to create an HTTP API, and this will take care of
deploying the infrastructure behind our Lambda function, and it'll
also help us write and update our function code as we go along
without having to do a ton of manual work.
So let's look at the serverless development process,
starting with a comparison between manual development and
frameworks. With manual development, we have various disparate deployment steps,
and different processes might develop for different teams or projects.
This leads to some siloed knowledge and experience, and can
also develop into a patchwork of homegrown tooling for our
organizations. With frameworks, however,
we get standardized,
simplified builds that are familiar in structure for different projects or
services. We'll also be able to benefit from larger open source
communities who are using the same tools that we are,
so we can all contribute to bringing those tools along together.
These communities will also lend themselves to common debugging
tools and use cases and help looking at those use cases when we
have issues with them. Now,
when we're thinking about Lambda function deployment in the
rest of this course that we've done so far,
we've had to gather up our code and dependencies,
zip code and dependencies together, and then we had to upload that
zip file from S3 or from our machine to Lambda, and then create,
update, or remove the function later on,
depending on what we want to do. Now that might also require us to
configure event triggers or to have those event triggers be changed if
we need them to be changed. Now on top of that,
there's a bunch of other Lambda settings,
not all of which we even got to. Now, imagine having
to do this over and over again,
and we haven't even managed to introduce other resources and their
deployment processes yet. If we wanted to add DynamoDB tables or API
Gateway resources, or any SQS queues.
This whole process would start to get a little bit overwhelming.
Now,
I want to point out here that manually developing everything like this is
hard, and frameworks can really help us with this process.
Let's take a look at an example using the Serverless
Framework's serverless.yml files. Now this Serverless
Framework example contains a few different parts,
including a function configuration, which will allow us to define,
in this case, a function called createUser.
Now,
this function is going to also have events that it's going to use.
In this case, this http event will be all we need to add in here
to get an HTTP endpoint created by API Gateway using this
Serverless Framework. From here,
we can also specify other things like other functions,
and each of those functions can have their own different events.
In this particular configuration,
you'll see that we have an event for our createUser that is
a path of /user and a method of post,
whereas our getUser is the same path with a method of get.
We're also configuring cross origin resource sharing here.
Now, there's a lot going on here, and a lot going on in the background,
and I won't explain everything in this course,
but I want to give you a feel of some of the easier methods
of serverless application development.
Here's one other example of what our application structure might look like.
We might have, for example,
some serverless function code in a back‑end directory,
and we might also have maybe some front‑end application that's going to
leverage API endpoints that we're creating with the back‑end code.
Then, we could also have the serverless.yml configuration inside of that folder,
similar to the one that you just saw earlier.
Now this sort of structure would be pretty typical
for a Serverless Framework project, and it looks pretty straightforward,
so you can start to see why these sorts of frameworks might end up being useful
for us to get some standardization in what we're building.
So let's take a look at a few different frameworks
that we might want to rely on.
Some frameworks come directly from AWS, like AWS Amplify,
and others are developed independently, like Sparta,
specifically for the Go language.
There's also Zappa,
which has been developed specifically for Python, and the Serverless Framework,
which is the one we'll be working with in this course.
So why would we use the Serverless Framework over some other possible
frameworks for serverless application development?
Well, for starters,
if you compare the number of watchers from some of the other frameworks, as
well some of the stars and forks and other values from GitHub,
you'll see that the Serverless Framework by far is the highest
number of all of these different metrics,
just a general indicator of its popularity among the community.
Now this means that you're going to get the best of everything
that comes from community, from community plugins to community
conversation, and help trying to solve the same problems that
others have faced in the past.
Now these numbers are from November of 2019, so always go back onto GitHub
and look for serverless frameworks and compare how they line up in terms
of the numbers of people engaging with them. In the next videos, we'll take a closer look at the Serverless Framework.