Now that you have all the context you need,
let's deploy our first Lambda function. In this demo,
we'll deploy a Lambda canary function,
which regularly checks the availability status of our
imaginary client, Globomantics Pet Care.
We'll start by using AWS' Lambda canary function blueprint.
Then we'll configure a CloudWatch schedule in order to
trigger our function on a regular basis.
After that,
we'll review the function code that AWS provides for the
Lambda canary and make some adjustments to the Lambda
function's configuration settings.
Then we'll configure a default test event to make sure our function is
working properly. And then finally, we'll review our function's results
inside of Amazon CloudWatch and also make sure that we have an alarm set up
to be notified if there are any errors.
So let's go back over to the AWS console and get started. From the AWS
Management Console home page, let's go to the Lambda section of the
console by clicking on our Lambda icon here.
Then let's create a Lambda function.
If you see a get started page before you get onto that create a function page,
just go ahead and click get started and then create your function.
Instead of authoring a function from scratch,
we're going to be using a blueprint for this function,
and we're going to need to search through the existing
blueprints for a canary function.
Now,
once I type in canary and hit Enter there, we should see
this python3.7 lambda‑canary function in the available
selection from the drop‑down.
Once we're done with that,
we can click Configure, after selecting it, and start the process
of configuring this function and creating it.
I'm going to call this function lamda‑canary.
I'm also going to leave the default,
Create a new role with basic Lambda permissions,
selected underneath the Execution role.
This will, by default,
allow my function to send logs to Amazon CloudWatch. After I put the function
name in and leave the Execution role as, Create a new role with basic Lambda
permissions, I can scroll down and choose how I'd like to configure this
function. Because this is a Lambda blueprint, it already knows we're working
with a CloudWatch Events trigger, and we can go ahead and click the drop‑down
here to pick between a CloudWatch Event rule that might already exist, in this
case we don't have any, or we can click to create a new rule. So we'll do that
now.
Let's call the rule name for this particular function our
canary, and let's give it a description of the frequency with
which we'd like this rule to run.
In this case,
we're going to do it every 5 minutes, so let's say a five minute rule. And then
below we'll be able to specify how we want this rule type to work. We can either
choose a schedule expression or an event pattern.
Now,
a schedule expression would be something like the rate of one day or a
cron expression that would allow us to specify when,
specifically with a cron‑style event, we'd like this to trigger.
Now, I'm going to use the rate of 5 minutes,
and this will allow us to run every 5 minutes.
If I wanted to do something like an event pattern,
I could also click that. This would allow me to trigger my function
based off of things happening in Auto Scaling groups, EC2 instances, or
other services inside of AWS. But because I just want to trigger this
every 5 minutes, I'll stick to that schedule expression and just keep my
rate of 5 minutes there.
Now,
I don't want to enable this trigger quite yet because I don't want to have
my function start running until I'm done configuring it.
So I'm going to leave this as unselected and then scroll
down to the Lambda function code here.
Now,
we can actually review this inside of our Lambda console here and edit it and
make any changes we need to before we create the function.
But I'm not going to do this right now,
so I'm going to keep scrolling down and review the Environment variables
section. In this section with the environment variables,
we're going to be able to change what website our function is going to,
by default, be pinging to check if it's still up and what the expected
text on that website is. In this case,
it's been prepopulated as amazon.com. And if I go to amazon.com,
it's expecting us to see the text Online Shopping on that page.
So let's not change anything here either, and for right now,
let's just click Create Function.
We'll change the rest of these configuration values in just a moment.
This might take a few moments, as it's also creating the role and permissions required for this Lambda function to work.