Let's take a look at how we can install the Serverless Framework using
Node.j and npm or by using these serverless binary installer.
After that, let's take a look at how we can configure it,
either using the AWS CLI and access keys or by using the
AWS IAM role in the Serverless Dashboard.
After that, we'll take a look at how we could bootstrap a service from scratch.
So let's go ahead and get started.
Now, I've loaded up the serverless.com website, and on this page,
I'm going to go over to the Docs section here.
In here, I can go to the get started section to get the installation
instructions that I need to get up and running.
Now, the first option here is to install as a standalone binary,
and I'm going to go ahead and copy the values that we have inside of this code
sample here to do this on my local machine. Now, you could choose to do this on
macOS or Linux, or if you're on a different system,
you could scroll further down and learn how to do this on Windows.
There's also the option to do this with npm,
but then you'd have to install Node and npm on your local machine,
and I don't want to make you do that at the moment.
If you'd like to learn more about that process and how to get set
up using JavaScript on the Serverless Framework,
you could take a look at my Serverless Framework course here on
Pluralsight. So now that I've copied this curl command here,
I'm going to go to VS Code. And in VS Code, let's paste in
this curl command here and hit Enter.
Now,
this will go through the process of downloading the serverless
binary and installing it on our local machine.
Once this process is finished, we should be able to use the Serverless Framework.
So now that this has been installed,
we're going to need to open a new terminal and then run Serverless.
Immediately we're not going to be able to run Serverless because our terminal
will need to source the recently installed information.
So I'm going to type in exit here, this will exit out this current
terminal, and then I'll open a new terminal in VS Code.
I'll open this up with Ctrl + ~, and then I'll use the serverless
command to start bootstrapping a serverless service.
This will take me through a workflow of several questions in order to get my
first serverless service or serverless project set up.
Now,
I don't have a project on my desktop right now because I don't have
anything there, so I'm going to answer a Y for Yes, and this'll take me
through the process of creating this project.
I'm going to specify a Python project instead of Node, and let's call
this project our gpc, for Globomantics Pet Care,
‑api, for our application programming interface.
So now that I clicked Enter on that, it's created this new folder for me
inside of my desktop. And this has a few different files.
It has a gitignore file to help me work with it if I'm
using Git and a handler.py file for my first Lambda handler
using the Serverless Framework,
and it also has the serverless.yml file with the needed
configuration to start working with the Serverless Framework. So
let's go ahead and decide if we want to enable monitoring and
troubleshooting with the Serverless Dashboard.
Now I could create a serverless account,
so let's say Yes for right now. And I'm not logged into an account right
now, and on my system I don't have one created, so I can decide if I wanted
to register a new account or log into an old one.
In this case, I'll hit register.
And let's use my pluralsight.fernando email address @gmail.com,
and let's register with that and a password.
Now I'm going to paste my password in here,
but the input is hidden, so you won't be able to see it, and then I'm
going to hit Enter. Nowt this should take me through the process of
registering that account, and if I wanted to,
I could go log into that account.
So let's try this now.
In order to do this, I've navigated to dashboard.serverless.com,
and this will redirect me to a page to sign into my account. Now,
because I just signed up for my account with the pluralsight.fernando
email, we'll need to enter this again in here,
and then I'll need to use the password I entered during the
signup process. Now, you'll need to make sure to save these
values down so you can access your account.
So, I'm going to log into this account and see what's in there.
Let's close out of that so I don't remember my password in Chrome, and now
you'll see that I have this Globomantics Pet Care API app created inside of
here. Now, we'll be able to add functions and other stuff into that in
something called a service. So we could go through the process of adding
services inside of this dashboard here, but I want to show you how to do
this from the CLI.
So let's go back to the VS Code editor and keep going.
Now,
I'm going to clear the screen here, and in order to deploy this gpc‑api service,
we can change directories into the GPC API, and you'll see
in this directory we have the serverless.yml file. In
order to deploy this service, we can run serverless deploy,
and this should send our code out to AWS.
And this should start the process of creating a function package,
then bundle in all the dependencies that we might need, and deploy
everything to AWS. Now, in the background, this will be relying on
something called CloudFormation.
Now, AWS CloudFormation is a service that helps us
manage infrastructure as code.
However,
it's syntax can be a bit overwhelming, so let's compare
what it's syntax looks like to the serverless.yml file.
Now, CloudFormation, in this case,
if we take a closer look at it, is going to be about 256
lines of code for our entire service.
Now,
this can be a bit overwhelming, and that's part of the reason that I rely
on Framework sometimes to develop my serverless applications. Inside of
the serverless.yml file here, there's a lot of stuff that's commented
out. Now, all these comments are really achieving nothing here. They're
just to give you a guide on how you could use this serverless.yml file.
So for right now,
I'm going to remove them, and let's take a look at how many lines of code
we're actually using inside of this serverless.yml file. Looks like so far
we're at seven, and these first few lines of code are configuring our service
to interact with the Serverless Dashboard.
That way, when we deploy this service and when anything happens to it,
the dashboard can monitor it for us. Then the provider section here is
specifying the AWS cloud is where we want to deploy our code and the runtime of
Python 3.8 as which runtime we'd like to use with that.
Now we can scroll down through the rest of these comments and delete them
as well, and then we get to the functions section here.
Now the functions are referring to a single function that we're naming
hello in serverless.yml, and the handler for that function is in the
handler.py file, and if we look in there,
we should see a function called hello.
So it's a very similar configuration to what we were doing earlier
inside of the AWS CLI and the AWS Console. It's just all
standardized in this same serverless.yml file. And if I scroll down
through the rest of these comments too and get to the very bottom,
you'll see that overall, this configuration is about 11 lines.
When you compare that to the 256 lines of CloudFormation,
you'll understand why we're using frameworks. Now, in the next videos,
we'll see how we can extend this into a more complicated service that
leverages things like DynamoDB and the AWS API Gateway service.
So let's see what the results were from our deployment.
I'm going to open up that terminal again, and you'll see that it went
through the entire process of creating our service,
packaging everything up, and setting up our dependencies inside
of a ZIP file that it uploaded to S3 for us.
And if we wanted to find it,
we could actually go back down here and run aws s3 at ls and
see what buckets are created in our account.
You'll see that we have this new
gpc‑api‑dev‑serverlessdeploymentbucket here with some gibberish on
the end.
And that's where our gpc‑api.zip file was deployed to and
then used to create the Lambda function.
We also have this new function called hello,
which is the gpc‑api‑dev‑hello function. Now,
if we wanted to,
we could find all of these resources that we created over in
the AWS Console, but we could also go to the Serverless
Dashboard to review what just happened.
Back in the Serverless Dashboard, we have a deployment
that happened just a few minutes ago.
And if I click into here, we'll be able to see this new service
appearing. Later on, when we have stuff that's actually happening with
our service, we'll be able to see alerts, API requests, and function
invocations, and explore through some of the details of our service and
be able to monitor it more effectively.
But for right now,
we've created and deployed our first service using the
serverless bootstrapping process. In the next videos, we'll continue to iterate on it.