In this demo, we'll be looking at AWS IAM. I'll take you through the
process of examining what AWS managed policies are and how we can use
the AWS Policy Generator to create our own custom AWS policies. I'll
also show you how we would create IAM roles inside of AWS Identity and
Access Management.
So let's go ahead and get started.
I've loaded up the AWS console here,
and I'm going to change the pinned icons that we had
before from Icons and Text to Icons Only.
This should make it a little easier to see which icons we're working
with and navigate to the appropriate services. Now, I'm going to click
on the Services drop‑down a few times, and this will get rid of our icon view.
Now I'm going to go to the AWS Identity and Access Management console,
which is located by clicking on the key.
From there, I'm going to be able to look at AWS managed policies.
I'll go over to the Policies section on the left and then click Create policy.
Now,
here I could create my own custom policies by picking a service, the
actions, and the resources that I want inside of the policy, as well as any
conditions that we might want to apply to the policy.
Now, instead of doing this, I could also use an AWS managed policy.
So, rather than creating my own custom policy,
I could choose one that AWS has already created and provided for me.
So I'm going to go back and take a look at those.
You'll see that here in this Policies section that I clicked
before, I automatically have a variety of different policies
already that AWS has created and managed for me.
And if I wanted to search for any particular policies that
apply to services we'll be using later,
like SES, I could find different managed policies to help me use
those services. Fortunately for us, we'll be using mostly managed
AWS policies for all of our interactions with AWS Lambda, until the
last section of the course.
So we don't have to create any custom policies here right now,
but I do want to give you the ability to do that on your own later on.
So if you needed to,
you could click this Create policy button and go through that workflow; however,
you could also use something called the AWS Policy Generator.
Let's take a look at this now.
You could go to the AWS Policy Generator by googling for AWS
Policy Generator, or going to
awspolicygen.s3.amazonaws.com/policygen.html. Now, this website
makes it a little easier to create your own custom policies,
depending on what you want to do with them.
The website has a bunch of different kinds of
policies that are used inside of AWS,
including IAM policies, S3 bucket policies, SNS
topic policies, and a few others.
In our case,
we're going to select a type of policy from the drop‑down and specify
IAM Policy because that's the majority of what we'll be doing when
we're working with policies in general. Now,
after we select the policy type that we're working with, the Policy Generator
will give us a few options down below in the Statements section. We'll be able
to specify allow or deny, and this will end up being that portion that I showed
you earlier inside of the JSON statement that either allows an action or denies
an action on some resource.
Then, we're going to have to say what services we want
to be applied to this statement.
I could say all services and just have this be the star for the service
that we're working with, or I could uncheck the box and pick a particular
service like Amazon's Simple Email Service, SES.
From there, I could specify particular actions associated with the service.
So if I go to the Actions drop‑down for SES,
there's a variety of different actions that I might end up using,
things like sending emails and creating things inside of SES that are
resources we might use. Now in this case,
we'd be using things like SendEmail and SendRawEmail,
and we could select those actions and close out of that Actions window.
However, because we're going to use AWS managed policies for the time being,
we won't need to use this statement and the policy that it will be
inside of right now. You can go back to this, and as you're
creating new services use this to generate the specific permissions
that those services might need.
Now the last part of creating a statement for our policy
would be to specify the Amazon resource name that the
action would be applicable to.
So what can we actually do with these actions, and what can we act upon? Now,
in the case of SES, we won't be acting on any particular AWS resource names.
For example,
we won't be doing the SendEmail action on an S3 bucket, instead we'll
be just taking that action. So we can specify the star here in this
case to say that any resource name is fine.
Now,
this might be overbroad or overpermissive when you're doing it with
other services, so keep in mind to use the star very sparingly as you're
going through and creating your statements.
Now, when we're ready to add this as a statement in our policy,
we can scroll down and click Add Statement,
and this will automatically add that to our entire policy.
If we had additional actions and resources we wanted to grant permissions
on, we could go back up and continue that process again and again until we
were happy with the content of our policy.
But once we're done, we can click Generate Policy,
and we get the policy that we could actually paste in inside of
the AWS console or attach to the command line to whatever
resource we wanted it applicable to.
Now, if we wanted to create our own custom role,
we could then copy this policy here,
and then we could take it over to the IAM management console again,
click on the Roles section here, create a new role for ourselves,
and then we'd have to specify who can assume this role.
Would it be an AWS service like EC2 or Lambda, or maybe another AWS
account that we want to give access to our AWS account?
Potentially, we could also grant permissions to a web identity,
like through the Amazon Cognito Service or an OpenID identity provider.
And this could allow us to grant access to mobile application users.
Finally,
we might grant permissions to an actual user through an alternative
directory than IAM, like through SAML 2.0 federation.
Now in this case,
if you wanted to add additional roles that your Lambda functions could use,
you would stick with that AWS service option here, and then specify a Lambda.
Then we'd attach the permissions to this role that we wanted to.
We could either include the managed policies from AWS that you
see here, or we can create a new policy from what we just
generated in the AWS Policy Generator.
Now we could go through the visual selection here,
but because we just created the JSON,
I can click on the JSON window here and then I can override everything
here and paste in this statement that we created.
Now I'm going to review this policy, and let's just call this our
testpolicy here, and once we're done naming this,
we could give it a description too. I'm going to also
name it testpolicy, and you'll see a summary of what
we're actually allowed to do here,
which is to send email through the Simple Email
Service or through Pinpoint email,
which is another AWS service. Now, once we're confirmed with all of this
being correct, we can go down and click Create policy,
and then this policy will be created in IAM,
and we could use it inside of our role.
So if I go back to that earlier window where we were creating this role,
we could look up testpolicy here,
and if we don't see it in the drop‑down we'll need to refresh
this list, and then we could be able to pick it out from our
newly created policy that we just added.
Then I can click Next: Tags, Next: Review,
and we would be able to create a new role that would then be
assignable to a Lambda function So we could call this testrole, and we
would see this later on in the AWS Lambda console window to be able to
attach this to that Lambda function.
Now I'm going to create the role,
and you'll see it under the full list of roles created under our account.
So, this is the entire process of creating custom roles that we
might then attach to our Lambda functions.
Later on,
I'll show you how we could take this entire process in a
more automated fashion, but for right now,
don't worry too much about this process as we'll be creating roles
with managed policies that are created by AWS for us.
So now that we're done with this demo, let's take a look at the module.
What have we done inside of this module?
Well, we've looked at what we could build with the AWS Free Tier,
and we have a better understanding of what's included within the Free
Tier and how to find out more of those details in case we're deciding
to build other applications later on.
We also have a better understanding of some of the AWS services that we'll
be using inside of the demos later in this course. And, we created our own
AWS IAM policy that we then attached to a role.
Now we should be able to do this in the future if we have custom needs for
the Lambda functions in the projects that we're creating,
So what's next for us?
So now that we have all this foundational knowledge, we'll be
able to take our first steps with our first AWS Lambda project. Let's get to it in the next module.