So now I've gone ahead and added a few things here.
I've updated the handler file so that it contains the
code from the demos for this section.
It's got a bit more information in here, and now it's using a
few different libraries that I've also added.
I have added the notify.py library,
which inside of it should allow us to use the SES client and
verified emails that we verified in earlier sections to send an
email to an admin. In this case,
one of the email addresses that we've already notified, letting them know that a
client with the email of email has been added to DynamoDB.
Then it'll send that message out with the ses.send_email method.
Additionally,
we have this users library. Inside of this users library, we're creating
a boto3 resource to interact with the DynamoDB table.
This will allow us to, in the create_user function down below,
send an item into DynamoDB with the email of an email that we're passing into
it and some data associated with a new client email. From there, we'll be
returning a status code result. If the request succeeds, we'll return 200 for
the status code, and if the request fails,
we'll return a status code of 400 and also say that the request is
invalid with the status right there. From here,
we're going to go ahead and go back to the handler function and see how
we're using these inside of it. We're importing the users create_user
function and the notify_admin_of_new_client function.
And inside of our handler, we're going to be taking the event that's coming in,
printing it out just so we can see this in the logs, and
then creating a payload from what should be inside of the
event, inside of the body.
Now inside of this body,
we're going to expect to see an email that we can set as the client email and a
data section, which will contain the data related to this user. From there,
we'll run the create_user function from inside of that users.py file with the
client email that we're expecting from this incoming payload and the data
associated with that. That will either return a status code of 200, if we're
successful, or a 400 status.
So in the case that it returns a successful status code of 200,
we'll send an email to the admin in order to let them know that
there's a new client with that client email.
And if it doesn't have that status code,
it'll end up sending a 400 response back to the client.
But if it does,
it'll keep that 200 response and send it along through the return response here.
So let's go ahead and deploy this using serverless deploy. Now once we do this,
we'll have all of this updated code out inside of our AWS environment,
and we can review any tests of this API using the Serverless Dashboard.
So we're also going to test this API using something called Postman.
So once this is finished deploying,
we should be able to scroll up and make sure we have this POST endpoint here so
we can paste it into Postman and test this new endpoint out.
So let's go back over to Postman here,
and I've already created a request for us here.
So I'm going to paste this into Postman just to make
sure the API endpoint is the same.
And then I'm going to configure the request that we're sending out.
So in this case, I'm sticking with a POST here,
and not using another HTTP method, and I'm also creating a body inside of here,
which I am setting as raw JSON that I've used inside of this JSON selector here,
and I've pasted in some information inside of the JSON.
That's what our API expects to get in this format.
So once I do this, I should be able to hit Send,
and we should see the results below.
So let's scroll down now.
It looks like there's an internal server error with something that's
happening here. Now in order to debug this more fully,
we could go over to the Serverless Dashboard. Over here on the
Serverless Dashboard, I could go into the app we created earlier and
into the dev stage here, and let's go to the explorer. Now, I've been
testing this out a little bit previously,
so you might see some errors that are unrelated here
to what we've just been doing.
But a few seconds ago,
we just ran this function. So let's take a look at the most recent failure here.
And it looks like this has to do with the SendEmail operation
when we were trying to notify an admin.
So let's go back to our permissions and see why this might be the case. If
we look at the provider section inside of serverless.yml,
we currently have one IAM role statement,
and it's giving us the actions of dynamodb:PutItem and SES:*, but it's
only allowing us to do that on the DynamoDB table,
and we're not trying to email the DynamoDB table, we're trying to email a
separate email. So this means that we had an error here that we actually need
to resolve by updating our permissions and redeploying.
So let me fix those really quick and show you what they look like.
So I've gone ahead and updated the iamRoleStatements here, and
now you can see we have two different statements, the effect of
allow for the dynamodb:PutItem over to that resource of the users
table, and a new statement,
which is allowing the SES:* action, so allowing us to send emails
or send raw emails or send HTML emails, basically any of those
actions on any resource this time.
So with this update,
we should be able to run serverless deploy one more time and then update
the permissions on our service to avoid this error.
Once this finishes, let's go back to Postman.
Now that our service is finished deploying,
let's go over to Postman. In Postman, let's try and test this one
more time. I'm going to hit Send to send it out again, and let's
scroll down and see what happens.
It looks like now we get back the results of our request,
which is what we'd expect if this worked correctly.
So let's go over to my Yahoo email and see if I got a notification about this.
Over here in my Yahoo email,
it looks like a new client has been added, so let's open
up this email. And inside this email,
it's showing us that a new client has been added with the
values that we just sent into that API.
So this means that our service is up and running correctly,
and we've managed to do a lot of different things with it.
So let's go back and review what we've done in this module. In this
module, we managed to create our own serverless service and integrate
it with the Serverless Dashboard using the app and org values that we
had in severless.yml. We also configured the service with several
different IAM role statements to give it permissions to act on
DynamoDB and on SES.
And, we created a new function that had an http endpoint that allowed us
to trigger it using something like Postman, cURL, or to integrate this
URL into our front‑end web applications.
We also created a DynamoDB table using the resources section of
serverless.yml. This DynamoDB table allowed us to store our user's
emails, and then after we added the users in that table, and then
after we added users to that table,
we used the notify_admin_of_new_client function in notify.py to let
ourselves know when that user has been added.
So there's a lot of different things that we did in this section,
and nice work getting it all done. Let's review what we did inside of this course.