So now let's connect the Lambda function we created with the CloudWatch events
that we created. We'll start by using aws events list‑rules.
Now,
this should list out all the ARNs of all the events
that we've created in the past.
And if you didn't get a chance to copy down the ARN of the pickup and the
daily_tasks and the come_to_work ARNs, you could do this now. Now, I'm going
to clear the screen because I already copied those down, and instead, I'm
going to set up the Lambda function we just created to trust events that come
from the CloudWatch Events system.
So I'll do this with aws lambda add‑permission, and then I'll do a
backslash here, and we'll type in the function‑name for the thing
that needs to get the permission.
In this case,
it's gpc_cuckoo. And I'll do another backslash, and we'll do a
statement‑id here. And I just need to give a unique statement‑id so
that as we add permissions to this Lambda function to expect to get
events from different CloudWatch events,
they have unique IDs so there's no conflicts in this.
So I'll just make sure to give this a statement‑id of 1 since
it's the first one we're configuring here.
Then I'll do another backslash, and we'll add in an action here that
we're going to expect to happen on this Lambda function.
And I'll need to do lambda:, in this exact capitalization,
InvokeFunction. Now, in that string there, I do a backslash, and what
this is saying is that we're going to expect Lambda to be invoked by
the next thing that we're entering in, which is going to be a principal.
Now, this principal will be the events system of AWS. So
this is the CloudWatch Events system,
and we'll have to put in this domain here of amazonaws.com
with the events subdomain, and that'll tell Lambda to
expect events from that principal.
Now we're also going to need to specify a source‑arn,
and this is going to be the ARN of the events that we
just created just a moment ago.
So if you haven't copied down those ARNs from earlier, go ahead and rerun the
aws events list‑rules command and then get back to this step.
So since I already copied this,
so I'm going to paste it in here, and then I can hit Enter to add
this permission to our Lambda function. Now, I'm also going to need
to add a few other permissions, so let's clear the screen here, and
let's run this command again,
except we'll need to change the statement‑id from 1 to 2,
and we're also going to need to change the source‑arn from
the source ARN related to our come_to_work event to the
source ARN for our daily_tasks event.
Now let's run this again.
Clear the screen one more time, and let's run this now with our third
statement, so let's change the statement‑id to 3. And finally,
let's change the daily_tasks to the pickup event.
Let's hit Enter one more time here. And now that we've
added all these permissions to allow CloudWatch events to
trigger the Lambda function,
we can go in here and set the CloudWatch event targets
to target the Lambda function itself.
For this, we'll be using a new command.
So let's clear the screen, and let's run aws events
put‑targets. Now, this is going to allow our CloudWatch rules
to have a target of the Lambda function,
so we need to specify the rule name, so we'll say daily_tasks for
the first one here. And I'll do another backslash,
and we'll specify the targets that we want this event to
trigger. For this target, we'll need to pass it in as
string, but inside of the string,
we're going to need to give it a dictionary of some different values.
The first value is going to be an Id value,
and I'll put that in double quotes. And then I'll do a colon,
and we can refer to This is just Id 1 because we'll need to have unique
IDs for our targets. And then I'll put a comma here.
The next property will be Arn for the Amazon Resource Name, and
we'll specify another colon here. And now we'll have to be the
ARN value for our Lambda function.
Now, if we don't have this value,
we can get it by going over to the AWS Console and then copying
the value from the ARN at the top of our Lambda function for
gpc_cuckoo. Then we can go back over here,
paste that in, and then hit Enter for our events put‑targets here. Next,
we can press the up arrow, and we can run this again.
In this case,
I'm going to change the rule from daily_tasks over to the new rule, which
will be come_to_work, and I'll change this from Id 1 to Id 2, and hit
Enter. Now we'll get this exact same result, and we can do it third time,
again, changing this from come_to_work to our final event target that we
want to set up here,
which is setting up the pickup event to target this same function. In
this case, we'll use Id 3 here and then hit Enter. Now,
finally, these should all be set up with our Lambda function.
So let me clear the screen here, and let's go back to the
console and check if these have been set up.
I'm going to refresh the screen here, and let's see if
we now have three CloudWatch events.
So it looks like all three have been set up on our function,
and if I scroll down, I should see pickup, daily_tasks, and come_to_work.
So this means we successfully created our Lambda function.
So let's go back and look at what we've done in this module. In
this module, we worked with new AWS services,
including the Simple Email Service, SES, and the Simple Storage Service, S3.
We also learned about some of the resources that we used,
including more parts of the boto3 SDK and how we could use it with Python,
as well as another library called Jinja2 that we used as
a templating engine for those emails.
And then finally,
we created and deployed our Lambda function using the CLI to
set up different events for our Lambda function in order to
trigger it with CloudWatch.
Now that was a lot of effort to get this done. In the next module,
we'll look at how we can simplify this entire process with modern serverless application development.