[Autogenerated] Hi, I'm under Morgan on Welcome to the course.
Introduction to Spring Cloud contract in this module will be building on what
we've learned so far by introducing some more advanced,
consumer driven contract testing principles.
First of all,
we're going to take a look at how we can support multiple
contracts between a consumer under provider.
As currently, we have only supported a single interaction.
We'll also look at how a contract can support multiple
requests via regular expressions,
which is particularly useful when we account for dynamic
data such a your I DS or Time stamps.
Then we'll learn about how we can have more granular control over
both the consumer and provide a side of our interaction by
leveraging the consumer and producer methods and finally will learn
about the shared repository pattern, a means of centralizing all of our contracts together into a single repository.