[Autogenerated] So far,
we've introduced in detail the consumer driven contracts testing technique.
That's because without this foundational understanding,
learning a framework in it would be pretty challenging.
So now this is done is tying to introduce Spring Cloud contract,
which basically provides a scaffolding for us to bear with the Dukan.
She maturing contracts testing in JV M based applications in order
for us to be able to produce contracts sprinklered contract
providers with contract definition language.
This is basically a grieving TSL where we can define all of our
interactions between our consumers and our producers.
Don't worry if you don't know grieve Edo,
as all this uses a very small subset that wouldn't require any prior knowledge.
In fact, the contract DSL is designed to be expressive and easy to use.
Spring Cloud contract also comes with a plug in that is
used to generate stops from our contracts.
These are stops that will be used in the consumer side test.
We can feed our contracts in and get our stops out is part of
a fully automated maven or greater build.
It also providers within easy means of actually
downloading and actually que in the stops,
Jury Narcan Sheamus.
I test runs.
This is through the use of something called the Stop Runner,
which will cover shortly and finally, on the producer side.
Shrink loud Contract generates contract verification tests for is,
there's a variety of configuration options for fundamentally.
The only way for Earth's is to make these tests pass.
The generation off them is fully automated for us by the framework.
As you can see, spring car contract essentially pieces together.
All the parts of consumers of in contract testing on automates as much of the workflow forests is possible.