[Autogenerated] the first thing we're going to do is
create a failing consumer side test.
This is because it's the first step in the consumer
driven contracts testing workflow.
To do this, Robin, including an existing project,
will make use of spring initialize er to create a
vanilla spring boot Micro service.
Well,
then you spring boots to create a failing test for
our credit card functionality.
And then we'll try and fix our test Valya,
by implementing functionality ourselves and finally will do some
test failure analysis as Jesus one network harp.
We won't be able to get our test to pass unless me introduce Steuben.
To get started, we can visit start dot spring the I O.
This is a website powered by sprint initialize er,
a quick start generator for spring boot projects.
In our case,
it will be used to create the scaffolding for our credit card Micro
service at the top we can select are built all maven.
Although Grader is also supported, we can choose a language in our case Java,
and we can also choose our screen beat version in our case,
the latest stable release.
Well, Entercom,
that retail bank is our group and credit card services are artifact i.
D.
And we'll also add Web in the dependencies form,
as will be built in a hasty T p a p I.
And now we're ready to go.
We compress the download ported and generate our project.
The next step is to import our newly generated spring
boot micro service into our I d.
E.
We'll be using intelligent A to do this,
but as it's just a maven project,
it should be straightforward enough to do this in any of the major alternatives.
First will browse and select our project, then moved so quickly.
Economy, even pump file.
We can leave all these default sayings as they are bar in this one,
which means our project will be completely initialized on lows.
We can also choose our sdk in this case,
this job or eight, as that's what will be working with for out this course.
Finally, let's click next and finish importing the project.
Now our projects open.
We can take a look at what has been generated for us in our source directory.
We have a single class with the main methods,
which doesn't do anything overt in start our spring view application.
As this isn't a spring boot course, we won't go into too much detail here.
But essentially, what this means is that when we run our main method,
our spring context will be initialized with some sensible defaults.
Because this is a Web project,
that will mean we get a Web server with a Haiti T p a p I that
we can start calling right away in a test.
If you're more interested in how this works,
I would recommend checking out the pleura site course,
creating your first spring beat project moving to the test directory.
We can also see that as a skeleton spring boo
integration test already set up for us.
When we run this,
our application will be fully initialized with a mock Web
environment that we can fire some automated tests against.
Okay,
so now what we want is a test which applies for a
credit card fire in a P I call on,
then asserts a response to make sure the application has been approved.
First of all, let's Satti all to configure Mark NBC annotation to are test class.
This means that when we ran,
our tests are mock NBC Bean will be in Stan Shades on Configured to Point,
so I'm Marc Webb Environment.
We can.
Then Orta wired out Mark NBC being into our tests like we
would do any off a normal spring bean on,
then immediately start using it to make a P.
I request to our Mark Wiebe environment.
Maybe none said a test.
We will give it a name should grant application.
When credit score is high, we should be self explanatory.
We can then start using Mark NBC to call our A P.
I will start with a post.
Requests to slash credit card applications will be sending Jason,
so we'll make sure that's a content type and in the body itself.
Or just send a citizen number on a card type were ashamed.
Every person in the world is uniquely identifiable by
citizen number in order to keep, for example,
simple.
So that's all we need to do to make our requests.
So now we can move on to our response decision as we want some decent locking.
When we've run the test, we'll also add a print statement.
So all of our hates TTP responses are outputs at a console
for easy analysis of our test failures.
We can then start actually asserting the response,
starting with the status code, which we will expect to be 200.
We don't need a response body with her field.
It states the application has been granted on a content type,
which is application.
Jason on this should be our test complete.
So let's run it and see what happens as we expected.
We've got a failure as we've yet to start implementing any fan.
But what is that failure scrolling down from the top of the locks?
We can see that spring boot has started successfully.
We can also see from the mock NBC logs.
Our request was made as we expected, but from our test assertion,
we can see that Robin and getting a 200 status codes.
We got forward for not found.
This is what our spring boo application does by default when
handling a request it has no controller mapping for.
So the next step is to create a controller for handling our request.
This will at least get out test a little bit fervid in the 44 error.
We'll start by creating a new class called credit card applications controller.
We'll annotate it with the rest controller annotation.
So its able to handle our requests and then we'll create a handler
mapping for the Post requests that a credit card application
general by annotation a method with that post map in We don't need
spring to be able to read our Jason Request body and convert it
into a method argument.
This can be done by simply creating a method argument with Fields,
which match a request Body will create a class to be able to do
this and call it apply for credit card request.
We can use alternate ER to create and navigate to it,
and then we can create a citizen number field on a cart tight field,
matching the field names in our test.
In this case, car type can be anin um, this time with a single value gold,
which is a valued our test depends on.
We can also generate Ghattas and status for our fields so
spring is able to set them when stunned,
shaky in our object and so we can get them in our
controller switching back to our controller.
We now have a citizen number from our request.
What we want to do next is send out citizen number
after our credit check service,
which has yet to exist in order to get a credit score.
We can then use that credit score to decide whether the
application should be approved or not.
In order for our service to make a request to the credit score service,
we first need a hate TTP client.
To be able to do this, any would be fine here,
but in this demo will stay within the string ecosystem.
A new spring rest template.
First, we'll declare, is a final field on and set it in the constructor,
meaning that spring will try and wiry in.
When the application booze intelli J gives us an
Carriedo on by hovering over it,
we can see that it won't actually work because we have not
create arrest template being to fix this,
all we need to do is switch back to our application class and declare one.
We can do this by creating a method that returns one on,
then annotation it without being so.
Now we have our rest template being Let's use.
It's a call are yet to exist.
Credit score service.
First of all will do a get requests to the credit scores
en pointe on local host Port 80 80.
It's true that in production, the euro would be different,
but we relieve it is local host for now and in fix it later
will then pass in a class representing a request body with a
citizen number called Credit Checked.
Request a nem pass in a class representing our
response called credit share response.
We can then use Sultan enter to generate our credit shot request
class at in a single citizen number fields.
And we can also use Alston enter to generate a response,
which in this case will now contain a single field called Score,
which is an 18.
Um, that only needs a value of high.
For now.
On completion,
it's apparently get request isn't quite right here as our code doesn't compel.
If we switch the post for object, that will fix things.
As that method is able to take a request body,
it also makes more sense as a credit check should
never be safe nor riding potent.
Now we have our response.
We can check it to see whether we can grant our credit card application or no.
First of all,
we can check into scores high and also check if the credit card type his goals.
If both these conditions are true, we can return our response a granted,
just like over requests and responses.
We can create objects for this.
Whatever objects we returned from our method,
Spring will convert into Jason on incent it in a
responsible day with his status of two hundreds.
We can call this apply for credit cards and give it a parameter of granted.
We can then use all 10 enter to generate it and give
it one Inam field called status.
Finally, let's switch back to the controller.
We can fix any compilation areas caused by our own imported class and
also at a default room time exception which is phone.
If our condition is no matter over time, this would go away.
If we add more task coverage, we've now implemented RM point end to end,
but it should be pretty obvious that our test is still not going to pass.
This is because it will call out to the credit check service,
which does not yet exist.
Let's navigate to our test, and that's run it to see what happens.
Looking at the stack trace,
we can see a connection refused error to our credit score service.
This is caused by a call being made to local host on our machine only for
there to be nothing running there without contract testing.
This is where a developer would have to make a decision to
even stop this endpoint or end to end test.
For the numerous reasons we've already covered in the previous modules,
this could end up producing poor tests when stubborn um,
point.
There's no guarantee that it will match the rial
endpoint on when end to end testing.
We would have to run and coordinate multiple services
together in an end to end test environment,
one of which does not even exist year.
Fortunately,
we're working through the consumer driven contracts testing workflow.
So this is actually the point where we will define office contract, which will ultimately be used to make artists pass