[Autogenerated] in Ness demo.
We're going to make use of the consumer and producer methods to allow
our contract to support more complicated use cases.
Specifically,
we're going to use these methods so our contract supports
different data on both sides of the interaction.
This will help his make a failing test pass where we'd over ways being a
chicken and egg situation where one side of the interaction needs the
support rejects on your beside needs to support static data starting with
far consumer last chains are assertion.
So we expect to your I d.
Well, a shame that this year your I d should be generated by the provider.
Let's run the tests on Look a failure.
As we can see, the issue is that we're missing a year, I day.
So we need to change our contract so it returns well,
switching back to the provider.
Let's put the same New York idea that's in our test assertion into the contract.
Then switch into the terminal lights installed latest contracts
locally by running maven clean installs get tests.
A nan Back in Arkin Shima,
we can update our credit chat response so it returns
a U U I day working backwards.
We don't need to modify the gateway.
So when we return the credit shot response, it contains issue you.
I day.
We don't need to pass a you your i d instead,
a credit card response and then generate a year I d Field
in our credit card response object.
And then let's run our tests again.
Getting a green billed as we expected.
Now back in our provider,
we can run a full install to regenerate our contract
verification tests as expected, both of them and now failing.
Let's navigate through them and confirm it's because of the year your i d.
Assertion that we just introduced.
Yes, that looks like it's the case as we can see the assertion taking place here.
Let's navigate through our credit checked response class
and get it to generate a new your i d.
Each time it's it's done, she hated.
We want the your i d to change these time,
as this is what the rial production system would do.
Okay, let's run our tests again and see what happens.
As she'd expects,
we have a failure on its because the you I did every
return is randomly generated on does not match the one
that we declared in our contract.
So this is a point in which we have a problem,
because in our consumer side, stop.
We want a specific your I d to be returned.
But in our provider side test,
we want to be out to assert any your I d and not care about the specific value.
So let's modify our contract to use a producer and
consumer methods to allow us to do this.
Under consumer, we can keep the same hard coded geo I d.
So I stopped still returns the same value on our
consume aside test still passes.
However, in the producer method, we can use the any you i d method.
They should fix our provider side test decision by making the
only assert that AU ideas present and not care about the
specific value we should also switched,
are over contract on repeat the same process as they're
both for exactly the same M point.
Okay, let's run out tests and see if they pass, they dio.
And if we navigate to our contract verification tests,
we can see this is because the assertion is now based on a your i d
regular expression rather than attacks comparison again.
This regular expression is the one that we put in the
producer method of our contract.
We should also switch back to our consumer project
and make sure our tests still pass.
Since making I'll change as expected, they dio on.
We can see this is because the your I d returned by our stop is a one
defined in the consumer method in the contract.
Finally,
back in the provider lecture p a similar process for
the requests part of the contract.
We dont technically need to do this in our use case as a test pass already,
but to prove that it works,
let's do it will pass any day instead of consumer method so I can shame aside,
tests continue to function the same,
but let's provide a specific date value to the producer methods.
17 7 2007 We can then Rohan install and then we can get a green build.
Only now if we navigate.
So our contract verification test,
we can see that the request that it makes is our specific day and that's it.
Really, As you can see,
it's useful to be able to control both sides of the interaction like this on.
It's straightforward enough to do by leveraging the consumer some producer methods.