[Autogenerated] As we've learned,
consumer driven contract testing is about continuous
testing on both sides of the interaction.
This is where the contract verification tests will come into play.
Contract verification tests do the opposite to our stops.
Robert.
In giving the agreed response.
When the agreed request is made,
they make the agreed request on assert agreed responses Made this way,
we are able to know that the way we interact with the stop is the
same as the interaction with the rial provider.
Spring Cloud Contract makes creating these contract
verification tests easy as it creates and Fouras.
It does this by passing the contracts using Spring Cloud contract verifier on,
then performing some cogeneration.
The tests that produced can be generated in free modes.
Mark NBC,
which uses Spring mock NBC against the mock Web environment to
make the request and assertions explicit.
Which does say we're for real Web server on Jax RS,
which creates a Jax RS claim to do it.
It also presents a choice of Eva J Unit or spot Tests will be
working with Jean Unit during this course,
but if you're familiar of groovy and spot would be worth checking out to a spot.
Tests are particularly expressive.
Let's take a look at how all of this will fit together in a workflow.
First, we run this spring cloud contract.
Verify a plug in in order to create our contract verification tests.
As already explained,
this is done by pausing a contract year sell on performing cogeneration.
Then we executed tests.
This can be done directly from the I.
D.
A.
Or via the bill.
Tool, of course, has nothing to implemented yet the test will fail.
It's a desk point that we need to investigate what's wrong.
And finally we made the required changes in order to make our test pass. This will then mean our provider is fully compliant with our contracts.