[Autogenerated] Hi, everyone.
I'm wondering Morgan on Welcome to my plan or psy course
introduction to spring Cloud contract.
I'm an independent consultant, trainer and conference speaker,
most recently specializing in both Java micro services and continuous delivery.
Although micro services architectures are becoming very popular,
Tassan um can be hard on overcome in any challenges.
Could be tough when using the more traditional testing strategies.
This course will introduce you to Spring Cloud Contract,
a consumer driven contract testing JBM based micro services framework.
Some of the major topics it will cover includes micro services testing
challenges on the short communes of traditional testing approaches.
How we can use a consumer driven contract testing technique to test micro
services more effectively and finally building and testing both.
Hate TTP driven a message driven Java micro services with spring
cloud contracts on consumer driven contract testing.
By the end of the course,
you'll notice basics of spring cloud contracts and consumer driven
contract testing on you'll be able to use it to develop and test your own
job and micro services before beginning the course.
You should know Java,
and it would also be beneficial to have some knowledge
of micro services on spring boot.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn how to more
effectively Tash Java Micro Services with the introduction to Spring Cloud contract course Applera site.