[Autogenerated] in the first demo will be walking fruit,
a consumer driven contract.
Testing workflow is normal,
but this time are micro services will be message driven,
Robin and hey http, driven, we'll start by writing of failing consumer side test,
this time making use of the stop trigger next will define a
message driven interaction in a contract on,
then install that contract locally and then finally will make Harkin Sheamus.
I test pass.
Starting in our consumer will navigate to our existing
test and then copy and paste it well,
Adam messaging suffix to the end of the new test class.
We're just taking a set up short court here so we can
delete our existing test methods.
We can then remove the weapon Fireman.
This is because our new test will not require a Web
server as nothing will happen over Haiti.
TP we'll leave the auto configure stubborn annotation bay as
we'll be using the same stuff Jarrah's Before on.
We wanted to be downloaded and executed as normal.
Okay, let's create our test calling.
It should store results of a credit check.
Then we'll wiring instance of the stuff trigger into are test class
spring Cloud contract will or to configure this forest,
so there's no settle for us here now.
The interesting part we want to test our consumer behaves as
expected when it receives a message as we're no longer working
with the request reply architecture.
It's an external service, which will make the decision to publish the message.
So to simulate this external service,
publishing a message would use a stop trigger.
Let's call still trigger dot trigger an impasse in the label.
We'll call the credit score this comm bt identify for
the contract that we want to trigger.
Next.
We need to work on our assertion.
What we'd like to do is save the credit score when it's received,
So all we need to research is that this has happened,
will create a repository to store our credit score.
Let's make it a field or tow wire it and then
generate it with alternate er following.
This will put a you you i d in our test and then we'll call gets
score on the repository on past in that you you i d.
Again we can generate a method with Alz and enter.
Finally, we can write an assertion to chat that the scores being saved.
Remember the trigger for saving the score will be the consumption off a message.
We'll also make our repository of spring bean.
So it's part of our spring context when we run our test.
Okay, now attest, compiles.
Let's run it and see what happens.
It fails as we expected, and we can immediately see the problem.
We have yet to declare a contract with our label,
so the stop trigger has nothing to execute.
Switching to our provider, Let's define our first mashes driving contract.
First,
we'll navigate to two contracts directory and then we'll
create a new file for our contract.
Will call.
It should grant a credit score of High to a Citizen with messaging, Doc.
Groovy, once in the file will call Contract out, make as normal.
Then I will declare label score off high well,
then define an output message closure.
This is slightly different to the hay.
Http request closure,
but still quite similar in it will declare a senti parameter.
This is a channel Q or topic that the message in our contract will get sent to.
Then comes a body closure.
We can provide a score of high on we can provide a u I day.
Finally, we can provide a closure for message headers.
We'll give it a single one content type,
so I can Sheamus will know how to marshal the message.
Payload is Jason switching to the terminal?
We can now run a maven Clean install skip tests is normal.
This will install are mentioning contract into the stub jar,
just like with the hay http.
Contracts Now let's switch back to our consumer and start
implement in the rest of our function.
Alice e.
First of all, we need to add some dependencies,
so we'll open our palm file and get started.
As already discussed,
Spring cloud contract plucks into many messaging frameworks.
But for this demo, will you spring cloud stream, rub it.
This is an arbitrary choice on you should be aware that nearly all
of the spring cloud contract specific code we will use here is
common across all supported frameworks.
Now let's at the starter maven dependency to reduce the amount of
configuration that we need to get going on also lets out the test
support dependency just to clarify.
As we implement this,
I'm not going to go into defining details of how spring cloud stream is
working as a focus here is on string cloud contract.
First, we'll annotate our application configuration without enable Binding,
which configures abounding of our application to rabbit,
will then create a listener class which will consume
messages from our credit scores.
Que will make it a spring component and then create a receive score.
Mefford passing in the credit chat response.
Well, then annotate it with upstream listener,
meaning this method will be called when a message is received.
Then we'll take the repository class on where it into the list.
No, we want the listener to save a credit score once it is received.
Let's give it to arguments.
The your i D in the score using Alton enter to generate the method.
Now we can actually implement.
A repository will just store everything in memory in a hash map.
Robin, Amusing.
A real database will achieve this by creating a field which maps between do you,
I DS and scores.
Then we'll implement to get score method so we can return a score by you.
You i d from this map and then we'll implement the save method
where we put data directly into the map.
There's one last step,
which is to configure our application properties to bind to our credit
scores channel using the input destination property.
Okay, now we can run our tests and see if it passes.
Woops Simple error here,
which is that we've accidentally put the wrong label in our test.
We should have put score of high as that's what went into our contract.
Let's rename the label and then rerun our test.
Great.
This time our test passes,
meaning we've implemented our first match is driven interaction using spring cloud contracts.