[Autogenerated] in this demo will be implementing a feature where
an input message triggers an output message.
We'll start by writing a failing consumer side test,
which sends an import message on expects an output matches to be consumed well,
then define an input output, matches contracts and then,
by using the stoves generated from that contract,
will make our consumer site test pass on.
The provider side will then generate our contract verification tests
and finally will make our provide aside tests pass.
Starting in our consumer, let's navigated a palm file.
Although it hasn't affected any functionality so far,
we should be used in the spring cloud contract.
Stubborn a starter.
We can update our dependency to reflect lists as now it's required in
order to auto configure everything for the next steps.
At this point,
we could have also been using a bomb foul to manage all
our various spring cloud dependencies.
But we'll stick with what we already have.
For now,
let's navigate to our tests and create a new one for the Emperor output pattern.
We'll call it should Output Credit school when requesting credit.
Score well, then call a method requests credit score on a yet to exist.
Credit score producer will pass in a credit check
request with citizen number 1234 as usual.
Okay, let's make the class of field on the news old and enter to generate it.
Well,
then scroll to are yet to be implemented Method unused alternate enter to
generate that to and also make our class a spring component.
Following this,
we can retrieve a school from the repository will create a year I d field and
pasa en on then asserted the score we received is high to clarify what we're
expecting here is for is to produce a MASH is requesting a credit score on then
for another mashes to be consumed containing that credit score which will then
be written Czar Repository We can then assert that this happened by reading from
the repository Okay, let's run our tests and see what happens.
We haven't no points for exception here.
If we navigate back to the test,
we concede it's because the credit score producer will be No,
This is because we forgot to add the auto wide annotation
Let's scroll to the top and at the auto wide annotation
and then run the test again.
Great.
The failure is now the one we want.
We read from our repository and gotten all as a repositories MNT on.
We didn't get high, which is what we actually want.
Okay, let's navigate.
So our producer and start to implement it will continue
using spring cloud stream here on.
Remember, we're not going to go into the final details off it.
As a focus of this course is purely on spring cloud contract.
Well, first, add a string cloud contract stream source field on auto,
wire it via constructor,
then in the method will use it to send our credit shot request.
Well,
then switch back to our application configuration on bind the source class
and then we'll switch star application prophecies first.
Although this may not be necessary, will add to content types are input channel.
Then we can copy and paste everything,
changing the word inputs output and then Rina in the
destination to credit score requests.
This means our producer it will send a message to this channel.
Okay, lets one our test again and see what happens.
We got exactly the same result is before this is because even
though we should be produced in a message.
We have no contract which causes and over masses to be consumed in return.
We'll need to implement this now.
Okay, sweet sheen back to our provider.
Let's copy and paste our existing messaging contract well at
an emperor output suffix to the end of it.
Well,
then change the label to score of High Emperor Alpert and
then delete our existing input block.
This is because our input will now be a message from our credit score
Request channel as opposed to an intern or method.
Call Well, first,
declare a message from Block providing US Credit score Request
Channel as an argument will then provide a body well,
then at the citizen number that we send in our consumer side test.
And then we'll add a U I day as the U ideas randomly generated by our consumer.
Will you see which is short hand for consumer UN
provider rejects of any your I D.
On the provider side will provide the same you your i
d as a one in our output message.
The output Messi's block can be left as it already is.
This is because consuming in it and storing the results in a repository
has already been implemented in the previous demos.
Okay, now our contract is complete.
Will switch to the terminal on remaining clean installs.
Get test to install it in our local repository.
We can then switch back to our consumer on rerun are
failing test behind the scenes,
we expect spring cloud contract to receive the input message
on in Fired a corresponding output message.
We've already implemented decode for receiving the output message.
So we expect everything to function right away also,
what's nice here is that everything will happen in the same frat,
meaning we don't have to implement any concurrent kowtow.
Wait for our output message to be returns.
Okay, lets from the tests.
Great artists pass, meaning we fully implemented everything in our consumer side.
Switching Baxter are provider.
We now need to implement its side of the interaction to First,
let's run and install to generate our contract
verification tests and see what happens.
Our newly generated test fells is expected,
so lets navigate to it and do some analysis.
First we concede a contract verifier creating import message in our contract.
We can then see it sending that message down the channel in our contract.
And finally we can see it receiving the message from
the Output Channel of our contract,
asserting that it matches the output message in our contract.
Okay, lets from the test directly and see why it fails.
We can see the problem is that there's no credit score requests.
Bean.
What this error actually means is that we haven't declared anything which
sends messages down the credit score Request Channel.
Let's fix this will start by switching to our application
class on binding the sink to this allows our provider to
consume is while his produce messages.
Then we can create a consumer class will call it credit school.
Consumer lets them make a spring component a nan crea Can she?
Mefford, which takes a credit shot request parameter,
we condemn Bind it to are saying,
using the extreme listener annotation on after days will wiring in
our credit check service and then use it to calculate a credit score
based on the input from our message?
Finally,
were wiring our producer sending the results of our
credit check fruit afterwards.
Now we have a simple method which receives a message.
Does some logic and then outputs and over message.
Just like our contract verification test needs.
The final step is to modify our application.
Properties will copy and paste.
What's our already change?
Inputs output on, then chains, destination to credit score requests.
Okay, let's navigate back to our test run it and see what happens.
We're still getting a failure this time because our matches payload is no.
But why is this while if we remember, we never actually implemented our service.
If we navigate to it, we can see that it always returns.
No, the reason our offer tests paths is because they use a mark.
So we should be using the mark here as well.
We can set this up in the base contract test class,
so lets navigate to it, will create a test configuration on,
innit?
Declare our credit, Jack services a Mark bean.
This means a mosquito mark will be in Stan.
She hated instead of the rial instance off the being well,
then point are Tacitus configuration,
then will create a post constructs annotated method.
This will be called after our spring context is initialized.
But before our test rooms, Well,
then wire in our mock service and then using mosquito.
We will configure it so it returns to score in the U I.
D.
In our contracts when it receives a citizen number in our contract.
Okay, lets one our test again.
Fix this minor compilation our and then try running it again.
Great artists passes,
meaning we fully implemented our last messaging scenario wherein input message triggers an outfit message.