[Autogenerated] that covers it for this module.
We've managed to learn how message driven micro services
still benefit from unarguably need.
Consumer driven contract testing.
This is mainly being defeated,
a Coplin introduce by shared schemers and channels.
We've also learned how we can use the spring cloud contract DSL to
model the sorts of masses driven interactions.
This hasn't been too hard as it's being more or less the same as what we were
doing with hate TTP on the consumer side of our interaction,
we've used a stop trigger to test it.
We consume the messages in our contract correctly.
Onda on the provider side,
we've generated Messi's based contract verification tests
on learned tell to make them pass to.
We've also implemented a temper output pattern where consuming
one message causes another to be produced.
Andi, That's it for the course we've made it on.
We finally managed to learn spring cloud contract going forward.
We should be able to use it to test our own JV M
based mocha service applications. Congrats