Hello and welcome to this new editorial and the previous one we made our first class said the hybrid
parameters you know we put all the hyper parameters in one same class and now we're going to make another
class which will be used to normalize the state.
So very simply the class that we're about to make will you know issue some objects some instances of
the class and one object will be the normalizer itself and we will apply the normalizer understates
to normalize them.
So first of all let me remind you what exactly are the states and why exactly do we need to normalize
them.
So it's important to understand that here we're not doing some deep reinforcement learning and therefore
the state of the environment are not the images that we see on the screen.
Instead the states are some vectors describing perfectly what's happening at each time t.
So basically each state is represented by a vector which will contain the coordinates of the different
points of the virtual robots you know each vector describes perfectly what's happening in the environment
so that we can almost draw the picture by just looking at the vector.
All right.
And that's the state that's going to be the input of the perception or the policy.
The policy is the function to put the States and returning as output the actions to play.
So these are the states.
Now let's explain why we need to normalize the state.
Well the first important reason is that of course the paper says to do it.
So that's the paper I remind simple random search provides a competitive approach to reinforcement learning.
And if we scroll down that's the introduction you know related work the problem explanation of the problem
first.
Basic random search algorithm that already existed and then their proposed algorithm by the author which
is this one augmenting random search.
Well they say that in order to improve the performance of the algorithm we should normalize the states.
All right so you can read this section here.
They will explain that we must do it and how we should do it.
We're going to do it of course in a tutorial so you're going to see the math details of how we're going
to do basically we're going to do some online learning of an average and the variance because indeed
in order to normalize some values you have to subtract by the mean and then divide by the standard deviation.
So you're going to see the mathematical details.
But if I wanted to explain to you why we should normalize to states intuitively That's because the neural
network basically will make a much better difference between values that are comprised between 0 and
1 rather than values that are for example between 100 and 200 or 50 and 300 you know because I tell
you that the states are encoding what's happening in the environment so basically they are some vectors
containing some coordinates.
And of course the coordinates are not values between 0 and 1.
There are more higher values maybe a couple of hundred.
That depends on the metric.
But the neural network will make a much better Association of values between 0 and 1 than values between
100 and 200 for example.
So that's why we're going to take all the values of the input state vector and we we're going to convert
them between 0 and 1 by normalizing them.
That is to each of the value we're going to subtract the mean and divide by the standard deviation.
So that's the reason but feel free to have a look at this paragraph here.
Read it.
And now we're going to go back to Python to make this class that will normalized the states.
So here we go.
It's a class so I'm going to start with class again and.
Well since this class since the object of this class will represent the normalized itself.
Well I'm going to call it of course with a Keppel and normalizer.
Normalizer with some parenthesis.
It's not taking an argument still.
So we can just add colon.
And here we go.
We are ready to define this class.
So as for every class we have to start with the init method separated by two double underscores just
like that exactly like before.
But then remember for the previous class it just took self as argument because basically we just had
to define some hyper parameters but here the method is going to take not only self but another one it's
going to take self.
And now this other argument is going to be the number of elements inside the vector that is the number
of inputs of the perception.
As I told you a state is described by a vector of several components and the number of components of
the vector is the number of inputs of the perception.
And that's exactly what we need to specify here as a second argument.
Number of inputs.
OK that's the only arguments we need.
And now let's define the variables that are going to be the variables of the future instances.
That is if future objects of this normalizer class that's always what we need to define here in this
first init method.
And so let's say what they are the variables of the future normalizer object will be first a counter
saying how many states we've encountered since the beginning of the experience.
Then it's going to be the mean the mean of the values of the states.
That is for each of the inputs of the input vector and then it's going to be the variance because basically
with only the mean and the variance we can normalize the values with the state.
However we're going to add an extra variable which we're going to call mean def and that's basically
the numerator in the calculation of the variance you know there's some of the squared differences between
the values and the mean in the condition of the variance.
So we'll initialize our objects with these four variables.
Let's start with the first one.
As we said the first one is a counter and calling self-doubt and itself is to specify that these are
indeed going to be variables of our normalizer object.
So Soledad N and then what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a vector of any input values all initialized
to zeros Y and being put values because the input is the number of elements of your input vector.
That's what we specify here.
So right now I want to initialize everything to zero because then we'll update the mean and the variance.
But we have to initialize all these values to zero first.
And how can we do that easily with non-pay.
Well we take them by first and by the way we can use the following shortcut.
That's a classic but then you have to add here as and P so that you don't have to type the whole non-pilot
library you can type here and that zeros so zeroes will create a vector of a certain number of elements
and the number of elements is what you have to put here.
And this zeros function and that of course and B inputs so that now we just create a vector of inputs
values all initialized zeros are equal to zero.
And that's our first variable of the object.
And the second one as we said is going to be the mean so subduct mean and then exactly the same we're
going to initialize that to zero.
So I'm just going to copy that and paste it.
So that means still a vector of and being puts element and then later on when we observe the new state
we will do a non-land computation of the mean which means that this vector is going to be updated with
the mean of the values for each of the input of the input vector.
You're going to see we're going to do that in the next tutorial with the new method.
Right now we're just initializing everything.
Then the next one is self.
That it would be Varians but we want to break the consideration of the variance in two by first calculating
the numerator which we can call mean diff and same.
Of course we want to compute the variance and therefore the mindif for each of the input of the input
vector of the input state.
So I'm still initializing this as a vector of any input zeros.
OK.
And finally the Varians self-taught var which same I'm initialising as a vector have been put zeros
which later on will be updated containing the variance of the values of the states for each of the input
of the input.
OK.
So now we have initialized the mean the numerator of the variance and the variance.
And now in the next tutorial we're going to make a function which each time we observe a new state we'll
update these variables here.
That is the mean mindif and the variance to compute the mean and the variance of each of the values
of the input states as soon as we observe a new state.
All right so this will be an interesting computation and by the way this is a classic to know in math
statistics or machine deep reinforcement learning.
I will do that in next tutorial.
And until then enjoy AI.