Hello and welcome to this new tutorial and this new code section because now that we're done with the
section on normalizing the states we're going to move on to a new code section an important one that's
the section where we build the AI.
So the first thing to keep in mind and that is very important is that our AI is a policy a policy which
is a function taking as input states of the environment.
We explained what they were and returning some actions the actions to play in order to work.
So the AI is a policy and then the second very important thing to keep in mind and to understand is
that the algorithm that we are doing here that we are implementing is based on an exploration on the
space of pulses.
In other words we're going to be exploring a lot of different policies and will converge to the one
that will return the best actions in order to work.
So since now we are about build an AI AI not training yet but build its foundations.
Well you might guess that we will do it into a class again because we're not only going to build the
architecture of the policy we will build the policy and we will give it its tools that will update it
there in all the training.
You know in the different steps of the training we will update the policy by applying some perturbations
and updating the weight of the policy because its a perception in the direction that increases the rewards
and thats why a class is perfect for that because a class can contain different methods which are actually
different tools.
And of course these measures will be to apply some perturbations on the weight of the perception of
the policy.
So we'll make a class that will call policy we will initialize all the variables of our future policy
object which will be nothing else than some AI's represented by perception and we will integrate in
this class several methods which will update the policy all along the training.
All right so lets do this.
Lets start by defining the class.
So as usual we always class and then the name of this class will be either actually a I for I prefer
to call it policy just so that I can remember that the AI is a policy function of the input states and
returning the actions to play.
No argument here we go.
We are ready to define this class as a job we need to start with the in its method which will take as
arguments.
Well first of course self our future policy objects or future AI's and also input size.
So thats just the size of the inputs you know basically the number of elements in the vector of input
states and output size which is of course the number of actions to play I remind this is another important
point.
But I remind that the AI is not only returning one action it is returning several actions because indeed
in order to walk you need to do several movements in your body and only one movement.
So what are these actions.
Are basically the angles between the axes of the virtual robot and also the muscles impulsion.
Right which impulsion should you make on a certain muscle of a certain member of your body in order
to walk.
So here we go.
That's our arguments input size output size.
Now let's define the variables property the objects are future policy objects are future AI's and these
variables are actually only one variable.
Can you guess what it is.
If you understand that what we're building here is the policy and the policy is nothing else than a
perception and a perception is nothing else than a one layer neural network composed of several neurons
therefore composed of several weights.
Well the only variable that would really be essential to initialize here and to introduce is of course
the matrix of weight which we're going to call theta.
So the variable that I'm going to introduce here and the only one of our function.
Basically the only one proper to the future object is self theta.
The metrics of weights of the neurons of the perception of the policy are to solve that data and as
how we usually do in the init method we are going to initialize this matrix of weights theta to zeros
only zeros.
But remember this zeros function by non-Thai needs to take one essential argument that you can see here
the shape and that is a couples that's why I'm adding new parenthesis here.
A couple containing the dimensions of this matrix of zeros you want to build.
So here zeros.
We just entered one argument that means it's going to be a vector.
But here since we want to initialize matrix all we have to do with these parenthesis here to specify
the dimensions of the matrix.
And these are going to be.
Be careful it's not going to be input size and output size.
It's actually going to be I'll put size for the number of lines so there are going to be output size
lines therefore same number of lines as a number of actions to play and in what size columns.
So there is going to be as many columns as the number of elements in the vector input states.
And why do we have to take it in this order.
That's because we're simply following what they do in the article in the paper.
They do a multiplication by the left side.
You know they do a matrix multiplication by the left side and therefore it must be the output size that
goes first.
You can check that on the paper but we could have totally done in precise first and output size but
then it would have been a multiplication by the right.
Basically it's just a conventional order.
All right and that's it.
That's only what we need to initialize here for our policy.
So it's quite simple for now but it's going to get slightly more challenging now.
And that's why we're going to take a little break and move on to the next tutorial to make this first
function this essential function for the are as you know it's at the heart of the IRS and that is going
to be the function that applies to perturbations on the weights.
You know we will take several directions for each direction will apply a perturbation on the weights
and we will measure the rewards that we get with this specific perturbation in this specific direction.
And if you want to see peril with the article Well basically in the next tutorial we will be implementing
exactly this.
You know the papers suggest two ways of doing things the one which is applying the perturbations in
one direction here and the opposite direction year.
So we will call this by the way the positive direction.
And this one the negative direction which is to say that these are opposite directions.
So V-1 is applying these perturbations without normalizing the state and V-2 is saying applying those
perturbation positive direction negative direction but with normalization applied.
And as you can see this is exactly what we did.
We subtract by the mean here and we divide by the standard deviation the root of the variance.
And of course what we're going to do is V-2 because we already normalized the states.
OK so we're going to apply those positive perturbations here and those negative perturbations here.
But keep in mind that positive negative just means that we're playing the opposite direction for a specific
perturbation here.
OK.
So we'll do that in the next tutorial.
Actually since you already have the formula the exact formula in the paper.
Maybe you could try to make this future function before the next to Tokyo and that could be a nice exercise
and you can get the solution in the next it's also.
Basically you only have to apply this in a new function that we're going to call evaluate.
All right so good luck and I'll see you in the next it's oil to make that function.
Until then enjoy.