In order to understand the benefits of using AWS CloudFront,
let's step back and touch on a few basic concepts like the role
of a web server and what a CDN actually does.
When serving web content,
there needs to be a source or an origin where your content actually resides.
This could be a physical or virtual server running a web
server application like Apache or NGINX.
Static content can also reside in cloud objects
stored solutions like Amazon's S3, Azure's blobs,
or digital ocean spaces just to name a few.
These origins contain the content you are serving,
as well as they are able to provide an endpoint which can
receive and respond to a browser's request.
We won't go into too much detail of how web server's
work other than what we've just stated.
Pluralsight has other courses on how web server technologies
work which you can view to learn more.
Okay, so we now have a general understanding of the role of the origin server.
This is great,
but what happens when more than just a few people want to view your content?
Add more servers?
Sure, but that only resolves the local bottlenecks.
What happens when requests come from all around the globe?
No matter how much capacity you add to your cluster,
the request times from around the world will be
dependent on the distance travelled.
Well,
let's say you're making a request from LA to a server that is located in Berlin.
Now follow with me.
The TCP/IP handshake creates three instances of approximately 250 ms each.
So we're already looking at approximately 750 ms before
your computer sends the HTTP request,
which taking approximately 250 ms to reach the server and
another approximately 250 ms to respond back with the web
page and a 200 status code,
this adds another 500 ms so we're currently at 1 and a quarter seconds.
Now if this page has maybe 5 additional assets that need
to load like JavaScript or CSS images,
we need to add those times for those requests and for
them to respond asynchronously,
this could possibly add an additional 1500 to 1700 extra milliseconds.
So it's perfectly normal to see a web server set up regardless of the
horizontal scaling serving content to request from the other side of the
world taking the best part of 3 to 4 seconds to load and that's if
everything goes exactly as expected.
This can be a costly overhead when response times have a financial impact.
CDN stands for content distributed network,
which refers to a geographically distributed group of servers which will
work together to provide fast delivery of internet content.
CDN allows for the quick transfer of assets needed for
loading internet content including HTML pages,
JavaScript files, Style Sheets, images, and videos.
There are many popular CDN services which continue to grow in popularity,
and today, the majority of web traffic is served through them,
including traffic for major sites like Facebook,
Netflix, Reddit, YouTube, and Twitter.
CDNs work by reducing the distance between your origin and your target audience.
Like stated a moment ago, your origin web servers,
regardless of their scaling capabilities are a single location serving content.
The further you move away from the server, the longer your request will take.
The CDN replicates the setup in multiple regions around the
globe reducing the distance a request and transfer has to
travel to and from your end users.
Think of it as a remote cache of your static objects that a visitor can
reach rather than having to go all the way to the origin.
So at its core,
a CDN is a network of servers linked together with the
goal of delivering content as quickly, cheaply,
reliably, and securely as possible.
I think it's important to consider this when you decide
that you might want to use a CDN.
These reasons will provide motivation for the rest of this course.
The key items from this lesson, and which we'll expand on in the next videos,
are that CDNs are geographically distributed networks,
they cache static content,
they reduce the distance between visitors and the origin, and they reduce your response time.