Log files give us a lot of useful data to work with when an issue occurs,
but you also need a mechanism to notify you or your operations team
whenever there is a potential issue as it happens.
To deliver alarm notifications, we'll use Amazon SNS,
a fully-managed pub sub messaging service.
Since CloudFront is already integrated with CloudWatch,
it's already publishing metrics in us-east-1.
This means we'll need to set up our SNS topic in the same region.
Just to keep on topic with CloudFront monitoring,
I've already set up and subscribed my email address to an SNS topic.
If you'd like more guidance on setting up SNS,
please search in the Pluralsight catalog for topics on implementing SNS.
You can also choose to send notifications to other destinations,
such as custom monitoring systems or services like PagerDuty.
Now we'll need to configure alarms using CloudWatch.
CloudWatch is a monitoring and management service that provides you
with data and actionable insights to monitor your applications and
respond to system-wide performance changes.
CloudWatch currently provides the following metrics at no additional cost and
these metrics don't count against your CloudWatch limits.
These are requests, BytesDownloaded, BytesUploaded,
400ErrorRates, 500ErrorRates, and TotalErrorRates.
When viewing metrics,
you can specify a time interval of as little as 1 minute
for time periods in the previous 2 weeks.
Head over to the CloudFront service console,
in the left side Navigation pane, click Monitoring,
then choose a distribution, then click View distribution metrics above it.
On this page, you have a dashboard with metrics already charted for you.
Let's take a look at a few of these metrics.
Requests, this shows you the total incoming requests within a 5-minute window.
Data transfer is the average bytes uploaded and
downloaded within a 5-minute window.
And error rate is handling a little bit of math to crunch the numbers and
display a percentage of all the errors verse all incoming requests for
the distribution within a 5-minute window.
If you prefer,
you can add these to a CloudWatch dashboard so you can view
these metrics from within CloudWatch.
Let's build an alarm.
Why don't we set an alarm for 500ErrorRate metric.
Let's jump into the CloudWatch console within the us-east-1 region,
that's North Virginia.
On the left side, click Alarms, click on Create alarm,
click Select metric, then go to CloudFront,
Per-Distribution Metrics,
scroll until you find 500ErrorRate for your CloudFront distribution Id,
and then check the box, and click Select metric at the bottom.
Scroll down a little, in the period field,
choose 1 minute, scroll a little further and we'll set our condition.
Let's set the alarm to trigger whenever 500ErrorRate is greater than .1 %.
You should adjust the value to be whatever is appropriate for
your distribution and your application, and click Next.
Under Notification, choose Alarm.
Then since I've already created my SNS topic,
I'll choose select an existing SNS topic,
then select the SNS topic called PS_Alerts,
but you could use whatever topic you have.
Scroll to the bottom and click Next.
Give the alarm a name, click Next, and review your settings,
and when you're satisfied, click Create Alarm.
Now you should see your alarm.
At first, you'll see insufficient data is the state,
that'll quickly change to OK.
From this point on,
if the rate of 500 errors goes over .1 % of its current baseline,
CloudFront will email me.
Setting alarms should be repeated for each one of the
available metrics that are currently available,
but for the sake of this lesson, we'll skip over that for now.
In the next video,
we'll take what we've built here and put it to use to help us troubleshoot as an issue occurs.