So by now, you should have a high-level understanding of how a CDN works.
Let's expand on what the benefits of implementing a CDN are.
Although the benefits of using a CDN vary depending on the
size and needs of your internet property,
the primary benefits for most users can be broken
down into four different components.
Improving website load times,
by distributing content closer to website visitors by using a nearby CDN server,
visitors experience faster page loading times.
As visitors are more inclined to click away from slow loading sites,
a CDN can reduce bounce rates and increase the amount of
time that people spend on the site.
In other words, a faster website means more visitors will stick around longer.
Reducing bandwidth costs.
Bandwidth consumption costs for website hosting is
a primary expense for websites.
Through caching and other optimizations,
CDNs are able to reduce the amount of data an origin server must provide,
thus, reducing hosting costs for the website owners.
Increasing content availability and redundancy.
Large amounts of traffic and hardware failures can
interrupt normal website function.
Thanks to their distributed nature,
a CDN can handle more traffic and withstand hardware
failure better than many origin servers.
And finally, improving website security.
A CDN may improve security by providing DDoS medication,
improvements to security certificates, and other optimizations.
You may be asking yourself, Andy, how does a CDN improve website load times?
When it comes to websites loading content,
users drop off quickly as the site slows down.
CDN services can help to reduce load times in the following ways.
The globally distributed nature of a CDN means reduced
distance between users and website resources.
Instead of having to connect to wherever your websites origin server may live,
a CDN lets users connect to a geographically closer data center.
Less travel means faster service.
CDNs can reduce the amount of data that's transferred by reducing file sizes
using tactics such as minification and file compression.
Hey, smaller file sizes mean quicker load times.
CDNs can also speed up sites which use TLS certificates by optimizing
connection reuse and enabling TLS false start protection.
And don't forget,
hardware and software optimization such as sufficient load balancing and
solid-state hard drives can help data reach users faster as well.
Okay, so how does a CDN reduce bandwidth costs?
You might be thinking to yourself that implementing a CDN
will have its own costs and rightfully so,
yes, there will be a new cost for whatever CDN solution you implement,
but bandwidth costs are usually where your web host tries to get you.
A few gigabytes of monthly transfers can quickly add
up and outspend the CDN costs.
Every time an origin server responds to a request, bandwidth is consumed.
Utilizing TTLs, or time to live,
on the content you host from your CDN can greatly reduce how often your CDN
has to request and transfer data from your origin servers.
Regarding content availability and redundancy,
how does the CDN keep a website always online?
Uptime is a critical component for anyone with an internet property.
Hardware failures and spikes in traffic as a result of either malicious attacks
or just a boost in popularity have the potential to bring down a web server and
prevent users from accessing a site or service.
A well-rounded CDN has several features that will minimize downtime.
Load balancing distributes network traffic evenly across several servers
making it easier to scale rapid boosts in traffic.
Intelligent failover provides uninterrupted service even if one or more of
the CDN servers go offline due to hardware malfunction.
The failover can redistribute the traffic to the other operational servers.
In the event that an entire data center is having technical issues,
anycast routing transfers the traffic to another available datacenter
ensuring that no users lose access to the website.
I mentioned earlier that one of the roles of a CDN was to provide security.
Well, how does a CDN protect your data?
Information security is an integral part of a CDN.
A CDN can keep the site secured with fresh TLS certificates which
will ensure high standard of authentication,
encryption, and integrity.
One of the most substantial security vulnerabilities of web
properties on the modern internet is the use of distributed
denial of service attacks, or DDoS.
Over time,
DDoS attacks have increased in size and complexity with attackers
utilizing botnets to target websites with high traffic.
A large and properly configured CDN has the potential benefit of
scale as a protective factor against DDoS.
By having enough data center locations and sizable bandwidth capabilities,
a CDN is able to withstand and mitigate an amount of incoming attack traffic
that would easily overwhelm the targeted origin server.
Web application firewalls, or WAFs,
protect your internet property from common
vulnerabilities like SQL injection attacks,
cross-site scripting,
or cross-site forgery requests with no changes to your existing infrastructure.
Most CDNs allow you to apply these protections to your
traffic before it reaches your origins servers.
Wrapping up, in this lesson, we learned,
in general, how CDNs are designed to improve website load times,
reduce bandwidth costs, increase content availability and redundancy,
and improve website security. Next, we'll learn how Amazon's CloudFront applies these principles.