Hello welcome back to the course on computer vision in today's tutorial we're going to talk about adaptive
boosting or other boost.
So previously we left off when we discussed how the algorithm uses input data or images to find which
features are important to recognizing faces.
So it uses the face images to understand which features are common among faces and it keeps those.
And then it uses the nonfatal images to understand out of the ones that are the features that it's kept
which features give it high rates of false positives.
And then it discards those features and makes them less important and focus on the features that are
present and faces and faces only that do not come up very commonly in other types of objects or the
pictures.
And so that's basically how the algorithm is trained.
And then we have these different features and there are thresholds at which they are considered to be
present in an image and so that sounds like the end of the story sounds like.
Ok cool.
We've identified the features we've identified thresholds all we have to do when a new image which is
going to watch is going to look at the features that we've identified check if their present check the
thresholds are met.
And we're going to know if it's a face while everything is not that simple.
The reason for this hurdle is that even in a 24 by 24 pixel image the number of features is huge the
number of features actually is over a hundred and eighty thousand possible features that can fit into
this image.
Sounds it sounds unbelievable because the image is so small it's only 24 pixels but it is true.
So the the reason for that is that these features as we discussed there are scalable.
So not only are we looking at these features on all their different positions in this image.
We're actually looking at all of the variations of each one of these features.
For instance this feature looks like for example it looks like there's one 2 pixels here and 1 2 pixels
here.
So you need to look through this image and try all all possible positions of this feature or very likely
like that and then all possible positions here here all different positions here.
And that's that's the start.
But now you need to also extend that as to be like one to three pixels three pixels here and three pixels
here and again you have to try out all possible positions for that feature.
Next you might make it like four pixels high.
Again you have to try it out all the positions the next you might make it for pixels high and then two
pixels wide so that one.
One two three four one two three four here and one two three four one two three four here and you need
to try that out as well.
And then once and then you keep doing that you keep expanding making it wider and so on and all the
possible widths and heights of this feature.
And then once you've run out of options for that you need to move on to the next one and the next or
next on THE NEXT ONE.
And so in a 24 by 24 pixel image these base features they all possible variations of them and their
different positions.
They add up to over a hundred and eighty thousand possible options that we would have to explore.
And that is a huge number.
So and it poses two concerns.
First of all during the training that would be very hard because you know not only have to check 180000
features for one image you need to check hundred eighty thousand features for all the images in the
training data which is nine thousand eight hundred thirty two faces in the original Old Jones paper
plus the huge number you know thousands and tens of thousands of images of known faces so you'd have
to check that across all those images so training becomes quite long becomes like a nightmare.
And the second thing is that even during your application so when you're detecting you're in if you've
somehow managed to train those all those features now when you're detecting the faces you have to check
180000 every single time.
And that is practically impossible to do in real time.
Take a lot of computation to do that for every single frame or every single image.
So this is where adaptive boosting comes in to help solve this problem.
So we've got we're going to take our features and we're going to put them together into a classifier
which will look like this so here on the left we've got the classifier f f of x and then here f one
of two and three are the features and Alpha 1 2 and 3 are the way to those features so we'll just add
some features here.
For instance there's a feature so that feature could be that's one that's commonly talked about the
bridge of the nose of the nose is usually lighter than on the left on the right.
So it's it's a feature that can help detect faces and this is the feature that the eyes are commonly
darker than the area under the eyes.
And so just even these two features will get as I say.
So that's those two features and then maybe there's another feature and so on.
So we've got our features aligned and that and it keeps going like that.
And each one of these features is called a weak classifier on its own.
He doesn't get a very high rate of success so as long as it gets over 50 percent that's already good.
So for instance maybe this bridge of the nose if you just used that feature on its own maybe gets a
60 percent success rate or a road or 65 percent success rate out of the images.
And then this image that or this classifier or this part on the left the effort the F couple of X that's
called a strong cost classified.
And the way it works is that when you have one classifier by itself it's not as good.
It maybe has a 60 percent success rate.
When you have two week classifiers together even though this one might also be only like 60 or something
percent or 55 percent.
But together all of a sudden they're much stronger.
And then as you keep adding they get stronger and stronger and stronger so you don't actually need.
You don't need all hundred and eighty thousand of them.
You might just need a couple of thousand to get a really really good result very strong classified.
And this is called an ensemble method this is called ensemble because you are leveraging the power of
the crowd as they call it.
So it's like the power of one is not as strong.
But when you put lots of we classifiers together they become a strong classifier and that is what I
was going to say that even just these two features the bridge of the nose and the eyes and the area
under the eyes.
It's the exact numbers in the village on paper but I think they said something like it gave them an
80 percent accuracy just those two features together or really made it so much more powerful.
Not it wasn't close to 90 or a hundred but it was already much better than each one of those on their
own.
And so as you can imagine by adding more and more and more you can get better and better better results.
So the question is now how do we find these right features how do we add the right ones.
So the most important ones are want to have the most important ones at the front.
And then.
So then because our of the 180 thousand then the ones at the end you don't even need to worry about
them after a certain point.
So how do we find the best ones and this is where adaptive boosting comes into play.
We won't go into the mathematics behind the algorithm we'll just go into the intuition.
So let's say you have 10 pictures you have five faces and five known faces.
And during the training process you apply.
You want to identify the like the best feature.
See I don't you want to identify how to build that strong classifier So you identify a feature that
is important.
And for instance the bridge of the nose feature and there you you apply it to your images.
And so you get a result for for instance it says identify that these three are indeed faces.
That's great.
And then it's identified out of the ones on the right.
It's identified that these three are not.
And hasn't found that feature in those images.
So for the for the algorithm those are not faces that's also good but then it does have some error.
So it's got some these false negatives.
Right so it's it's a Negat saying it's a negative but it's actually false.
It's not so correct.
These got two false negatives that says these are not faces when they are actually faces so didn't find
the feature on these on these two pictures.
But these are actually faces.
And then it's got two false positives.
It's identified these as faces even though they're not faces so what adaptive boosting does is it says
ok cool.
So we we like this feature because and the way we found it was perhaps that it is present on a huge
number of images it's the one that comes up most commonly and through our like empirical training we've
identified that yes this is a good picture but now what adaptive boosting will do is.
OK I need to compliment like I might have a lot of very good features I might have this feature is good
then another feature is good and so on.
So but our idea is to go back here so the point of adaptive boosting is that we don't want to just combine
the strongest features or because they might they might actually be leveraging off very similar things
or that might not be the best approach the best approach that we want to take this is the important
part is we want to take a strong feature but then we want to complement it with something that will
help you know help fix where this feature is strong.
That's good but where it's weak where it's making mistakes.
This will help complement that area and will help improve the performance in those areas which are falling
behind in this feature by itself.
And then this feature will be used to complement these two.
And we're they're falling behind.
And so each next one we're not just taking the strongest features we can find we're staying a strong
feature or the strongest and then we take in the one that best complements this one and then we're taking
the next one which best complements these two and the next on and so on.
So basically instead of just taking the strongest all the time we're constructing the strongest classifier
to resulting classify that we can rather than.
And so basically by leveraging the strengths of this one and then fixing up its weaknesses with this
one and then fixing up their weaknesses with this and so on so we covered.
That's very kind of like a strategic approach.
And so here again we've got these are this is all good but then we've got these two false negative false
negatives and false positives.
And so what adaptive boosting our will do is in the next round it will now look for something that complements
this feature that we found and how we'll do it.
What I'll say is it will give more weight to where the errors were made.
Ill say Okay so now I'm going to let's go let's go back.
Although explain this or so it's decreased the sizes.
This is just to just to symbolize what is going on so we've decreased the size of these images increase
the sizes of these zones highlighted in blue and decreased the size of these on increase the size of
these ones so you can see again if I go back.
So there you go.
So it's increased the sizes of these ones saying that it's not actually increasing the size of the image
which is doing it here on the PowerPoint just so that it is clear.
It's like it's easier to follow along but what it's doing is just increasing the weight the importance
of these images for the next for the next horror like feature one is going to be looking at this whole
system is going to now is going to know that the importance of these images is higher and it's going
to find a feature that treats them the best that helps I classify them properly.
And that's what we do.
That's how it accounts for that is how it implements that notion where we want to fix the problems of
the first class fire the first feature that we had so.
So now if we add a new one it finds the next one that best works with these images that predominantly
classify these images properly and find this one.
And so as you can see this now it applies to classify these five images correctly.
Unfortunately classify that or an incorrectly so that's a false negative.
And then it's classified these images correctly and then it's classified.
This one still incorrectly it's a false positive.
So maybe it was not possible to find a classifier that would classify these two very well so what the
algorithm did is it found one that classifies these four including this one very well.
And now we're going to have to fix find a new classifier that fixes these errors.
And that's what will happen next.
Next we would focus on these two.
So everything will become smaller and would focus on these two as predominantly the ones that we need
to fix in order to create that very strong overall classifier.
And and this would keep going.
And in the end the goal is to create a classifier that classifies all of these correctly and classifies
all of these correctly as well.
These faces spaces these are known faces.
So of course it's not never going to be ideal.
But the point is to keep building this strong classifier through these weak classifiers just keep building
it and minimizing the error rate until you get to a satisfactory level until you get to a very high
percentage of correct classifications like 99 point something percent.
And at that point you don't need the hundred and eighty thousand You just need that first couple of
thousand that or hundreds however many you can get to.
You mean you'll need to get to that good satisfactory conversion rate and then that's it.
And that's all you need.
And then you don't classify as really.
And that's a first step to reducing the number of the computation expense of finding find these images.
That's the first step is the added boost in what we discussed today.
And then the next step is going to be the cascading.
And once you combine them together you'll see that it actually improves the efficiency substantially.
So there you go that's how the Arab Boosler adaptive boosting algorithm works.
If you'd like to read a bit more about it there is a paper by Gene you and Paul Viola.
It's called boosting image retrieval.
And this paper inspired some of the work in the violin Jones paper which we were talking about at the
start.
So hope you enjoyed Sterle 40 next 14.
And until then enjoy computer vision.