Hello and welcome to listen to toil to they we're going to do the face recognition with the web cam
by playing the detect function that we made in the previous toils on each of the images coming from
the webcam.
All right.
So let's do this.
And if that doesn't take a while we might actually see the results at the end of this tutorial.
So the first thing we need is the last frame coming from the webcam because that's on this last frame
that we will apply the detect function and so to get this last frame we're going to create an object
of another class which is video capture.
So that's a class working on the web cam and basically this object will contain several entities several
informations and one of them will be the frame.
The last image last frame coming from the webcam.
So this object is going to be called Video underscore capture because this is actually an object from
the video capture class which is a class of the CB2 much all.
So let's not forget CB2 here video capture class and that class takes one argument actually which is
0 0 1 0.
If it's the webcam of the computer and one if it's a webcam coming from an external device that is if
you have an external webcam that you plugged into your computer.
I'm going to use the webcam of my computer the internal webcam so that's going to be zero.
But if you have an external webcam you will have to put one here.
All right.
So that's basically all we need to do to get this video capture object that contains the last frame
coming from the webcam.
And now we are ready to start the loop to apply to detect function on all the images coming from the
web cam that we get things through this video capture object and on all these images.
We will apply to detect function to detect the face and the eyes.
So that's why we're going to start a loop now which is not going to be a for loop because it's going
to be an infinite loop and we will break it by using the break trick.
And by then you know you can end the loop by just typing break and actually break will be applied.
If we type on q on the keyboard to turn off the webcam.
So this while loop.
The trick is to do well here and then trick which means we repeat infinitely until daybreak.
All right.
So what is the first step in it to do.
Well the first step is to get the last frame coming from the webcam and to get it.
We're going to use a method for more video capture object which is the read method and this read method
returns two elements and the second element is the last frame coming from the webcam.
And since we're only interested in that we're going to use this trick here underscore cummer frame because
the read method returns two elements and we are only interested in this one.
And the fact that we're putting an underscore here means that we won't get the first element returned
by this read method.
All right and so now we need to call this read method to get the last frame of the webcam and to do
this since this method is a method of the video capture class.
Well we need to take our video capture object then that and then read with some parenthesis.
Perfect.
That gets us the last frame of the webcam and now we are almost ready to apply to detect method.
Remember the Digic method not only takes the frame as input but also the gray that is the black and
white version of the frame and therefore we need to do something here to get this black and white version
of this frame that we just got thanks to the read method of our video capture object.
And to do this we're going to use the city color function CVG color is a function of our of each module
that allows to do some transformations on some frames.
So there will be some transformations on our original colored frame and this transformation will be
of course to convert this color image into black and white so that we can get the second argument here
Grey which will be the black and white version of this frame.
So let's call it actually gray black and white version of the frame.
And now we're going to take our city to Mudgal because we want to take the CVT color class which takes
two arguments the first one is of course frame because that's the image we want to convert into black
and white.
And the second one will be civil to that all in capital letters color underscore b g are to gray.
So what is this.
This argument Sivi to that color B.G. are two gray cells.
In fact to do an average on blue green and red and that's to take a scale of gray because you know cause
the Cascades are applied on the gray images.
But in order to get the right contrast of black and white well we need to do some average on the blue
red and green to get this contrast.
You know if we have some parts of the images that are with dark colors and some dark red blue green
Well we will get some dark gray in the great image.
So that's just a trick to obtain the right shades of gray.
All right then I think you guess what we have to do we have to frame the original color image and gray
which is the black and white version of the image.
So we are ready to apply the detect function.
We have the two arguments grand frame.
So basically we're ready to get the original image with the detector rectangles detecting the face and
the eyes.
So we're going to introduce a new voice will here that we're going to call canvas and that will be the
result of the detect function applied to our frame which is the last frame captured by the webcam and
gray the black and white version of this frame.
So what we simply need to do here is to call our detect function and then apply gray and frame gray
and frame and that will get us the last streamed image of the web cam with the rectangle detectors Okay.
Then we need to use some more tricks.
The first week we need to do is to display in an animated way all the successive outputs that is all
the successive processed images in a window.
And to do this we're going to use from RACV to Mudgal the eum show function.
So that's that is just a function that will do that for you.
Display all these processed images in an animated way in a window.
And so this show function takes two arguments.
The first one is video and the second one is the canvas canvas which is the output of the detect function.
That is the original image coming from the webcam but with the detector rectangles right then we need
to use another trick which will be used to stop the webcam and face the election process if we press
on cue on the keyboard.
So the trick to do that is to blame if conditions saying that if see that wait key and you put one and
0 x f f equals equals or in some quotes.
Q That's Q On the keyboard.
So is this then what do we want to do.
Remember where I told you about the while loop the infinite loop.
Well we want to break the process that is set stop everything.
So this well loop will be over and that will allow us to end the process.
So basically it's not very important to understand the techniques and syntax of this.
This just means that if we press on cue on the keyboard Well this will break the process.
No more facial recognition.
OK.
Perfect.
So actually the while loop is over so we can just go back to the main code and we have only two things
to do left.
The first thing is to turn off the webcam and to do this we take our video capture object and we're
going to use this release method to exactly turn up the webcam and eventually we need to destroy the
window inside which all the images were displayed and to do this we take our to Mudgal and then dart
and then we're going to use to destroy all Windows function and there we go the code is over.
Congratulations.
Now we're ready to detect our face and our eyes.
So let's do it right now because everything is ready.
So here we go.
I'm selecting all this.
You have to select all this code.
Make sure that you are in this fuller to be able to load the Cascades.
And if that's the case just press enter.
There we go.
The code is well executed and hi guys.
Welcome to my place.
This is actually where I'm recording all these tutorials for you.
So super happy to have you here.
As you can see well we are detecting very well my face and my eyes.
I think that's the case for you to execute your code.
So of course sometimes we see some false positive.
We can see some rectangle around my mouth detecting the eyes are open to the things that's my eye but
if I don't make too much expression or if I don't talk yet there we go.
We have this blue rectangle detects in my face and these two green rectangles detects in my eyes.
So there we go.
That works pretty well.
If you are not 100 percent convinced of the power of this model Well remember that in the next modules
we'll be using some much more powerful models open.
Definitely doesn't contain the most powerful models.
We actually saw it from module to module 2 will be about object detection and we actually tried Open
survie to detect some very cute bouncing dog that we actually filmed ourself.
But it really turned out to work very bad.
So instead we implemented a much more powerful model based on neural networks.
So hold onto that.
This is going to be interesting and mostly much more powerful.
So I was very happy to show you this.
This was just a warm up.
Keep up the good energy for what's coming next because it's going to be much more challenging but also
much more fascinating.
So I'll see you soon for the next module object detection.
But first I'll give you a little homework.
This will be the homework of this module one face detection and this will be about detecting some of
the features in the face.
So good luck with that.
And until then enjoy computer vision.