The goal of this video is to discuss the absolute value of a number.
I'm going to give you a definition and show you how to interpret the absolute value of a number.
And of course we will switch to Python and you'll see how to compute the absolute value of a number
in Python. And then also in this video I'm going to review a little bit of the syntax a little bit of
the material for printing out latex
code to make nice looking formulas. And in the exercise at the end of this video you will get a chance
to improve your programming skills in particular with regards to for loops and if statements.
All right.
So let's begin.
So I'm going to start by giving you what I consider to be a bad explanation of what the absolute value
of a number means.
And then I'll give you a good explanation.
So I would say a bad explanation is that the absolute value of a number means to strip off the negative
sign of that number.
So if the number is a negative number then you just remove the negative sign and that gives you the
absolute value.
Now that kind of is true a little bit it's not a great definition.
It is an algorithm for computing the absolute value but I think a better way to understand the absolute
value is to think of the absolute value as the distance from a number to the origin of the number line.
So let me show you what I mean by that.
So here is the number line, you can see there's zero in the middle,
negative numbers off to left, and positive numbers
off to the right. Now,
this number here is two units away from the origin,
away from zero.
And so therefore the distance is two.
So the absolute value of this number is two and this number here it's off to the left.
However it is five units away from zero.
So this distance is five units.
So therefore the absolute value of minus five is five.
Now if you are thinking that this explanation is entirely consistent with what I said is the bad explanation
of absolute value then you're correct.
In this case however when you get to learning about complex numbers in mathematics then you will learn
that there is also an absolute value of a complex number, and for a complex number that's like a two
dimensional number.
This is these real numbers, or one dimensional numbers.
When you start learning about complex numbers on a plane then the definition of absolute value as distance
to zero makes sense.
Whereas what I consider the bad definition of just stripping off the negative sign actually doesn't
make any sense.
OK so that aside, I want to show you now a little bit of notation for indicating the absolute value. It's
either abs for absolute value, and then in parentheses will be the number that you're taking the absolute
value of. Or you will also see it written out with these vertical lines around the number or around the
variable.
So this indicates the absolute value of variable x.
This notation is also pretty convenient because that is exactly how the function in Python looks.
So let's switch to Python and I'll show you this so let's start by just saying abs of four.
How about that.
So the absolute value of four is four and the absolute value of minus four is also four.
Not surprising.
Now this also works with variables.
I can say A equals minus four.
And now I can say abs of four.
And that's also going to be four.
You can also print or save this as a variable so B equals the absolute value of four.
And now I can print out a or I can print out b and this might be new syntax.
I don't believe I've shown this before; but you can print out two variables at the same time like this
with the notation a comma B and that's going to give us this output minus four and that corresponds
to the variable a and plus four which corresponds to the variable B.
All right.
So I want to do a little bit of a review of printing out with latex. So let's set some variable let's
call it X equals minus about four point three.
So now what I'd like to do is print out that the absolute value of variable x is four point three or
whatever you know whatever we happen to set X equal to. So I'm going to write display and then math.
Now here is where I put inside these single quotes.
This is where I put the latex code. So the latex code for those single vertical lines that I showed in
the slides is called the pipe symbol in Unix.
It's a vertical line. On my keyboard,
I have to press down shift and then there's the key on top of the enter key.
So on your keyboard it might be located somewhere else but you should be able to find something that
looks like this.
So this is gonna be X here.
So this is the absolute value of X equals X.
Now as I mentioned in previous videos when I'm writing out latex code I like to first write out what
I want the code to look like or put in this kind of place holders before I finish writing all of the
code.
So that's generally what it's going to look like except of course X is going to be replaced with whatever
we specify X to be here.
So this has to be percent G equals percent G.
And now here I type percent.
And then in parentheses the two items -- the two variables that are going to replace this percent G and
then this percent G.
So the first place holder is X and then the next one is the absolute value of X.
Okay.
So now I'm going to press control enter and run this.
But we get an error and it says name math is not defined.
Now I hope that you caught this before I actually ran this code and got an error. You might remember
that the display and the math functions are not actually built into the default Python workspace.
So instead we need to import these two functions and that comes from...
So we say from IPython
and now I'm also going to teach you something that might be new to you.
So there is something called tab completion.
So let's say you don't remember exactly what this was called here you knew it was Ipython.
dot something. You can actually type the tab key and that's going to show you all the possibilities
for what you can possibly complete here.
So this was called Ipython display.
So from Ipython dot display we want to import display and math and I believe that that is the correct
syntax.
So let's try it again.
Yep.
And now we get this really nice printed out message, it says the absolute value of minus four point three
is four point three.
So now it's good to play around and test a few things. We can say the absolute value of seven
is seven.
And so this seems to work well. Now it's time for the exercise.
This is your chance to show off and improve your python coding skills.
So what you want to do here is write a little bit of Python code that will print the absolute value
of each number from a set of numbers, but only print anything only print the absolute value if the number
is either less than minus five or if it's greater than two.
So here is the set of numbers: minus four six minus one 43 minus 18 two and zero.
So you have to program in this list of numbers into Python, loop through each one of these numbers individually
or loop through the set and for each number you have to print out one of two messages.
Either you print out that that number was not tested, or you print out that the absolute value of that
number is whatever the absolute value is.
So the number is not tested if it's between minus five and two.
All right.
So good luck.
Have fun.
Now is your opportunity to pause the video and then I'm going to now switch to Python and show you how
I've completed this code.
So I'm going to get started by creating this list of numbers.
Let's just call this numbers and I'll say minus 4 6 and then minus 1 43 minus 18 2 and 0.
OK.
So now we need a for loop.
We are going to... I'm going to even make some comments here. for loop over the numbers.
So let's say for... now we can call this looping variable whatever you want. I'll call it numi. num for
numbers and I for the i-th index, or just for indexing in general.
So for I in numbers because this is the set that we want to loop over, so now each iteration inside this
for loop numi -- this variable numi -- will take the value of minus four.
And then the second iteration 6 the next iteration minus 1 and so on.
OK.
So now we need to print a message but we print that message only if the number is less than minus 5
or if it's greater than 2.
Let's say if I is less than minus five or if the number is I greater than 2 and just keep in mind you
don't actually write if here again.
So it's not like this.
You don't have to do this.
You only need one if here in the beginning.
So if this is the case then we print out that the absolute value of, then it's going to be the
number, is the number.
Okay.
And I'm going to replace this with percent g this one with percent G.
And now I have to indicate what these percentages get replaced by... this was I.
I'm sorry.
No, I mean numi and then absolute value of numi.
All right.
So this code is not yet finished however it's generally good practice when programming to test your
code before writing too much code.
And that's because you want to catch errors as early as possible.
So here you go.
I've already run into an error and says name I is undefined.
OK.
So that was actually a pretty stupid mistake.
This should be numi.
and this should also be numi.
I wonder if you caught this error before I did ;)
Let's try it again.
All right.
So we get printed out the absolute value of six is six forty three and 18... so far so good.
Now we need another case to handle what happens when the number is between minus five and plus two.
So then we want a printout on the screen I think I showed that the number was not tested.
So it was not tested.
Now you could write it out like this and maybe you also wrote this out in later code like this.
It's totally fine. The way that I'm going to do this here is by converting this number, so I'm going to say
str numi.
And then plus.
So I'm going to take this number here at each iteration in the loop, convert it from a number into a
string, and then I'm using the plus sign, not for addition, but for concatenation for string concatenation
okay.
Let's run this and make sure that works.
All right.
Minus four is not tested minus one 2 and zero.
Not tested.
All right.
So that is pretty good.
Now I realize that in this code and this code this line of code and this line of code, I have showed
you three different ways of printing out information into the python display.
Now normally I would recommend keeping the display options consistent, that helps you keep better track
of your code; it makes for cleaner code.
But in this case I want to remind you of all the different options for printing out information. In this
video
I taught you (or perhaps reminded you) of the definition of absolute value and how to compute the absolute
value.
And you saw computing the absolute value in python and I hope you also got a nice refresher on creating
for loops and writing if else statements.
See you in the next video.