This video contains the bug hunt for the section probability.
So if you haven't already.
Then now is your chance to open up this file here the bug hunt file and go through all of this code
and see if you can find and fix all of the errors.
All right so I'm going to start by running this salt import num pie and map plot lib and let's see what
we're doing here.
This says show the the plus probability distribution.
So the LA plus probability function is an interesting function.
You can see it's it looks a bit like e to the minus X and this is a function that we've looked at in
earlier sections of the course.
Probably Algebra 1 or algebra 2 anyway except that it's not exactly e to the minus X. It's E to the
minus of the absolute value of X..
So here's what that function looks like it's a pretty interesting looking function.
So I don't see any coding errors and the plot kind of seems okay except this says probability distribution.
The y axis label is probability.
So that means if this is really a probability distribution then all of the values should sum to 1.
However we can see that in fact the largest value is 1.
So there is no way that this entire function sums to 1 and we can even print that out so print.
I want to write some of data and that's definitely larger than 1.
So let's see what we need to do is normalize the data.
So I'm gonna say data equals data divided by some of data.
So now these sum over all the data points is 1.
And that means that this in fact is a probability distribution.
All right let's have a look at the next cell.
So this says a shifted and stretched normal distribution.
So let's see we are creating a normal distribution.
Normal random points and then doing some plotting.
So let's see what is going wrong here.
Mm hmm.
Okay so we get some data points it certainly is normally distributed.
Let's see what this red line is supposed to be.
So this red line is supposed to be the shift parameter.
And remember the shift parameter corresponds to the offset which should be the mean of the distribution.
Now this is definitely not the mean of either or of this distribution.
So what is the problem here.
Well the problem here is actually pretty straightforward.
We just have the two parameters swapped.
So we are supposed to multiply by the stretch parameter and then add the shift parameter.
Okay.
So there you go.
That looks a lot better.
Let's see what we have next.
Here we are generating data from various distributions and then some.
This sounds an awful lot like the central limit theorem.
So let's see we are creating two signals and this is a cosine.
This is uniformly distributed random numbers that get squared.
And then here it looks like we are means centering this distribution and then creating a signal from
the to the.
Okay.
Let's just run this code and see what happens.
Again no explicit Python errors.
Here we see the.
Okay so I already see the first error here.
This is sine wave but it's actually a cosine.
Now the relationship between sine and cosine is merely a phase difference.
But still it's more accurate to write this as a cosine wave rather than a sine wave anyway.
So here's the cosine and its distribution that seems correct.
The squared uniform numbers and their distribution.
That also seems correct.
We can think about these numbers being from 0 to 1 and when we square them.
Remember that number is greater than 1 get large when they're squared.
But numbers between 0 and 1 actually get smaller after they're squared.
So it does make sense that the distribution would shift towards smaller numbers.
So and then we have the combined signal.
And based on the central limit theorem we would actually expect this distribution and the distribution
of this combined signal to be closer to a gaussian to approach or tend towards a normal distribution
relative to either the distributions individually.
So let's see what's going on here.
So what's going on here is happening in this line and what I'm actually doing or what this code is doing
is summing these distributions which is not the way that we are supposed to approach the central limit
theorem.
Instead we have to compute the histogram of these sum signals not the sum histogram.
So let's see let's do that here.
I'm going to add another line.
So this is going to say histogram data.
I think that's what HD stands for histogram data.
3 and I'll make this sig 1 plus Sig 2 and then here this is going to be HD 3.
Okay.
And let's have a look at this.
All right.
So this is also not really a full Gaussian distribution but you can see that relative to these distributions
it certainly looks more normal.
It's tending towards a normal distribution.
Okay.
Let's have a look at this one which is the last one.
So this is called a dumbbell curves.
That's pretty interesting.
I'm curious to see what this dumbbell curve looks like.
Okay.
And here we get some errors and the error says X and Y must have the same first dimension but have shapes
1000 and 2000.
Let's go back and have a look at this thing.
So it looks like we create X to go from minus one to plus two in 1000 steps and then why is appending.
So we are concatenate.
Two things we're contaminating this function.
So this is X squared times the square root of 1 minus X squared.
And then we have minus X.
Okay.
So it actually it turns out that this function is the same as this but that does mean that X is not
the same length as y.
So why is in fact twice the length of x.
So because why is the concatenation of two functions of x.
I'm going to create another variable I'll call that x x and that's going to be num pi.
Append X comma X and then here I plot x x by y OK.
Mm hmm.
That's a pretty neat looking function.
You can see why they call it a dumbbell function.
Let's see what is this warning about invalid value encountered in square root.
So now we have to think back to our math skills and try and figure out what's going on here.
So we have here the square root of 1 minus X squared.
Now the square root is not going to return a real valued result.
If what's inside the square root is negative but when X is larger than 1 or less than minus 1 then this
term here is going to be larger than this term than the number one.
So therefore everything inside the square root is going to be negative.
So I don't think this is actually the appropriate range.
I think an appropriate range for this dumbbell curve for this function is minus one to plus one.
Okay.
So that is looking better we don't get a warning here.
But now we do get an error it says S.A. not defined.
So S.A. you remember from the previous few videos this is the Seabourn module.
So that one is pretty easy to fix.
I think I'll actually go all the way back to the top and import that here.
So let's see.
Import sea borne as S.A. so run this code again and let's try to run this code and see so it looks like
we are creating.
Okay.
Brain I don't know if that's a valid type of plot.
Let's see how that kind must be either scatter regression residual Katie or hex.
So we don't get a plot here.
I think this is supposed to be a joke not scatter brain but scatter.
So here we get the original function drawn out in map plot lib.
And then here we see what's supposed to be a two dimensional histogram of the same function.
But somehow this doesn't look quite right.
Let's see what's going on here.
Aha.
So here this is plotting Y by Y.
So in fact it's really just the you know the unity line here.
This is not correct.
We have to plot X X by Y.
Let's see how this looks.
All right.
Now this is looking better.
So here you see the joint distribution of the dumbbell function over values of x and over values of
Y.
And it's also pretty interesting to see the marginal distributions that on the x axis the data are perfectly
uniformly distributed.
Now that's really not so surprising because this is X X just goes linearly spaced steps from minus one
to plus one.
And on the y axis you see that there's this kind of multi peak tri Facebook distribution where we have
a large clustering of values at the top end and at the bottom end and towards the center.
And with that that concludes this bug hunt for the section on probability theory.
I hope you found this interesting and enjoyable to work there.