This video follows up on the previous video about computing the matrix inverse.
In this video I'm going to extend that and also get into the exercise by talking about something called
these pseudo inverse.
So these pseudo inverse is an alternative procedure to the inverse.
And it's basically what you apply when you don't have a fully in vertical matrix.
And the idea of a pseudo inverse is that it gets you as close as possible to a full inverse.
And it's not necessarily a full inverse in some cases these pseudo inverse actually does act as a full
inverse.
And in other cases the pseudo inverse is basically just like the best approximation to a full inverse.
These pseudo inverse is often indicated with an asterisk or sometimes with a dagger in the superscript
instead of a minus one.
So what you want to do in the exercise for this video is compute the pseudo inverse and make images
of a and a inverse pseudo inverse and a times a pseudo inverse for the following two matrices.
First of all a five by five matrix or a matrix with five rows and five columns that contains random
integers between minus five and plus five.
So it's going to be lots of fives in this matrix.
And importantly you want to set the first column to be equal to the second column and then the second
case the second exercise here is to create a five by seven matrix of Gaussian distributed random numbers
are normally distributed random numbers and compute it's pseudo inverse.
Now I haven't actually told you how to compute these pseudo inverse in Python so you are going to have
to do a little bit of guesswork maybe a little bit of Internet searching but it shouldn't be too difficult.
You have to just figure out what is the name of the function that computes these pseudo inverse.
All right.
So now is the opportunity to pause the video switch to Python rights and code explore these pseudo inverse.
And now I'm going to switch to Python so let's get started by creating a new cell down here.
Actually I don't really like looking at all these error messages.
So I think I'm going to just fix this very quickly because this is a much nicer screen to look at.
Let's see.
So we want m equals five AND THEN A it's gonna be our random number.
So it's going to be random that Rand end and then minus.
I think I'll even do it this way minus M to M plus 1 and then it's going to be an m by m matrix.
Today is the day of the m.
I hope you use the word the letter M a lot today.
All right.
And let's just see what this matrix looks like.
Okay.
So it's a five by five matrix and lots of numbers you can see the smallest number is minus five the
largest number is five.
So that looks pretty good.
Now what we want to do is set the first column to be a a repeat of the second column and so we actually
did that in the previous video.
So that's something like this and now we print printed again and you see that all these numbers look
random.
And then this column is the same as this column.
All right.
So we already discovered in the previous video that this matrix does not have an inverse.
And in fact if you try to compute a inverse what am I doing here.
Lin announced that in.
We are going to get an error message.
OK.
However we can compute a pseudo inverse and the function is actually pretty straightforward.
It's p enough and you just input the matrix.
OK.
So I'm going to call this a P in because this is these pseudo inverse and let's have a look at this
thing Woops I meant to write print P in.
There you go.
Okay.
Well you know it still just looks like a random collection of numbers still.
It is difficult to or basically impossible to look at this matrix and just by I say something about
the relationship between this matrix the pseudo inverse and the original matrix.
Now let's see what these look like.
So I'm going to set up another figure with three subplots or subplots one by three and then just like
in the previous video I'm gonna set the first subplot to show a and the title is going to be that title
a and then a little bit of copy paste.
So this is the second or the third subplot.
And the second subplot and here I'm going to show a P in.
So this is going to be a.
And then with later coding an asterisk in the superscript.
And actually let me I would I'm curious to see what these look like before moving on.
Okay.
So here we have a.
And the pseudo inverse of A.
All right.
So now let us compute the matrix times its inverse of eight times a P in.
So and then this is going to be a little bit of copy paste here.
All right.
Pretty interesting this thing.
Whoops I see I made this same mistake again.
This has to be an ad symbol for matrix multiplication.
Okay this looks more like what I expected.
So you can see that this is definitely not the identity matrix.
However you can also see that it's like it's trying to look like the identity matrix.
You can see that the diagonal is large and the off diagonal elements are smaller.
So let's also see I'm going to print this out so we can see what this looks like.
Let's see print this out here.
And I don't really care about printing out this matrix.
Okay.
So this matrix is a times these pseudo inverse of A.
And if you look at the diagonals in fact you know what I'm gonna do to make this more clear I'm going
to say none pay it up.
Round and round this to let's say one significant digit.
Okay.
Now when you look at this matrix you can see the diagonals here this is one close to one not really
close to one and exactly one.
And this one is close to one.
And the off diagonal elements are not exactly zero but you can see that they round to zero when looking
at one significant digit.
Okay.
And now if we do let's say two significant digits you can still see that you know this matrix is trying
to be the identity matrix.
It's just not quite good enough.
All right.
So I would like to get rid of these tick marks so I'm going to remind you of a little trick that I've
introduced you to before and that is basically by treating this axis as an integral.
So I'm going to loop through this should say in going to loop through all of the axes individually and
turn off the axis.
So there you go.
So this was the first part of the exercise.
The second part of the exercise was to create a five by seven matrix.
So we we want to comment on this part because we don't need to change the relationship between the columns
but I am going to make this m plus two.
So this ends up being a five by seven matrix and we will also print this thing out.
Okay.
So here you see what this matrix looks like.
It's definitely not a square matrix harm but this is interesting.
It looks like when we compute these pseudo inverse of this matrix and multiply the matrix by its pseudo
inverse we still get exactly the identity matrix.
So that is pretty interesting.
And we can also confirm that if we tried to do this with the regular inverse.
So not these pseudo inverse then we get an error and it says well it's not possible to compute the full
inverse of this matrix.
However it turns out that for this kind of a matrix A times A pseudo inverse still gives us the proper
identity matrix Oh and you know I just realized that I I failed.
I didn't do this exercise correctly.
The exercise was actually supposed to be to create Gaussian distributed random numbers.
That is actually something like this Rand and.
Okay.
I hope you caught that mistake nonetheless.
That doesn't change the end conclusion.
We still see that a random numbers matrix times it's pseudo inverse.
Even if that original matrix is not in vertical because it's not square these pseudo inverse times the
full matrix does give us the identity matrix in this video and the previous video you learned about
the matrix inverse and you also learned about these pseudo inverse.
I introduced you to y a matrix inverse is necessary basically to solve equations matrix equations.
I showed you the two conditions for a matrix to have an inverse.
So it has to be square and every column has to be unique and I introduce you to the idea of a pseudo
inverse.
Now obviously there is a lot a lot a lot more that can be said about the matrix inverse and the pseudo
inverse but I hope you found that this video and the previous video was an interesting introduction
to the concept of the matrix inverse.