This video contains the exercise that follows up on the previous video on computing Tangent lines.
So if you haven't already watched that video then it's probably a good idea to go through that video
before going through this exercise.
So the goal of this exercise is essentially to produce a graph that looks like this.
This is a graph of Tangent lines to a function x squared and I think it's a beautiful example.
Yet another example of an intersection between aesthetic design so art and mathematics in this case
calculus.
To me this looks like some abstract eagle that is flapping its wings and zooming in for the kill.
In fact I wasn't sure whether it looked better with the white background or without any background like
this.
Maybe you can let me know in the comments.
All right let's get back to work.
There are two exercises are two components to this exercise.
The first is to create a python function that returns a tangent line given three inputs so a function
itself.
And this has to be the mathematical function a simple expression a point at which to compute the Tangent
lines.
I'm calling that X of A and domain bounds the domain bounds here I'm referring to you know the the smallest
and largest point on the x axis.
Okay so once you've created this python function then you can use that function to create this graph.
And this graph is generated using the function F equals X squared you can actually see that in this
black line here that's the X squared at points for computing the tangent.
So x of a ranging from minus to two plus two.
All right.
So now as with all of the exercises.
This is your opportunity to pause the video switch to Python.
Write some code see if you can reproduce exactly this figure this graph or at least one that looks very
close to it.
And when you're ready come back to the video and then I will show you how I solved this problem.
To produce that graph I'm going to use the simple AI module num pi module and matte plot lib.
So let's get started.
I'm going to start by creating the function so I'll call this compute tangent.
That seems like a pretty good name for a function that's going to compute the tangent.
So I said we need three inputs.
The function the point at which to compute the function and the bounds which I'll call B and D S for
the boundary points on X..
So let's start by defining the derivative and values at point X..
Sub a.
So let's see.
So we already have the function from the input so we can compute the derivative as some dot diff of
f and then we need the value of the function at point A.
And actually I think I meant to call this x sub A.
The value of the function at point X of a and the value of the derivative at point X of a.
So I will call this F A equals f that sub.
So we are substituting for X the value of a.
And now as I'm going along writing this function you have to notice that I'm making some assumptions
so I am assuming that these symbolic variable in the function f is called X..
So it's always important to keep these kinds of assumptions in mind.
Okay.
And then I need DFA and that is def subs X at X A.
So again this is giving me the derivative of the function.
This gives me the value of the function at point X equals X obey.
And this variable is going to give me the value of the derivative of the function at point X equals
X A.
Okay.
So then we need to evaluate the tangent tangent line so let's see.
So I need to create an x axis vector on which to evaluate the tangent line and that is going to be linearly
space numbers between the.
Basically the first and second point in this vector.
So here is another assumption and I'm assuming that this input is going to be a list of two elements.
So we are going to go from B and D S zero up to B and and d s 1.
Let's see.
Like this and let's go in two hundred steps.
Okay.
And so now I have all of the components that I need to create.
The tangent line now what I could do is create another variable called tangent line and then return
tangent line.
However because I only need to use this variable to return it I'm actually not even going to create
that variable I'm just going to compute the tangent line directly after the return statement here.
So you will recall from the formula that I explained in the previous video that the tangent line is
graded as the slope which is D F A times the x variable shifted by the point X A plus the Intercept
which is the function evaluated at point X of a.
So that was FAA getting a little confusing to talk about these F's and A's everywhere.
All right.
So let's run this so we don't get any errors.
Now I'm gonna need to run this next out in a loop in order to create a lot of Tangent lines to plot
them.
However before getting full on into the loop I want to just run this code once just to make sure that
it's working.
So let's start by defining the function.
I'll call that variable F and that's going to be X squared.
So now I haven't yet created X.
Let's say X equals symbols symbols and then x.
So now what I need is a vector of X points.
So I'll call it X X equals known pi.
Lynn space and let's go from minus two to plus two.
Essentially because that's what I said to use for the value of X A.
In these slides OK.
Now it's no coincidence that I'm using two hundred points here and two hundred points here.
In fact I'm also making another implicit assumption that there's going to be two hundred points to compute
or to evaluate for the tangent line.
Now another way you could have set this up would be to directly import x x here and then get the tangent
line directly from that third input.
However that's what the instructions say.
And you know I always stick to the instructions anyway.
Okay.
So let's try running this I'm going to get tan line tangent line equals compute tangent and then we
need to input F and x sub a which I haven't actually created yet.
But let's just say it's the value of 1 the point 1 and the bounds.
I'm going to say that this is going to be X X the first points and then the last point.
Okay.
So I just ran this cell which means it called this function and I haven't seen what the output is but
at least it didn't give me any explicit coding errors so I'm already pretty happy about that what I'd
like to do now is make a plot of this function and this tangent line and once I see those two graphs
then I will feel good about myself and then I can go through and finally finish this exercise.
So let's see I'm going to convert this function into a evaluate able function I'll call that f fun equals
simple land defy x F and that's going to be evaluated at all of the points in X X that I specified here.
Okay.
So now this is a vector of points of numbers that I can plot alongside this tangent line.
So let's say P L teed up plot x x by fun and then P L teed up plot x x by 10 line and then let's see
what this looks like.
All right.
Very nice very comforting.
This looks exactly like the plot that we made in the previous video.
Okay.
So now I feel confident that I've done everything the right way here.
So now what I'm going to do is run through a loop over all of the points in x sub a.
Now I haven't created a variable here for X of a.
However it actually is pretty sensible just to use all the points in X to be the x sub A's.
So I'm going to say for me we'll call this a.
So for a n x x what we want to do is get the variable y and that's going to be compute tangent we input
f we input the point a and we input the boundaries which is x x and then the first point and the last
point and then what do we do with this thing.
Well we want to plot it of course.
So I'm going to say P L T dot plots X X by Y.
And let's see if we can get rid of this and let's just see how this is starting to look all right.
This actually looks pretty neat.
It doesn't quite look like what I showed in the slides yet.
We're gonna make it look better but it already looks pretty cool.
So you can kind of see the function here.
X squared let me adjust this plot to make this look a little bit better.
So first of all I'm going to set the axis to be square and then I'm going to change the axis limits
to go from.
How about on the x axis.
Well it makes sense to go from minus two to plus two on the x axis because of what we specified up here
and the y axis.
I think something like minus one to three is gonna look good.
And now we don't need this axis to be visible so I'm going to turn that axis off and there's another
one of these typos that I've made a million times.
Hey now this is looking great.
This looks really nice.
It's not quite perfect.
It's not quite yet what we need because the colors are off but otherwise the plot itself looks good.
Okay so now getting this plot to look exactly like how I created it is a little bit tricky and I'm just
going to show you what took me a little while to figure out.
So I'm going to specify the color so I'm going to specify the RG b coordinates for this color and the
way that I set this up was to be a V S A divided by 3 a B.S. of a divided by 4 and then a B.S. a divided
by 2.
And so essentially what this is doing is setting the color to be mostly blue and a little bit less red
and even less green.
And then the purpose of having this be a B.S. is first of all that color coordinates have to go from
zero to ones.
They can't be negative whereas this looping variable a can be negative.
And secondly setting this to to be absolute values is also going to produce a curve in color space.
And that is how I got this to be a nice floating shade or alternating shades of purple going from purple
here down to it gets a bit black here and out here and then back to Purple again as we get two numbers
that are say intersection points that are further away from the origin like this Well that does it for
this video you learned about the tangent line to a function in this video and also in the previous video
where I focus more on the math and the elementary implementation.
And most importantly you made another beautiful plot.
And as I've mentioned in previous exercises where we make really nice looking plots I challenge you
to make a nicer more beautiful more interesting looking plot than this one.
And when you make it please post it to the Q and A forum so I can see it and give you the praise that
you deserve.