I have decided to call this thing a random exploding oiler.
It looks like there's this sun or star.
Do you know something in the middle is just exploding out these colorful laser beams shooting out of
this thing.
And the goal of the exercise in this video is to make this graphic.
Well you won't make exactly this graphic but something that looks remarkably similar to this.
So how did I create this.
What I did was use Oilers formula m times e to the I K where M is a length it's the distance from the
origin and k is the angle in radians and then I generated random MS and random ks to make each one of
these individual vectors and then I specified that 40 percent of these should be pink lines 40 percent
should be purple lines and 20 percent should be green lines.
Now these probabilities are actually approximate because I used random numbers to generate the colors
so random numbers to assign different probabilities to each specific vector.
So with 40 percent probability this vector could be purple with 40 percent probability it could be pink
and with 20 percent probability it could be green.
Now there are several ways several correct ways to solve this exercise and make a plot that looks something
like this.
So positive video start coding in Python see if you can figure out a way to get an image that looks
like this and now I'm going to switch to Python and show you how I solve this so I'm going to draw two
hundred vectors I'll create a variable called and vectors.
Let's make this plural and vex equals 200 and then I'm going to generate a bunch of random ends and
KS So the ends are going to be random random uniformly distributed numbers and there's going to be n
vex of them.
Now the Ks are also going to be random so uniformly distributed numbers.
But now these are not going to be numbers between 0 and 1.
They should be numbers between 0 and 2 times pi.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do now is loop over all 200 of these vectors.
So for i in range 0 2 and vex and now it turns out you actually don't need to worry about imaginary
numbers in here.
You don't need to write out the full Oilers formula because I'm going to use BLT that polar.
So this polar function where you specify the angles that's going to be chaos and then it's the ice angle
and the magnitude.
So 0 2 ends.
So this is going to create a line that goes from the origin.
So zero angle zero magnitude to this magnitude.
M with this angle.
K okay and then let's just see how this looks.
So peel.
T that show.
Whoops.
That should be a multiplication there.
Okay so we get a bunch of exploding lines coming out from the center here.
Let me turn off this axis and say peel t the Axis off.
Okay so this is already starting to look good.
We have random or vectors with random lengths and random angles.
And now what I need to do is get the color to work.
So the way that I have implemented this is with random numbers.
And that's because I want you to get a little bit more experience working with random numbers.
So here's how I did it.
So if actually not so first I want to create a random number let's just call this RSA NPD at random
that Rand.
So this is going to be some number between 0 and 1.
Now the idea is that with this uniform distribution every number between 0 and 1 is equally likely to
be selected.
So therefore there is a 40 percent probability that this number will be drawn between zero and point
four.
So I'm going to write.
If R is less than point four and there is a 40 percent chance that this statement is true then I'm gonna
set the color to be pink which is 100 percent red 20 percent green and 70 percent blue.
Okay so that's that color.
And now I say color equals color.
Now I have mentioned this before in a previous video and I'm going to say it again.
This is legal but it's a little bit confusing.
So here the word color is used as a keyword as an input into the polar function.
And here the exact same set of characters is a variable that I defined to be this RG B code.
So this can get confusing although it's legal so I'm going to change this to b c maybe I'll say S.L.
R for color so S.L. are now what do you think is gonna happen if I run this code.
Let's see.
I'm going to run this code and then we get an error and it says name CLIA is not defined.
And now let's try to run this again.
Still get no plot and no plot.
So what's happening here is that in the times that I've run it so far R has never been less than point
four.
So this variable was never defined.
Okay so let's try another once I'll say l f now I'm going to say if r is between point four and point
eight.
And the reason why I want to say that is because there is also a 40 percent chance that this randomly
drawn number from a uniform distribution has a value between point four and point eight.
So l If so else if r is greater than point 4 and if r is less than point 8 and then I specify that the
color should be this one is gonna be purple.
So in fact I'm just gonna swap the red and the blue proportions here.
There's gonna be 70 percent red 20 percent green and 100 percent blue.
Okay.
So let's try running this code again.
And now we don't get any errors but we also don't see any green lines.
Now it's no surprise that there is no green lines because I haven't specified any green lines in here.
But why don't we see any errors.
Doesn't it ever happen that R is greater than point 8 which means that this is not true.
And this is also not true.
And the answer is yes that will definitely happen that R is greater than point 8.
And in that case when R is greater than point 8 then the color the value of color C LR is going to be
the same as whatever it was in the previous iteration.
So for the previous vector so that means that this variable C LR is actually not being updated on every
single iteration of this loop approximately 20 percent of the time it's not getting updated.
Okay.
So then the last step is to say else and then we specify that the color.
Color should be green.
Which I will make just as pure green.
Like this.
Okay.
And then we get this nice exploding Euler with lasers shooting out with different colors.
Great.
As I mentioned in the beginning of this video there are multiple correct ways to solve this problem
and other problems like it.
So if you have a different solution then that's totally fine as long as your solution also works.