In this video I'm going to introduce you to the idea of a system of equations.
If you're not already familiar with that.
And then I will explain that the key to solving a system of equations is to first convert that system
from a set of equations into a single matrix equation.
And in the exercise you will also see the three possibilities for solutions to a system of equations.
So what is a system of equations anyway.
Well it's just a set of coupled equations that might look something like this.
In this case in this particular example we have three equations and also three variables x y and z.
And the idea the reason why this is a system and not just three totally separate equations is that these
X's these Y's and these Zs are all exactly the same.
So any X that satisfies this equation also has to work for this equation and for this equation.
So these are coupled equations.
So how do you go about solving a system of equations like this.
If you're working with let's say two equations and two variables then solving a system of equations
can be pretty easy.
You just have to look at the numbers and make some educated guesses.
But for a larger system like this and for practical applications these systems of equations can get
huge.
It's really not feasible just to kind of try and guess and poke around a little bit.
So the solution is to convert this system of equations into a single matrix equation.
So that looks like this.
So here you see a matrix of vector equals another vector.
So this matrix comes from the coefficients on the left hand side.
So you can see all of the numbers that are multiplying these variables are the coefficients.
So the first row is two one minus one.
And here you see two one minus one and so on down here you have three four and two three four two and
one minus five and minus two.
And that you see here.
So this is the matrix of coefficients.
Here you see the vector of the variables.
So in this specific example there are three variables.
So you see one two three variables here and this is a vector on the right hand side of the equation
of the constants These are called the constants so 1 13 0 and that's just copied over here.
Now we can actually just rewrite this in a more general form by calling this matrix X. capital X. This
matrix beta and this matrix or this vector Y.
So in other words what we've done is convert this system of equations into a single equation where we
have matrices and vectors.
So here you see this form again.
So x times beta equals Y.
Now X is some matrix of known numbers Y is also known numbers but beta contains the unknown coefficients
X Y and Z.
So how do we solve for beta.
Well I actually introduced this concept to you in a previous video.
I think it was two videos ago where I talked about the matrix inverse and why we need a matrix inverse
now in this specific example that I showed here.
This is a three by three matrix.
So this matrix actually is in vertical.
We can compute x inverse and then solve for beta that way.
But we also need a more general solution that's going to work even if we have a rectangular shaped matrix.
So for example if you would just add a fourth equation here a fourth couple the equation.
Now this matrix is no longer in vertical and yet we still need to solve for beta somehow.
And that's where this solution comes in.
So it turns out that this solution so X transpose X and then this whole thing inverted times X transpose
times the vector Y.
So this is a general solution that will work regardless of whether x is square or rectangular.
This is called the least squares solution.
This is perhaps one of the most important equations in all of statistics the least squares solution.
It is the underlying solution to regression and Nova and general linear models and so on.
Now going through the proof that this really is the right solution and then it's the best way to solve
for b is a little bit outside the scope of this video it's not a terribly difficult proof but it's something
that takes a little bit more time to work through.
Instead what I want to focus on now is showing you how to implement this kind of a solution in python
what I'm going to do here is create exactly the system that I showed you in the slides.
So I'm gonna create the matrix X so that is a matrix it's a known pi array and it has three rows.
So this is gonna be the first row the second row and the third row.
And then the first row was to come one come up minus one.
The second row was three come a four comma two.
And the third row was one minus five and minus two.
So this was the matrix X and then we have the vector Y.
And that was 1 13 and 0 and then the idea was we need to solve for beta.
So how do we solve for beta.
So I'm going to do this in two ways.
And in fact maybe I'll call this beta 1.
So Lin LJ that in so what I'm gonna do first is implement the formula directly that I showed in the
slides.
So that was X transpose matrix multiplication with X and then matrix multiplication X transpose times
vector y.
Okay.
So I ran this cell and we don't get any errors so that's good I didn't make any silly little typos and
let's see what this result happens to be.
So Beta 1 so the solution happens to be 3 minus 1 and plus 4.
And if you like what you can do now is pause the video and go back to the slide where I showed the system
of equations and prove to yourself that when x equals three y equals minus one and z equals four That
all three of those equations are true.
Okay so this is a rather long way to write it out.
It turns out there's a shortcut which is also computationally more stable and that is I'll call that
beta 2 and that is to use known PI that Lin ouch dot solve.
So we are solving for a system of equations and then you simply input the coefficients matrix X and
the constants vector Y.
So this was the left hand side of the equation the right hand side of the equation and the output of
this solve function is going to be the data value and let's print this out.
So Beta 2 now.
No surprise we get exactly the same solution whether we use this method or this method.
Now in practice this method is better not only because it's fewer characters to write out but also because
here we are explicitly inverting this matrix and Matrix inversion is something that's best avoided whenever
possible.
So Python has advanced numerical processing libraries that actually figure out how to solve this set
of equations without using the explicit matrix inverse the exercise for this video is to implement these
three different systems and compute their results analytically as I just showed you in Python and also
geometrically by plotting.
So what do you want to do here.
So what you want to do is first implement each of these systems of equations as matrix vector equations
in Python.
So I already showed you how to do that.
In that example of a three by three system of equations.
So three equations in three variables.
And this is even a little bit easier because here you have two equations in two variables.
And just note that this is a system.
This system is totally separate from this system.
That's why I call this X1 and X2 and X3.
So these two are the same.
These two are the same x2 and x 2 These two are the same because this is its own system but the solution
to this system is not going to be the same as the solution to this system.
Okay.
So implement these three systems.
That's part 1 part 2 is to solve for x and y.
And again each of these systems needs its own separate solution and then part 3 is to draw lines for
each equation.
So each of these equations can be represented as a line in a two dimensional space so an x y axis and
to get that to work to be able to plot this in a line.
You're gonna need to do a little bit of algebra first and that's because this is not the typical expression
that you see for a line.
Typically you see the form of Y equals M X plus B.
And of course I had a couple of videos about this in an earlier section of the course.
I think it was algebra 2.
So you're gonna need to do a little bit of conversion to be able to plot lines but once you do you can
see that there's two equations.
So for each system there's going to be two separate lines on the plot.
All right.
So good luck.
Switch to Python write some code.
This exercise is a little bit more challenging than many the other sect exercises in this course but
I believe that you can do it.
I am going to start by creating the variables x 1 and why 1 and x 2 and Y 2 and so on so x 1 was a known
pi array.
So a matrix and it's going to have 2 rows and in fact I think to make this even easier for myself I'm
going to write out this like these shells.
So this is X and Y and then I'm going to copy and paste and so then it's gonna be easy for me to replace
this with system 1 system 2 and system 3.
So let's see system 1 was the first row was 3 minus 1 and the second row was minus 1 1 and then why
it was 6 and 2.
Okay then we get to System 2 that had coefficients 3 comma minus 1.
You can see that a lot of these systems are pretty similar.
They're not exactly identical but they are pretty close to each other.
This was six comma three four why.
And then here we had and I believe this one was exactly the same as system two in terms of the coefficient.
So one point five comma minus point five.
And then this was 6 and 2.
So in fact the only difference between system 2 and system 3 was this one number here.
All right.
So that is all of our x's and y's and what I'm going to do next is generate the plot and solve for the
solution for each one of these systems separately.
So let's go for Case 1.
So this is set 1.
So the first thing I'm going to do is plot.
So we need to convert to Y equals M X plus B format.
So this one is a little bit tricky to figure out but I hope you managed to solve it.
So I'm gonna call this variable y y 1 because this is going to be the y coordinates for equation y one.
So if you write this all out it turns out to be x 1 0 0 divided by x 1 0 comma 1 times.
Well we need to specify some X limit which I haven't yet specified plus y 1 0 divided by x 1 0 comma
1.
Okay.
So let me create an X limit variable here.
So we are going to draw the plots on the x axis from zero to 10.
Okay.
So let me take a moment to explain what this equation means.
Essentially we need to convert this equation into Y equals M X plus B.
And so the way to do that is to subtract the coefficient for x 1 from both sides so we say minus.
In this case 3 x 1 and subtract that from both sides and then divide by whatever is the coefficient
on y one.
So then this entire right hand side of the equation needs to be divided by the coefficient for y one.
And that's what I'm doing here.
So this is the minus X coefficient here and then I'm dividing by the Y 1 coefficient here.
Okay.
So this was for the first equation in system 1.
So then I'm going to copy and paste this for the second equation.
So the second equation is exactly the same code except we use the second row instead of the first row.
So I'm just replacing these first zeros with ones okay.
And again run the cell C that I didn't make any silly typos to get Python errors.
And now let's generate the plot so I will write P L T dot plot x limb and y y 1 and let's make this
a blue line and the label is going to be equation 1 and then copy paste all of this stuff is the same.
Well a lot of it is the same.
I'm gonna make it a red line and this is now equation 2.
Okay.
And then I'm going to activate the legend.
I'm going to make a grid and let's see what this thing looks like.
All right.
This is pretty interesting.
It looks like these two lines corresponding to these two equations actually meet they cross each other
right here and that is no coincidence.
It turns out that if you draw a line corresponding to each of the equations in a system of equations
then the solution to that system of equations is exactly where the lines cross each other.
So the solution here is you know X equals 4 and Y equals.
Maybe this is 6.
Okay so let's see what the exact solution is.
So I'm going to solve the system.
So I'll call that B for beta equals and Peter Lin alleged solve and then this is x1 and y one and when
I'm going to do now is both print out the solution and I'm also going to put a draw a dot on this plot
where the solution is so P L T dot plot and this is going to be the x component of B and the y component
of B and let's make this a black circle and I'll make this a nice big circle and then we have to give
this a label and the label is going to be the solution.
All right that was pretty cool.
So the solution turns out to be for 6 and we see that that solution geometrically is the location where
these two lines intersect.
Very nice.
So now what I'm going to do is just copy and paste all of this code because System 2 is essentially
the same so the code is of course all the same but we just need to be really careful about changing
all of these ones into twos so this becomes a two that becomes a two.
Here and here and I want to be really careful to check that I don't need this anymore.
I almost missed this one has to be 2 and 2 also super important and everything else looks good.
Mm hmm.
Here we get an error.
This says singular matrix and we only actually see one line here so what is going on.
Let's see first of all I'm going to just comment out this code so we can take a closer look at what's
going on here.
I'm going to change this from a solid red line into a dashed red line.
And the reason why I did that is so you can see that both of these lines are oversight are overlapping
So in fact these two equations are exactly the same.
And that's actually visible when you just look at them.
Maybe you notice this or maybe you hadn't noticed it yet but if you take the second equation and multiply
it by 2 you're going to get exactly this equation.
So what does that mean.
That means that there is an infinite number of solutions to this system.
There is no unique solution because you know the solution is where these two lines intersect.
But these two lines intersect everywhere.
In fact there isn't a single point where these two lines do not intersect.
Okay.
So in fact nothing went wrong here.
We didn't make any coding errors.
We didn't do anything wrong.
This is simply a degenerate system of equations.
It has an infinite number of solutions and therefore it's not actually a terribly interesting set of
system of equations.
Okay so let's see what's going on with the 3rd system.
So again all of the code is the same.
We just need to be really really careful about changing all of these ones to threes where appropriate.
So let's see there.
And in solving.
And let's see what's happening here.
Oh another error.
Mm hmm.
Another singular matrix.
And here we get a slightly different picture now the two lines corresponding to these two equations
in this system are parallel.
They never touch.
So that means that there is no solution to this system of equations.
This system of equations does not have a unique solution.
There is no set of x and y values that can simultaneously satisfy both of those equations I hope you
found this lecture interesting and insightful.
I covered a system of equations how to solve a system of equations by converting it into a matrix equation.
And in the exercise you saw the three possibilities for solutions to a system of equations.