The goal of this video is to show you how to use Python to visualize matrix vector multiplication so
matrix vector multiplication is an algebraic procedure but it also has a geometric interpretation and
this geometric interpretation is actually pretty interesting and it's really insightful because that
is going to be an intuition a foundational understanding for ion vectors and what it means for a particular
vector to be an icon vector of a matrix.
And in the exercise you're going to get to make more beautiful art using the intersection between math
and coding.
All right so let's just dive right in and start with coding in Python.
I'm going to start by creating a matrix.
I'll call this matrix M.
It's going to be a two by two matrix and that's because a two dimensional matrix facilitates visualizing
in two dimensions of course.
So let's see there's going to be two rows and I'm going to put these in two separate lines of code like
this.
So the first row is going to be point five comma one.
And the second row will be one comma.
Point five.
Okay.
So here is our two by two matrix.
And now I'm gonna come up with a vector.
I'll make this a num pi array and let's say one comma too it doesn't really matter exactly what elements
This vector has in fact I'm going to even generate some random vectors in a moment.
Okay.
So now we have our matrix M and our vector V and now I'm going to compute matrix vector multiplication
by multiplying M times V.
All right so let's already run this cell and we don't get any any errors.
We don't see any python coding errors so that's a good sign.
So now I'm going to make a plot I'm going to make a plot of vector V and vector envy.
Now we can't really make a line plot of Matrix m because it has two elements.
We could make plots of the rows or of the columns but that's not really relevant here.
So I'm going to plot two vectors in standard position.
So that means they start from the origin and this first vector is gonna go to the first element of vs
the x coordinate a V and then the y component of this line is going to be the second element of V.
And what do you say we make this a blue line and let's make it nice and thick so line width with equals
How about two.
So this is plotting V and then let's already show that.
Okay.
Again I'd just like to make sure that we haven't made any coding mistakes so far.
You have learned throughout this course that I am prone to making coding mistakes.
Let's see and I'm also going to set the axis to go from minus five to plus five on both the x and y
axes.
And how about a grid P L T dot grid.
All right.
This is starting to look pretty professional.
Let's see I want to label in here.
So this is going to be label equals V.
Pretty straightforward label P L T dot legend.
All right.
So now we're ready to plot envy.
So I'm just gonna copy and paste all of this and basically just hear the V's need to go to m these and
let's make this a red line maybe a red dash line.
How about that and then MTV and now little drum roll we get to see what this looks like.
OK so this looks pretty interesting.
We see here is the original vector and here is the matrix times the vector.
So there are two interesting things that we can observe about the matrix vector product compared to
the vector itself the original vector V.
So you take a vector and you multiply it by a matrix and generally there are two things that happened
to this line.
When you multiply it by a matrix one is you either stretch or shrink the vector so you can see that
this matrix made the vector a little bit longer.
So the length is larger and what's obviously more noticeable is that it rotated the angle so it looks
like this angle got rotated back.
Maybe this is like minus 15 degrees approximately.
And that is generally what happens when you take a vector and multiply it by a matrix the matrix will
do two things it's going to expand or shrink the vector and it's going to rotate the vector.
So it's going to point off in some other direction.
And so just to illustrate that to you you know I want to convince you that this matrix didn't rotate
this vector just because these are the particular numbers that I happened to pick.
So instead I'm gonna say V equals random that Rand N to sun.
Now just making up totally random numbers.
And now you can see every time I make up these random numbers the plot changes every time.
But we almost always see the same thing that the resulting vector.
So the matrix times the vector is either stretching or compressing but more importantly it's rotating
it.
So it's not pointing in the same direction as the original vector.
Okay.
And now I'd like to try something else so now I'm going to replace this let's comment this out.
I'm going to change this vector so I'm going to make this the vector 1 1 huh.
And now look this is pretty interesting.
So now these two vectors are actually pointing in the same direction and they're along the same line.
Now the red vector envy is a little bit longer so it does look like the Matrix stretched out the vector
a little bit but it didn't actually change the direction.
And if you remember back to the video towards the beginning of this section on scalar vector multiplication
then this is actually the geometric perspective of scalar vector multiplication.
So when you multiply a vector by a scalar you don't change its direction you just make it either longer
or shorter.
So that's pretty interesting we multiply this vector by this matrix and it's almost like we just multiplied
by a vector by a scalar by a single number.
So that's not to say that this matrix is a single number but the effect of this specific matrix on this
specific vector and not any other vector was that the matrix is kind of acting like a scalar on this
vector.
So now that was one example I'm going to try another example I'll just take this vector to B minus one.
And here we get another interesting thing so now it looks like the original vector is pointing this
way the matrix times the vector looks like it's it kept the vector on the same line if you imagine this
like infinitely long line going like this so we have the matrix times the vector on that same line but
pointed in the other direction.
And let's see you know we can change this.
The minus sign over here and that's just going to flip it around.
Okay.
So here was this.
Generally this concept that mostly when you multiply a matrix by a vector the resulting vector points
off in some other direction.
But there are some very specific cases of vectors and matrices that when you multiply them together
the effect of the matrix on the vector is basically just the same as scalar multiplication.
So that is an important concept that you should keep in mind for the next video.
I think it's the next video when I introduce I can composition let's make some art.
What do you think about this.
I think it looks really beautiful.
It almost looks 3D it's like these two fans that are intersecting that are kind of going through each
other.
In fact this is just a two dimensional plot.
I'm going to show you what I did to create this plot.
Well I'm not going to show you everything.
I'm going to give you some guidelines for creating a plot like this.
And then the goal of this exercise is basically to reconstruct this image or something that looks a
lot like it.
Okay.
So start with this matrix M and this vector one a.
So this first element of vector V stays fixed and then the idea is that you change this element a to
b a bunch of numbers that range from minus two to plus two.
And what you're seeing here is a plot a V and a plot of M times V all on the same graph.
So it's a little bit similar to what we just did in Python except now the vector is getting is changing
at each iteration according to this range.
All right.
So positive video.
Have a go at this I think producing this image probably isn't so difficult figuring out exactly how
a set these colors is probably the hardest part.
But don't worry if you don't get that that's just aesthetics.
And now I am going to switch to Python.
I will show you how I will implement this and I will reveal my secrets for how I made these colors all
right so let's get a new cell in here.
So I'm going to create a variable a.
It's going to be linearly space numbers between minus two and plus two.
And let's go for 40 steps.
The number of steps is a little bit arbitrary but 40 is the number that I picked.
OK.
So now I'm going to loop through let's call this.
Actually no.
Just to be more consistent.
I think I would call this looping variable name a n and then I need to rename this I call this V comp
because it's the component of V.
So for a in V comp let's see.
So I'm going to start by creating the vector so num pi array the first element is always 1 and the second
element is a.
And then I create M V and that is simply M times V.
And now depending on where you are with the code you may or may not need to define M that matrix that
I showed in the slides is actually exactly this matrix here.
So I already have it from the previous cells so I don't need to reconstruct it again.
Okay.
And then we're going to plot.
So I'm going to copy and paste some of this code here because a lot of this is the same.
So let's see.
I'm going to get rid of the color and the label first I just want to make sure that I can get this plot
looking nice.
Let's see plot Dot.
Show all right.
So already we can see that we're getting there now.
Which one of these fans is V and which one of these fans is M V.
Well this first one that's kind of fanning out to the right here.
This one is V and you can tell because the first element is always the number one.
So the X axis coordinate is always going to be one.
Okay.
So this is starting to look pretty good.
I'm going to set the axis to be square and turn off the axis.
So now this is basically complete except for the colors.
So now let me reveal my secrets and show you how I created this color.
So the original vector V.
That's again this fan that's sort of coming off straight to the right over here.
I set this to be.
So the red component is 1 minus a B.S. of a divided by four the green component is fixed at point five
and the blue component is a B.S. I divided by two.
And then I also set an alpha of point two.
So it's gonna be partially translucent.
Okay.
A little typo there.
All right.
So that is for V and then for m.
These are the transformed vector that one I set to be one minus the absolute value of a divided by two.
And then the green channel was the absolute value of a divided by four.
And then Blue was fixed at point five.
And I didn't set any color transparency on this one.
I see this is too light.
This was actually set to be point eight.
Aha.
Okay.
There you go.
And this light transparency also gives it this kind of 3D field because you can actually see the matrix
times the vector behind the vector itself the original vector so you know by this point in the course
that I'm a big fan of encouraging you to feel inspired by this general approach and come up with something
that looks better and more artistic than what I have here.
And when you do please post it along with your code if you like to the Q and A form I would be very
enthusiastic to see what kind of art and sort of interaction between math and art that you have come
up with.
So the art is great of course but the main point of this video was to illustrate to the idea of visualizing
matrix vector multiplication and in particular the geometric interpretation of matrix vector multiplication
leads to building intuition for ion vectors.
And that is coming up so stay tuned.