In this video I'm going to discuss the natural exponent and the logarithm.
I'll show you a little bit about what these functions look like and then in the exercise you will get
to use python as a tool to help you visualize the fact that these two functions and natural exponent
and the logarithm are in verses of each other.
So the natural exponent or e to the X and the natural logarithm or the log of x are nonlinear functions
that have this kind of curved shape like this.
So if we look at the function Y equals E to the X then for various ranges of X E to the X gets arbitrarily
close to zero.
So it never gets to be zero but it becomes really really really close to zero as X goes to minus infinity
and then up here y.
So the function each of the X goes up to plus infinity as x gets larger.
So that's the function e to the X.
And now if we look at the log of x of the natural logarithm of x you can see it also as kind of a similar
shape in the sense that it's bent and it looks like it's going to infinity in both directions.
However in this case the log of x goes down to minus infinity on the y axis.
You can see these numbers are getting smaller as X goes towards zero and now the log of x is not defined
for any negative numbers.
So if you would try to take the log of a negative number you would end up getting a complex number.
And that's why on this graph here you only see positive values of x and going up this way.
The logarithm basically continues to grow up to infinity here as x gets arbitrarily large.
However it grows to infinity slower and slower and slower unlike either the X which grows to infinity
faster and faster.
I'm not going to demonstrate to you these two functions in Python so we're going to use the NUM pi module
and the map plot lib dot pi plot module.
So I'm going to start by creating a variable X and let's set that to be linearly spaced numbers go from
minus three to plus three.
In How about a high.
Actually no.
Hundred is too much of a nice round number.
Let's go for ninety nine steps between minus three and plus three.
So now I'm going to generate a plot of X by e to the X which is N.P. num pi dot X and then X in parentheses.
So in the mathematical formula you have e to the power of x.
And here in Python this syntax would be exp and then in parentheses is whatever would go into the exponent.
All right.
So let's see what this looks like.
So this is the function each of the X and it's essentially just what I showed in the slides.
So I'm just gonna attach a Y axis and an x axis labels so plot the X label.
This was facts and then plot that y label.
Now I could write e to the peoples e to the power of x like this.
However this doesn't really look so great.
What I would like to do is convert this to latex to get the x into the exponent of E and so to do that
you will recall that inside just a bit of string in here for graph labels you can use a dollar sign
on either side.
So that converts to later code but the latex code for getting exponents or suit prescription is not
a double asterisk.
Instead it is the carat symbol like this.
Okay so now we get e to the x all right.
So that looks pretty good.
Now what I'm gonna do is plot the natural log of x.
Now I could plot this in a separate cell a separate cell of code however I want to show you that you
can use the same cell of code and generate a different graph so get a different axis.
As long as you have the dots show in here to display this plot.
Okay.
So in fact what I'm gonna do is copy and paste.
And now this is going to be n p dot log of x.
And of course this has to be the log.
And for this we don't really need latex code I'll just write log of x like this.
Okay so now notice we get two separate plots so this one corresponds to either the X and this lower
one corresponds to the log of x.
Now we're also getting a warning notice.
This is not an error message.
This is just a warning.
And remember that error messages are things that you urgently need to deal with.
There is something wrong with your code.
If you get an error message if you get a warning message it doesn't necessarily mean there's anything
wrong.
Python is just saying hey you better check this out because your code could be different from what you
expect.
So here are these two warning messages are related to negative values of x and also zero values of x
in the log function.
Now I already know that the log of x is not defined in the real numbers for zero or negative numbers.
So therefore I'm just going to ignore this warning.
I think it's fine.
Okay.
And then the last thing is just to drive home this point about generating two different plots in the
same cell.
If I were to comment out this line plot that show then we would actually see both of these lines plotted
on the same graph.
Now of course this can also be useful if you want to see them on the same graph.
But this shows the importance of this plot that show function.
Now it turns out that e to the X and the log of x are inverse functions of each other.
And that means that if you would embed one function into the other function you basically did the two
functions will cancel each other out.
So for example if you would say e to the X where you're replacing X with the log of x.
So in other words eat the log of x then that ends up just being equal to x.
And that's really the main point of this exercise here.
What you want to do is generate two data series two time series.
Here I call them Y 1 and Y 2.
And you said why one to be equal to the log of each of the x and y 2 to be equal to E 2 the log of x.
Notice here the entire logarithm is in the exponent and you can use X ranging from point 0 0 0 1.
So basically just a little bit above zero going up to 10 and then you want to generate a plot that looks
like this.
And the reason why you see a straight line here is that you're plotting X by Y 1 or y two.
But as I just mentioned the log and the natural exponent cancel each other out.
So these two cancel out.
So in fact y one equals x and y two equals x.
So really you're just plotting X by X here.
All right.
So now is your opportunity to pause the video switch to Python and write some code to produce this graph.
And now I will switch to Python and show you how I would go about solving this.
All right.
So let's start by creating our variable X so that's known pi.
Lynn space point 0 0 0 1 10.
And I didn't actually tell you how many increments to go between point 0 0 1 and 10 but let's just say
10.
Okay so now I'm going to write why 1 equals num Pi the log of num pi exp x.
So this is now the natural logarithm of E to the X and we want y to to be essentially just the opposite.
So number pi that he XP and then inside here we get none paid out log of x.
Now notice again how I'm using spaces here none of these spaces are necessary but I think having spaces
inside these functions helps the reader.
It will help you and other people who might be reading your code in the future understand that this
is one function embedded inside another function.
Okay.
So that's for y one and Y two.
And now we just need to make a plot so P L teed up plot x by y 1 and let's make this one a blue line
and I'll give this the label of log of E to the X..
Now I want this to be latex code and actually you know let me get back to this I want to make sure that
we get a nice looking plot first and then we can come back and worry about some of the finer details
here.
Okay.
So then the second one was basically the same so why are X come up Y two.
And this one was orange dots so I'll just leave that as a circle and the label here is going to be e
to the log of x and again I'm going to worry in a few moments about making this look a bit nicer.
Okay.
So BLT that show.
And this looks good although actually the colors are different from what I showed in the slides.
I mean just get rid of the blue.
Okay so now the colors look good of course we don't see the legend here and you already know why and
that is the answer is that we have to activate the legend like this.
All right.
So this is basically finished.
Maybe I'll make this access Square actually that should look a little bit nicer appeal to you that access
square.
Okay now the last thing I want to do is just touch this up a little bit so that the legends look a little
bit nicer so let's make this latex code like this so therefore we get X in the superscript of E.
So that looks good except now the log is in italics so we can actually write slash slash here and that's
going to activate the latex version of log which is actually just going to make this b normal upright
text.
Okay so then here let's see if this is working.
Mm hmm.
This actually looks like it says the dog and you can see there's a tiny little sliver of a lineup here.
This is actually the L up here.
So what we need to do is tell latex that all of this text should go into the superscript not just the
first letter after the carat symbol.
And so to do that we use curly brackets as you will remember and then I'm also going to put slash slash
here for the log.
All right so that looks pretty good.
I think so in this video you learned about the natural exponent and the logarithm and plotting them
in Python.
And importantly you learned how to use python as a tool to show that two functions in this case the
natural exponent and the natural logarithm are inverse of each other.
So when you in bed one into the other they end up canceling each other out.