This is going to be a really exciting video.
I know,
I know, I say that about almost all the videos. But this one really is exciting.
And that's because you are going to learn how to create your very own functions in Python. Creating functions
is a really important skill for python and programming in general.
And so without further ado let's jump straight to Python and I'm just going to start coding and you will
see how easy it is to create your own functions. So to create a function all you have to do is type def
def.
That's for define.
And then the name of the function, let's call it my function.
And then we need parentheses and a colon.
Now I'm going to explain more about what each of these things mean
throughout the video.
But I just want to dive right in and show you how easy it is.
So let's say print... you know people always do "hello world."
It's like a typical thing for programming.
OK.
So notice when I run this cell, nothing happens. We don't get any errors or any warning messages.
Nothing particularly interesting happens.
But now I can type myfunction and I actually use tab complete here.
So I wrote myfun and then I pressed the tab key on the keyboard, and it auto completed because Python
already recognizes this as a function.
And then parentheses indicate that I'm calling a function.
Now when I run this code it prints out hello world.
So basically Python -- even though I'm not running this cell, when I ran this cell
nothing happened.
I'm running this cell here, but this cell is calling this function, which is defined in the python workspace.
And what's inside that function is just this.
So hello world.
All right.
Not a super useful function but it's a great place to start.
Now functions can take inputs and that you've seen many times before.
So for example you can say int and then three point two.
So the input into the integer function, the int function, is three point two, and the output is the number
three, it's the integer from the input.
Okay.
So here it works the same way.
So I'm going to write.
Let's write
name. So I'm going to create a new variable in here.
Call it name and then instead of saying hello world, this is going to say percent s and then.
Percent name.
So now this is interesting: I ran this cell again and I haven't actually defined any variable called
name.
And to show you how weird that is, that we didn't get any errors.
if I just say name here, python is going to say Name name is not defined.
Kind of funny but the variable
that's what this means -- the variable name is not defined.
However when I ran this code here nothing happened.
Python didn't give me any errors.
So the variable name is the input into this function.
And this is how I'm using that input variable.
So now I can run my function and let's put it in my name is Mike.
And now this function is going to print.
Hello Mike.
And that's because the input into this function is here is called name.
But here I call it Mike.
And then that variable gets used over here.
Now because this is a course about using python as a tool to learn mathematics, not using python as a
tool to say hello to yourself, I'm going to change this function.
Actually I'm even going to get rid of it and start from scratch.
So essentially what I want to do is create a function that will print out the remainder, so the integer
division and the remainder, just like what we did in a previous video, except there in the previous video
we were writing everything out.
And here I'm going to put it into a function. So let's call this function computeremainder. And this
function needs two inputs.
I'll call them X and Y and that's going to correspond to the numerator and the denominator or basically
the thing that you are dividing and the thing that you're dividing into.
So from that previous video I call these variables.
I think I call it divis and that was the integer of X divided by Y and then we have the remainder and
that was x percent Y.
Now if you're not sure what this means here, this percent Y in the modulus operator, then you might want
to go back and consult that previous video on the remainder and the modulo operator.
OK so now I've done a little bit of math with these two inputs here, separated by commas and now I want
to print out the results. I'm going to write print.
Let's see it's going to be Y goes into x N times with a remainder of M.
Okay.
Now obviously we need to replace a lot of these letters here.
And these are all going to be numbers.
So these all get replaced with percent G.
So percent G goes into percent G percent G times with a remainder of percent G.
By the way you'll notice that there's also a bit of character overloading here. This term overloading
in programming means when you use the same term or the same function or the same concept multiple times
to indicate very different things in different context.
So here the percent sign is used as a modulus the modulo operator.
And here the percent sign is used to indicate a text replacement.
So now we need yet another percent sign, these percent signs are all over the place here.
So we say why goes into X divis times with a remainder of this variable remainder.
All right.
So now I'm going to run this cell again.
I haven't defined X or Y, and yet when I run this cell we don't get any errors. We don't get any errors
because we are just defining a function here and here I'm going to actually call that function and say
compute remainder.
Now notice what happens if I call the function without giving any inputs whatsoever.
We get an error.
It says it's missing two required positional arguments x and y.
So basically python is trying to run this function but it says hey! we need a input x and we need an
input y.
Okay.
So let's provide some inputs.
So I'm going to use the same numbers that I did in the previous video.
So three goes into.
Three times with a remainder of one.
That's really great.
I know that that answer is correct.
I wonder how many times do you think six goes into a hundred.
The answer is 16 times with a remainder of four.
All right.
That's pretty neat.
But we can get even better than that.
Let's say I want to use this function to be able to type in some user input so I don't want to have
to hard code these numbers here.
I want Python to ask me what two numbers to use.
So to do that we need a different function.
So I'm going to copy and paste this here.
Now I have two functions.
I can run this code here and that's going to override this function here.
So then I lose this function. However, that's generally confusing and not really great programming.
So what I'm going to do instead is rename this function. Let's call it division with input.
And now I'm not going to put any inputs directly into the function because instead I'm going to ask
the user for input.
So I'm going to write X equals... now I'm going to use this function called input.
This might be a new python function for you.
Maybe you haven't seen this before.
It's actually really simple and actually maybe I'll take a moment to explain how this works.
I'm going to add a new cell... insert cell below. And here I will say let's say a equals input input a number.
Now I'm going to run this cell and you can see Python here says input a number -- that's exactly the text
I wrote here -- and I'm going to write on it just some random number like this and now I'm going to say
insert a new cell below.
Now I can print out what A is, and A is this number here except a isn't actually that number; a is in fact
a string.
You can see it has these single quotes around it.
In fact, if we write type A and you can see that a is a string.
So if I want to actually use this as a number I would need to make this an integer so I can say int and
then input a number.
So now input... let's say sixty five.
So notice what I'm doing.
I'm using one function and I'm directly embedding that function into another function.
So the output of this function "input" becomes the input to this function int.
It's a little bit confusing with all the words but I hope you get the idea.
Now we can see the type of a is an int; it's now an integer.
So this is no longer the string sixty five.
It's actually the number sixty five.
And that's convenient because I can add, you know, three point two.
OK.
So with that out of the way what I'd like to do now is input the two numbers.
I want to input x and we'll call that the the input the numerator
and then I need a Y and that's going to be input.
The denominator.
all right.
And then the rest of this is the same.
Now I'm going to run cell, make sure we don't get any errors and we didn't.
That's a good sign.
So now we can run this division with input and let's see if this works.
All right.
So input the numerator. So far this is looking good.
The numerator will be 10 the denominator or the division is going to be three... oops!
And then we get an error. The error says it's a type error and basically unsupported operand type
for a division string and string.
So this is maybe not the most interpretable error but you can see it has something to do with a type
of the variable something to do with division and something to do with the string.
So let's go back to the code and see if we can figure out what the problem is.
So the problem is related to what I explained up here: When I input these numbers I was typing in numbers
on the keyboard and I'm thinking about these numbers.
But in fact Python has interpreted these as strings and I'm trying to divide a string by a string which
doesn't make sense.
You might as well try to divide w by h.
It's not a sensible operation.
So the solution, which you might have already guessed, is to encase these inside the int function to convert
these into integers.
OK.
And now let's try this again.
Now we say input the the numerator.
Let's make that 10, the denominator will be three, and then we get a nice result.
Three goes into 10
three times with a remainder of 1.
Now this is not yet a perfect function.
There's some other weird things that can happen with this function.
One is that because I'm converting this into an integer, if you try this with a decimal. Let's say the
numerator is ten point four and we already get an error.
And that's because the int function doesn't know how to deal with a string that already includes a decimal
point.
So you can see here the importance of testing out your code with a range of different types of inputs.
Now this is not a problem that I'm going to fix in this video because I want to focus more on the basics
of defining functions and working with functions.
You will see later on in the course how to deal with this kind of error and how to avoid this issue.
I hope you enjoyed this video and found it useful.
You learned the basics of creating functions in Python including how to get user input to make your
code more interactive.
I'm going to continue teaching you about working with functions over the next several videos.
So please keep watching.