In this video you are going to learn the formula for a Gaussian function.
This is also sometimes called the bell curve or the normal curve.
If you are not already familiar with what a galaxy and looks like then you will soon learn.
And I'm sure you've seen a function that looks like this before.
And then that's going to lead us into a discussion of how to find a particular point on a function.
That's pretty cool.
We're gonna do a little bit of arithmetic a little bit of algebra and obviously you are going to see
how all of this stuff looks in Python code.
So let's begin.
Here is a crazy looking formula this says Y equals E and E Here is the natural exponential that you
learned about several videos ago and all of this complicated looking business.
This is all sitting inside the exponent of E.
So we have a fraction minus four times the natural log of two times T squared and t here is a vector.
So it's a list of time points you can imagine for example that this would be a time vector and then
in the denominator we have h squared.
This is an important parameter of the gaussian and I will discuss in a few moments what this parameter
refers to.
So this H is actually the denominator of the fraction that is all inside the exponent of E.
So it gets a little bit hard to look at.
So therefore mathematicians have come up with a solution for difficult looking equations like this.
And instead we write it like this.
So if you ever see e XP and then with parentheses like this this is not experience or experiential.
This is actually standing for exponent like the natural exponent.
So and then all of the math that is sitting inside the parentheses is what is actually in the exponent
so the power of the natural exponential.
So these two are the same.
Now I just want to point out briefly that there are several different ways to mathematically express
a galleon.
So as you go through your adventures in mathematics and data science and engineering physics statistics
biology you see this galaxy and all over the place finance it's really everywhere you might come across
slightly different formulations of the gaussian but they always have the general form of E to the minus
something squared over something else squared.
Okay now you know this is just a bunch of letters and numbers.
The real understanding of math the real beauty and intuition of math comes from visualization.
That's a point that I try to stress very often throughout this course.
And obviously I'm going to stress it right now.
So this is what this formula looks like here we have the t axis over here.
So this plotting this variable t and this is the the Y variable so this is the galaxy in function here.
So this is called the Galaxy in curve or the Gaussian distribution or the bell curve or the normal curve.
It's given a bunch of different names.
Okay.
So now I want to talk a little bit about this H parameter here and what that means for this graph.
This parameter is sometimes called the width of the Gaussian or the shape parameter of the gaussian.
And it's sometimes referred to as the full width and half maximum.
I'm gonna write out that term for you in a moment but first I just want to explain what this term means
on the graph.
So if you look at this graph and you find the 50 percent mark between zero and the peak of this Gaussian.
Now this Gaussian peaks at 1 so 50 percent of the gain or halfway up means a value of Point 5.
So we draw a line or we think about a line that goes through the Gaussian function.
This y axis at point five and then we find what are the two points where this intersects the Gaussian
function.
So that's going to be these two points here and then we draw lines from these two points vertically
we just drop straight down to the time axis or the x axis space axis whatever this axis is.
And then you find what is this distance here from this point to this point.
So this distance here and in this case I'll let you guess what that parameter is here what that value
is here.
I'd say it's about 1 This looks like minus point 5 and this looks like plus point 5.
So this total distance is 1 and that is an important feature of the gaussian and it is called the full
width at half maximum.
So it's the width at half of the maximum between 0 and the peak or the maximum of the gaussian.
So this H parameter here corresponds to the full with that maximum.
And for this particular graph each would be equal to one approximately.
Okay.
Now what I want to do next is show you how to figure out what values of t correspond to any arbitrary
values of Y.
So for example if we set this equation to be one three say one equals E to the.
And then all of this business.
My question is what value of t satisfies this equation.
Where.
What do you set t to in order for this equation to be true.
Now if you'd like to pause the video and work through the algebra yourself then that's great.
Now is your opportunity to do that.
Okay.
So the key to getting started here.
Because it's a bit tricky we have the T squared inside the numerator of a fraction which is inside the
power of this exponential.
The key insight is to think back a few videos ago to where I discussed the relationship between the
natural logarithm and the natural exponential and you will remember that those two operations are inverse
of each other so they cancel each other out.
So therefore the way to get started here is to take the natural log of both sides of this equation.
So that looks something like this.
We have the natural log of 1 equals the natural log of the natural exponential of this term here.
Now the cool thing is that these two operations cancel each other out.
They just totally disappear and that gives us 0 and then it turns out that the natural log of 1 is equal
to zero.
So this simplifies to this expression here and now it turns out we don't even need to really do a lot
of arithmetic anymore.
And that's because we can basically just solve this equation pretty simply by taking advantage of the
fact that this is zero.
So for example multiply both sides of this equation by h squared.
That's still zero over here.
And then we divide both sides of the equation by minus four times the natural log of two still zero
on the left side.
And then we take the square root to isolate t and we take the square root of zero and actives on zero.
Okay.
So that was a lot of like you know algebra analytic solutions etc. But we could also have just figured
that out by looking at this plot you know you look at this and it's obvious that when the galaxy and
equals one we are exactly at the center.
And t equals zero which is what we get here.
So I wanted to start off with an easy example here but it's not always so trivial to figure out this
solution.
Let us for example consider the value of t when the function equals point five.
Now again if you'd like to pause the video and work through the algebra here then now's your opportunity
to do so.
So we start with the same trick.
We take the natural log of both sides of this equation and again we can cancel out these two or these
two terms cancel each other out.
So that gives us the natural log of point five equals the inside of the gaussian exponential over here
and then we just have to do a little bit of extra algebra to isolate T.
So here I'm doing actually two steps at once I multiply both sides of this equation by h squared and
then divide by minus four times the natural log of two and that gives us this solution and we're not
quite done because we actually want the value of t and this is giving us T squared so we need to take
the square root of both sides of the equation which looks like this of course you always have to consider
both the plus and the minus.
When you're computing the square root that's actually going to be pretty important.
When we switch to Python in a moment.
So there's a few simplifications we can do here.
The main one is pulling this H parameter outside of the square root.
So now we have the result that t equals plus or minus H times the square root of this stuff in here.
So this is the natural log of the value on the y axis that we are looking for divided by.
This is essentially just a scaling factor minus four times the natural log of two.
All right.
So this is a lot of you know like sort of pure math.
I'm sure you are super excited to see this stuff implemented in Python so let's switch to Python.
We will be using the NUM pi and mom and Pi plot modules here.
So it's already started by importing those and I'm going to just dive right in and start creating this
Gaussian so the galaxy and formula let's call that G.
I guess in the slides I call this y but here are called G.
So we have known pi dot e XP.
Now you can see why Python developers and also in matlab and many other numerical processing software
is why they call this e XP.
So it's to be similar to the mathematical notation I introduced you YouTube.
So we have the numerator was minus four times the natural log which is num paid out log of two times
t and then squared and then all that was divided by h squared.
Okay so now we need to define some of these variables here.
So we have t and I'm going to set that to be linear these space numbers from minus three two plus three
and let's go in one thousand and one steps so why am I doing one thousand and one.
Is it because I'm just sort of a quirky guy and I don't like even numbers like a thousand.
Well that is.
That's probably part of the answer but actually there's a good reason for doing that here.
And that's because if we want this function to have the exact number zero the exact center then we want
0 to be in this we want to have t equals zero to be in this vector.
And if we go from minus something to plus something in an even number of steps then we're not going
to have zero in the middle.
And if we have an odd number of steps we are definitely going to have zero in the middle.
Okay.
And then we need to define H.
So let's add h to be about point 9 9 9.
It seems like a good number.
All right.
So I'm gonna run this code so it doesn't output anything of course I haven't requested any output but
I just wanted to make sure that I haven't made any stupid little coding mistakes okay.
Now we want to plot.
So let's see we do a plot of T by G and then we'll set the Y or say the x axis label to B T.
And you know it's kind of arbitrary that I'm calling this t you could call it X you could call it s
anything you like.
I do a lot of signal processing and so I often think about these Gaussian as functions of time.
That's why I tend to use a variable T.
So then we want a y label and I'll call that y just to be consistent with what I showed in the slides.
And then let's say the title is The Gaussian with a full with half maximum equal to.
And now of course you know that there are many ways to setup printing here with a variable.
I'm just going to use the possibly kind of clunky but relatively simple for small problems format of
saying plus and then string h.
Okay.
And then let's activate the show thing and then here we see our nice little calcium.
So now it's pretty interesting to play around with these different parameters so we can say what if
H equals something much smaller then we played it again.
In fact now it's impossible even to see that there is a galaxy and it looks like it's just a an impulse.
It looks like a delta function here all the way in the middle.
In fact we could zoom in.
Let's try zooming into like point three or minus point three to plus point three.
Oh wow.
Okay.
You can kind of start to see a little bit of this.
Let's do maybe a little bit more.
Okay.
Well I think you get the idea.
You can play around with this x axis range and with the full with the half maximum I'm gonna set this
back to what it was before and rerun that code.
Now what I want to do is show you how to find the x axis variable for this function given some function
value that we want to identify.
So what I'm really gonna do is implement the formula that I showed in the slides.
So let's start by picking the y value that we want to find.
I'm calling this variable Y Val to find that I'm using the number two as you know instead of the letters
two.
So let's consider this to be point five.
Let's say we want to find the value of t where y is closest to point five and we know that there's gonna
be two values there's gonna be one value on the left of the peak and one value on the right of the peak.
So now what I'm going to do is say t values equals and then I'm just gonna implement that formula that
I showed in the slides.
So that was h times the square root of the natural logarithm of Y vowed to find.
Divided by and then I'm going to use parentheses here to make sure that we are associating the minus
4 and the natural log of 2 all in the denominator.
Okay.
So again I will run this code just to make sure it didn't give any errors and then I'm gonna print this
out so let's print out t vowels and we had a value of point 4 9 9 5 and that's actually sensible it's
almost point five and the H parameter was almost 1 and we saw visually in the slides that when h was
equal to 1 then the value at point 5 this was going from minus point five to plus point five.
Huh.
But now this seems kind of strange because we know from the slides and also just from math in general
that when you take the square root of something you should actually get two values you should get a
positive value and a negative value.
So why do we only get one result here.
Well let's look at the dock string the help file for num paid out square root.
So I put the cursor inside the square root function and on the keyboard I press shift tab and then let's
read this a little bit.
This says return the non negative square root.
Okay.
So that right there tells us what the situation is what the confusion is.
So this is only returning the positive square root is also sometimes called the principle square root.
So therefore I'm just going to manually specify that we're looking for a negative of the same value
as well.
So here we get our two solutions.
There is an exercise for this video is really cool you get to create a pretty cool looking image that
looks something like this but you have to wait until the next video.
So keep watching.