In this video I'm going to talk about partial derivatives how to interpret partial derivatives and of
course how to implement them in Python and to already give you a heads up computing partial derivatives
is lots of fun.
And it's probably a lot easier than you might think it is.
If you don't already know how to compute partial derivatives so let's get started.
When are partial derivatives useful partial derivatives are useful when you have a function of more
than one variable.
So in this case we have a function of two variables x and y and that function is defined as two times
X times Y squared.
So if I asked you to compute the derivative of this function you would have to ask me back which variable
to compute the derivative relative to so it can be X or it can be Y.
And that's the idea of a partial derivative.
So a partial derivative is basically just a derivative of the function relative to one variable while
holding constant all of the other variables.
So let's see how the notation works and what the derivative will be of this function.
So the partial derivative is formally written like this with this kind of funny looking I don't know
it looks like a D but then you know it's a little bit sad.
So it's kind of like drooping over on the top here.
Anyway this is formally pronounced the partial derivative of F with respect to x and as a shortcut.
People often say partial f partial X it's also sometimes written like this which is a little bit more
condensed.
So the function f and then a little X in the subscript so why is the partial derivative of this function
with respect to X to Y squared.
Well the key insight is to realize that because X and Y are separate variables these are independent
variables x does not depend on y and why does not depend on X then from the perspective of X Y is actually
just a constant.
And that's how you compute a partial derivative.
You treat the other variables as constants.
So let's just pretend that this is a constant.
Just like the number two is a constant.
So then the derivative of x is 1 right because implicitly there's a 1 here in the superscript in the
power.
So the derivative of x is 1 and then this drops out.
So then we get to times Y squared.
Likewise the partial derivative with respect to y is for X Y and the reason why this is the correct
answer is that from the perspective of why X is a constant.
So therefore we just differentiate with respect to y and the derivative of y squared is two times Y.
So then we get the Y and then there's the extra 2 that comes out and that multiplies this 2 giving us
4 x y what I'm going to do now is show you how to compute a partial derivative using simplify and how
to display the partial derivative using LaTeX coding like what I just showed in these slides.
So therefore we are naturally going to be using the simple module and the display and math functions.
So let's see.
I'm going to import from Sim PI that ABC import x and y variables and let's define our function to be
X squared plus X times Y squared.
So this is not exactly the same function that I showed in the slides but it's going to produce an interesting
looking graph a three dimensional graph as you will see in the exercises.
So let's see.
Display math and the first thing I want to show you is how to produce that partial f partial X symbol
that I showed in the slides.
So it's actually probably what you would guess it would be it slash partial.
So partial F.
And then in the denominator we have partial X so let's already see how that looks.
Okay so that looks pretty good and then equals and let's do a percent s here and now you know how to
C I need a percent sign here.
Now you already know how to compute the derivative of a function that's with Cin diff and then you input
the function and let's check out the doc string the help file to see what we can do about a partial
derivative so in the beginning this is telling us a little bit about computing the third derivative
with an optional third input like this and let's see well I guess the answer.
Okay.
So I think the answer actually comes from looking at the second input here.
So the second input into the diff function is the variable that you want to compute the derivative relative
to.
So we want the derivative.
The partial derivative with respect to x and then we simply write seemed that if F comma x.
So here's the answer and then it's good to look at this and make sure that this is what we would expect
it to be.
So the derivative of x squared is 2 x and then the derivative of x times Y squared would be just y squared.
Again because from the perspective of X Y is simply a constant.
All right.
So then repeating this for the partial derivative with respect to y is pretty straightforward as you
might guess.
Let's see and let's also confirm that this is the right answer.
So here we only get one term.
Here we have two terms.
Now there is no y term or there's no Y variable in this first term in this function.
So that means that the derivative of this term is actually zero.
From the perspective of Y and then here we would get the derivative of y squared is to Y and then times
X now the interesting thing about functions of two variables is that they have three dimensional graphs
associated with them and that should make sense when you have a function of one variable that produces
a line in a two dimensional space.
So therefore when you have a function of two variables that produces a surface in a three dimensional
space.
And of course if you have a function of three variables if this was F of X Y and Z then you actually
have I don't know it's like a four dimensional hyper surface that's floating on top of a three dimensional
axis.
I don't really know what that looks like but anyway let's stick to two variables for now.
So what you want to do in this exercise is implement this function here which we just looked at in Python
so X squared plus X times Y squared and you want to generate three graphs.
They're going to look like this.
So the first is the function itself.
That's what this function looks like it's kind of this magic flying carpet or something that's going
up to the moon I guess.
And then you want to compute the partial derivative with respect to x and the partial derivative with
respect to y and then make 3D plots of these guys.
Now I am about to give you a hint and the hint is the function is simply that you use to generate these
kinds of plots.
If you don't want this hint if you want to figure it out on your own then pause the video now.
Okay so the hint is to use the functions Sim dot plotting thought plot 3D.
Now I'm not going to tell you how to use that function to produce these inputs.
You're going to have to figure that out on your own but at least that will get you started okay.
So now I am going to walk through this exercise.
So we call the function simple thought plotting that plot 3D and this takes a couple of inputs.
Let's just see what happens if we plot only with or if we run this command only with one input.
OK.
So first of all we get really nothing.
This tells us that we have created a simple plotting object.
So we need to actually request an output in order to get this plot to produce something.
OK.
So already this is looking pretty good.
I want to add a few optional inputs and that is going to be the range of x and the range of Y.
So the ranges of the axes.
So these come in tuples.
So it's gonna be X and then minus three come plus three.
And this is telling Python or the simple plotting engine that we want to plot on the x axis range from
minus three to plus three.
Okay.
And now it looks like it didn't obey our commands but it turns out that we also need to specify a range
for Y.
So y goes from minus three to plus three along with X and now we see that the function is limited to
these domains.
So the domain on X from minus three to plus three and on y again from minus 3 to plus 3.
And then I'm going to add a title so that's gonna say title equals and now I want this to be in latex.
So I'm going to use dollar signs to indicate that I should be planning in latex.
F of X and Y equals percent.
S and let's do a replacement of percent simply latex of f.
All right.
So this looks great.
Now we need to basically repeat this line three times four or I guess repeat it twice so we already
have ones for the full function.
And then we want the derivative with respect to y.
So that's going to be some dot diff f first with respect to x and then let's see the rest of this code
is the same except we want to change the title.
So this is no longer the function f but instead the derivative of x hour of F with respect to x and
let's see what that one looks like.
Good.
That looks like this sort of half tube thing that I showed in the slides and we can also do a super
quick confirmation that the derivative is what we expect it to be.
So X squared goes to X and X times Y squared just goes to Y squared.
All right.
And now I'm going to copy and paste again.
And then we need to change everything from X to Y.
So let's see that's going to be here as well all right.
Very nice.
So I introduced you to computing partial derivatives.
You saw that it's actually quite simple it's pretty straightforward to compute partial derivatives and
you got to see how to make really nice 3D graphics in simple.