This video is a follow up to the previous video on AI Gandhi composition and in particular what you
want to do in this video is two exercises.
So let me first discuss exercise one.
So you want to implement this matrix.
1 2 to 1 in Python and then use eye candy composition to extract its icon vectors and eigenvalues.
And then once you get those you want to make a plot a line plot of the vector lambda V and the vector
M V.
Now of course you're going to get two icon vectors and two associated eigenvalues from this matrix because
it's a two by two matrix so you can plot either one of them you know the first icon vector or the second
I can vector as long as you plot one of them and you can explore a little bit on your own okay.
Then the second exercise is to create a six by six matrix of random numbers but you need to make sure
that it's a symmetric matrix.
Now I have told you in a previous video in this section how to create a symmetric matrix of random numbers
and then from that 6 by 6 symmetric random numbers matrix you want to extract the ion vectors and eigenvalues
although actually in this exact exercise we don't really care about the eigenvalues just the ion vectors
and then what you want to do is generate a new matrix which will also be 6 by 6 and that matrix is going
to contain all of the dot products between all possible pairs of ion vectors so this will be a six by
six matrix where each element in that matrix contains the value of the dot product or the result of
this our product between for example I can vector I and I in vector J.
All right.
So now is your chance to switch to Python positive video do some coding and when you're ready come back
to the video and I'm going to show you my solutions to both of these exercises.
Let's start by creating this matrix so m equals num pi dot array and then to create a matrix you remember
we need to set double sets of square brackets.
So one common two that's the first row and then the second row is to come up one.
Now I'm going to perform the I can do composition and we are going to get out to output.
So it's going to be a vector of eigenvalues.
I'll call those D and a matrix of I can vectors and I will call that capital V.
So that is known PI that Lynn algae that I beg and then m okay.
And I'm actually gonna print these out because you know sometimes it's really easy to get the order
swapped you know so you might accidentally say v come a d It's a really easy mistake to make but you
would see that by printing out V and printing out d that in fact this is a matrix so this has to be
v and the first output of the IDE function is going to be a vector that contains the two eigenvalues.
All right.
So let's see now what I want to do is compute LV and that's going to be D 0 not 9 0 times the icon vector.
So the first I vector and then M V and that's going to be equal to m times.
That same I can vector so like this.
And now let's make a plot of this so it's gonna be P.L. T dot plot and these are going to be vectors
drawn from the origin.
So the X coordinates will be L and then l the the first component and then the y component of this line
is going to be 0 and then l the 1.
All right.
And let's make this a blue line.
I'll give it a label of let's see.
I'm gonna use a little bit of latex coding to get lambda and V okay.
And make this a nice thick line.
So line with equals four.
All right.
And then do a little bit of copy paste here.
This is going to be M V but most of the code is the same.
So this needs to be MVA instead of LV.
Let's make this red and I'll make this a dash line maybe a dotted line is better.
And now this is going to be M V and it can also be lined with four.
All right.
So let's see.
Then I'm going to.
What we need to activate the legend of course.
It would be nice to have a grid on here and let's already have a look at this thing.
Okay.
Here we go.
So this looks good.
You see that the two lines are the same they overlap.
So lambda V equals envy.
That's exactly what we said.
What is the eigenvalues equation that I showed in the previous video.
I just don't really like that this plot has the origin of the graph all the way at the lower left corner.
So therefore I'm going to say axis square and axis minus three two plus three on the X and minus three
two plus three on Y.
Now this looks much better here.
Okay.
And now what I would like to do is just also show you what this looks like for the other I can vector
so I change all these from zeros to ones that gets us from the first I can vector value pair to the
second I can vector value pair and then one happens to be plotted over like this.
And now I also just want to show you that if you would say you know the first I can value and times
the second I can vector then we're actually going to violate the icon value equation.
So now lambda V does not equal envy.
These two lines are not the same as each other.
So it actually is really important to pair the correct eigenvalues with the with its associated I can
vector they're not really interchangeable.
So that is the first exercise.
Let's get to the second exercise.
So now we need to create a random numbers matrix that is six by six.
And I think I'm going to soft code this and you'll see why in a moment.
So I'm going to create a variable that says m equals six and then maybe I'll call this a.
Now actually you know it's nice to use different letters.
How about the letter Q So let's call this matrix.
Q So this is going to be known PI that random that Rand N and we start off by making this a random numbers
matrix.
Now I said that we should create this to be a symmetric matrix.
Well it's kind of hard to see here.
Here you see this is definitely not a symmetric matrix.
This element here does not equal this element.
So how can we make this be a symmetric matrix while still being filled with random numbers.
You guessed it I hope I assume you guessed it.
We need to replace que with que times que transpose.
So you'll remember that a matrix times as transpose is always a symmetric matrix.
I discuss that in an earlier video.
And now you can also see you know this element is the same as this element and this element is the same
as this element and so on.
So all the elements are mirrored across the diagonal.
All right.
So now we have our six by six symmetric matrix of random numbers.
It's time to do.
I can do compositions and piled up.
Lynn Alcott II of the matrix.
Q All right.
And then what we need to do is so actually let me let's just print out V and have a look at it.
So this is the matrix where the ion vectors are in the columns.
And so what we want to do is compute the dot product between each pair of columns so the dot product
between this column and itself the dot product between this column in this column and this column in
this column this column and so on and so on.
Now there's actually ways to implement this using matrix multiplication and if you solved this problem
using matrix multiplication then great.
Good for you in the interest of clarity here I am going to solve this problem by using a double for
loop.
So I'm gonna say for I in range M and for J.
In range.
Remember this is equal to zero comma m.
So these two ranges here are equal.
I think I often prefer this.
I think it's just looks a little bit clear.
But anyway now what we want to do is compute the dot product between the IMF column in V and the I.S.
column in J So that's going to look like this.
But of course we need to store these in a matrix.
So let's call that matrix DPW for dot products.
So then we have the highest row and the J column equals the top product between these two ion vectors.
And of course sometimes these are gonna be the same.
Right.
So for example in the beginning of this loop this I is going to be 0 and J is going to be 0.
So then we're computing the dot product between the icon vector and itself which is totally fine.
Okay.
Now we just need to initialize this variable.
Otherwise if we try to run it Python's going to complain that this.
So this variable name DP s is not defined so I'm going to write DP s equals zeros I will initialize
this as a zeros matrix of m by m.
So you can see how often I'm using little m here and that's why it's a good idea to soft code this appear
rather than writing six in all of these places here.
All right so let's see.
So I'm just gonna run this cell.
See if we get any coding errors which we haven't.
So and then let's see of print out DP s Let's see what this looks like.
Mm hmm.
It's a little hard to interpret.
There's a lot of stuff going on here but you can see looking at these elements that there's an awful
lot of elements that are like e minus 16.
So remember this from scientific notation.
This is for example this element.
This is minus two times tend to the minus 16.
So this is a tiny tiny tiny number.
This is basically computer rounding error.
And then we have some other numbers here that seem to be exactly one.
This is E zero zero.
So this is one times ten to the power of zero which is actually just one.
So there's a couple of ways we can get around this are to make this plot are this set of numbers a little
more visible.
So one thing we can do is round and then I will round to let's say you know two significant digits.
How about that.
OK.
So now this is looking pretty interesting.
So I'm just rounding it to two significant digits and I don't see anything past the decimal point.
Wonder what would even happen if I go to five.
Yeah.
Still nothing past the decimal point.
And remarkably this is the identity matrix.
So we have a matrix that's all zeros on the off diagonal elements and all ones on the diagonal elements
in this video and the previous video you learned about eigenvalues and ion vectors.
You got a brief introduction to the algebraic and geometric interpretations of ion vectors and you saw
a couple of interesting properties of agony composition.
Now I can be composition is a really big topic as I mentioned in the beginning of the previous video.
Nonetheless I hope you found this a pretty interesting taste of what I can do composition means and
in the next couple of videos you're also going to learn about these singular value decomposition which
is closely related to eye candy composition.