When you are studying calculus you will come across something called the fundamental theorem of calculus
which has two parts.
The first part is essentially saying that the derivative and the integral are opposite of each other.
And that's usually expressed in some formula that might look something like this.
So the derivative of a function and then the integral over the derivative of the function gives you
back the original function itself.
You might also see it written the other way.
So first you integrate over a function and then you compute the derivative of that integral and you
get back the function itself.
Now there is actually a little bit of ambiguity in here because when you compute the integral you also
get a constant at the end a constant term but ignoring the constant term for now.
Basically this is saying that integration and derivation are the opposite of each other.
And so your goal in this exercise is to illustrate this concept using a specific function and that is
two times X cubed plus the sign of X..
So what you want to do is implement this function in python in simple.
And then take the derivative of the function like this and then take the indefinite integral of the
derivative of the function and hopefully if you haven't made any coding errors then you will get back
the original function which is of course this thing.
All right.
So switch to Python and have a go at this.
And now I'm going to switch to Python and show you how I went about solving this let's see.
So we will need a symbolic variable so x equals symbol symbols X and then we define the function.
So that was two times X cubed plus the sign of x.
Okay.
And now what I want to do is create new variables for the derivative of the function.
So simple.
Def of X and for the integral of the function.
Sorry the integral of the derivative of the function.
So this is going to be the integral of D F and that equals sim that integrate integrate.
D f Okay so now we have the three variables I just ran this cell and confirm that we didn't get any
python error messages here.
And so now what I'd like to do is basically display some of these.
So I'm going to start by displaying the original function so let's see that is F of X equals.
Percent s and then percent Sim the latex f.
Let's see how that looks.
Okay.
So this is the original function that we start with.
And then I want to show the derivative of this function.
So let's call that f prime equals.
And then we have to change this to def and then it's worth just taking a second to confirm this in our
head.
So the derivative of two times X cubed.
Well we take down the three.
So that's gonna multiply the two and give us six.
And then we have X to the power of one minus the original power.
And so that's 2.
And then the derivative of sine is cosine.
All right.
And now we want to show the integral of the derivative.
So that is going to be slash slash inch.
And then I'm gonna put this in parentheses just to facilitate visual grouping here and then add the
D X that's important to add.
And then we want the integral of the derivative of the function.
Okay.
So then here we see the integral of the function derivative equals to X cubed plus sine of x.
And amazingly enough that is our original function.
And as I mentioned in the previous video you have to be a little bit careful because technically formally
there should be a plus C after here but simply it doesn't show it so in this video and in the previous
video I introduced you to the concept of an integral which is all about finding the area under some
curve.
And it's basically implemented as adding together a lot of really really tiny thin slivers of bars.
You saw how to compute the definite and indefinite integral in Python.
And in this exercise you saw that the integral is the inverse of the derivative which is also known
as the first part of the fundamental theorem of calculus.