This section of the Course is about using Python to understand concepts in trigonometry.
However before we get into trigonometry persay I want to have a video to introduce you to random numbers
and generating random numbers in python in particular random numbers with different kinds of distributions
that you get to specify the parameters of so it turns out that there are different distributions that
random numbers can be drawn from here I'm illustrating two.
These are probably the two kinds of distributions that are most often used when generating random numbers.
So these two are typically called the normal distribution.
Also sometimes called the Gaussian or the bell shaped curve.
But I will call them a normal distribution because that's also how they're referred to in Python.
And then we have the uniform distribution which is shown here in Orange.
So what do these shapes mean.
So let's start by talking about this blue line.
The normal distribution.
So this shape means that if you draw random numbers from a normal distribution you are more likely to
randomly get numbers that are close to zero and you are less likely to get numbers that are close to
let's say minus two or plus two so this curve shows the probability of drawing a number at random given
this value.
Now this function never actually gets to zero but it gets really really really close to zero.
So if you are drawing numbers randomly from a normal distribution it's possible to get a number of minus
4 or value around minus 4 but it's really really unlikely.
So you can see that this distribution is centered at zero.
And that means that the numbers close to zero are most likely to be picked.
Now it's possible to push this distribution around to have this center value B for example 17.
If you want to draw numbers randomly with a center of 17 and in python I will show you how to shift
this distribution and also how to modulate the width of this distribution.
All right.
So that's for a normal distribution.
Then we have a uniform distribution and that means that if you draw numbers randomly from a uniform
distribution you are equally likely to get numbers that fall between the values of 0 and 1 and the probability
of getting a number larger than 1 or less than zero is zero.
So you can draw numbers from a uniform distribution until the cows come home and you will never get
a value of minus one because this probability density here this orange line is zero below zero.
Now that said it's also possible to change this uniform distribution so that you shift it on the x axis
and stretch it around to change the width of the distribution.
Okay.
So let's now switch to Python and I will illustrate these concepts to you we are going to be using the
name pi and map plot lib modules.
So let's start by generating some random numbers.
So I'll say no this will be the variable and then we type NDP for number pi dot random dot Rand.
So there is a sub module inside known pi called random.
And this module random contains a bunch of functions.
And one of those functions is Rand.
So in fact I can just call it like this.
And then let's write names.
Now if I run this cell we get some number point seven eight seven seven and so on.
Now if you ran this code on your computer you are not going to get 7 8 7 7 you're not going to get exactly
the same number.
And that's because this number is randomly generated.
So in fact if I run this multiple times you can see I'm going to get a different number each time so
that is for a single number if you want to generate let's say two random numbers you can write two in
the input.
And now we get two numbers.
So let's generate 1000 random numbers.
Now I'm not going to display all of these I'm going to print them out.
So P.L. teed up plot number and I'm going to print them out as squares and let's already just have a
quick look and see what this looks like.
Okay.
So it looks like a UN organized cloud of dots which is exactly what it should look like.
These are randomly drawn numbers and you can also see on the y axis that they all go between 0 and 1.
So that shows you that this Rand function is generating from a uniform distribution between 0 and 1.
So there is another way we can look at this which is through something called a histogram.
So I'm going to use the function hist and Peele to show.
So here is the histogram of these numbers.
Now these two plots have the same data.
They come from the same data but they show the data in a slightly different way.
So here you see the values on the y axis and the ordinal position on the x axis.
Here you see the values on the x axis.
So this x axis here corresponds to the y axis here and here the y axis corresponds to the count.
So the way that you interpret this histogram is that there are about eighty five numbers between the
values of zero and whatever this ends up being I guess that's probably point 1.
So that means if you would look here count all these dots that are between zero and point 1.
There are going to be around eighty five of them.
Now you might be a little bit surprised to see this histogram the shape of this histogram because I
said in the slides a moment ago that a uniform distribution means you are equally likely to draw a number
between 0 and 1.
And this doesn't look like equal likelihood but the thing to keep in mind is that these are randomly
generated numbers.
So there's gonna be some variability and purely by chance there's going to be of you know some range
that's a little bit more likely to be drawn in another range.
But this is not systematic.
So you can see now it looks like there's a bulge in this distribution at around point 4.
But if I run this again you can see well.
OK.
But still maybe a tiny bit of a bulge here.
Let's run it again.
OK.
Here you go.
Now if anything there's a bit of a dip here around point four and there's maybe more values up here.
So you can see that each time you run this code each time you generate new random numbers.
It's going to look a little bit different but in general the shape of the distribution will be the same.
So this distribution is always varying between 0 and 1.
But what if you want to generate random numbers outside of this range or in some different range.
So to do that you need to shift and then possibly also stretch this distribution.
So for example let's say I want this distribution to be centered at three instead of being centered
at point five.
So then I say numbers equals numbers plus three.
So now I'm just adding three to the entire distribution.
So when I run this code again now you see that this distribution which originally varied between 0 and
1.
Now it varies between 3 and 4.
And you can also see that in the histogram there are no values less than three no values greater than
four.
And the values between 0 and or between 3 and 4 are basically equally likely to be generated.
So you see some different examples of histogram for rerunning this code.
Now it turns out that for a uniform distribution there is a pretty simple formula.
There's a pretty simple algorithm for getting the minimum and maximum values to be whatever you want
them to be.
So let me show you how that works.
I will say Min Val.
So this is going to be variable.
Let's say we want numbers to go from two to 17 17.
So how can we change this distribution which initially comes out varying from 0 to 1 to a distribution
that varies between 2 and 17.
So the formula is you say numbers equals so first you generate the uniformly distributed random numbers
and then you multiply them by the difference between the Max.
Max Val and Min Val and then add actually let me just start right there with this.
So I'm doing here is taking this set of numbers that ranges between 0 and 1 and multiplying it or stretching
it out so that it varies now between 0 and 15.
And it's going to vary between 0 and 15 because the smallest number here is going to be or the smallest
possible number will be 0 so 0 times this is still going to be 0 and then the largest number is going
to be the largest possible number is 1.
And so that will get multiplied by 15 which is 17 minus two.
So let's have a look at how this looks so far.
So you can see now we have numbers between 0 and 15.
You see that also in the histogram here.
And then to get it to go from between 2 and 17 we add to this distribution the minimum value.
So now we get numbers that very randomly that are drawn randomly from a distribution with a minimum
of two and a maximum of 17.
So this is about creating a uniformly distributed set of random numbers.
I'm not going to show you how to generate normally distributed random numbers.
So that is NPR that random dot ran.
You can see that this part looks just like above.
But now we add one letter which is the letter N the N is for normal.
So this is now going to be a normal distribution.
The rest of it is very similar.
In fact I think I will copy and paste some of this code here for the visualization.
So here I generate 1000 normally distributed random numbers and then I plot the numbers and a corresponding
histogram.
Now these two plots look quite a bit different from the plots I showed earlier.
You can see that these numbers are centered at zero and you can also see that there's a lot more clustering
around zero around the center of this graph and the dots are the squares are getting sparse or as they
get further away from the origin.
And here you see this beautiful looking histogram showing pretty much exactly the normal distribution.
So there are lots of values close to zero and the further away you get from zero negative or positive.
The smaller these bars get by the way I want to just make this look a little bit nicer.
I'm going to say alpha equals point five.
So Alpha corresponds to the transparency of the objects in the figure.
So by changing the alpha value I'm going to make them 50 percent translucent so that now they look like
this.
I think this looks pretty neat in this video.
I talked about random numbers and drawing random numbers from two different distributions.
A normal distribution and a uniform distribution.
There are several other distributions that you can draw random numbers from.
However normal and uniform are the two most commonly used now there is of course an exercise that goes
along with this video but in the interests of time I've decided to put that exercise into the next video.
So keep watching and you will have an opportunity to apply and expand on your knowledge of drawing random
numbers in Python.