In this video I'm going to show you how to use Python through the Jupiter IPython notebook, which
comes with the anaconda package.
So in this video I'm going show you how to install Anaconda and Jupiter notebook. In the next video,
I'm going to show you how to use Python online without any installation.
Now if you are already a comfortable Python user and you have Python installed on your computer you
might just skip this lecture and the next lecture or maybe watch it at twice the normal speed just in
case there is anything new.
Now I generally recommend using python by installing the Jupiter notebook locally on your computer.
The advantage is that it's a local installation.
You don't have to worry about Internet access.
It's free, it's cross platform.
And if you install Python with the Jupiter IPython notebook that's going to be the easiest way for
you to follow along with the course.
And that's because this is the program and this is the environment that I have filmed this entire course
in.
The main disadvantage of installing Python locally on your computer is that you need to be able to install
new program.
So maybe you're using a shared computer or a computer at your university where you don't have administrator
access and you're not able to install new programs. In that case then no worries you can just see what
I have to say in the next video.
So in a moment I'm going to switch to my browser and go to Anaconda.com. So here is this Web site
Anaconda.
.com
This is essentially just a program that will install a bunch of python and other applications onto your
computer.
So from this main web site Anaconda you go over here to download and then essentially you just want
to download whichever is the right installation package for you.
So there's Windows and Mac and Linux and then you just have to note whether you are going to install
Python 3 or Python 2 super important do not install Python 2.
That's the wrong thing to do.
You want to use Python 3 version.
I've made this entire course in Python 3 and if you try to follow along using Python 2 then it's likely
that you are going to start getting errors when you run exactly my code.
And that's just because you're using an old version of Python.
All right.
So then you have to choose whether to use the 64 bit installer or the 32 bit installer.
Most likely the 64 bit is going to be the appropriate version for you. And then you just download the
installer.
Now I'm not going to go through the entire installation process here because well I already have Anaconda
installed but suffice it to say it's really easy.
It's really straightforward.
You don't need to pay.
You don't need to register or sign up or give your email address.
Essentially you just click through a couple of windows and you keep clicking Okay and install. Once Anaconda
is installed on your computer, you can access it by for example going to the start menu and searching
for Anaconda navigator.
There's going to be a bunch of different things related to Anaconda or that have Anaconda in the name.
You want the anaconda navigator. And you can look out for this little icon this this green circle broken
thing I'm not really sure what this icon is supposed to be.
But anyway it looks pretty nifty and of course you can also make a shortcut to this navigator on your
desktop or whatever you find most convenient.
So that is going to load the anaconda package.
You will initially get to this screen here, this window. The Anaconda navigator. So Anaconda basically provides
a bunch of different platforms for you to use Python or r or other languages and there's different ways
of using anaconda navigator. It's actually quite a lot that you can do with this.
That said, you don't need to worry about any fancy things, you don't need to worry about changing any
settings.
It's very simple: you just look for this Jupiter notebook option here and then you click on launch. That
will open up a new tab in your web browser.
So notice that the Jupyter IPython notebook is going to run inside whatever is your web browser of
choice.
Now when you first open it it's going to show you the folders and files that you have on your computer.
So what you want to do is click through here and basically find where you have downloaded the files
for this course. The first lecture of every section in this course contains a zip file that you download
and that contains a bunch of files and mostly what you're looking for is this Ipython notebook file.
So this is gonna be called something whatever is the section of the course.
And then I P Y and B for I Python notebook.
Now you click on that file. That's going to open up a new tab over here and this is the file that contains
all of the code that corresponds to the code that I go through in the video.
Now I have discussed in the previous video on how to get the most out of this course how to succeed
in this course that I actually don't recommend just going through and you know just kind of running
this code each cell at a time without really thinking about that much.
Of course I recommend writing code in a fresh notebook as you follow along with me.
So to get a fresh notebook you can go over here click on new Python 3 notebook again make sure you click
on python 3 in case you have older versions of python also installed.
So a new Python 3 notebook and that's going to open up a fresh notebook for you.
So I'm going to... you can click on untitled1 here and rename this to you know my favorite notebook.
Okay maybe that's not such a great name but you know you get the idea.
So in this video I showed you how to download and install the anaconda package which will allow you
to use the Jupyter IPython notebook to follow along with this course.
This is the way that I recommend following along.
I think it's the easiest and most convenient way to participate in this course.
That said if you prefer not to do a local installation or if you're unable to do a local installation
then stay tuned -- in the next video, I'm going to show you how to do everything online without any local
installations.