The previous video was all about summing up things and multiplying things and so therefore I thought
it would be useful to have a video about subtracting things about computing differences.
So I'm going to tell you in this video about the discrete difference operator which is also sometimes
called the discrete derivative.
And if you haven't yet taken a calculus course or encountered concepts in calculus then this is an important
lecture because the discrete difference operator is like a gentle introduction into something called
a derivative which is one of the most important topics in calculus.
So what is the discrete difference operator.
It's actually a pretty simple concept despite the kind of confusing long sounding name.
So it really just means that you take your time series.
So the difference operator is generally applied to a time series or it can also be applied to images.
But in this case we are just considering one dimensional vectors of numbers.
So your data time series X at T plus 1 minus the data time series at the current time point T.
And that is the value at the difference vector Y so y of T equals x of T plus 1 minus T.
So you can see that at each time point really all you're doing is subtracting the following value from
the current value.
It's really that simple.
So let's switch to Python and I'll show you how to implement this.
Well for starters we can actually just write two minus one.
Obviously that's computing the difference but if we have a vector so a list of numbers that is 1 2 then
what we want to do is say 2 minus 1.
Now I could write this out I could hard code this set this to be a variable let's call this maybe I
guess I'll call it X because that's what I call it in the slides.
Now you could write x 1 minus x 0 and that's going to give you the right answer here.
But what do you do if you want you know let's say you want this to be for well you know you could add
another term under here but eventually this is not really a scalable approach.
What we need is a function that will compute these differences for us.
And fortunately such a function exists it's in the NUM pi module so let's say import num pi as N P and
then I can write no pi dot def and then I will input x and the output in this case let me rerun this
code.
So now I've redefined X to be this three element vector.
So now the DIF of this vector is 1 2 now.
Okay in this case the output is a little bit confusing because it could be interpreted that this function
is just getting the first two points let me change this.
How about let's make this 1 3 and then yeah I guess 4 is also okay then I'll get rid of this.
OK.
So now the output of num PI that diff is 2 1 and this is interpreted as the difference of the first
element here is this number three minus this number which is 2 and then the second element here is the
third element minus the second element which is of course 1 for minus 3.
And you could go on this could be these could be negative numbers.
So if I were to write 4 minus 4 here then the third element here is going to be minus 8.
And that's because at the third element here in this output of the diff operator the dysfunction we
take the fourth element and subtract that from the third element.
So minus four minus plus four gives us a total of minus eight.
Okay.
So now there's something else I would like to try.
I'm going to come up with a range of numbers a num pi range of numbers that go from zero and they end
at 10.
Well I want the numbers to go up to 10.
So in fact this is not going to be exactly correct.
This function NPD that a range is going to print out integers because I'm providing two inputs so integers
between including the first input and up to but excluding the second input.
So if you actually want the numbers to go up to 10 you can see that you have to write the number eleven
here.
Okay so what do you predict is going to be the output of print num PI that diff of V What do you think
is going to be the result of this line here.
Well it's going to be a bunch of ones and that's because well 1 minus 0 is one basically.
Yeah.
These are in counting integers.
So the difference ends up being 1.
Now there's another optional input into the DIF function and so I'm going to write that as two and now
I'm going to press shift tab on the keyboard to look at the the little help file or the doc string that
corresponds to diff.
So a and then the default for the second input is 1 and the first line of the help file says calculate
the end discrete difference along that given access.
So that means that this is the first order difference that we compute by default here without specifying
anything.
And so this is going to be the second order discrete difference.
So what does that mean you probably guess or you might guess that that is going to give a bunch of twos
because if you think about the second order derivative then that's like you know two minus zero and
three minus one and so on.
But let's see what this actually returns Mm hmm.
It returns all zeros.
Why is that the case.
Well it's actually the case because what the second order derivative or difference really means is not
to go in steps of two here but instead take the difference of the difference.
So the first difference of the first order discrete derivative is all ones.
But then when we take the second order it's actually taking the difference of the ones and obviously
these guys don't differ from each other.
So the output is zero.
Now this line of code here is literally exactly equivalent to saying n p that def of n pitot diff V.
So we're just taking the derivative of the discrete difference of this vector and inputting that into
the diff function again.
So that's going to give us a row of zeros in this particular case.
Now there's also something interesting which I haven't explicitly discussed yet and that is that the
output of the DIF function is always going to be one number less than the original function.
So here we had four numbers four elements in this vector.
But here there's only three elements that get returned.
Now that actually does make sense because this is computing the difference at each point between you
know the next point and the current point.
And so when you're at the element four there actually isn't a plus one element.
So the algorithm has to stop here.
Okay.
So that's something to keep in mind for the exercise.
The exercise for this video is to implement this function.
So it's pretty simple function f of x equals X squared.
If you've already come across this function you'll know it looks a bit like a smiley face a kind of
it.
It starts off really high and then it comes down to zero and then it goes back up again.
So you want to implement this function in num pi and then generate a plot of this function.
And also of the discrete difference or the discrete derivative of this function.
And when you successfully complete this exercise you're going to generate a graph that looks something
like that.
So here you see the function this is f I call it F here.
But that's this F of X..
And then here I'm calling this D F this is for the derivative of F for the discrete difference of F
and that's this red line here.
All right.
So now is the chance to pause video switch to Python do some coding see if you can reproduce this slide
so I hope you were able to solve this problem.
I'm going to start by defining the x values for the x axis.
So let's say linearly space numbers between minus minus two and plus two and let's go in one hundred
and one steps because I don't know there was some old cartoon movie about 101 Dalmatians.
I think it was in the 80s.
Anyway let's see what X looks like.
So X is just a vector of numbers it's a name pi array.
It goes from minus two and you can see it's getting bigger and bigger.
It crosses through zero and eventually we get up to plus two.
Okay.
So now let's define the variable F and that is X squared.
And then I'm going to call this D F and that is going to be known pi dot diff of f.
Remember this is the DIF of f not the diff of X all right.
And then we won a plot so I'm going to start by just plotting X by f just to make sure that this is
looking good so far.
Okay well we get an error and that's because I haven't yet imported the plotting routines.
So import mat plot lib dot pi plot as P L T.
Okay.
Now it should work.
All right.
This looks good.
This is what I expect for the function F equals X squared.
So you can kind of see when x is zero.
Then the function is going to be zero.
And as x gets larger gets further away from zero these numbers so value F on the y axis here is going
to get larger and larger and it's symmetric of course because you know minus two squared is the same
thing as plus two squared.
So the function looks the same on both sides of zero.
All right.
So that's the function itself.
Now we need to plot the derivative.
So that's X by DLF.
Mm hmm.
We get an error.
What is this.
This says X and Y must have the same first measure but the shapes are one hundred one and one hundred.
So this is the problem that I hinted at earlier before I switched back to tell you about the exercise.
So this variable here x this contains one hundred and one numbers but this contains only one hundred
numbers.
So what we need to do here is basically say that we want to plot not all of the vector x not the entire
vector X but we want to slice it from the first point until the pen ultimate point to the second to
last point.
Okay.
And then we get the right answer.
Let's see.
So that's basically the end I'm going to make this plot look a little bit nicer.
So let's put some labels in here I call this def and then in the slide I called this f and then I'm
going to let c put on a grid and activate the legend and then the last thing I want to do is zoom in
a little bit because you know most of this plot is dominated by all of this stuff here.
This is mostly empty space.
I want to zoom in a little bit to this area here.
So let's see.
I will write P L T dot axis and then set the x axis to go from minus two to plus two and the y axis.
Let's try minus one to plus two and maybe even I'll make this two plus 1.
Actually no.
Okay I changed my mind.
Plus 2 looks a little bit better.
Okay so this is the successful completion of the exercise.
I just want to take a moment to explain how to interpret this plot in particular how to interpret this
discrete difference because this is related to the derivative which as I mentioned is one of the most
important concepts in calculus.
Now the derivative plot of a function is a little bit tricky to interpret at first and what you notice
here is that the derivative is negative.
It's below zero and then here it's above zero.
And what that means is that here the when the derivative is negative the function is going downwards.
And that's because each subsequent point is lower than the previous.
So when you say you know this point minus this point you're gonna get a negative number.
This point minus this point you're gonna get a negative number.
So the derivative here is all negative.
Here the function is going up and so therefore you know this point minus this point is going to be positive.
This point minus this point is gonna be positive and so on.
So that explains the sign why this is the derivative here is negative and the derivative here is positive.
And then you can see that the derivative is larger negative and it's getting less negative here.
And that's also because the function is getting less steep.
So this point minus this point is a really big negative number.
But this point minus this point is still negative because the function is going down but the function
is going down by less.
Likewise here the function is just barely creeping up very slowly.
But the further out we get the faster the function is increasing and therefore the derivative is positive.
And it's getting larger so in this video I introduced you to the discrete difference operator.
And when you start learning about calculus you will see that this is kind of the same concept as a derivative.
The main difference between a derivative and a difference is that the derivative is differences that
are really really really really really tiny.
So super duper tiny and then you have then basically the difference operator turns into the derivative.