At the end of the previous video you saw some of the limitations of just trying to print directly sympy
variables, and that motivated doing something extra, which is going to be latex coding.
So this video is a more thorough introduction to the integration of latex coding and python.
Now the good news is that you don't already need to know anything about latex coding in order to print
out nice looking equations and mathematical expressions in Python and in Ipython in particular.
And of course I already introduced you to some of the concepts of latex coding in Python in the previous
section of the course on arithmetic.
So in this video and the next several videos, you're going to get a more thorough introduction of using
LaTeX in the context of Python programming.
The good news is that you don't need to be an expert in coding in latex, in fact you don't need to know
anything about latex before getting started.
So let me first explain why latex is so useful when you are writing about mathematics, in particular
writing expressions and equations in mathematics.
Essentially, what latex is going to allow you to do is to convert a sentence like this -- the square root
of two -- into an expression like this.
Likewise, here you know if someone says write down pi in a document you want to be able to have a PI
character that looks really nice and fancy like this.
You don't want to have to write out something that's long and potentially ambiguous in your text or
in your python code.
All right.
So let's switch to Python and let's see what we can do with latex. So let's say we want to print out
the equation four plus three equals seven.
You could write it like this four plus three equals seven.
However, that's going to give you an error because a single equals sign in Python is interpreted as assignment.
So this kind of means that we're trying to create a variable four plus three and that's not a legal
variable; we can't create a variable like that.
and set it equal to seven.
Now what you can do is say print.
And in case this in the print function, however, that also doesn't work.
But you probably know by now that what does work is putting this inside a single quotes (double quotes
will also work).
And this is just printing out the text four plus three equals seven.
Now for very simple expressions like this, that's fine, but to go further in mathematics you will need
to print out Greek characters and fractions and exponents and all sorts of things.
So for that we are going to use the display and then the math functions.
And again, you've already been introduced to these ideas.
So notice how this looks here in fixed width font.
OK.
So in a moment I'm going to press control enter on my keyboard to run this code but I would like you
to predict what's going to happen -- what information we are going to see printed out here given that this
is a fresh instance of Python.
OK.
So the answer is that we get an error, and we get an error it says name
Math is not defined and that's because we haven't yet imported the math function from Ipython. So you
will remember this from previous sections of the course. We have to say from IPython dot display import
math and also import display.
And now this works.
Now this looks a little bit nicer.
Now you think OK.
So you know this looked fine as it was.
And so do we really need this fancy stuff to make it look basically just a tiny bit nicer?
In this case we don't.
But you will see soon that we are going to move beyond just printing individual numbers in a way that
is not possible when just using the print function. But before moving on,
I would like to just note that in here.
So this is actually latex code.
You will see it more in a moment.
But this is not actually evaluating any math, so I could say four plus three equals 17 and python will
print out four plus three equals 17.
Now Python is not actually checking whether this is an accurate mathematical expression.
It is simply printing out the text that I have implemented here.
So that's just something to keep in mind.
In fact I'm even going to change this back.
I don't like the way that looks.
OK.
Now what I would like to do is illustrate to you some of the possibilities for the kinds of special
characters that you can print out using LaTeX coding.
So if you want to write a Greek character such as Sigma, you can type slash slash -- you need two slashes here --
and then the word sigma.
And now when I press control enter I see an actual Sigma character here.
If you are not familiar with this this is a Greek lowercase character called Sigma so I can say sigma
equals.
And then there's all sorts of Greek characters that you can use here.
So let's say mu, and then I will say times and then let's say the square root of five.
How about that.
So now we get this nice expression that says sigma equals mu times the square root of 5.
Now I have no idea what this means.
Maybe this is relevant somehow, but for now I'm just illustrating to you what you can do with latex code.
So this is all latex code that goes inside the math function, which then goes inside the display function.
Next I'm going to show you how to write subscript and superscripts.
So it's display math.
Now a subscript is a little character that is below the main character, so let's say X and then I use an underscore
here.
Notice this is an underscore and then whatever comes after the underscore is going to be printed below
in these subscript.
So I can say X M.
Now notice what happens if I put another M in here.
That second M is not in the subscript; that just becomes a normal letter.
So that means that this subscript applies only to the character that immediately follows that subscript.
So you might be thinking that if you want to get both M's into the subscript underneath X then you
have to use another underscore character like this.
So it turns out that is not a good solution.
The better solution is to use curly brackets.
So the idea here is that you have an underscore and then curly brackets and everything that's inside
the curly brackets is going to go into the subscript of this letter here.
So now we get X underscore m m in the superscript.
So I've also introduced you to previously in the course.
So just to give you a reminder, let's say x underscore m m and let's say I have a plus and then the caret
symbol for superscript, and let's make that nk. Now if I want both the N and the K to be in the superscript
to be in the power of y then just having one caret like this is not going to do it.
That's only going to put the N into the superscript.
So the solution, which you've already guessed I'm sure, is to use curly brackets just like with the subscript
over here. And you can also make these longer. Let's say I wanted this to be N plus two K minus 15.
So now we have an entire expression that's in the superscript of this variable Y.
So you can see that these curly brackets here are very important
operators in latex. They're used in two ways for coding math and latex.
One is the way that I've shown you here where you can apply some text operation, some context operation
like superscript or a subscript to multiple letters like you see here.
The other way to use curly brackets in Python is for getting a special function like this.
So we have slash slash square root.
And then inside the square, the curly brackets here is whatever you want to be underneath the square
root.
So if I say five x plus three Z minus 17.
u.
So now we get this entire expression underneath the square root indicator here.
And this also shows you how to solve one of the problems in the exercises of the previous video that
I highlighted as a limitation.
I've just printing directly from sympy.
So you might remember that the goal there was to print out the square root of x times the square root
of X, but in fact python just printed out the answer x, because that is really the answer of the square
root of x times the square root of x.
But if you actually want to print out the square root of x times the square root of X, then this would
be the way to do it.
All right.
So along these lines, I'm now going to show you how to create fractions.
So let's say display math.
And now the latex function you need is slash slash frac.
And then in this case you need actually two sets of curly brackets.
The first set is for the numerator.
The second set is for the denominator.
So let's make our fraction 1 plus X.
And how about the denominator is to 2 v minus X to the power of T plus four.
okay.
I'm just making this up as I go along.
But I went to highlight to the way of integrating multiple expressions in latex using embedded curly
brackets.
So here I have curly brackets and this corresponds to the superscript for the s.
And here I have curly brackets and that corresponds to the denominator of the fraction or frac function.
So when we print this out, you see the numerator is one plus X here and the entire denominator is 2 v
minus s to the power of -- or in superscript -- T plus four R. Now, embedding latex coding into the math
function like this is really all about mathematical expressions.
If you want to have normal text also display inside the math function.
Then you need a special function like this for a fraction or a square root.
You need a special function to indicate that you want to have normal plain text.
And let me show you what that means.
So if I would type in, the answer to this equation is, now when you write it here it seems like this should
be the right thing to do.
However, when you run this cell you'll find that we get something that has no spaces and it's a little
bit difficult to parse.
So we need to tell latex coding explicitly that this is supposed to be text embedded inside this
mathematical formula.
So we say slash slash text and then all of the text that you want including these spaces has to go inside
curly brackets like this.
And now it says the answer to this equation is you know whatever this answer means. There is one more
concept that I want to introduce you to here in this video, which is markdown code. Markdown is essentially
a way of printing out a message that is not explicitly related to code or related to math.
So I'm going to say hash and then this is a markdown.
So now if I just run this code nothing happens.
And that should be no big surprise because this is a comment. I've used the hash mark to indicate a comment.
So this code doesn't get interpreted by Python and now follow along with me I'm going to go up here
to this menu option up here where it says code, and I'm going to select markdown.
And now immediately this changed all this in the font became huge and blue.
And now when I run this cell you see it's a big bold face header.
So now I double click so I can edit this again. And now watch what happens if I put a second hash mark.
You can see it just got smaller.
Actually you know,
maybe the I'll do it this way. This one here and then I'll put two here.. a subcell. And then I'll do
one with three here even smaller text.
Now this is Markdown.
This is actually just regular code.
So I have to select and make this markdown and here I'm going to change this code from being Python
code to markdown.
But now I'm going to do it with a keyboard shortcut so I'm going to type escape, I press the escape key,
and then I press the M key for markdown.
notice that also change the menu option up here. And now I can press control enter or shift enter and
I'll do that here as well.
OK.
So this is markdown. You will see this often when people share code.
It's a way of demarcating different major sections of the code.
Now once you have indicated that a cell is down and not regular code, you can actually start typing things
that are not Python code.
So for example you know this cell is not for running actual Python code.
Now I just get normal text.
So this would be a great way to write some text that explains a little bit more about what the rest
of the code does.
Now the reason why I'm telling you about this markdown option here is that you can also put latex coding
directly in here.
Now the format is slightly different.
You don't need to use display math.
Instead you use a double dollar sign like this.
So double dollar sign, that indicates the start of latex coding.
It doesn't mean that it's going to be a very expensive line of code.
Now here we can write... let's say I'm going to write the same fraction here that I had up there.
Here was a double dollar sign to indicate the start of the latex code.
So then you need another double dollar sign here to indicate the end of the latex code.
So now I press control enter and... huh.
This is kind of funny, it's a little bit strange, because up here this code which I said was latex coding
that produced this really nice fraction here.
But here it was exactly the same code and now it looks... well it doesn't quite look right.
Also it says the word frac in here.
So what's actually going on here is that in real latex code, you only need one backslash here for the
fraction function and also for text and square roots and all these other things.
The reason why you need a double backslash up here inside the python code is that the first slash actually
means something different from the second Slash.
So the first backslash is like an escape operator.
It tells Python that the next piece of code is going to be something other than just a regular Slash.
So it gets a little bit confusing but you'll get the hang of it soon.
Essentially, when you are using LaTeX code embedded into the math function, you type slash slash and otherwise
when you're using LaTeX outside of Python code cells you only need one slash as you see here. Finally,
if you  use double dollar signs like this, you get the latex code to be in it's own line and if you have only
a single dollar sign like this then the mathematical expression will evaluate in the same lines.
So let's say Python code,
we can make the following math expression.
So now this looks a little bit more sensible.
So here are the exercises for this video.
Basically what you want to do is get these expressions to all print out exactly how you see them here
using LaTeX coding in Python.
All right.
So we had... the first one
was... so I'll do display and then math, and then this one was pretty easy: that was four X plus five Y minus A
Z equals seventeen. OK so now we get this nice expression.
Now it may look like there is an extra space in here and I didn't put one in here.
In fact in latex spaces are not counted.
So even though I've typed all of these spaces in here, when I run the code I get exactly the same result.
So the second one was display math.
And then this was the signed formula.
So that was now you could try like this sine of two times pi.
This needs to be in single quotes here: sine of two pi F T plus theta. Now that isn't really wrong.
But the sine is in italics.
And really this is a sine function, so we don't want that to be italicized. So let's try with two backslashes
like this, and now we get a nicer result that someone who is familiar with reading math expressions
might expect.
All right on to the third one.
This one was actually pretty straightforward.
So display math.
And then we needed E equals m c. And then the main thing here was to remember how to indicate a superscript,
which is with the caret symbol here. And then the last one was a fraction.
So let's see that was
display and then math.
So now we need slash slash frac.
And then here's for the numerator here is for the denominator.
It was four plus five X squared.
And then in the denominator was 1 plus X times one minus X.
So I think this is all looking pretty good. I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
I hope you feel like you have a little bit better grasp of integrating latex coding with Python coding
in order to write out equations, mathematically equations, and special characters.
I also told you a little bit about markdown code versus regular code in Python.
You will get lots and lots of more practice with latex and Python later through the course.
But I believe that by now you have a pretty good solid foundation to print out beautiful equations in
your python notebooks. In the next video,
We are going to continue learning about sympy.