This video is a continuation of the previous video.
I have three exercises for you to solve here but they are a little bit more involved than some of the
exercises that you've had in previous videos
in this course. Therefore, to prevent the past video from getting really really long,
I decided to break it up into two. So that means that if you didn't yet go through the previous
video, then it might be a good idea for you to watch the previous video before trying to solve these
exercises here.
So here are your three exercises.
Implement this equation in Python and simplify. In particular, simplify as much as you can.
That is to say, allow sympify to simplify for you and then solve for q.
So that is exercise 1.
Here is exercise 2: You want to now implement this equation in sympy.
Check out the functions symplify, which I've already introduced you to, and cancel -- the function in the
sympy module called cancel.
I haven't yet introduced you to this but you can read the help text and look at the output to see if
that helps you understand the difference in the output of the symplify function and the cancel function.
Finally, we get to the third exercise, which looks like this.
There are square roots all over the place.
Implement this equation in sympy. Simplify this equation, and then you can test by substituting various
numbers for Q. So you can substitute q equals, you know, 10 or minus 15.
Or anything you like. Substitute a couple of different variables or numbers for Q and see what happens.
And if you are a little bit surprised at the result, then what you should do is get out a piece of paper
and a pencil, and confirm the algebra on your own.
So basically, try to simplify this expression on your own using paper and pencil.
All right.
So now is your opportunity to pause the video and work through all three of these exercises. So I'm definitely
going to be using the sympy toolbox, and the display and math functions.
I'm already importing those right from the start.
Okay so here was the first assignment, so you needed to implement this equation.
So we need q. I'm going to say sym dot symbols, and then q and let's call this equation eq for equation.
And that was three times Q plus four divided by Q plus three equals five times q minus one divided by
Q minus one.
Now if you try to run this code you're going to get an error and the error is related to this equals
sign here.
Now you might remember from the previous video that I mentioned that in Python and in sympy,
very often you have to convert an equation into the homogenous form, which basically means setting the
entire equation to be equal to zero.
And the way to do that is by moving
so basically subtracting all the terms in the right hand side and putting them on the left hand side.
And when you do that, you have to be really careful that you are subtracting all of them.
So you're setting minus signs on all of them.
And I realize now that what this should have been is actually these were all plus signs in the equation
in the slides.
I'm sure you noticed that before I did.
And then when you move these three terms to the right hand side of the equation, they all need to get
a minus sign.
Now you could do it like this.
You could in case these in parentheses and then leave the plus signs in here, or you can set each individual
term to be minus. But you have to be mindful because this equation is now incorrect.
This is not the equation that I specified in these slides because of this term here.
This needs to be minus.
All right.
So now we get this equation.
And now I haven't explicitly set it to zero but that's implicitly assumed by sympy.
So let's write out this equation display math sym dot latex eq.
Now I told you in the slides, in the instructions, that you have to simplify this equation as much as
possible.
It turns out that sympy already does the simplification for you, or at least it does some of these simplifications.
Now in this particular case it's not even possible to simplify it further, so you can see the plus three
and the minus one got combined into two and so on.
Same with the q's. So the three times Q and the minus five Q turned into minus two q.
So if you want to simplify this further, I showed you using the function sym dot simplify in a previous
video. But you can also call simplify as a method on the equation object, on this sympy object. So I can
write eq dot simplify. And then with parentheses because this is a function, and then run this.
Now it turns out that in this case it's the same because Python has already done the easy simplifications.
All right.
So this is already in its simplified form.
And now to solve for q, let's see... I'm also going to write this out here.
So I'm going to say Q equals and then a plus sign for string concatenation sym latex.
Now we don't want to simplify the equation.
We want to solve the equation.
And actually this needs to be sym dot solve.
And then the equation and we are solving for Q. So here we get q equals
Now this is a list.
You saw this before, with the square brackets here and the comma in between.
This is a list in Python, and this is telling us that there are two solutions to this equation.
One solution is Q equals one half plus the square root of seven over two.
And the other solution is one half minus the square root of seven over two.
All right.
So that is enough for the first problem.
Let's go to the second problem.
So here the equation was two Q Plus three times Q squared minus five over q minus four divided by Q
And then that one was cubed.
And again you will remember from the video about order of operations, this shorthand for remembering
order of operations, it was PEMDAS. so exponents have priority over division.
So that means we don't actually need the parentheses here.
You can leave them in for visibility if you like, but python will know that it's the Q that gets cubed
and not the four over Q that gets cubed.
All right.
So here is the equation.
So I just ran this cell by pressing control enter on the keyboard and we didn't get any errors.
So that's a good sign.
Let's start by just displaying this on a display math sim dot latex eq, and now we get this nice
looking expression here.
So now the instruction for this assignment was to test the function sympify and the function cancel
and see what those two look like.
So to start off with, I'm going to say latex and then sym dot simplify
oops.
We get an error.
Let's see.
Oh.
Simplify.
T simplify.
Okay.
Now the fact that sym dot simplify gives us the same as the original equation tells us that Python
thinks this form is already as simplified as it can get.
So there's no like terms that can be combined like what you saw appear with the you know the Plus Three
and the minus one got combined into two.
Python has looked at this equation and said well it's basically already simplified.
All right.
So let's see what would happen if we replace simplify with cancel.
Now we get an expression that is actually identical to this expression but it has a slightly different
form.
In fact, what Python has done here is put the entire expression into the numerator and then Q cubed in
the denominator. You can confirm by dividing each of these terms by Q to the power of three that these
two expressions really are the same.
For example three times Q to the fifth power divided by three times.
Ah sorry.
Q to the third power is three times Q squared, which is this term that you see over here, and so on.
So these two terms actually are the same.
And now we can put the cursor inside the cancel function and then press shift tab on the keyboard and
that's going to open up this little help file.
And if you press the plus sign here you'll get sometimes a little bit more detail or sometimes some
examples like what you see here.
Now sometimes these doc strings, as they're called, these explanations of the functions are more helpful,
sometimes they're a bit less helpful. If you're still unsure about what a particular function means, you
can try looking it up on the Internet.
One good thing about Python is that because it has a really large user base all over the world there
are people all over the world who are writing on the Internet and stack exchange and on blog posts about
explaining functions in python.
But essentially, what the cancel function is trying to do is put as many terms as possible together into
one single term.
So this expression here is one two three four separate terms and we were able to combine them into one
single term.
So this is one term.
It's a rational expression.
All right.
So now let's move on to the final exercise. That was number three.
So here what we wanted to do was implement this expression in sympy, and then test for a couple of
different values of q. So that expression was... let's see, it was a little bit complicated.
So it had a big numerator and a big denominator. The numerator was the square root of three.
So sympy dot square root of three plus sym dot square root of 15 times Q. And then in the denominator
we had sym dot square root of two plus the square root of 10 times q.
All right so a lot of square roots going on in here.
So the first thing I want to do is display this expression to make sure that I've implemented it correctly.
So display math and then sym latex expr.
All right.
So this looks good.
You might remember from the equation in the slides that this is what it looked like.
The terms were the other way round so I had the like I wrote up here.
So the square root of three and the square root of two on the left.
But it doesn't matter.
That's the same thing.
Okay.
So I'd like to see what happens if we start plugging in different values of q so let's say expr dot
subs and I'm going to substitute Q. Let's start with about the number 10.
So you might be a little bit surprised to see that this answer is still in its symbolic form.
So we still have square roots here instead of returning a single number.
And what's going on here is that sympy is seeing that the square root of three is its own number, that
is just the square root of three.
What we want to do is force simplify to evaluate this expression within some tolerance of accuracy.
And so to do that we can add another method or we can call another method after subs which is called
evalf, and that is going to return a number and this number is basically this expression substituting
Q for 10 to 15 degrees of precision or however many decimal points this is.
Okay.
So here we found that when we set Q to be 10 this is the answer.
It's about one point two.
Let's see what happens if we set Q to be....
I don't know how about three.
Huh.
And it seems like it's the same number.
How about if we set Q to be minus eighty three.
Hmm.
Still the same number.
That's really strange! It seems like whatever I set
Q to be, I'm still getting this same number.
How about if it's like a large number like this.
Wow it's still the same number.
What is going on here? To understand what is going on here
Let's try to simplify this expression.
So now I'm going to write out this latex, but first I'm going to simplify, so sym dot simplify.
Simplify this expression and then print it out and then we get to the funny result that when I simplify this
expression, the Q's actually completely drop out, and we just get the square root of six divided by two.
Now if you disagree and you don't think that that should be the right answer, now is the opportunity
to get out a piece of paper and a pen or pencil and work through this equation do a little bit of arithmetic
and see if you can simplify this down to root 6 over 2.
I'm now going to switch back to the slides and show you the answer.
All right.
So if you haven't already paused the video to work through this, then now is your last opportunity to
do so.
Okay.
So to work through this problem what you need to see is that the square root of 15 can be simplified
to the square root of three times the square root of 5, and square root of ten can be simplified as
the square root of two times the square root of 10.
So when you rewrite it out like this you see a couple of interesting things popping up.
There is the root 3 and root 3 and root 2 and root 2.
So there's like terms here and there's also root 5 Q and root 5.
Q And these are like terms over here.
So now what we can do is group these two sets of terms together.
So in the numerator we grouped together, or we pulled out, the square root of three from both of these terms.
That gives us square root of three times one plus the square root of five times q.
And in the denominator you get the same thing.
So that means that these two terms will cancel and we are left with the square root of three divided
by the square root of two.
Now your math teachers and the people who write your math textbooks and the people who wrote sympy
believe that it is somehow ugly or wrong or just plain weird to have radical signs in the denominator.
Now why that is the case
I honestly have no idea.
I don't see anything wrong with having square roots in the denominator.
Nonetheless, many people don't like it, so it's common practice in mathematics to try to get rid of the
square root in the denominator.
And in this case you can do that by multiplying both sides,
so the top and the bottom of this fraction, by the square root of two.
And that gives you square root of two times the square root of 2 in the denominator, which of course
is just 2, and the top is the square root of three times the square root of 2, which is the square root
of 6.
And this was the answer that you saw in Python so that's pretty funny.
You saw that even though there is a variable Q In this expression the answer turns out to be the square
root of six over two regardless of what Q is equal to.
So in this video and the last video you learned about using simplify and Python to solve for a variable
in an expression.
In the next video we are going to continue our adventures in learning how to use Python to understand
algebra, and that's going to be done by expanding terms.
I'm also going to show you some new concepts in sympy.
So keep on watching.