This video contains the exercise that corresponds to the previous video on computing limits and simplify
and displaying them in Python.
So if you haven't already gone through with that video it would behoove you to watch that video first.
All right.
So here are your exercises.
Consider these two functions.
So we say F of X equals E to the minus X times the square root of the quantity x plus 1 and G of X equals
the cosine of the quantity x plus the sign of x.
So this exercise has two parts.
The first part is to just implement these functions and make a plot of them.
Now I've implemented this by specifying these two functions first in simple way and then generating
new functions based on the simple function lambda Phi.
So I recommend you do that as well.
Okay.
So that's part one of the exercise.
Part two of the exercise is to show this interesting property of limits that the limit of one function
divided by the limit of another function is the same thing as so is equal to the limits of the function
divided by the other function.
I hope that makes sense.
So here what you're doing is computing the limit of F of X as X tends towards 5 totally independently.
So when you're computing this limit you don't know anything about the function G and then you compute
this limit for function G and this happens totally independently of the limit for function X. Our f
excuse me and then you get a limit here and you get a limit here and you compute this division this
ratio here.
So that's one thing and then that's the left hand side of this equation the right hand side of this
equation is forget about computing limits first you just divide F of X by G of X and once you make that
division that's going to give you some other function and then you compute the limit of x as X goes
to 5 of that ratio of functions and it's an interesting property in mathematics and calculus that these
two things are equal to each other.
And that is part 2 to confirm this property of limits for these two specific functions.
All right.
So now is your chance to switch to Python.
Write some code.
And now I am going to switch to Python and solve both of these parts of this exercise I will start by
importing the variable x.
Let's say some r x equals symbols symbols X and then I will define the function.
So that was f of x equals let's say sin.
So notice I'm using the symbolic square or I should say the square root function in the sin pi module.
And that's because to use the simple I limit function.
We need these to be symbolic expressions.
So the square root of x plus 1 times Sam dot XP of minus X and then we had G of X and that was the cosine.
Again I'm using the cosine function in the simple module not in the NUM pi module.
So Sim dot cost x plus similar sine of x then I will immediately extract the or convert these into functions
that I can evaluate at specific x axis points.
So let's call this f x x equals Sim Lam defy x and f x and then I'm going to copy and paste because
this is all basically the same except replacing F with G.
All right.
So now I've written a bunch of code I'm just gonna run this real quick just to make sure that I haven't
made any silly little typos which as you know by this time in the course I make quite quite a few typos.
So now I didn't tell you exactly what x axis range to use for plotting out these functions.
So if you came up with your own ranges then that's great.
You might have discovered that X is limited by some specific value which is basically minus 1.
So if X is smaller than minus 1 then this is not going to produce a real value output.
So but I'm going to let this go from zero to 10.
And how about one hundred steps okay.
So let's start making some plots so P.L. T dot plot f our SA x x and then f x x evaluated at x x.
That's an awful lot of x's in there and then let's do make a label of F of X and then I think I will
also do another copy paste here and now all the Fs turn to GS and let's see how this looks so we need.
Let's see P L T the legend.
We need to activate the legend and P L T does show all right.
This looks pretty good.
So we have our two functions here.
F of X and G of X and it's always interesting to look at the functions and make sure that we can kind
of make a sensible mapping between the function in algebra.
So you know that sort of symbolic version of the function with the graphical visual version of the function.
So this one is cosine and sine so we certainly expect G of X to be wavy like this which it is and you
can see that F of X is kind of dominated by this e to the minus X expression and E to the minus X..
Certainly when it starts at zero is basically just going to be this decay downwards towards zero.
All right so that looks good.
I would consider this to be the successful completion of part 1 of this exercise and then we get to
part 2.
And so what we need to do here is compute the limits of f and g separately and the limit point was 5.
So here I'm going to say Lim of F of X equals Sim.
That limit effects comma X comma Lim point.
So it was the function the symbolic function the variable and then the limit point.
Now it's important to look at these functions and determine whether we are going to need to compute
a one sided or two sided limit.
So looking at both of these functions you know the value of 5 is somewhere around here.
It certainly seems like the functions converge onto the limit of whatever the limit happens to be both
coming in from the right and coming in from the left.
In this case we do not need to worry about any separate directions for the limits.
Okay.
So that was the limit of F of X then we have the limit of G of X and that is essentially the same code.
Just like this.
Okay.
So run this cell.
We didn't get any mistakes so that's good.
Now I want to compute the limit of f divided by G.
So let's see.
I'm going to copy and paste this business and I will call this Lim f g x and essentially all I'm going
to do here is just directly in this function divide F of X by G of X.
Now if you want you could have also done it this way you could say like h of x equals f of x divided
by G of X and then of course here you would input H of X that's also h of x.
Totally totally fine solution.
So now we have all of the individual limits that we need.
And the question is whether this divided by this is the same thing as this.
Now my claim in the slides is that it is and this is a good example of what I mentioned in the first
video of this section of the course which is that this statement is true.
So this claim is true that this divided by this is the same thing as this.
However I'm not proving it to you in this course.
What I want to do is show you how to use python as a tool to help you build intuition for this important
property of limits.
Okay.
Now we could just print all of these things out but I want to make this look nice in latex coding so
display math and then let's see.
This is going.
This kind of have to work up piece wise here.
So I want a fraction and in the numerator of the fraction it's going to be the limit as x goes to well
percent g g that's going to be this Lim point here of F of X and then in the denominator it's going
to be pretty much the same thing.
Let me see are missing a and curly bracket there.
So then the denominator is essentially the same thing except this is going to be for G of X..
So before getting any further let me just finish this code here and make sure that all of this is looking
good.
So we have two substitutions here and they're both Lim point and limb point okay.
So this looks pretty good.
We see the limit of F of X as X goes to five divided by the limit of G of X as X goes to five.
And now I need to say what these things are equal to and I'd like to show both of these here.
So I'm going to put actually another fraction and this is going to be.
Percent G and percent G.
And then here I'm going to put the limit of F of X. So lim f f of x and the limb of G of X.
Okay and let's plot this again.
Okay.
So here you see the kind of symbolic expression of what we're doing here.
These are the actual values for this particular F of X and this particular limit point.
So as x goes to 5.
And then I want to show what these what this ratio is X actually equal to and that's gonna be a pretty
straightforward percent G.
And then here this is going to be well I actually don't have a variable for this yet.
So I can simply divide them.
So lim f x divided by Lim g x.
All right.
So this is starting to get to be a really long line of Python code.
So what I'm going to do is break this up into two separate lines of text even though it's the same line
of code just makes a little bit easier to read it's a bit softer on the eyes.
Okay.
So this ratio happens to be minus point 0 2 whatever that means.
And then the next one is actually going to be a little bit easier isn't it.
So here we say that the limit as x goes two percent g of actually now this is going to be a fraction
f of x f of x divided by G of X.
And let's just start by replacing this number here with Lynn point
okay.
So so far looking good.
And then we say equals.
And then another present G for then whatever the answer is going to be.
So the answer here is going to be Lim f g x.
All right.
So that's pretty cool.
We have seen here that the limit is exactly the same for computing the limit separately and then dividing
them versus dividing the functions and then computing the limit of that function ratio in this video
and in the previous video you learned about limits of functions.
You learned how to compute limits and functions and you learned how to use latex coding to display those
limits in nice formatting.