Let us continue our journey on learning how to use Python and sympy as tools for understanding
mathematics.
What we are going to do in this video is focus on expanding terms.
And I'll also show you a little bit more about how to work with the sympy toolbox, and how to see what
variables and functions and modules are already loaded into python.
So expanding terms means something like this: if we say eight times the quantity b plus c then you
can apply eight each of these terms individually.
That's called the distributive property.
So this can be expanded into this expression: a times b plus a times c.
Another example of expanding terms looks like this.
So if we say the quantity A plus B times the quantity C plus D, then this whole thing can be expanded
into eight times C plus eight times D plus B times C plus B times D.
And of course these parentheses are necessary because they're grouping together for the multiplication.
These parentheses are not necessary.
I just put them in here for visual aesthetics basically, so you can drop the parentheses and expand these
terms into these terms.
Okay.
So when you have a really simple case like this, then you don't need a computer, you don't need Python
to tell you how to expand these terms. But as you move more into more sophisticated areas of mathematics
then knowing how to expand terms can become really useful.
So let's get started.
I've already written the code here to import sympy and the display and math functions because we
are definitely going to need them here.
So I'm going to start by writing two terms.
Let's call this term one equals four times x plus five, and then let's say term two equals x and then
basically what I want to do is print out a term one times term 2.
Now you can probably already guess that this code is going to create an error.
It is not going to run and that's because we haven't yet defined X.
So I want X to be a symbolic variable. Now, so far in this course, the way that I've taught you how to
create symbolic variables is by typing X equals sym dot symbols and then in single quotes x.
So this is fine of course there's nothing wrong with this syntax, but I want to introduce you to another
way of importing or creating symbolic variables.
So here I'm going to write from sym dot ABC ABC.
This has to be sympy from sympy dot ABC import x.
So this is a pretty neat syntax here.
Essentially we're importing from the method ABC in the sympy module the object X and now when I run
this code, this is going to work.
Now just be mindful that this only works for a single letter.
So if I were to type X and how about qwerty.
Now this is not going to work.
It says cannot import name qwerty from sympy dot ABC.
So if you want any arbitrary variable name, then you're going to have to use the method that I showed you
before.
So asdf... I think I had this qwerty didn't I?
So qwerty equals sym dot symbols qwerty.
So there you go.
Now I'm going to delete this because I'm not actually going to use that variable qwerty.
OK.
So now I printed out.
Term one times term two and not literally just print it out.
What I wrote here.
So we didn't get any expansion of terms.
So let's try print.
Now I'm going to use the function sym dot expand, and then the input will be the same thing.
So term one times term two and now we get four X squared plus five X, and that makes sense because the
four goes here.
Times... sorry the X goes in here and makes us X squared.
And then we get five X and now you know by this point in the course that I am not a big fan of this
kind of printing. I don't think it really looks nice.
The thing is if you are looking at this line of code you can read it and if you give this code or if
you give this output to someone else who is really familiar with Python coding and sympy coding, then
they will also be able to interpret it.
But if you would show this to someone who is not really familiar with Python, then they might not know
for example that this means squared.
Furthermore, once you get into math notation, the asterisk is often used to indicate a procedure called
convolution, which is not the same thing as multiplication.
All right.
So for all of those reasons, it's nice to use nicer looking formatting.
So let's say print and then we want the math function.
Math function and then sym dot latex.
Now this is basically all review except when I run this.
Now it no longer shows me this nice looking equation.
Instead it says that this is some kind of object.
It's a display dot math object.
So what is going on here?
Well, what's going on here is just that I use the print function instead of the display function and
the main reason why I showed you that is because if you ever carelessly -- it's you really easy mistake
to make -- but if you ever by accident use print instead of display then you'll get this message here, which
is just printing out what this thing is.
So this is a math object.
So if you see an message like this then you know what you've done wrong, or you haven't really done anything
wrong here, but probably not what you hoped you would be doing.
All right.
Now I'm going to add another term. Let's call this term three and this is going to be X minus seven.
So now I want to show you the difference between multiplying the terms and expanding the multiplied
terms.
So I am going to write out display and then math and then sym dot latex term one times term three.
And so that is essentially similar to what we printed out here.
So you can see that Python didn't actually expand the multiplication.
It just printed out the two terms in nicer looking mathematical notation.
All right.
And now what I'm going to do is copy and paste, except now I'm going to add sym dot expand inside the
latex code.
All right.
And now here with sym dot expand, so I've multiply these two terms, put that into the sym dot expand
function, and then I've put that into latex and I put that into math and I put that into display. Fwooof!
That is really a lot of embedded functions.
If you're ever looking at code and you see a lot of embedded functions like this and you're having a
hard time figuring out what's going on, then the normal way, the way that your brain probably wants you
to try and figure out what's happening in this line of code, is to start from here and say huh, display
and then math... but this is the wrong way to do it. The better way to decode a line of code that has a
lot of embedded features like this, is to start from the most deeply embedded piece of code.
So you want to start by looking for what's in the most number of parentheses. And then you start working
your way outwards from there.
So first we have the multiplication in these two terms and then we expand then we convert to latex code
and then we input that into math and so on.
All right. But the point is I wanted to show you that you need this expand function.
Otherwise the printout is going to be the same as the literal input.
OK.
The next thing I want to show you is expanding with two variables.
So we already have variable X so let's create variable Y.
So I'll say from sympy dot abc import y.
So let's say our expression is X times two times Y squared minus five to the power of x divided by x.
So who knows what this equation means, but it's something that looks kind of interesting.
So let's display this using nice looking math notations, so sym dot latex expr. Here is what
this equation looks like.
And now I'm going to run this again, expanding this, so sym dot expand.
And I guess the main idea that I want to show you here is that the expand function will work also with
multiple variables. So it's not just with expressions that have only one variable.
You can also use multiple variables in this case x and y and that's really no problem.
So we've created quite a lot of variables here.
Well OK maybe not a lot but we've created several variables here.
The question is what are all the variables and the functions and the modules that we have imported into
python?
You can type percent
whos. And then basically just run this in its own cell and you will see a really nice, really useful
printout of all the objects and variables and things that have been imported into python.
So you see some of these are variables like X and Y.
We created these as symbolic variables.
Some of these are variables that we created like term one term, term 2 and term three.
And remember I also imported qwerty here, and then here is the entire module of sym that I imported.
And then we have math and display.
So anyway.
Percent whos is a really useful tool to show you what are all the things that you have in the python
workspace.
And it gives you some information about them including their class.
Here is the exercise for this video.
So what you want to do is create this function.
It's a function of two variables, x and y. Four plus X times -- so the quantity four plus x times the quantity
two minus Y. It's a pretty straightforward function.
Now what you want to do is loop through different values of x and y, in particular X and Y being 0 1
or 2 and then basically substitute for this function.
Each of these values, all of these values for x and all these values for y, and then print out a table
that looks something like this. So you can say when x equals zero and Y equals zero and then you keep
looping through.
So here are the three different possibilities for X and all the different possibilities for Y.
So now is your opportunity to pause the video.
Write some code.
Make sure you can get an output that looks like this and now I'm going to switch to Python and show
you my solution for this exercise.
All right.
So let's get started by writing out this function.
So let's say F X Y.
That's gonna be the variable.
And this is going to be that function was for plus X times two minus Y.
And of course I've already created X and Y to be symbolic variables.
So if you hadn't done that you would need to first run a line that looks something like this.
You could import X and Y at the same time but that is already done.
So now we have our function, and then let's just make sure we can get this to work for one variable.
So you have to remember that x y dot subs is the method for doing substitution and then the formatting
which is called a dictionary.
I'm going to talk more about what dictionaries look like and how they work later in the course.
But for now the only thing you have to remember is the variable name.
And then colon and the value.
So let's just start with one, and then a comma and then the next variable name and a colon and
then the value to substitute for that variable and let's do this about zero.
All right.
So we run this and we get the answer of 10.
Now it's probably worth going through the math quickly in our heads just to make sure that we get the
right answer.
Also it's a good exercise doing arithmetic in your head.
So we set X to be equal to 1 and that gives us five over here.
Times 2 minus 0 which is just used five times two equals 10.
All right, so that is pretty good.
So now we have our function. And the way that I'm going to set this up is to say num range equals range
of zero to three.
And that's because we want to create a set of numbers that goes from 0 to 2.
Remember it was 0 1 and 2.
So the range has to go from 0 to 1 greater than the top number.
So this has to be three here.
All right.
So now we need a double for loop.
We need to loop over values for x and we need to loop over values for Y.
So for let's call this X Y and num range and for y in num range.
And then what do we want to do inside this double for that.
So what we want to do is print out this message.
So let's see, that was when x equals zero and then I'm going to get back to replacing this in a moment.
When x equals zero and Y equals zero then F of X comma Y equals and then whatever it equals here let's
call that zero.
Okay.
So now that I have all this code written out I'm going to start doing some replacement.
So this is going to be %G, we're replacing with a number replacing with the number.
And then again replacing with a number.
So we have three number replacements.
So we need three numbers.
So when x equals xi, and Y equals yi, then the function f of x and y equals.
And then that's going to be almost this code not exactly this code.
So I'm cutting and pasting and now X we replace with x y and Y we replace with yi.
So this looks pretty good.
And now it's interesting to pick a couple of these at random and go through the math and make sure we
get the right answer.
And I think in the interest of time I will just pick one of these to go through.
So let's see.
So when x equals 1 and Y equals 2.
So when x equals one then we get five over here.
And then when y equals two we get two minus two is zero.
So then that ends up being zero.
And in fact every time Y equals two this second term equals zero.
So we should get a zero here which indeed we do.
So in this video I covered expanding terms using sympy.
And I showed you a few new tricks in the sympy module and python in general.