I'm pretty sure that you know what a circle is and you might even know the formula for a circle.
But if you don't then don't worry I'm going to give you a reminder on the next slide.
But the main point of this video is going to be to show you how to use the mesh grids that you learned
about in a previous video to making circles.
It's a pretty interesting application of those matrix grids.
All right so here we have a circle a circle has a particular radius typically indicated by R and it
has a center point which is often indicated as the coordinates H comma K where h corresponds to the
location on the x axis.
And k is the corresponding location on the y axis.
Here is the general formula.
So it's Y minus K and then the quantity squared plus X minus H.
And that quantity squared equals R squared.
Now when the circle is centered at the origin then k equals zero and H equals zero.
And that leads to the possibly more familiar looking version of this equation which is X squared plus
Y squared equals R squared.
All right so let's switch to Python and see how we can make a circle that looks like this.
In fact there are several ways that you can use python to create a circle and you've already seen some
of these ways in the past.
For example when creating the unit circle in the section on algebra 2.
So I'm going to show you a different method here and that is using mesh grid.
So let's start with the parameters.
So we have H equals about 2 and then K will set to minus 3 and then we need the radius.
And how about plus 3.
Okay.
So what we need now is a mesh grid so going to say capital X Capital Y equals num PI that mesh grid.
And then what should we put in here.
So this is certainly going to be something like vector X comma vector Y although in this case I'm going
to make a square mesh so this can be simplified to X by x.
So what should we set X to be.
Well we can write this out say in PI that Lynn space let's say like you know minus three two plus three
in one hundred steps.
But how do you know that minus three plus three is a good range.
In fact for these parameters this is probably not a good range because we're not going to see the entire
circle given that the center is at minus three and the radius is at or the radius is three.
So what I'd like to do is make this a little bit more dynamic so I'm gonna make this be a variable maybe
we'll call it X LIM So X minus X lambda plus X Lim.
So then we need to figure out what is an appropriate axis limit for this plot.
So one way we can do that is by considering what is going to be the most extreme point on the circle.
It's the most extreme point on the circle is going to be the larger of K or H plus R.
And if that reasoning doesn't totally make sense yet then don't worry I'm actually going to show you
a picture of this and then it will be a little clearer.
All right.
So let's define now this variable X Lim equals R Plus and P that Max H comma K.
But the thing is that K here is a larger offset.
So this is further away from the origin than this one.
However H is going to be the maximum.
What we really care about is the distance away from the origin.
So I'm going to do I'm going to write A B S H and then a B.S. K and I'm going to run this code but I
believe that this is going to crash here.
Yeah.
So this is gonna crash here and that's because the max function is actually expecting one input for
the numbers so that then the second input would be the axis or the dimension over which you are computing
the maximum.
So this extra set of parentheses will force both of these numbers to be in the first input into the
max function.
Okay.
So let's have a quick look at X and Y.
So I'm gonna write P.L. t that I am show X and I am show why it's always interesting to look at these
things and in general to plot your code as you're going through it.
Okay.
So what we're gonna do now is create the function so f of clients F of X Y because the way I think about
this is that you know if you would write this out in math notation it might look something like this
because a circle is a function of x and y.
So the function according to the slides is X minus a.
That should be h x minus a squared plus Y Capital Y minus K squared equals R squared.
However when we're defining functions in python you don't actually.
In fact you can't even set an equals sign like this because there's already another equals sign here
and this is definitely going to produce an error.
So the solution you will remember from earlier in the course is basically to set this entire equation
to be zero which means you have to move this term to the left.
So I'm going to say minus r squared and now implicitly the rest of this equation says equals zero.
But in Python we don't need to write this all right.
So that is our function.
Now how should we visualize this function.
Let's try making an image using I am show just like what we did to look at the mesh grids.
So.
Mm hmm.
Doesn't quite look like a circle.
I guess you can kind of see that there's a circle in here but it looks more like a colorful patch so
I'm going to actually take a totally different approach rather than showing this as an image.
I'm going to show this as a contour map.
So let's see what happens if I write BLT dot contour so a contour map is a map that shows lines around
regions that have the same height or the same magnitude.
This is kind of like if you go hiking with one of these topography Maps that shows you elevation.
So this would be the highest elevation.
And then you go down and these are constant elevations along these contour lines.
Now this still doesn't really quite look exactly like what you'd expect for a circle.
But what we can do is provide some extra inputs into the contour function.
In particular I'm going to write zero.
And that is only actually going to plot only the first contour.
And now I'm going to actually also provide a couple of additional inputs and that's going to be the
X and Y matrices and then python is going to use that to define the x axis labels and the Y or the Y
tick labels and the X stick labels.
All right.
So this is starting to look.
There's a couple more things I would like to do.
First of all I would like to plot some guidelines at the zero marks.
So at C P L T dot plot and now how far along do we go on the x axis.
Well on the x axis we actually go from minus X limb to plus X limb.
So this was in fact how we defined the x axis.
So the X axis for the line is going to go from minus X limb to plus X limb and on the y axis we go zero
to zero and then this is going to be a black dashed line like this.
And then I want another one to go on the basically to go to cut across this vertical up here at x equals
zero.
So therefore I'm going to just swap the orders of the zero line and the X limit.
All right.
And now no circle would be complete without a dot in its center.
So I'm going to plot a dot at the center SPL T dot plot H comma K and how about let's go for a green
green circle because this also spells go which is a little bit fun.
Okay.
Now this doesn't look like a circle it looks like an oval.
It actually is a circle.
The problem is that the axes are not square.
The x axis is wider than the y axis is tall.
And so to fix this I'm going to use P ulti that GCA forget get current axis which refers to this current
axis dot set aspect and then equal all right.
Now this is starting to look pretty good.
I would say and I'm sure you agree.
And now just to get back to this discussion here.
So the idea of defining these axis limits is we take the larger magnitude of the X or Y center of the
circle and then add a radius three and then whatever is that largest number.
That's basically going to be the outermost boundary of the entire circle and that happens to be this
point right here I think this is a pretty cool looking picture right here.
I hope you agree because the exercise for this video is to produce exactly this picture.
So let's see what I did what I did hear was create a bunch of circles with different radii and also
two circles at different locations so you can see here's a circle and then there's a circle and another
one and so on.
And then when you draw these two they get these kind of interesting interference patterns with each
other in the middle it's almost a bit like a venn diagram here and then at the end I just thought it
would look nice to draw a thick black line that goes from the center of one set of circles to the center
of the other set of circles.
All right.
So here's a few parameters I specified the circle centers to be minus one point five and plus one point
five on the x axis and the radii for the different circles go from point five up to three and you can
see that I also change the color so as the radius increases the color also gets lighter and later all
right.
So pause the video switch to Python see if you can figure out how to produce this exact image.
And now I'm going to switch to Python and you can watch me solve it.
All right so let's start with our parameters.
So we have the center is going to be minus one point five and one point five.
And then we need the grid spacing for mesh grid.
So let me start by writing this code here.
And B that mesh grid and let's call this a little X and a little X is going to be inspired.
Lynn space and what axis limit should we use here.
Well the top radius of the largest radius is three.
And here we have a center of one point five.
So we definitely need 4.5.
We couldn't go lower than 4.5.
Otherwise we're going to start cutting off the circles.
And so just to make sure we have enough room.
I'm gonna go from minus five to plus five and let's say a hundred steps.
Okay.
So just gonna run this code real quick.
I think it's good to run code every couple of lines that you add just to make sure that things are still
working right.
Good.
So what I'm going to do now is loop over the different radii and loop over these two centers.
So let's start with the radius loop.
So 4 are in and then here I was right.
And Peter Lin space from point five up to three.
And now I didn't tell you exactly how many circles you need.
Let's start with five.
And then here we want another loop.
Let's call this HDI for high in age.
So we have a loop that goes over radii and we have a loop that goes over the well the ages.
But this is really that the Centers for the two different circles.
Okay so now what I'm going to do is define the function for the circle.
So X minus and now it's high squared plus.
And you know you could write it Y minus zero squared but that's you know this is like formally correct
but it's a little bit redundant.
So I think it's easier to read like this minus r squared.
So this R is changing at each iteration of this loop and this center location is changing at each iteration
of this loop.
Okay.
So now we have our function and then we just plot a contour so plot dot contour X comma Y comma F of
X Y and then we want zero indicating that it's just gonna show the first contour.
All right.
So let's see then I do peel t the show and let's already see how this is looking.
So it's already looking pretty cool.
There's of course some more things we need to add to get this to look really good.
So I'm going to start by saying axis off and P L T that get current axis that set aspects to be equal.
All right.
Slowly looking better now one thing is there aren't enough circles here so let's try.
Let's go for 15 circles over here.
So 15 different routes 15 different radii.
Now it's 15.
There you go.
So this is the right number of circles.
There's only two things that are still missing.
One is the black line that goes from one center to the other center and the other is the color to make
the circles kind of fade off into the ether of non-existence as they get further away from the center.
It's going to start with this black line first.
So let's see this is gonna be P L T dot plot.
Now where do we want the plot to go.
It actually has to go from minus one point five to plus one point five.
So in fact this variable is already set for us.
So we just say h on the x axis and the y axis goes zero to zero.
And it should be a black line.
So this is kind of good except I want it to be a little bit thicker.
So how about line with equals 10.
Okay.
It's a little bit thick.
Maybe three.
Okay that looks a little bit better.
Right.
So now we need to change the color.
So colors equals.
And then this is gonna be the colors for the contour plot.
Now in this case we only need to specify one color because we just have one contour.
So for example if you set this to be like point four come a point four come a point four let's run this
code and see if that works.
Okay.
So that works.
But now every circle has the same grayscale.
So we need to figure out a way to make the color here be a function of r be a function of this to go
from point five to three.
Now these colors the way that Python once these colors specified it's in fractions of total RG B values.
So if you try to specify color values RG B values that are greater than 1 then you're going to get an
error it's actually really really longer.
So you can see it worked for a couple of circles but then after I guess the third circle this becomes
this value becomes larger than one.
So then what you can do is basically just divide this by something.
So it has to be divided by at least three because that's going to give us a result of 1 1 1 and then
if you like you can try some more value.
So you know you can say set the middle one which is the green let's make this a little bit smaller.
And here we have red.
Maybe I'll divide that by four.
And then you're gonna get some interesting different color patterns emerging.
But this is the set of colors that I used for the plot that I showed in the slides I hope you agree
that that was a really cool looking graphic using concentric circles.
And if you don't think that was a cool looking graphic if you think that was really boring and totally
lame then I challenge you to make a much nicer one and post it on the Q and A forum so you can make
a fool out of me.
I look forward to seeing your results.