The goal of this video is to introduce you a little bit more to the sympy module and integrating
sympy with latex.
So this goes a little bit beyond what I showed you in the past couple of videos and it will give you
a bit more experience and more comfort with working with symbolic variables and printing out nice looking
equations in a python notebook.
So let's just immediately switch to Python and get started.
So we start of course by importing the sympy module, so I'm going to say import sympy as sym.
All right.
Now I press controlled enter to run this cell and give me a new cell below it.
So in the last video, or I guess it was two videos ago, I showed you how to create a single symbolic variable.
It was something like this, sym dot symbols and then with an X.
So that's fine.
And what I'm going to show you here is that you are not limited to just using single letters like this.
In particular, I'm going to show you using Greek characters as variable names, so let's say we have mu
Alpha and Sigma and then they need to be called the corresponding things here.
So mu, Alpha, Sigma. And now we can run this code.
And now we get three new variables in the workspace, so I can now use these as symbolic variables so
for example let's say we want to have an expression that's e to the something.
So I'm going to say in this symbolic tool box the function for the natural exponent e and if you're
not familiar with the natural exponent yet then don't worry, I'm going to introduce that in the next
section of the course.
but it's the function is called exp for exponential, it's the natural exponent.
So let's say we want this to be mu minus alpha squared divided by two times sigma squared.
So this turns out to be the formula for something called a Gaussian, which is also called a normal curve
or a bell curve. It's something that starts close to zero
and it comes up smoothly and then it goes back down to zero.
OK.
So I can run this cell and then the output is basically just what I inputted here, and now what I'm going to
do is set this entire expression to be a variable.
So let's even call that variable expr for expression.
So let's see if we can make this look a little bit nicer so I can try printing out the expression and
that doesn't really look any nicer.
This is certainly not a nice mathematical formatting.
Maybe we should try using the display function which I like to use.
And of course for this display function to work we need to import from IPython dot display
is from
IPython dot display we want to import the display function.
OK.
So run that.
And now I run this and now this doesn't really look any nicer than it did with the print function.
So in a previous video I introduced a function that you can activate in the sympy toolbox called
init.
Printing. And then, that is going to make this equation look a little bit nicer.
So here I have sym dot exp for the natural exponential, and then in the parentheses is everything that
goes into the exponent.
So this is E to the.
And then you can see, or maybe after zoom in a little bit on your display, minus alpha plus mu.
So it actually turn this around here about mu minus alpha, squared divided by two sigma squared.
So the point of this exercise, the point of this cell here was, to see that you can have symbolic variables
that are longer than just a single letter.
And if those correspond to Greek characters then sympy will know that when you write mu, when you
use mu as a variable name, it should convert that into the Greek letter mu.
You can also make up your own longer variable names. For example you can say hello equals sym dot symbols
and then I'm gonna call this variable.
Hello.
And now I can write Hello.
Divided by three.
So there you go.
I'm not totally sure what that means mathematically.
One third of a hello... but this does show that you can create arbitrary variable names to be symbolic
variables.
OK.
So let me get a single variable X in here. So I can introduce you to substitutions sym dot symbols and
let's make this X.
So now I previously showed you that you can have some expression that is let's say x plus four.
And if we look at what this expression is, it's really just X plus four, X is a symbolic variable.
It doesn't yet have a value so it just prints out as x plus four.
This is how it's represented. But there is a method in sympy expressions, called subs which stands for
substitution.
So here I can substitute X for let's say how about six.
So I write
Expr, which is just this variable name, dot subs and then X comma six.
And now the answer I get is 10.
And so what Python did here, what the sympy module in Python did here, is look inside this expression,
this expression here, for a symbolic variable called X and it substituted 6 for X. So it replaced wherever
you see X in here, it replaced that with six in here.
So we can try this with some other variables I can say minus four.
And then we get zero.
So this is for one variable.
You can also substitute for multiple variables.
So let's say X comma Y equals sym dot symbols X comma y.
Okay.
Now so far I haven't changed anything but now I'm going to put X or say y in here as well.
So let's make this expression x plus four plus two times y.
Okay.
So now what do you think is going to happen when I run this code again?
I'm only substituting X I'm not specifying anything for y to be I'm just telling Python to substitute
X with minus 4.
So what happens is that we get two Y. And this should make sense because I told Python to replace X with
minus 4 so it did that.
So this becomes minus four plus four is zero.
And then what we're left with in this expression is two Y, but I haven't told Python how to replace y
or substitute anything for Y.
So the answer is just two y.
Okay.
So how might we go about substituting a value for X and a value for y? You might think that it would
be something simple like this, let's say, let's make this how about three.
However that is not the proper syntax.
This is the error is that subs, which is this method, here accepts either one or two arguments and we've
provided four arguments. So the correct approach here is to input not a list of variables and substitution
numbers like this but instead to input a dictionary.
Now if you're not yet familiar with dictionaries in Python don't worry I'm going to have a whole video
later on in the course just about dictionaries and introducing you to dictionaries. For now you don't
have to worry about the terms you can just pay attention to the syntax itself.
So what I'm going to do is have curly brackets like this.
Now this is actually just one input into this method and then we need to change this slightly so it's
going to say X colon minus four comma Y colon three.
So now I'm letting Python know that I'm going to replace X with minus four and Y with three.
So now I can run this and the answer is six and let's make sure that makes sense.
We have minus four plus four that turns out to be zero and then two times Y and Y equals three.
So that's six.
So in fact we can confirm that this is the right answer.
Okay so now I want to get back to talking a little bit about latex coding and integrating latex
with Python.
So let's start by making another expression. How about three divided by x.
Pretty simple expression.
So in the sympy module there's another function called latex.
And if you input an expression, then the result is going to be the latex code that you can use in Python
to print out this expression.
So now I can write display math and then the latex code corresponding to this expression here.
All right.
Now in this case we got an error and I believe that you are knowledgeable enough at this point in the
course to diagnose this error and correct it. And I'm sure you've guessed it right.
The problem is that we haven't yet imported the math function into the python workspace.
So I'm going to scroll up to the top here and say from Ipython dot display import display and also import
math and then I run this cell again and now I believe that this should work.
So here we get three divided by X.
Now notice what's going to happen if I delete this sympy latex function.
Here we get an error and the error is that the math function expects text.
So the math function is actually looking for latex code, not a sympy expression. So we need the sym dot
latex in order to convert from this expression into latex code and then the output of this function
is the latex code that gets input into math and display and that's what gives us this nice message here.
I would now like to show you a little bit more about using the sym dot latex function.
So I already showed you here that the output of sym dot latex is going to be a string it's going to be
text which corresponds to latex code that you can then use in Python.
So that was for this expression. This already is a simple expression because I've defined X to be a symbolic
variable. But what if you would just put in some fraction and let's say three divided by four.
Now here sym dot latex actually outputs point seventy five.
So when in fact it computed three point three divided by four which is point seven five.
And then just converted the number point seven five into the string
point seven five. You can see those single quotes surrounding it.
So this is in fact a string.
Now if you would like to get the latex code corresponding to three divided by four, you might think that
the way to do that would be to already start with a string.
However this doesn't work either. Now in this case, latex is just seeing the string three
slash four.
And it's simply printing out the latex code for this string.
But you know the latex code in this case is just the same thing as these characters here.
So in fact what we need to do is convert this string into a sympy object. And the way that you do that
is with another function called sym dot sympify.
It kind of a weird function name because there is another function called simplify with an i.
That would be to simplify an expression and you'll learn more about using the function simplify in
the future.
But this is actually sympify, like to convert this string into a sympy object.
So now let's see what happens when we run this cell and we get slash slash frac 3 4.
So this is now code that you could input directly into display and and then math exactly like this.
And this would be the way to get this fraction three divided by four to be printed out using LaTeX in
Ipython notebook
Here is the exercise for this video. So you can see this mathematical expression: X squared plus four.
And what you're going to do is substitute X for minus two, minus 1 0 1 and 2 and then you basically print
out the results, so print out the substitution and then print out the final result like this.
So that's the important part, getting this part and this part. If you want a little bit of an extra challenge
then you can also figure out how to print this right arrow in latex.
And also a space that you can see there's a big space here and then a right arrow and then a big space
over here.
All right.
So now is your opportunity to pause the video, switch to Python on your own and see how far you can get
with this challenge.
And then when you're ready, you come back to the video and you can watch me switch to Python.
And now I'm going to solve it.
All right so let's get started by just printing out one line and then once I have that one line working
then I'm going to put that one line inside of a loop and then get the whole thing to display.
So let's start with our expression.
I'll say the expression is X squared plus four.
Now of course I don't need to redefine X because I've already defined X up here to be a symbolic variable.
So if you're starting from a fresh Python workspace you would also need to set up this and of course
you would need to run this stuff as well.
Okay.
So here is our expression.
And then to display, we want to say display and then math
and now this has to write with...
Now first I'm just going to hard code everything and write this out and then I'm going to go back and
start replacing all of the variables where necessary.
So with X equals minus two.
That's what it's going to be on the first run.
X squared plus four.
And now to get a large space in latex you can use the expression quad.
So that's going to give me a big space and then to get a right arrow.
You can say right arrow.
All one word, of course with slashes because we don't want the word right arrow.
We want slash right arrow and then we need this escape character here to let Python know that we are
going to be using a special latex word here. And then add another space here quad.
And then it's going to be minus two squared plus four equals.
So this is going to end up being four plus four.
So that equals eight.
Okay.
So I'm going to run this cell now and make sure that it looks good.
So this part looks fine.
So with X equals minus two, X squared plus four goes to minus two squared plus four, which is eight.
However this with doesn't look right.
And the problem here is we need to make this explicit text so like this.
All right.
So this is starting to look good.
And here you can see this nice big space that I got from using the quad keyword in latex.
All right.
So we're getting there.
I need some substitutions now.
So this needs to be substituted and this and the answer needs to be substituted.
So I'm going to say percent G here and then we need another percent G here and a third percent G here.
And then I need to indicate all of these substitutions into everywhere I've written this percent G.
So the first substitution is going to be minus two.
And then again minus two.
And then it's going to be the answer.
So that is expr subs and here I'm substituting X with minus two.
All right.
So now I'm going to run all of this code again and we see with X equals minus two comma X squared plus
four goes to minus two squared plus four.
And that does indeed equal eight.
So now this looks really good.
Now what we need to do is get this whole thing to work inside a for loop.
So let's say for i in range.
So remember this loop is going to go from minus two to plus two, which means that the second input into
the range function here has to be three -- one higher than the upper bound for the counting.
Okay.
So now this is no longer hardcoded to minus two.
This has to be I and I.
And then we are substituting in I.
Let's see.
So I think I've done that all correctly and yet this all looks really good to me.
So this is all fine.
There's one more thing I want to show you, just to highlight another feature of working with sympy
and substitution.
So here I've written this expression out explicitly, which is fine but it turns out that we can do even
something a little bit simpler.
So I'm going to say answer equals X plus four dots subs, and I'm going to substitute X for I squared and then
here this ends up just being the answer because I've already computed it.
So let me get rid of this and now I will explain what I'm doing here.
So here I'm not actually creating a variable for the expression; I'm just putting the entire expression
into parentheses. And I don't need to have a separate variable so then I'm substituting X in this expression
here for I squared.
Now of course you could have also written this to be X squared and then you're substituting an X for
I. I just want to show you some of the flexibility that you have when you are creating sympy expressions
and then substituting in variables.
So I'm going to run this again and make sure that this all works and we get 8 and 5 4 5 8.
So this is all still equally correct. So I hope you enjoyed this video and I hope you feel like you are
starting to learn how to use the sympy module in python. In the next video, you are going to get to see
a real practical example of using sympy to understand an important principle in mathematics.