In this video I'm going to show you one of the many many applications of the dot product which is something
called the correlation coefficient.
I'm sure you have heard of the correlation coefficient before it's one of the most popular ways of determining
whether there is a linear relationship between two variables.
It's one of the most foundational tests in statistics for looking at co variation between two variables.
And along the way you will of course get more experience working with dot products and vectors and other
sorts of things in python.
All right.
So let me start by saying that all the data that I use in this video are all fake.
I just made up these numbers.
All right.
So let's imagine that I did a survey I went around and talked to my students and I asked them how many
of my courses have they taken and how happy are they in life.
So this number speaks for itself.
So this person took four courses this person took nine of my courses good for these two people.
And here is how happy they are.
And this is rated on a scale from 1 to 10.
So one means you are totally totally miserable and 10 means you could not possibly be happier or you
are just screaming with happiness constantly.
All the time.
So higher is happier.
This is referring to the number by the way just in case of some ambiguity about that statement.
So now I would like to know is there a relationship between the number of courses that people have taken
and how happy they are in life.
Now the way that we go about computing this correlation is through a procedure called the correlation
coefficient more formally the Pearson correlation coefficient.
Here is the formula for computing the correlation coefficient.
This is a screenshot from the Wikipedia page on correlation.
So we have X and Y.
These are two variables.
So we could call x the number of Mike's courses that were taken and y the life happiness and the bar
on top of the x and y refers to the mean or the average value.
So essentially this means you take each individual element in X and each l l individual element in y
subtract the respective means from that variable and then element y's multiply and then some.
Huh.
Doesn't that sound familiar element Y is multiply and then sum up all of those multiplications.
That is exactly the dot product.
So that's the numerator of the Pearson correlation coefficient the denominator has two terms and it
initially looks a little confusing.
It looks like there's a lot going on here.
But if you break this down you can see that this is actually pretty straightforward.
So you take each individual element in X subtract the mean and then square it.
So when you're squaring it you're actually just multiplying this term by itself.
And now if you multiply this term by itself that's really just like what you see in the numerator.
Except this is X and X instead of here this is X and Y.
So in fact what you see in the denominator here is the dot product of X with itself.
And then you take the square root of that times the dot product of y with itself and then you take the
square root of that.
And there you go.
You have the correlation coefficient.
All right.
So now what we're going to do is switch to Python and I'm going to basically get this to work from first
principles from the ground up so I've already imported the NUM pi module and the matte plot live that
pie plot.
That's because I went to make a visualization of these data visualization is obviously super important
in statistics and data analysis and in math in general.
Okay so let's see what I'm going to do first is means center these data so mean center.
That's a fancy sounding term but it really just means to subtract the mean and also make these shorter
variables just for convenience so let's say variable m equals Mike's courses minus num PI that mean
of Mike's courses.
So now I'm subtracting the average of all these ratings are these numbers of course is taken from each
individual element and actually you know just out of curiosity let's see what that looks like.
Okay.
So you can see that now the numbers are negative some of them are negative some of them are positive.
Now of course when you subtract the mean from a vector like this the numbers themselves don't really
make any sense anymore.
You know what does it mean.
If someone took minus four point three courses it doesn't even that doesn't make sense but that's OK.
The goal is not to interpret this variable in terms of like the physical world.
The goal is to convert this into a form that we can use for computing the correlation.
All right.
So now we do the same thing here.
So this is l equals life happiness minus and P that mean life happiness.
OK.
So now we have our means centered variables and now I'm going to compute the correlation.
So I'm going to divide this up into two separate terms.
So there is the numerator and that was just the dot product between M and L and then we have the denominator
and that was the square root square root of the dot product of M with M times the square root of the
dot product of L with L.
Now if these terms look a little bit confusing then I encourage you to pause the video.
Go back two minutes to the slides where I showed you the formula or you could look it up on your own
online and compare that formula to basically these four lines of code here.
OK.
So then I'm going to call the correlation between them are 1 so our 1 was just the numerator divided
by the denominator and now just to make sure that I'm really doing the right thing I'm going to say
ah whoops R two equals end p that core Clef M comma l.
So now this is using the NUM pi function to compute the correlation coefficient between M and L.
All right.
So let's print out r 1 and then I will print out R to so let's see what we have here.
So our one is point six 0.
So let's just call this point six.
So there is a positive and a fairly strong correlation between the number of Mike's courses taken and
general happiness in life.
So that is encouraging the correlation coefficient varies between minus 1 and plus 1 where one means
a perfect correlation.
Zero means absolutely no correlation whatsoever and minus one would mean a negative correlation.
I certainly hope there wouldn't be a negative correlation here.
It would mean that the more courses of mine that people take the worse they feel their happiness goes
down anyway.
So that's our one.
What is going on with our two here.
This seems to be a matrix of numbers where the off diagonal elements are the same and they're the same
as the correlation that we computed here.
So what's happening is that the function core co F is computing a matrix of correlations.
So it's computing a correlation matrix.
The diagonal is showing that each vector is perfectly correlated with itself.
So the number of courses that you've taken is correlated with the number of courses that you've taken
obviously.
So that correlation is perfect.
So that's one.
Okay.
So what we want is any either one of these off diagonal elements here.
So I'm going to specify that what we want is you know let's just say this element over here.
Okay.
And now we get exactly the same result.
So that's helpful.
That confirms that I have implemented the algorithm for computing the correlation coefficient accurately
because I get the same result as Python's built in function.
All right.
So you should never just trust a number in statistics you always want to see a graph.
You always want to see what the plot looks like.
So let's say peel to dot plot and I want to plot Mike's courses on the x axis and life happiness on
the y axis.
I'm gonna make these magenta squares and I will set the label to be the correlation coefficient.
So G and percent are one or R2 it actually doesn't matter all right let's see how this looks.
Okay so here we have the number of course is taken and general life happiness.
And mostly this goes up except look at this one person he or she has taken nine of my courses and they
are still miserable.
I don't know what's the deal with this person maybe they need to take even more of my courses and then
I'll feel better.
All right.
So now let me take a moment to make this plot look a little bit nicer.
So let's say the Axis I'm going to specify this going from zero to 10 and zero to 10.
And now it doesn't make sense to have negative numbers in here because these are all positive numbers.
The number of courses you've taken and life happiness.
Well I guess that could be negative but I'm imagining that this goes on a score from one to 10 and let's
see we need to activate the legend and it's good to have a label here.
So let's write P L T that X label number of Mike's courses taken.
Now grammatically this should be a quote to indicate possessive but as soon as you use a single quote
here that's actually going to confuse python a little bit.
So there's two options.
One is you can use a double quote like this which will actually just print out.
Sorry I meant not a double quote.
This should be a slash and then a quote and that's going to be like an escaped character to print out
the quote.
Or alternatively you could use double quotes here in the outside and then you can just use a single
quote on the inside like this Oh right.
So then we need P L T that y label.
And this is going to be life happiness.
Let's see.
So I want this graph to be square.
I want this to be I want the aspect ratio to be the same so I'm also going to change the get current
axis that set aspect to be equal.
And then the other thing I would like to change is to round this off to two significant digits.
Basically this is a whole lot of numbers and we really only need to know let's say the first two.
So I'm gonna write and p dot round and then comma to to round this result to two significant digits.
Okay.
So in my imaginary world where I made up these data This clearly means that if you want to be happy
in life you need to take more of my courses except if you are this person and to this person I sincerely
apologize.
I hope it wasn't my courses that made you so unhappy all jokes aside you learned in this course that
the correlation coefficient which is one of the most important and basic operations in all of statistical
analysis is really just an application of the dot product which itself is a pretty straightforward operation.