Now that you are familiar with using sympy,
I'm going to show you an example of how to use sympy and Python more generally to understand important
concepts in mathematics.
In this particular example in this video we are going to discuss the law of exponents and we are going
to see how to understand the law of exponents by using coding in Python.
So if you're not familiar with the law of exponents, it sounds really fancy, it sounds really exciting...
but it's actually not such a big deal.
So the law of exponents basically says that if you have two terms that are multiplying each other and
they both have exponentials, they both have something in the exponents up here, then if those bases
are the same then you can add the exponential.
So X to the power of y times X to the power of Z can be simplified to X to the power of y plus Z.
And this is valid only when these two terms are multiplying each other.
And only when the bases are the same. It also works for division.
And that's because X to the Z or I should say 1 over X to the Z, is the same thing as X to the minus
Z.
So then X to the power of y divided by X to the power of Z is the same thing -- we can rewrite this term
as X to the power of y times X to the power of minus Z, which means we can rewrite this expression
as X to the power of y minus Z.
This third line down here is just highlighting that this procedure,
this simplification, works only when the bases are the same.
So if you have X to the power of y and y to the power of Z these bases are not the same.
So it's not possible to simplify this.
This is actually as simplified already as it possibly can be.
All right so with this in mind we are now going to switch to Python and illustrate some of these concepts
using sympy.
So let's start off by creating some symbolic variables.
We'll need X and Y and Z and then say sym dot symbols and then X comma Y comma Z.
So now I can create an expression.
So let's call this X for expression X to the power of y times X to the power of Z.
Now you might be wondering how I can be so sure that the X side of the Y is associated with x and z
is associated with X.
And how do I know that I'm not writing some weird expression that looks like this.
And that has to do with the order of operations, which you learned about in the previous section.
So essentially, the order of operations tells us that powers have higher priority than multiplication.
All right.
So I can write this out now to say display and then x.
So this just displays with the asterisks.
That's no more readable than this is already.
So if I want this to look nice, I basically have two options.
One is I can use display math and then sympy latex. So convert this sympy expression to latex. Or I
can set up the sym dot init.
printing. And then I can just use the display function, just like this.
Now sometimes it's advantageous to have the init printing and just the display, and sometimes it's advantageous
to do what I previously did, which is have the math function and the sym dot latex.
It really depends on how much you are going to show.
In this case I'm only going to show these simple expressions, without adding anything special or having
any string replacements.
So for now this is sufficient.
Now I'm going to use another sympy function, and that is called simplify. So sym dot simplify.
And essentially, that's going to simplify whatever is the input expression, so I input this expression
which is this expression.
So X to the Y and X times X Z.
And basically python is going to analyze this mathematical expression here and determine whether it's
possible to simplify this expression. And if it is, then it will return
that expression simplified.
If it cannot be simplified, then it will just return the same thing.
So now I run this.
You can see that Python simplified X to the Y times X to the Z, with X to the Y plus zed. And now,
out of curiosity, we can change this X to a y here, run this cell again, and now you see that both of these
expressions both these lines are the same.
And that's because this expression is already simplified as much as it possibly can be.
All right.
So let's change this back.
Great.
So now I'm gonna set up a couple of different expressions.
I'm going to say x 1 equals this guy again.
Essentially I'm going to write out the three expressions that I showed in these slides. x 2 equals x
to the power of y divided by X to the power of Z and then expression 3 is going to be equal X to the
power of y times Y to the power of Z.
So again, these are the three expressions or I should say the Python implementation of the three expressions
that I wrote out in these slides.
And essentially what I want to do is say that this expression equals it's simplified version.
I'm going to write display and now here I need to write a little bit more involved text.
So I'm going to need to incorporate math.
This math function and latex coding.
So this is going to say basically expression 1 equals the simplified version of expression 1.
So there's going to be percent x equals percent x and then I'm going to replace percent s -- these strings --
with x 1 and sym dot simplify x 1.
Okay.
So you can see what I'm doing: I'm saying the expression as I wrote it here equals the simplified version
of the expression.
So now I'm going to run this code and let's see what it looks like.
All right.
So this doesn't really look that nice.
It doesn't look like easily readable math notation, although you can see it did simplify the expression
to Y plus z in the exponent here. So the problem here is that I'm simply inputting a string into the
math function. But what I want to input is latex code into the math function.
So now you will remember from a previous video, that we can convert this sympy expression into
latex with the function sym dot latex.
So now we have half of this expression looking good.
And then we have seen that latex and now both sides look good.
Now there's something I would like to point out here, which is that this is a pretty long and pretty
difficult to read line of code.
There is a lot of sym dot going on here.
So there's one two three sym dot functions.
Now if you like, you could create separate variables for this, so you could say something like x 1 simplify
or simple equals simple simplify x 1.
If you prefer making additional variables to simplify this line of code then go for it but you can also
see the importance of building up your code
one simple straightforward piece at a time, and slowly adding more complexity to it as necessary.
All right.
Fortunately, once we have confirmed that this line is correct, then it's really easy to do this for everything
else.
I just need to replace the one with the two.
And here the one with the three.
So now we see the law of exponents in action. Here, the exponent simplified because the base term is the
same.
This also simplified and this does not simplify because here at the base term is different.
So this is one way to use Python and sympy as tools for understanding the law of exponents.
And of course this is just an example of how you can use this to understand concepts in mathematics.
I'm going to insert a new cell below and I'm going to show you another way to understand math concepts and
that's going to be using something called sym dot eq and this stands for equal.
And the way that sym dot eq, or equal, works is you give one or two inputs. So you can give one input,
corresponding to the left hand side of the equation.
So let's say for and then you can give a second input, which would correspond to these -- the right hand
side of the equation.
So what I'm writing out here this is equivalent to saying 4 equals two plus two, four equals two plus
two.
So the first input here corresponds to the left hand side of the equation.
And the second input corresponds to the right hand side of the equation.
And now what sympy is going to return is a boolean saying whether this is true or false.
Now in this case it's true because the left hand side of this equation does indeed equal the right hand
side of this equation.
I can make this two point one, and now of course it's false.
So that's just inputting numbers.
I can also use variables, so let's say l h s this is for the left hand side of the equation.
Let's say that equals 4, and then the right hand side equals let's say 6 minus
2.
And now we're going to write left hand side comma right hand side.
Okay.
And this is true.
So far nothing spectacularly novel.
The main thing that I want to show you is that you can also set up this equation with this function
with only one input and they're essentially what you're doing is converting this equation.
So just to show you before we had four equals two plus two so I can subtract two plus two from both
sides of this equation and write, for example, four minus two plus two equals zero.
Notice I've just taken this from... so I've taken the right hand side of the equation, and moved it over
to the left hand side of the equation with a subtraction of course, because really what I'm doing is
subtracting two plus two from both sides of the equation.
And then you get zero on the right hand side.
Now sometimes this can be a little bit more handy and when you don't provide a second input then you're
actually implicitly setting
the second input to be zero.
And by putting the cursor inside the parentheses here and then pressing shift tab to see the help function,
we can also see that the first input is the left hand side.
The second input says right hand side equals zero.
When you see this equals zero here, that means that the default for Python, if you don't provide a second
input, is to set the second input to be zero.
All right.
So let me get rid of these
and so what you might think of doing is saying something like e x 1, so expression 1, equals the simplified
version.
So simplify ex1. Now you might have expected this to return true.
However, in a strict theoretical sense it is difficult to prove unequivocally in the general case that
these two are equal for all symbolic variables.
Similarly, if I would subtract these two and set them equal to zero then I just get the expression printed
out essentially simply as telling me that there isn't enough information in this input to determine
unequivocally whether this expression is true or whether it's not true.
So therefore Python is just printing out the expression.
So if you're in a situation like this what you can do is expand everything, so you can say sympy dot
expand, which essentially undoes all of these simplifications.
And now we get an answer of true.
So here I've shown you a couple of different ways for showing simplifications of expressions.
In this case with an application for the law of exponents.
Now in this particular example, because we are dealing with exponents and powers, there is another function
which you could have used which is called sym dot powsimp.
.
So this is power simplification.
And then I can type e x 1 and the result is going to be X to the power of Y minus.
So you can see that there are many many functions in the sympy module.
You don't really need to worry about memorizing all of them.
Some expressions are more useful, you'll use them often; some expressions are a little bit more specific
and you won't use them so often.
But as you continue going through in this course and the rest of your career in mathematics and data
science and quantitative things in general, you will become more familiar with the many functions in
Python and in sympy. So I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
Essentially we took some of the knowledge gained in a previous few videos about simplify and latex to
understand an important mathematical concept which is the law of exponents.