In this video I'm going to introduce you to the concept of comments in Python.
It'll be a fairly short video because comments are pretty straightforward.
However, they are really important for writing good clean and efficient code that you and other people
can understand and work with and adapt.
So therefore I think it's worth having a whole video just about comments. So I'm going to start by setting
some variable X to be equal 5 and then if we just type x here then python will print out the value of
x which is 5.
So far nothing particularly weird or new or interesting.
Now I'm going to set another variable and let's say Y equals 3.
Now before running this code I'm going to put a hashtag here at the beginning of this line.
Now this is not the way of indicating that this is supposed to be trending on Twitter.
Instead this is indicating what's called a "comment" in python.
Now notice what happened to this code when I put the hash tag in the beginning of the line.
First of all, all the text turned green instead of being the normal colors.
Secondly, the font is now italics instead of being straight up.
OK so I can run this code again.
No problem.
Nothing has changed.
X is still equal to 5.
However when I type Y here and request that Python tell me the value of y.
I get an error message.
It says variable Y is not defined.
Now that may seem a little bit strange because I just defined it right here.
But what's happening is that this piece of code or this piece of text I should say is in a comment.
And Python ignores any text that's inside a comment which means any text that comes after a hashtag.
So if you actually want to specify or define y to be equal to three you can delete that hashtag.
And now of course Y equals 3.
So there are two ways to create comments in Python.
One way is what I just illustrated and that's having a comment be on its own line.
So you start with a hash like this and then you can write some useful comment.
Maybe you want to say, this is where the variables are defined. And then perhaps later down in the code
you're going to say, this is where the let's say the functions are defined.
And so on.
And then there's going to be more code here.
So this is one way to make comments in python. A second way is to have the comments appearing after a
valid line of code.
So in this case we say X equals five.
And then now I put a hash tag and maybe a comment.
Is this used to be two point three.
So maybe that's relevant for some particular reason that you're implementing in this code.
And just to prove to you that Python actually will interpret this part of the code I'm even going to
set this to be Z.
Now you can see z equals 5.
So python will still evaluate all of the text before the hash mark as code and anything after the hash
mark will be ignored.
And this is just going to be comments for you.
So the last thing that I want to illustrate to you in this video is a keyboard shortcut for toggling
whether a line of code has or doesn't have a comment.
So on windows you have press control and then the forward slash.
Now notice that as I press control forward slash over and over again that's toggling whether this
line starts with a hash or doesn't start with a hash.
So that's just a convenient keyboard shortcut.
You can also select multiple lines of code and then press control forward slash again.
And now I'm toggling whether all of these lines of code are commented or whether they are uncommented.
So there you go.
Now you know how to create comments in Python and you know a keyboard shortcut for setting an entire
line or multiple selected lines to be commented.
Comments are really useful for helping you organize your code and helping make your code be readable
not only to other people but also to yourself.
And that's because when you come back to your own code in a week or a month or a year, you're probably
going to forget a lot of what you were thinking about when you were first writing the code.
So making comments is really useful to help you remember and understand what the goal of the code is
and how the code is organized.