In this video I'm going to show you how to compute powers, that is exponents, using Python.
I'll also introduce you to the law of exponents in case you're not familiar with the law of exponents.
If you are familiar with the law of exponents, then this will be a useful reminder.
And you're also going to learn a little bit more about printing out really nice looking mathematical
expressions in python using LaTeX.
So raising one number to a power of another number in this case three to the power of two, which is also
called three squared, simply means multiplying the base number by itself
this number of times. So three squared equals three times three and therefore three to the Power of Four
means three times three times three times three.
So we have four threes that all get multiplied here.
Then we get to something called the law of exponents which sounds really fancy and formal but it basically
just means that if you have the same base then you can add the exponents.
So in this case we have three to the power of two times three to the power of four.
And this is equivalent to -- this is the same thing as -- we can rewrite this expression as three to the power
of two plus four.
And you have to be mindful that the plus four is also in the exponent here.
So this is not three squared plus four this is three to the power of two plus four which is three to
the power of six.
And basically that means multiplying three out six times.
Now the law of exponents also states that this is only possible when the base is the same.
So in this case we have three to the power of two times four to the power of three.
And you can't really simplify this much further, so you can write out three times three which is this
term times four times four times four which is this term and then you can multiply them altogether.
But it's not possible to simplify the exponents because the base term is different.
OK.
So now let's switch to Python and see how to compute powers in python
so to put a number into an exponent in python you actually use an asterisk, but a double asterisk.
So this might seem a little bit confusing at first because a single asterisk like this one star means
to multiply.
So here the answer would be three times two which is six.
But in this case we say three star star.
So two asterisks and then two.
And that means to raise three to the second power.
So there the answer is going to be nine of course because three times three is nine. One easy to make
mistake is say three caret.
-- This is called the caret symbol -- two.
Now when you're writing out exponents in text on computers people often use this caret symbol like this.
So sometimes people would write an expression like this and they mean three squared.
However in Python the caret symbol is something else.
This refers to the X or logical problem. I'm not going to cover that
in this video, but it's pretty easy to see that this gives you the wrong answer.
So three caret two is not the same thing as three squared.
So you just have to be a bit mindful of that.
Powers are always indicated with two asterisks.
Of course you can also use variables like you've learned in previous videos.
I can say x equals two and then three to the power of x is going to be nine.
And now it's really easy for me to change this to let's say six and then three to the power of six turns
out to be seven hundred and twenty nine.
Okay.
Let's make a little demonstration of the law of exponents.
So I'm going to say three to the power of three, which is twenty seven because three times three is nine
and then times three again is twenty seven.
So therefore three times three times three must also be twenty seven.
And you know by now by this point in the course you know that this is not going to print out twenty
seven twice because the output of this expression doesn't get printed.
Only the output of the final expression in each cell gets printed out.
So instead I'm going to use the print function, so print here and then another print here.
And now this is going to print out twenty seven twice this first twenty seven corresponds to this expression
and this corresponds to this expression.
Now what I'd like to do is use python to illustrate the concept that I showed in the slides that if
you have two numbers taken to the same power, multiplied by each other, you can add the exponent and keep
the base the same.
So I think I'll even use the example that I showed in the slide.
So that was three to the power of two times three to the power of four.
Now there's a lot of asterisks going on here in this line.
So it may look a little confusing at first but notice that I'm using spaces to separate this term from
this term.
As I mentioned in a previous video, you can write it out like this with no spaces and you get exactly
the same result.
However, adding spaces like this makes the expression a little bit easier to interpret.
Now if you're wondering why Python knows that this should be three squared times three to the four and
not for example grouping these terms together so three to the power of six and then that to the power
of four.
That's because of something called the order of operations.
I mentioned this term before.
Order of operations.
I'm going to have a whole video about order of operations.
OK.
And now what I want to do is write on a separate line three to the power of.
And now I want to say two plus four.
So if I would write two plus four out like this.
This is actually not going to be the right answer here.
Python is prioritizing exponential rating over additions.
So I'm going to use parentheses to show Python that I want to associate the two and the four together
with the plus operation.
And then this result which is six of course that goes into the exponent of three.
And now we run this and we get seven hundred and twenty nine in both cases. And this is a great lead
in to the next concept that I want to illustrate to you which is taking a number to a fractional power
such as the square root.
So for example we know that the square root of 4 is 2 because two times two equals four.
Now later on in the course you're going to learn other ways of computing a square root.
But for now I'm going to show you computing the square root using fractional powers.
So we can say four to the power of one half.
So you indicate the square root
using a power of one half.
But again we need to use parentheses here to make sure that Python knows that we mean to put one half
in the exponent and not one in the exponent and then divide the result by two.
So now you see that four to the power of one half is two.
And again that makes sense because two times two equals four.
Now I'm going to show you what would happen if you accidentally left the parentheses off the answer.
Well again the answer is two because now four to the power of one is four.
And then that divided by two.
Let's try this with nine. So nine to the power of one divided by two is 4.5.
However if I add parentheses here I get nine to the power of one half which is the square root of nine.
And that gives me three.
Okay.
So now you know how to implement exponents in Python.
What I want to do now is show you how to make beautiful looking equations in the Jupiter notebook.
Using LaTeX coating.
So this is a follow up of what I've discussed in previous videos.
So you remember from previous videos that we had display, Math and then we can write for example one
plus two equals three.
Now when I tried to run this cell I get an error it says name
Math is not defined.
And the reason is that we haven't called this function math or the display function into the current
work session of Python.
And so to do that you might remember this from a previous video we have to type from Ipython dot display
import display.
And we also want to import math.
So importing these functions from this module is something that you're going to have to do every time
you open up a new Python session.
As long as you're working in the same Python session,
so within this notebook, you only need to run a line like this once. But every time you open up a new
session you will need to run this line of code again in order to import these special functions.
OK.
So now I can run this code and I get one plus two equals three in nice formatting.
So what I'm going to do now is write out these two expressions here.
So I'm going to say three and now we want to the power of two.
Now here's where things are getting a little bit confusing with indicating the exponents because in
Python code you use two asterisks like this.
However I'm not writing Python code here.
I'm actually writing latex code inside this math function.
So the correct way to do it is not three star star 3 that's actually just going to give me three star
star or two.
I should said two instead of three. Instead in latex,
you actually do use this caret symbol here, so you have a caret symbol here and the number or letter
immediately after the caret is going to go into the exponent. You can see why this gets a little bit
confusing, because in Python itself you use a double asterisk to indicate powers.
But here in latex you have to use this caret symbol.
Okay.
Now obviously three squared does not equal three.
So we should change this.
I went to write three squared times.
This is a double slash here.
Times three to the power of four.
And I'm going to run this cell again just to make sure that this looks good.
Okay.
So this looks good.
Three squared times three to the power four obviously does not equal three.
I need to change this part equals so I want this to say three to the power of two plus four.
However if I just write it like this I get three squared plus four.
So what we need to do here is tell latex to associate all of these characters to these three characters
the to the plus sign and the four with this superscript indicator. And the way that you do that in latex
is by encasing these in curly brackets.
So notice these are curly brackets here.
These are not parentheses like these are this simple round parentheses.
These are curly brackets.
So there we go.
This formatting looks really nice.
Three to the power of two times three to the power of four equals three to the power of two plus four
now it's time for the exercises for this video.
There are three exercises here and what you want to do is define two variables: x equals five, Y equals
five point one. And then implement these three equations and make sure you get the correct answer.
So X to the power of three divided by four.
Be mindful that this is a fractional exponent.
So it's three divided by four all in the exponent.
And what you should do is not only implement these equations to make sure you get the correct result,
but also display these using the display math functions and latex coding as I've shown in a previous
video.
And in this video of course you learned how to do this exponential nation.
So good luck working through this exercise.
Now is your chance to pause the video switch to Python on your own.
Implement these three equations, and then when you're finished come back to the video and you can watch
me solve this problem
all right.
So now I'm going to work through the exercises.
So let's start by setting X equals five and Y equals 5.1.
So for the first problem we had something to say the answer equals x to the power of three divided by
four.
And remember that you have to put the three fourths in parentheses here.
Times four to the power of y.
And then I will display that, so I'll say display math.
And now I'm going to follow the latex coding that I illustrated up here.
So these this concept up here.
So this is X to the power of....
and then in curly brackets, three divided by four.
And then we have times four to the power of y equals
And then we need a %g and then out here percent ans.
I remember I don't need to import the display and math functions again because I've already imported
them in this cell up here.
Okay.
So this looks nice and this gives us the correct answer.
Now if you like you could also substitute X and Y the letters X and Y here for the numbers 5 and 5.1.
I'm not going to do that now but you already know how to adjust the code to print out five to the power
of three fourths.
So I'm going to move on to the next problem.
So again I'll start with writing out the answer.
So the answer was that C was three squared divided by X to the power of y and just to make this a little
bit more readable.
I'm going to put it in parentheses so that it's really clear to me and to Python that three to the power
of three goes in the numerator and X to the power of y goes into the denominator.
Now display math.
And here we need to use a fraction.
I hope you remember from a previous video how to write out a fraction using LaTeX coding. In case you've
forgotten, it's slash slash and then frac and then we need two sets of curly brackets.
So one set of curly brackets for the numerator.
Another set of curly brackets for the denominator.
So the numerator was three to the power of three.
And then the denominator was X to the power of y.
And then we set that equal to %g and then percent ans so there we go.
And this also matches the answer that I showed in the slides.
Very good.
Now we have the third one and I think I'll call that variable solution just to mix things up a little
bit.
So let's say a solution.
And this was 10 to the power of x minus four.
So then we say display math and then we have 10 to the power of...
and then in curly brackets because we want all of this expression to go into the exponent into these
superscript after 10 and that equals %g and then percent solution.
All right.
And then we get 10 to the power of x minus four equals 10.
And this might seem like a strange result at first except when you keep in mind that X is the number
five.
So in fact this is really just saying ten to the one and any number to the power of one equals itself
so this was a productive video.
I hope you enjoyed it.
I covered exponents or taking powers in Python.
I gave a review of parts of the law of exponents and you learned a little bit more about using LaTeX
coding or integrating latex coding with Python coding in order to compute mathematical expressions and
display them using nice formatting.
And I am really excited for the next video because that's the video where I'm going to introduce you
to something called for loops. For loops are one of the most important command structures in all
of programming.