In the past several videos we've moved from circles to ellipses.
And now we are going to discuss hyperbole.
I'll show you the formula of a hyperbole.
Of course you'll get to see it in Python and at the end of the video you will get to see how to make
more really cool looking graphics using hyperbole.
So hyperbole.
Looks a little bit like an ellipse but it's like inverted.
It's like if you would flip in the lips.
So here is the center or the focus of the hyperbole.
And then you can see the hyperbole opens outwards from the center instead of closing around it.
So there are also two radii or two radial components that are parameters so that's a that's from the
center to one of these to the closest point in the hyperbole here or this would also be a here and then
there's a another component of the radius called B.
This corresponds to the radius and the y axis.
And it's a little bit harder to exactly map this length or this value be onto the hyperbole.
But it is related to how the tensions coming off of this hyperbole will intersect this line anyway.
If you look at the formula here it might look a little bit familiar from the video on ellipses.
In fact it's almost exactly the same formula as an ellipse except for this one term right here.
So to create the lips you write exactly this formula except this is a plus sign.
So when you add these two terms together you get an ellipse when you subtract these two terms you get
a hyperbole.
All right.
So let's switch to code and we'll see how to implement this like all the other videos in this section
we are going to use the number pi module and the plot a map plot lib dot pi plot module.
So I'm going to get started by writing some parameters.
So I picked out a few parameters that I think look reasonable for getting started.
So a and b are respectively 1 and point 5.
And H is 1 and k is 2.
So then we need to set up the mesh so capital X Capital Y equals num PI that mesh grid and then little
X little X and on working a little bit backwards here in general it's sometimes useful in code to work
backwards so you start with like a target line of code and then you you work backwards to figure out
what X has to be.
So X is going to be known pi Lynn's space.
And here you will recall from the previous videos in this course that I said that to be a variable called
X Lim so minus X Lim to plus X Lim where X Lim is for the Axis limit.
So then we need to define that variable.
And this is almost going to be the same as for the Ellipse.
So that was the maximum of A and B plus the maximum of the absolute value of each and the absolute value
of k.
Now the main difference here is that I want to have a little bit more room for the hyperbole to open
up within the axis.
So I'm gonna multiply this by two.
Okay.
And now I've written several lines of code here so I'm gonna just run the code in this cell just to
make sure that I haven't made any silly typos here.
So far no typos.
All right.
So now let's create the function.
So I will use I always use f x y.
How about hyperbole.
Hyperbole equals.
So this was X minus H squared five any more videos on this you've probably memorized this formula right
now.
So here is the key difference again between an ellipse and a hyperbole.
So this is a plus sign that creates an ellipse but we want a minus sign to create a hyperbole.
And then we do Y and then we shift y according to K squared and then we stretch y according to B so
H and K are shifting a and b are stretching and then of course we need the minus one.
All right.
And then we can draw a contour so P L T that contour X comma Y comma the function so high per blah and
then zero actually l I'll show it without the zero first just so we can see what this looks like.
Okay.
So here you see all of the contour lines are.
Well not all of them but several contour lines.
And what we want is really just this primary contour line.
And that is indicated with a zero here by the way it's also interesting to see what happens.
You know if you would write to for example then you're gonna see three lines here so three contours.
This is I mean this is like technically two separate lines but this corresponds to the same contour
because they have the same amplitude here at the same height.
OK.
So let's set this back to two and then I'm going to set the current axis that set aspect ratio to be
equal and peel to you that show.
Let's see how this looks.
All right.
This is starting to look pretty good.
And again it's also interesting to see how important that factor of minus 1 is.
In fact this is this hardly even looks like a hyperbole anymore because the lines are basically kissing
right here in the middle.
All right.
So I also want to plot a dot at the center.
So I'm going to write P L T dot plots then the center is h com a K and let's make this a green circle
like Oh is that starting to look pretty good here.
And I guess the last thing I'm going to do is draw a horizontal line at x equals zero and a vertical
line at Y equals zero.
So P L T dot plot.
Let's start with the horizontal line.
So for the horizontal line where is that going to go what are the x limits of this horizontal line.
Well well we want them is from X limb or minus accident plus axiom so minus X limb 2 plus X limb and
because this is a line that goes across the horizontal slice here at Y equals zero the y coordinate
stays zero all of time.
Okay.
So then let's make this a black horizontal dotted line like this.
All right.
So then once you get one the other line is generally pretty easy because you just need to swap the X
and the y coordinates here.
All right.
So I'm actually going to take this opportunity to illustrate something to you about Python plotting.
So here this line is black.
Because I wrote the K here so I could write are here and we'd get a red line.
But now I'm going to provide an additional input to the plot function and that's going to be color and
I'll make this gray so point eight point eight point eight.
So 80 percent red 80 percent Green 80 percent blue.
And notice that I already have a color specified here.
So who wins when there's a battle between R and point eight point eight point eight.
Who wins.
Well the answer is that the point eights have it.
They get to win.
So this optional input here for specifying the color is going to overwrite whatever you specify here.
All right.
And now I don't really like this.
This looks unbalanced.
So I am going to also paste the same color up here.
Then we get nice balance over here.
All right.
So I always think hyperbole is really neat.
And because I think hyperbole is look so neat.
I created an exercise for you to explore and neat looking at hyperbole as well.
So if you are looking at here is to hyperbole is here.
So two sets of lines the like these cyan ones here and the purple ones over here and that corresponds
to to hyperbole.
So how did I create these.
Well you already know the formula.
And so the rest you are kind of going to have to figure out on your own.
So I'm giving you a little bit of a hint here.
I set H and K both to be equal to zero which means that these high hyperbole as are centered at the
origin of the plot.
That also simplifies the code a little bit because you don't actually need to say X minus H in parentheses
you can just say h squared or site X squared and then Y squared.
Okay.
So what I did to create these hyperbole is is I varied the A and B parameters but I'm not telling you
what I vary them between.
So it was from between one number and another number.
And this might be the same number or it might be a different number compared to a you are going to have
to experiment and play around with that.
All right.
So now is your chance to switch to Python.
Pause the video and try to reproduce this plot all right.
So let's get started with a clean sell here.
So I used n equals sixteen hyperbole.
I created sixteen hyperbole is to make that plot that I showed you.
And then the values that I used for a and b were actually both the same.
So in fact I'm even going to simplify the code a bit more here by calling this variable a B.
So I created this as linearly spaced numbers between 1 and 5.
And of course there are and of them.
Okay.
So then let's see so little X is going to be known pi Lynn space we're using Lynn space an awful lot
in this section of the course.
Minus X Linda plus X Lim and a hundred steps.
And I just hardcoded X Lim to be eight here because I played around a little bit and that seemed to
be a good value for this exercise for this image.
Right.
So X comma Y equals and p dot mesh grid X comma x.
And then what I'm going to do is setup a for loop that's going to loop over the different hyperbole
is and I will and plot them.
So let's see.
So for i in range 0 2.
And so what I'm going to do is create the first hyper bla and actually let's just start with with one
and we'll plot it and see how that look.
So x x squared divided by A B and then it's the eighth element in A B and that gets squared minus Y
squared also divided by a B squared minus one of course.
And then peel to that contour You guys must be getting so good at setting up these contours I'm sure
you could do them in your sleep by now.
So f 1 0.
Okay.
So now I'm going to say P L T THE AXIS off and peel to show you know actually when you're turning the
Axis off you don't actually need the x y here either.
Okay so this is getting somewhere.
Obviously we're not finished yet.
I'm gonna make sure that the aspect ratio is identical for the two axes to make this a square plot.
So peel to the GCA forget current axis that set aspect is equal.
Okay this is looking a little bit better now.
So far we have these like horizontal hyperbole as I haven't actually told you how to create a vertical
hyperbole.
So how to create a hyperbole that opens up and down instead of to the left and to the right.
But I guess that you probably have figured it out by now.
And the solution the way that you do it is essentially by swapping X and Y because that's kind of what
you're doing here.
If you think about this geometrically.
You want to rotate this thing 90 degrees which is the same thing as swapping x and y so to create the
other contour.
I'll call that f to all you do is well you can move the Y to this side and you can say Y minus X but
just to make things a little bit easier.
Well I find it a little easier I don't know if you find it easier or harder but I'm going to keep the
X and the Y in the same order and just subtract the X and add the Y.
Okay so let's see how that looks now.
All right.
So this is starting to look good.
The last thing we need to do is get the colors to look good.
So I will just show you what I did for the colors so colors equals I.
Divided by n zero I divided by n.
So let's see what this does.
So when I is in the beginning of this loop so when I is a small number relative to n then this is basically
close to 0 0 zero.
In fact it starts off at zero zero zero which means it's gonna start off at black.
So the very first contour here is going to be black.
And then as I increases which means that we are going through this loop through more iterations in this
loop which also means that the radius parameter a and also B is getting bigger.
So the parabola is getting wider this angle here is getting wider then the red channel gets lighter.
The blue channel gets lighter and the green channel stays at zero.
So that's how this turns.
Like this kind of purplish color you could set this to be you know point eight.
And it would look quite a bit different.
This also looks nice actually.
Maybe I'll leave it like this for now.
OK.
So now I'm going to copy and paste.
And then what I did just to show you how I set this up in the picture in the code.
So then I set the R channels so the red channel to be zero and then green and blue were set to be increasing
from zero up to one.
And so that's how you get this line here as with previous videos if you feel a little bit inspired to
start making your own beautiful images based on what I showed you in this section and in this video
then what I encourage you to do is take a screenshot and when you should show me is first this picture
and then next to it your version.
So you should show this just to prove that you can really replicate my results and then you show your
new and improved version and post it in a Q and A form.
I will be very happy to see what you've come up with.
So in this video you learned about hyperbole is and a little bit more about using simple geometry to
make really interesting minimalistic graphics.