I've already mentioned complex numbers previously in the course.
In particular in the last several videos and maybe you've also encountered complex numbers in your adventures
learning mathematics.
So what I'm going to do in this and the next several videos is give you a deeper introduction to complex
numbers.
In this video I'm going to explain what the imaginary operator is how to represent it in Python and
I will also talk about complex numbers and adding and subtracting complex numbers.
So let's begin and let's begin actually with an equation that looks like this So X squared plus one
equals zero.
Now you already know that this is just a polynomial.
In fact this is a degree to polynomial so the question is what are the roots of this equation.
In other words how do we solve for x.
Well you know we go about this the normal way you isolate X on one side so have to subtract one from
both sides of the equation and then you just take the square root of both sides of the equation and
that gives you that X equals plus or minus the square root of huh minus 1.
That's kind of funny.
Now what does this mean.
To take the square root of a negative number it kind of doesn't really make any sense because no number
of times itself can be a negative number.
But we need to have some kind of a solution to an equation like this.
So therefore mathematicians a very very long time ago invented a special operator for this case and
they call that I.
So I is for the imaginary operator.
Now for much of the history of mathematics I was basically the only letter used for the imaginary operator
for the square root of minus one in recent times like in the past hundred years or so people have also
started using J.
And that's because in engineering people use AI to indicate current.
So sometimes you see I sometimes you see J.
So it's good to be comfortable with using I or J as the imaginary operator Python for example uses J.
Okay so that's the imaginary operator.
Now one thing you can do with the imaginary operator is create what's called a complex number so a complex
number means that there are two parts to the number.
There's the real part and the imaginary part.
So here's a bit of terminology for you.
Z here is the complex number.
A is called the real part b is called the imaginary part.
Notice that B is not the imaginary number in fact B is just a regular number but it's attached to or
it's multiplying the imaginary operator which is the square root of minus 1.
Now there's an interesting geometric interpretation of a complex number and I will talk about that in
a few videos from now but for now in this video you can just focus on this kind of arithmetic interpretation
that a complex number has a real part and an imaginary part.
Some aspects of working with complex numbers are a little bit tricky and you have to learn the rules
and other aspects of working with complex numbers are really natural and intuitive and basically exactly
what you would think about addition and subtraction are really easy.
They work exactly how you think they should work.
So when you add Z plus W these are two complex numbers.
Then you just add the two real parts and you add the two imaginary parts.
The only tricky thing that you have to keep in mind is that there's still just one imaginary operator
here.
So you add these together but this doesn't give you to I.
This is still just I.
And that's because it's b times I and D times I.
So when you add this term to this term you still just get one imaginary operator here.
All right.
And subtraction also works exactly the same way.
So you just subtract the real parts and subtract the imaginary parts and you make sure that the imaginary
operator is associated with this difference or this addition here.
Okay.
Let me switch to Python and show you how to represent the imaginary operator and then how to do simple
arithmetic with complex numbers I'd like to start by showing you a couple of different ways to represent
the imaginary operator.
So let's start by just writing 1 j.
Okay.
So now python just prints out 1 J.
Notice that it's not giving an error.
So for example if I would type one How about 1 p now python is giving me an error.
This is invalid syntax so not any letter can validly go after the one for example.
Even I.
Doesn't work.
So the built in operator the built in name for the imaginary operator is I j.
Now we can try print.
Let's try.
Let's see how this works in num pi.
So I can type N.P. dot square root of minus one.
Now first of all this is just going to crash because I haven't yet imported the NUM pi module.
So let me go insert so above and I will import num num pi as and P OK.
So now we get that in num Pi the square root of minus 1 is n n.
So not a number.
This is a concept that I introduced you to in the previous video about the quadratic equation and taking
the square root of a negative number.
So it turns out that actually in num Pi you can get the square root of a negative number.
And that is by forcing the data type to be complex.
So now you actually do get one J here the imaginary operator.
Alternatively you could also use the CI pi module and that was the solution that I presented in the
previous video.
So in fact if you want it you could even go back to the code from the previous video on the quadratic
equation and replace Sy pi square root with NUM pi square root specifying that the data type can be
complex anyway.
Another method which is actually the least preferred method.
It's a method I don't recommend is to say minus one to the power of one half.
Now let's see what happens when I do this this kind of should be the same thing as this.
It's still the square root of minus one.
However here it looks like it's six times 10 to the minus 17 so there's is a really tiny number but
it's not exactly zero plus 1 J.
Now this part is the piece that we're looking for and this is computer rounding error.
So this is not a preferred method for representing the imaginary operator.
Okay.
One more way that I want to show you and that is getting the imaginary operator in simple.
So let's first import these Sim pi modules so import simple as Sim.
And now I can write prints
Sim thought I capital I.
And that's just represented as this capital I hear.
But this is generally used in the simple module to represent the imaginary operator so you can see there's
multiple ways to do this.
This is a good way.
This is a good way if you are using symbolic math.
This is also fine.
You can also do it in a side by Tool Box.
You can see there's multiple ways to represent the imaginary operator.
Basically you just want to avoid using this method.
Okay so now I'm going to show you how to create a complex number in num pi and also just in the main
Python set of built in functions.
So let's define a couple of variables I'll say the real part equals how about four and the imaginary
part equals Let's go for minus five.
How about that.
OK.
So we have complex number 1.
So complex number 1 is going to be any peace and umpire duck complex.
And now here you give two inputs the first input is the real part and the second input is the imaginary
part.
So and then let's see what this looks like.
All right.
So here we have our complex number four minus 5.
J.
Okay.
And now what I'm going to do is create another complex number which I meant this to be two without using
num PIs.
That's gonna be real part plus 1 J.
Times the imaginary part.
And then let's see what C and in fact I think I'll print these both out and say print c and 1 and then
print c and 2.
So here you go two different ways of creating complex numbers using num pi and without using num pi
and let's also check out the type or the class of these variables so say type and also type here we'll
see what the type of this variable is.
So you can see that these are both complex numbers there have class complex or type complex.
Now I'm going to show you how to add and subtract complex numbers.
It's even easier than you might be thinking it is.
So let's say complex numbers said 1 equals and P that complex about 4 and 5 and then we'll say said
2 equals and b that complex 3 and is not not 0.
Let's go for 2 How about that.
Okay.
So now really all you have to do is say said one plus said two and then you get the answer and we can
confirm quickly that this ends up being the real part of 7 and the imaginary part of also 7.
So there you go.
And now I can say I even do this right here.
So minus then we get 1 3 J and we can confirm that here.
So this is one minus two.
So four minus three is one five minus two is three.
And then the last thing that I want to show you before switching to the exercise is how to extract the
real and imaginary parts from a complex number.
So here I created a complex number using the real part and the imaginary part.
And now I can type NDP real said 1 and that tells me that the real part is 4 and then you can probably
guess what is the function name for extracting the imaginary part it's image.
And now I get the answer of five the exercise for this video is actually not terribly difficult nor
is it particularly mathematically insightful but it's good practice.
It will give you more experience working with complex numbers in Python.
So what you want to do is create two complex numbers W and Z.
So here is W it's two for I and Z is 5 6.
And then you want to add those complex numbers together just like I showed you a moment ago and you
want to show that this is equal to creating another complex number out of the real part of W and the
real part of Z and add those together and the imaginary part of W and the imaginary part of Z and then
adding those together.
So basically this is just illustrating that adding these two complex numbers together is the same as
separating the real parts and adding them together and then separating the imaginary parts and adding
those together and then combining them back into a complex number.
All right puzzle video.
Spend a few moments to work through this assignment and now I'm going to switch to Python and you can
watch me solve it.
All right.
So let's start by creating these two complex numbers.
So w was an P that complex to 4 and z equals NPD complex that 1 was 5 and 6.
All right.
And so what I'm going to do is sum the real parts separately.
So I'll call this real sum that equals num paid out real w plus none Pi the real Z.
And then of course we have to separate the imaginary parts.
So n peaked in Maj w plus and p dot image Z and I mentioned this when I talked about the terminology
or complex numbers in the beginning of this video but just to remind you the imaginary part of Z is
6.
It's not 6 I or 6 J.
It's only the number 6.
That is the imaginary part.
All right.
So let's call this w plus Z and then maybe I'll say 1.
So this equals end p dot complex actually.
You know even before I do this I just want to show you that even though W and Z are both complex numbers
I'm extracting the real parts and extracting the imaginary parts and these two variables are real value
numbers so I'm gonna write print real some and imagined some.
So this is just to show you that these are two real numbers.
These are not complex numbers OK so now I'm going to put these together using the complex functions
of real some and imagined some.
OK.
This was the first part.
And now what I want to do is add them together directly plus Z.
Maybe I call this separate and I'll call this direct.
And this is just w plus Z.
Okay.
And now we went to print w plus said separate and print.
Let's see print paste.
And then this becomes direct.
Okay.
And no big surprise.
You see that these are the same number.
So obviously this is a much more convenient way to add complex numbers compared to these three lines
of code.
Nonetheless it's nice to see that when you do it both ways you get the same answer.
In this video I showed you what imaginary operators are and where they come from and several ways to
represent them in Python.
I also talked about complex numbers and how to add and subtract complex numbers in python in the next
video.
You will learn how to multiply complex numbers.
It's actually a little bit trickier then addition and subtraction.
So I look forward to telling you all about it.