This video contains the exercise corresponding to computing derivatives of polynomials that you learned
about in the previous video and in particular what you want to do in this exercise is implement these
two functions f of x and G of X.
You can see these are two polynomials.
So implement these functions in simplify and then you want to demonstrate the product rule and the summation
rule of derivatives.
So what do these two concepts mean.
So if you wanted to add two functions so f of x plus G of X and then take the derivative of those functions
added together.
So this is the quantity f plus g prime OR THE DERIVATIVE OF F plus G then that is simply f prime plus
g prime now.
That's really great because mathematics sometimes just like life works simply and exactly the way you
think it should work.
So f plus g prime equals f prime plus g prime.
Now we get to multiplication on the other hand.
Mathematics also like life is sometimes not quite as simple as you naively expect it to be.
So f times geez.
So this function times this function and then the derivative of that is not equal to the derivative
of x times the derivative of G.
Instead it is equal to the derivative of x times G.
So the derivative of this function times this function not its derivative plus f times the derivative
of G.
So this is called the product rule.
So what you want to do is demonstrate the product rule so essentially go through these three equations
here and demonstrate that for these two functions this property whole or this I should say equality
holds this equality holds and this thing is not true here.
All right.
So switch to Python do a bit of coding and now I'm going to switch to Python and walk you through my
solution all right.
So we are going to need a variable X I'm going to say simple that symbols X and now I'm gonna start
by defining the two functions.
So f or f of x was three plus two times x minus five times x squared plus seven times X to the power
of four.
All right.
And then we have our second function G.
That was 4 times X squared plus X to the fifth power.
All right.
So as you know I like to run my code after running after writing a few lines just to make sure I haven't
already made mistakes.
So let's see.
So then we need the derivative of each functions.
I'm going to call that D X equals sim that diff of f and then D G equals since that diff of G and then
I also need a few other terms that are gonna simplify what I'm going to do in the future.
So I'm going to write the derivative of f times G.
So that is simple that diff of f times G said on multiplying the functions first and then computing
the derivative vs. computing the derivatives separately.
So that's going to be def times the G equals in that def of f time sim that def of G.
Okay.
So the whole point of this cell is basically just to setup all the possible variables that I will want
to be using now that I have that I'm going to write out some later code to show some of these equalities
and see whether they hold.
Okay so let's start by writing display math and I'm moving on to start with a little bit of text here.
So I'm going to write with or without applying the product rules so this is going to be how things look
when you try to take the derivative of multiplied functions as the multiplication of the derivatives
of those functions.
So that's kind of like the the simple naive way that you think that the universe should work.
Let's see and then I'll put a little bit of space in here.
So this is going to be f times G primes.
So that's how I'm going to indicate the derivative here equals percent.
S Okay.
And now I want to replace percent s here with the derivative of f times G.
So that is this piece.
This simple object here.
So D F x g or f times G.
And then this should be the latex version to make it look nicer so sim that later.
Okay.
So we still have a bunch of product terms here multiply terms here.
So what I actually want to do is expand this and expand and that's going to simplify and get all of
these expressions out here.
So in other words multiply the two functions and then take their derivative.
Now the question is is that equal to this thing here.
Now without applying the product rule that is the simplistic way that you might think that it works.
So display math and then another quad just so you know I like to have a little bit of inventing here.
Whoops that's supposed to be single quotes and then like this.
So the question is when I say f prime times g prime and that is equal to.
And then on C I'll just copy and do a little bit of pasting here and now this variable is actually D
F underscore.
Times underscore DG okay I hope that makes sense what I'm doing here.
So I say without applying the product rule the question is whether this expression here is equal to
this expression.
And the answer is very clearly no.
Okay.
So now we are going to try applying the product rule that I just showed you.
So let's see.
I'm going to copy.
Actually I think I'll copy and paste all three of these lines.
So let's see this is with applying the product rule.
Now this part is the same.
And then what I'm going to write here is F of prime times G plus f times g prime.
And now this is no longer the right thing here.
Instead I'm gonna need to write out a couple of terms here.
So this is going to be def times G plus f times the G.
Okay.
So now we are applying the product rule.
So the derivative of f times G is equal to the derivative of x of f times G plus f times the derivative
of G.
And that you can see in this example by matching up all of these numbers here and you can see that every
single one of them matches.
So this is a way to use python as a tool to reinforce the concept of the product rule.
And also I guess the summation rule but that one.
Oh wait I didn't actually apply this summation rule ups my apologies.
So let's also do that.
So we will write up here.
I'm going to put that variable here.
So that's going to be d of f plus GM and go do an underscore like this equals simple dot def of f plus
G.
So then the question is whether this term is equal to this plus this.
Okay.
So let's see here.
Going to write.
Display math and then f plus G and then prime equals percent.
Yes.
Let's see what it's equal to.
That's equal to sim that latex and then sim that expand.
And then that's this term here.
So D of f plus G.
So there we get this expression.
And now when I replace that for F prime.
Let's see.
So this is going to be f prime plus g prime equals and then this is going to be the F plus DG.
All right.
And here we get the same answer.
So you can see that when adding functions the derivative is very simple you just add the derivatives
and when multiplying functions it's a little bit trickier.
You have to apply the product rule so in this and the previous video we exploit the derivative using
simple by using graphs in Python and using Python and latex as tools to help us understand the product
and some of different functions as it relates to the derivatives in the next video.
We're going to talk about derivatives of trigonometry functions.
So stay tuned.