Well we certainly can't have an entire section on trigonometry without talking about the Pythagorean
theorem.
So that is the purpose of this video.
It's going to be a quick review of the Pythagorean theorem.
You'll get to see the Pythagorean theorem implemented in Python and we will draw triangles from you
know kind of from.
From the ground up from first principles in Python and the exercise you will also get to see an application
of the Pythagorean theorem to these crazy complex numbers that keep popping up further into mathematics
you get.
OK.
So what is the Pythagorean theorem.
So if we start from a right triangle and a right triangle means that one of the angles is exactly 90
degrees.
So that's typically indicated with this little box here.
So if you have a triangle with one angle being equal to 90 degrees then there is a relationship between
the length of this line the length of this line and the length of this line.
And that relationship is that C squared.
So the length of C Square this is also called the hypotenuse of the triangle.
So C squared equals a squared plus B squared.
And of course that means if you want to solve for C if you want to know what is the length of this line
here this hypotenuse then you have to take the square root of a squared plus B squared.
Okay.
And so what I'd like to do now in Python is basically draw this triangle and these letters here so we're
going to use and text in Python and then determine the length of C..
All right.
So let's get started.
So I'm going to define a and b.
So how about a equals eight and b equals four.
Actually no I think I'll start off with three and four because there's a couple of these famous Pythagorean
triplets and three and four is one of them.
So a equals three and b equals four.
Then I know that C is going to be equal to five.
I don't have to write that down in fact I'm going to compute it.
So let's see C equals the square root of a squared plus b squared and we can already have a look and
see what C is so C is five.
That's one of these Pythagorean triplets.
There are several of them.
All right.
So what I'd like to do now is start drawing the triangles or draw the triangle.
Let's see.
So we have a couple of things that we need to draw.
And I think I'm going to start by drawing the base here.
So drawing this line that's flat along the x axis.
Now drawing this triangle is going to be easier if we consider that the right angle point of the triangle
is at the origin of the graph.
So zero zero.
So let's say P L teed up plots.
So we want a line that's going to go from the origin meaning X or sorry 0 on the x axis and 0 on the
y axis.
Now where does it end.
Well on the x axis it ends at a that's the distance along the x axis and then on the y axis that line
just ends at zero.
So let's see and I'll make this a little bit of a thicker line.
So in line with how about two.
Okay.
So here we get a straight line starts at the origin and it goes to three which is the point A.
Oh right.
So then I think next I'll draw this vertical line here.
So that is going to be a line that goes also from zero on the x and y axes.
And then on the x axis it basically stays at zero.
We don't travel on the x axis at all.
And on the y axis we go up to be okay.
So this is starting to get somewhere.
And now the last leg of this triangle is the hypotenuse.
So let's see that's going to be P L teed up plot.
So where does it start from.
So let's say that it starts from here Well you could start it from here and end here or you could start
from here and end here.
But I'm going to start it from this point here.
So that is the point x equals zero and Y equals B.
So we need zero comma B and then it ends at X equals three or a more generally and Y equals zero.
So and this should also be a black line website.
I mess this up.
I hope that you caught this mistake before I did so in fact that the line on the x axis goes from zero
to a.
And on the y axis it goes from B to zero.
That looks much better.
Okay.
So here is our triangle.
Now what I'd like to do is draw this little box here to indicate that this is a right angle.
So let's draw that line.
So I'm going to start by drawing this line that comes up here.
So it has to be a straight line.
So it means on the x axis is going to stay the same.
And on the y axis it's going to move from zero to some point here.
So this is a little bit arbitrary but I'm just basing this on visual inspection.
So how about let's try on the x axis.
We're going to stay at point three and then on the y axis.
We're gonna go from zero to point three and then I'll also make this a slightly thinner line.
Let's see how that looks.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
Now we need that other line that goes across this way this horizontal line so that is going to have
x axis coordinates that go from zero to point three and then on the y axis.
It doesn't change it stays at point three.
And let's make sure this is also a black line.
All right.
So this is starting to look good.
I want to make this triangle look a little bit nicer before adding the text to these three sides and
in particular you can see that this box here is supposed to be a square.
This should be a perfect square and you can see that because all these numbers here to create these
sides these are all zeros in point three.
So that means that this distance here is the same as this distance here in terms of coordinates.
But these two axes are are not the same.
So we need to make these axes be the same.
So let's start by saying peeled to the axis square.
All right.
This is looking a little bit better now.
You can see the axis limits are the same.
So it goes from zero to four and zero to four.
But how do we know what is the right axis limits here.
Well they should be based on a and b.
So I'm going to change the axis limits to make sure that they're always going to work well even when
we change the sizes of or the lengths of the two legs a and b and so to do that.
I'm going to create a new variable called X limb and let's set this to be the maximum of a and b.
So whatever is the larger of a and b and then maybe we add a little bit as a buffer so then I write
P L T dot axis.
So now I want the x axis to start not exactly at zero but I like colors a little bit of space here.
So I'm gonna say that the x axis should always start at minus point five and it should end at X limb.
And then this is actually M plus point five.
All right.
I mean that the larger of a or b plus point five.
So that also gives us a little bit of space up on the top or over here on the right.
So this for the x axis and then the y axis limits are exactly the same.
Okay so that looks pretty good.
And now we don't even need this axis here this bounding box I'm just going to turn the Axis off.
All right.
This is starting to look good.
However I think our triangle looks a little bit lonely a little bit sad.
So he needs a couple of friends actually.
He needs three friends and those are going to be the sizes the lengths of these three sides.
OK.
So now let's add that.
I'll do that below here.
So I want to use text.
So you remember I introduced you to drawing text in figures.
I don't remember which video it was but it was a bit earlier in the course.
So as a quick review to use P.L. you got text you basically provide three inputs the x coordinate the
y coordinate and a string.
So what are these three coordinates.
Let's start with the text here.
So I want this to say A equals and then the size of a cell for this triangle it's gonna be a equals
three.
So where should we draw that text.
Well I'm going to say we start at the x axis coordinate a divided by three and the y axis coordinate.
Of point two five and then the text is going to say A equals and then I'm going to say plus string a
okay.
Now this looks a little bit small so I'm going to make this slightly larger so I'm gonna say font size
equals let's try 15.
Okay so that looks pretty good.
And you know I kind of just came up with these numbers by poking around a little bit a little bit of
trial and error.
So I kind of like the a to be on the inside of the triangle.
You could also specify it to be on the outside of the triangle if you like.
Maybe something like that looks good.
Actually maybe I prefer that.
Maybe that's better than having it in the Triangle.
All right let's keep it like that.
And now for B.
So that's gonna be on this side and I will put that on the inside of the triangle.
So let's say plot text and I'm gonna have it start at x axis coordinate of point 1.
So it's gonna be around here it's gonna start around here and then the B corner of the y coordinate
should say it's gonna be b divided by three and then this tax is going to be b equals string.
Now remember here I'm using a plus sign for string concatenation which is different from how the plus
sign is being used here.
Okay.
And then let's also make sure this one is a nice healthy fonts that we get.
B equals 4.
And then of course you know where this is going.
We need to add a C so how can we figure out where to put the text for C.
Well I'd like to have c b around here.
So here corresponds to half of the way across the hypotenuse.
So what is this halfway point on the hypotenuse.
Well it's actually just a divided by 3.
Sorry divided by two and b divided by two.
So that's exactly the middle.
So let's try that.
Let's say a divided by 2 be divided by 2 and then the text is C equals string C and then font size equals
15.
Okay.
So this is looking pretty good except the C is really just almost touching the hypotenuse.
I'm actually going to add a little bit of an offset point one like this.
All right.
I think this looks really nice and let's test this.
I'm going to ads and change these numbers a bit.
What if a is eight and B is three and then what is the length of C there.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
It's pretty interesting.
So we get this kind of longish triangle and c ends up being eight point five.
That s also seems pretty plausible that the length of this line is just a little bit longer than the
length of this line for the exercise.
I would like to revisit the complex numbers that you learned about in the algebra 2 section complex
numbers also show up in trigonometry or I should say there are many applications of trigonometry to
complex numbers in physics in linear algebra in signal processing and so on.
So you've learned that there are two interesting features that we can extract out of a complex number
and that is the length of this line which is the distance to the origin and this angle here of this
line with respect to the positive real axis.
So how do we extract those.
Well we can use trigonometry to get these values.
In particular we can use the Pythagorean theorem to get the length of this line.
So how does that work.
Well that works by thinking about drawing some you know thinking about drawing an imaginary line down
here and then look what we have.
We have exactly a right triangle.
This is a right angle here.
And so this is the hypotenuse of this right triangle.
So that means that to compute the length of Z which is also called the absolute value of the complex
number we say that the length of that number squared equals the real part squared plus the imaginary
part squared.
And here you have to be careful that you're not squaring eye because you're not squaring the imaginary
number as well you're only squaring the distance along the imaginary axis.
And that is three not three eyes.
So two squared plus three squared or more generally the magnitude or the length of the complex number
of squared is the real part squared plus the imaginary part squared.
And then we have this angle here.
Let's call that K and we can compute K by considering that the tangent of that angle K is equal to the
imaginary part.
So the opposite divided by the adjacent.
So that is the imaginary part divided by the real part.
So in this particular case for this number the tangent of K equals 3 divided by 2.
So then if you want the angle of K in radians then you have to invert tangent and then you take the
arc tangent or the inverse tangent of three divided by two.
Okay.
And so this is basically the goal of this exercise to implement these two ideas these two formulas in
python in order to obtain the length of Z which is also called the magnitude or the absolute value of
this complex number and to get the angle K which is the arc tangent or the inverse tangent of the imaginary
part divided by the real part.
Okay.
So now you can switch to Python and have a go at this.
It shouldn't take you too long hopefully.
Now I'm going to switch to Python and you can see what I do here so let's start by creating a complex
numbers.
All right Z equals num piled complex.
And how about you know let's go for three and four because then I know based on what we did up here
that the length of this line or the magnitude of the complex number is going to be five.
So let's say that mag and I'm going to call this variable mag 1 and you will see why I call it one in
a moment.
So to compute the length of Z or the magnitude said we take the square root of the real part squared.
So real part of said squared plus the imaginary part of said also squared.
And now I want to compute this a different way.
So I already told you in the section on algebra 2 that you can compute the magnitude of a complex number
or the length the distance of the complex number away from the origin using this function a B.S. for
absolute value.
So we should actually see that both these numbers end up being the same.
So I'm going to print out mag 1 and mag 2 and sure enough they are both equal to 5.
Okay.
And then we need to extract the angles.
I'm also gonna call that Ang 1.
So now the function in num PI for computing the arc tangent or the inverse tangent is arc ten two.
And then we have to input the imaginary part of said and then the real part of Z.
And again I'm going to compare this to a built in function to extract the angle of a complex number
and that's just an P that angle.
So now I'm gonna print out both these make sure they look the same.
And not surprisingly they do.
Now of course in general when you're working with complex numbers in practice it's more convenient to
use a B.S. and angle.
But that said it's also interesting to see that you get the same number when implementing the Pythagorean
theorem like this so in this video you got a reminder about the Pythagorean theorem you gain some experience
in drawing in python in particular drawing really from the ground up.
So just drawing all the individual lines that make up a triangle.
And of course you could extrapolate this to any other shape that you want to draw.
And finally you got to see an application of the Pythagorean theorem and trigonometry more generally
to working with complex numbers and extracting information from complex numbers.