This is the exercise that goes along with the previous video which you want to do in this exercise implement
this function.
This is actually a family of functions.
I call it F sub a of X so we have the function cosine of X plus sign of X and the sine is embedded inside
the cosine and then out here you have this plus a.
So then the idea is that you create four of these functions for four different values of A.
And notice that they come from a set of integers 0 through 3.
So that's maybe a bit of a hint that you probably don't need to come up with for entirely separate simple
objects one for each function but anyway that's up to you to decide okay.
So this is gonna give you a family of four functions and then what you want to do is plot all for these
functions in the same graph and then in a separate graph you can plot the derivatives of each of these
four functions.
So all of the functions go in one graph.
There's gonna be four lines in that one graph and all the derivatives go in the same graph but not the
same.
Well they go in their own graph but a different graph from the original functions.
So you know the drill.
Pause the video.
Do some coding and now I am going to start coding in Python.
All right so I'm gonna start by creating some symbolic variables x and a sub X comma a.
Let's see then what I'm going to do is create the basic function.
So that's going to be F equals Sim dot cosine of X plus Sim sine of x and then out here I have plus
a and the way that I'm going to do this is I'm going to use the sub's method in simplified to substitute
for the variable a.
Okay.
So let's see.
So for a I'll call this variable.
This looping index variable a I because I'm it's gonna be indices over a.
So for a I in range 0 through 4.
Well it ends up being 0 3 of course and then you write for because this is a non-exclusive upper bound.
I meant to say a non inclusive of course it is an exclusive upper bound.
Okay.
So I'm going to do the same trick that I wrote above in the previous video.
So if a I equals zero.
Then we initialize the plot to b Sim plot.
And now it's not just going to be f it's going to be f dot subs and we are going to substitute a for
a I and then show equals false and then I will attach a label which is going to basically just say what
a is set to.
So a equals s and now you know actually we could do it this way.
But I'm just going to set it up to say plus string of a I you know just it's good to have some variety
every now and then.
Okay so that is what happens on the first iteration on every subsequent iteration.
Then we have to extend this plots and now this is going to be something very similar.
So I'm going to copy and paste and let's see.
This is gonna be almost exactly the same.
We're gonna run into the same problem that we did in the previous video with the colors but for now
I just want to run this to see if we're going to get any errors already.
And of course we already get some errors.
This is I see.
That was just a little typo.
It's supposed to be f dot subs not f comma subs.
All right so that looks pretty cool.
Looks like waves on a imaginary ocean in the winter wonderland of trigonometry or whatever.
Okay so this is looking good.
You can recognize this function.
I've used this function several times.
This form of a function several times already in this course.
Cosine of X plus sine X or something to that effect.
I like this function.
It looks pretty neat.
And then of course when we add different values of a.
This is really just acting as a constant offset.
So it's just pushing the entire function up or down on the y axis.
Okay.
So let's see.
So now I'm going to define these colors to be uh blue red black and magenta so appear I showed you one
trick for getting the colors and this is also fine.
But in this case I'm going to actually specify them up primary so let's see.
That's gonna go here.
So the color sets actually line color equals colors and then this is going to be the zero with element
and then copy and then paste down here and your eyes have to be careful to make sure you're getting
in the right parentheses here.
So now the color is going to come from index a I.
Okay.
This is looking pretty good.
I want to add a title so PETA title equals the functions.
And then we need to activate the legends.
Legend equals true.
All right.
I think this looks pretty good.
Let's move on to the derivatives.
So I'm just gonna put that in more code down here because I want the derivatives to appear directly
underneath all of these functions.
And in fact let's think about what has to change to plot the functions.
We can actually use pretty much exactly all of this same code so copy this entire block of code and
paste it again.
And let's go through line by line what we need to change.
Well obviously we don't want to change this stuff because the parameter a has to be the same.
Now we do need to change this because we are no longer interested in the function itself.
We are interested in the derivative of the function and then it's important to get the substitution
to be inside this derivative function.
And then let's see all of that is fine.
And then of course we also change this sim that diff of the entire function including the change of
the parameter a so and then this is going to change this to their derivatives.
Okay.
Let's see what this looks like.
Huh.
So here we get this kind of funny.
We get all of these lines all four of these lines are exactly overlapping on top of each other.
And the legend is also exactly the same for all four of these functions.
So first of all let's check and make sure we haven't made any coding errors because it's not necessarily
wrong if all four lines are the same.
But it can be an indicator.
It does look a little bit suspicious of every line is exactly the same.
And in fact I'm pretty confident that we've done the right thing because we confirmed here that we did
the right thing and then I really just copied and pasted all the code.
And in fact this is exactly correct.
We did nothing wrong here.
It turns out that the derivative of a constant is zero.
So these additions here plus zero which is not displayed but implicitly This is a equals zero.
So plus zero plus one plus two plus three the derivative of a constant is always going to be zero.
So that means that from the perspective of the derivative all four of these functions and all four these
lines are exactly identical.
Great.
So I think this in the last video was pretty exciting and pretty fun.
I hope you agreed.
You learned about these cyclist city of sine and cosine derivatives and you got some more experience
working with simpler plotting and thinking about derivatives graphically.