There are two exercises in this video.
This first exercise is actually pretty simple.
It's pretty straightforward.
All you have to do is implement these two formulas.
So translate these two formulas into Python code and then make a plot.
There is nothing particularly difficult or tricky about this but I think these are two interesting looking
functions so it's pretty neat to see what they look like.
The second exercise is a little bit more involved and there are some there's a little bit of problem
solving that's involved in this.
So essentially what you want to do is create a plot that looks like this.
So what are we looking at here.
So in gray you can see the unit circle and then you can specify some angle here I've specified seven
pi over six and then I drew an arc in this thick black line there's an arc that ends in a dot that goes
from zero.
So from an angle of zero all the way out to this angle here is specified by seven pi over six.
And then what I've done is draw some lines to indicate the sine part or the sine component of this angle
and the cosine component of this angle and then also with these dotted lines here.
So again there's nothing in this figure that you don't already know how to do but it does take a little
bit of time to figure out how to get all the components to work and to look good together.
All right.
So switch to Python implement these two exercises and then come back to the video and you can watch
me walk through my solution.
So let's start with that first exercise.
I'm going to specify that the variable x which is going to be the theta that's gonna be linearly spaced
number.
Now I didn't actually give you a specific range for plotting these but I'm going to go from minus two
pi to plus two pi in let's say two hundred steps lots of twos around here.
Okay.
So we had two functions why one was to take a cosine and embedded in a sine.
So that was NPD.
So sign of X plus the cosine of X..
And then we had y two was basically the reverse of this.
So that was the cosine of X and inside the cosine is the sine function.
So now BLT dot plot.
Now previously in this course or I guess usually the way that I plot things is to have one line of code
per plot.
So I would do something like this.
Now there's nothing wrong with plotting it this way.
However it's also possible to put all of these on one line.
So here I'm specifying X and Y and then another X and Y and you can see that this also works.
This produces the same result.
Now sometimes it's easier to do it this way sometimes for like aesthetics for making the code seem easier
to write.
I prefer to have one line of Python code per line of plotting but it's a matter of personal preference.
All right.
So let me add a legend here now because I have these two lines of of these two plotting lines on the
same line of code.
I'm gonna put the legend in here.
So this is going to say the sign of X plus costs X and then the legend for the second line is cosine
of X plus the sign of X..
All right.
So this looks pretty good.
And again the main point of me ask you to do this exercise was because I think these functions look
pretty neat.
So it's nice too to be exposed to this concept of embedding some trig functions inside other trig functions.
Now of course I encourage you to do all sorts of things to play around with this.
You can try you know what happens if we square the cosine here.
So that's kind of funny it looks a little wiggly.
Of course the legend does no wrong.
But but you are now free to continue playing around and of course that's the main point of this course
right to show you how to use python as a tool to explore concepts in mathematics.
Okay.
And just to make sure that this is totally legit.
I'm going to add the appropriate legend here.
All right.
So now we get to the second exercise.
And as I mentioned this exercise isn't really difficult persay but there are a lot of moving parts.
So I'm going to start by specifying some theta as an angle so let's call that known pi it up Pi.
And I guess in the slides I did seven pi divided by six.
So let's also go for that here.
OK.
So we're going to need to do this in multiple steps so I'm going to start by plotting the unit circle
so to plot the unit circle I want to have a gray line that just goes around in a circle.
So appeal to you that plot and then this is going to be cosine of.
I didn't specify angles yet.
So let's say x equals known pi Lynn space from 0 to 2 pi and let's go for two hundred steps.
That's probably more than sufficient.
So here we say costs X by sign of X.
And now I want the color to be gray.
Okay and then let's see how this is looking so far.
Okay.
So I mean this is supposed to be a circle but it's plotted as an oval.
So let's fix this.
I'll say P L T to get current axis dot set aspect and I'll set that to be equal.
Now you'll notice that sometimes I use this code sometimes I say plot axis square.
Of course there are multiple ways to solve particular problems in Python.
And it's good to be familiar with different ways.
I'm sure there are also many other ways that I'm not using.
Okay so that's the unit circle.
I would also like to have some great dashed lines going across the zero coordinates here.
So I'm also gonna add that up here.
So I want the horizontal axis to go from x equals well minus one point one two plus one point one and
then that means the y coordinates will go from zero to zero.
This is going to be a dash line and the color is gray all right.
So that looks pretty good.
And then we need the vertical counterpart and that's going to be basically the same code.
I'm just going to swap the x and y coordinates here.
All right.
So that's looking pretty good.
The next thing I want to plot is the arc that's going to be that thick line that starts from here.
And it goes to whatever point is specified by this theta here.
So let's see.
Plot the arc.
So I'm going to plot a.
So what do we need here.
Well we need it's not just theta.
We need numbers.
We need angles that go from 0 up to theta.
So in fact that's going to look similar to this.
And I think I will just put it all directly inside the plot function instead of specifying it as a separate
variable like this.
So I'm going to write none paid out costs and now embedded inside there is going to be linear at least
based numbers from 0 to theta.
And you know if you don't specify any third input into the Lin space function the default value is I
think it's 50.
Let's see starts up num equals 50.
Yeah.
So without writing a third input that is equivalent to providing a third input of 50.
So let's see if that is going to give us a nice line.
So NPR sign of Lin space 0 2 theta.
Okay looking good.
So we see this line it starts here and it ends here.
That's all correct.
But I want this to be a thick black line.
So K and then line with let's set this to be about 3 0 all right.
That's looking good.
Now I want a vector that goes from the origin to this point here.
Remember that was also in the slides so P.L. teed up plot and now the x component is gonna go from zero
to costs of theta.
And the y component is gonna go from zero to sign of theta.
And this is going to be a black.
Now I could make this a dotted line like this.
However I already have this r dash line I meant to say I already have dash lines here.
So I think that looks a little bit confusing.
So therefore I'm going to use a colon to make this a dotted line all right.
And then we need a little a little ball sitting there.
So let's say let's see.
Well copy and paste this here.
So now instead of a line that starts at the origin we just want a dot at exactly this theta coordinates.
So that is going to be k 0 4 knockout.
Just kidding.
Keto is for a black circle.
Very nice.
So we are getting there.
The last thing that we need.
Well not the last things a couple more things that we need.
The next thing I'm going to work on is getting these green and red lines in here.
So I'm going to call that plot the separate components and I see that s is the sine and cosine components.
So let's start with the sine part.
So the sine part is basically going to be a red line that goes along the y axis and then a red dotted
line that goes out to this point here.
So let's start with this red line first.
So that is going to be a line that goes on the x axis.
It's going to go zero to zero.
It doesn't go anywhere on the x axis and on the y axis it goes from zero to the sine component of theta.
And then this is going to be a red line.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
And then I want a dotted line here.
So this is a little bit trickier because it's not going to look exactly the same here.
This is in fact a horizontal line.
So it's gonna be fixed on the y axis and moving on the x axis are changing on the x axis.
So we want people to eat up plot.
So the x component is going to go from zero to this point here and this point here on the x axis is
the cosine part.
So N.P. that costs of theta and then the y axis component is fixed and it's fixed at the sign of theta.
So any Pitot sine theta and P does sign of theta.
And then this is going to be a red dotted line all right.
That looks pretty good to me.
So now we basically need to repeat these two lines.
But for the cosine part instead of the sine part so let's see so the blue line that goes out here is
going to be fixed on the x axis and on the y axis it's going to go from zero to cosine.
So going to do a little copy paste job here.
So let's see.
We want this to go on the x axis to cosine theta and then we'll make this a blue line.
All right.
Looking good.
And then let's see I think I'm not going to copy paste this I'll just write it again from scratch.
So BLT dot plot and now the x coordinates will go will stay at cosine of theta.
And Peter costs theta and the y coordinates will start from zero and then drop down to the y component
here which is known Pi the sign of theta.
And I said this to be a blue dashed line a dotted line sorry.
Very nice.
So the last thing that we need here is a title.
So I want the title to be.
So the title should essentially just say that theta equals.
And then whatever the theta angle is equal to.
So percent theta.
Okay.
So this is not exactly what I showed in the slides I showed in the slides that this was the Greek character
the Greek letter theta so that we know how to do we just need to convert this into latex code.
So let's see how this looks now.
All right.
So this looks better except what I actually input it here was seven pi over six.
And also what I showed in the slides was seven pi over six.
So to get that with the PI character and everything this needs to be in latex.
So I'm going to write some that later.
Now of course I haven't actually imported the simple AI module so I'm gonna have to go back up here
and import Sim pi as Sim run that code again and let's see keep our fingers crossed.
Oh.
That was very disappointing.
I was really hoping that this would have the PI character in here.
Now what is the problem here.
The problem here is that this variable theta although I'm specifying it in terms of Pi it's not actually
seven pi over six.
This is just an approximation of seven pi over six.
And that's because pi is an irrational number a computer cannot actually represent or compute exactly
Pi.
All it can do is estimate pi to some reasonable degree of accuracy.
So what we actually want to do here is be able to specify these angles symbolically.
So let's say first Sim.
I don't know how you would pronounce this sim and that is going to be Sim dot pi times seven divided
by six.
And then I can change this to be FSM and now we get a nice looking title here.
However now if you want to change the angle if you want to plot a different angle you have to change
both of these lines which is pretty tedious.
So instead what I'm going to do is say that theta equals fist him but then I'm going to convert this
into a floating point number.
So now all I need to do first of all run this code just to make sure we didn't get any errors.
All you need to do to change this angle now is I just changed the four Sims so the symbolic representation
of this angle.
Let's say I want this three over 16.
So three pi over 16.
And now that changes the plot accurately.
All right.
So unfortunately this is still only like 98 percent finished.
The other 2 percent is to have a legend in here but you already know how to create legends in Python
graphics.
So I think I will let you complete that part on your own in this video and in the previous video you
got more experience working with trig functions in the video you learned about the importance of resolution.
And here you learned more about plotting in Python and working with trigonometric functions.