Hello and welcome back to the course on statistics.
OK so today we're talking about a Student's t distribution a very interesting topic.
It may be a bit scary sometimes when you hear it because there's so many things to keep in mind as the
Zed's statistics which we very talked about.
There's a central limit theorem.
There's the p values the Zed test which is the hypothesis test then the proportions are already so much
and that's why another type of distribution might be a bit off putting.
But at the same time it's actually pretty simple.
We've had going into the complex math you will see that it is straightforward what is going on and it's
very easy to apply in practice.
Given that knowledge we already have.
So there's that straight into it.
Here we have a gentleman called William Seeley I hope I'm pronouncing that right.
Gosset and he was a statistician who worked for the Guinness brewery in Ireland.
And he actually published the t distribution under a pseudonym student and there's lots of speculation
about it.
Like I read on Expedia that maybe Guinness the Guinness brewery didn't want to know it didn't want their
competitors to know what they're using their distribution for and what he was using it for was he was
interested in analyzing chemical properties of samples sizes very small size as few as three elements
in a sample.
Can you imagine that like we were working with samples with 150 or 100 or 50 or at least 50 or like
larger samples.
Sometimes you might have a sample of thousands if you're doing a poll or something.
And he was trying to analyze you know make inferences about populations from samples as small as three
elements.
And so that's that's where the t distribution is like it has its place it has its little niche in the
world of statistics.
It deals with situations where your sample size is rather small.
So this is what distribution looks like.
Look familiar.
It's very similar to the normal distribution factors just like a modification of the normal distribution.
The formulas there on the right we're not going to go through that.
Is there an extra function and there is a thing we will talk about as the degrees of freedom.
So the normal this distribution it just has a new parameter that which we're going to have to keep in
mind.
Degrees of freedom and degrees of freedom is very simple.
Here it's thrown out one degree of freedom two degrees five or six infinit degrees of freedom degrees
of freedom is basically the number of the size of your sample minus one.
That's all it is.
So you distribution it has heavier tails is very similar to the normal distribution.
In fact we hear this black one the one where the degrees of freedom is infinity.
So your sample size is infinity or is like is huge.
That is a normal distribution.
So as new gets larger and larger and larger this whole thing it can register normal distribution.
So there's just something to keep in mind.
So it is a modification of the normal distribution and all it does is let's let's look at this orange
one for instance or the purple one you can see that it has heavier tails and it is useful because these
heavier tails suggests that this distribution that you're creating is you can actually produce values
further away from me.
So basically it allows for it facilitates outliers in an easier fashion than the normal distribution
so it's not as strict as a normal distribution.
And that's kind of like a penalty that you or the price you pay for having a small sample size so if
you still want to apply all of the same logic that we've been applying so far you can by using the t
distribution instead of the normal distribution but you will pay the price of it having law hightails
remember what we do have to tell the tale helps us reject the null hypothesis.
So we say if we're at 5 percent for instance in the normal the region we're at 5 percent we can reject
the null hypothesis.
Well in the t distribution the tail is thicker meaning your 5 percent it'll be further down on the tail
so if for a normal region the 5 percent sits over here or so if that's minus minus two standard deviations
then remember you're 5 percent sit somewhere like somewhere here below it before that minus 2 standard
deviations.
Well for a t distribution with few degrees of freedom like 1 your 5 percent will sit further away.
So it is basically it's harder to reject the null hypothesis when you're using the t distribution that
makes total sense because you have a small sample size.
So if it was as easy to reject the null hypothesis as in the case over a normal distribution then you
might get a lot of false positives you might all get a lot of situations where you can reject the null
hypothesis but in reality you shouldn't have rejected a new hypothesis simply because you know your
sample size was small and you had a sampling like you just you were lucky that you were able to reject
that one hypothesis.
That's what the t distribution combat's the situation where because your sample size small you might
reject a little hypothesis.
In cases where you shouldn't have.
That's that's all it does.
And therefore it has these white thick or tails.
And as you can see as your degrees of freedom increases meaning your sample size increases your tails
get narrower and narrower and narrower and they approach and converge to a normal distribution as degrees
of freedom gets to infinity.
In fact it doesn't have to get to infinity as long as degrees of freedom is all around 30.
Your tea distribution is pretty much identical to a normal distribution.
So think of it as 30s at infinity.
So yeah that's what that is.
So it has heavier tails.
It describes as sample sets also important remember that the t distribution doesn't describe your population.
It describes a sample but it's kind of like a technicality or it's a more of a it's quite an important
underlying concept but it's not really going to affect us as much because we're going to come up with
a way we're going to approach it.
We're just going to have a standard process that we're going to be going through and we do it will already
take into account the fact that it describes a sample so but it's just probably good for you to know
that describes a sample rather than the distribution originally originally which we've been working
with so far normal distribution.
We use it as a distributor of the actual population but this doesn't stop us from making inferences.
You'll see we'll be able to make inferences using that distribution.
And another thing is the larger the sample the closer is anomalous region we've discussed that already.
So there we go.
Your degrees of freedom increases because up to the top.
So let's have a look at that in action.
And this is all from Wikipedia.
There's your research just look at Bleus your normal distribution ideal.
So that's when you get large sample size large blue is just a normal.
Red is the t distribution.
Then what happens is we increase the 1 degree of freedom meaning the sample size is equal to two sample
size equal to three two degrees of freedom.
What's happening is the red is the new t distribution Green is the old t distribution so all of the
old distributions are going to be in green.
Blue is still that normal distribution which you as you can see the red distribution's coming closer
so you go from here to here to here to here to here to here.
So as you can see it's getting closer and closer and closer.
So one two three five ten thirty.
So three degrees of freedom while That's the sample size of 31 but which is which is going to look you
can see it's still not exactly on the blue but it's very close.
So our cutoff point is going to be 30 and that's where these rules come from that we use a T distribution
or t test.
It's also called the t test.
You probably heard that when the population standard deviation is unknown and the sample size is small
less than 30.
So very important that both of these conditions are met.
So the way this is this is interesting how it works.
The t distribution as you can see here allows you to calculate it remember with using it would normally
have your sampling standard deviation here.
But in this case we have the sample standard deviation divided by the square of degrees of freedom.
So basically allows you to operate in environments where you do not know the standard deviation of the
population but at the same time so that is kind of like the normal thing for the t distribution population
that division is unknown.
But at the same time as we saw previously when your sample size is 30 or greater your t test your t
distribution is becomes identical to normal distribution.
So the question is what's the point of using a t distribution in a case where even though you don't
know the cell division of your population it is identical to normal distribution.
So in that case you just still just use a normal distribution and that's a pretty straightforward and
you can approximate your your standard deviation from your sample standard deviation.
And that's that's all you need to do.
So basically as soon as you hit that 30 mark what happens is your distribution becomes a center becomes
your normal distribution and Eve whichever approach you take.
Romans are you going to be doing the same thing.
So we just use n t distribution only in cases when we don't know the population standard deviation and
the sample size is small and is less than 30.
So there we go.
That's a quick intro into the t distribution and in the next part we're going to practice our very first
test.
Very exciting.
Can't wait to get started.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.