Hello and welcome back.
My name is Vitale.
And today we're going to talk about the trends.
It is a very important topic in the business world and today in this tutorial we're going to talk about
the trends from the business point of view.
It is not a hard core statistician lecture.
It is a very much business related applicable and applied kind of course.
So we're going to begin with a number 42.
If you remember this was the answer to the Ultimate Question of Life the Universe and Everything.
According to the Hitchhiker's Guide To The Galaxy but from people not remembering what the question
actually was as the story goes.
As a consultant I have a few issues with this number and the main one is there are no numbers to compare
it with.
What do you mean by that.
We could have the number 42 could have been useful if we had it if we had a comparison to peers and
competitors or to some other numbers.
Two related questions.
If we had some sort of a trend to these 42 to this number 42 is the declining or increasing comparing
to the expected Drange compare to other numbers or ratios.
And there are probably other methods to make it a little bit more clear.
What I'm trying to convey in this message to you if I were to tell you that my weight is 80 kilos.
How much would you make out of it.
I could bet that probably not much because you need some context you need some background and something
to compare this number with.
You either want to know the weight of my peers that I hang out with my friends and for example I can
give you that.
Their weights are 80 to 85 and 90 you want to know the trend.
What was my weight a month ago two months ago three months ago.
And that it will give you an indication if it's increasing or decreasing.
You might want to know what were my expectations to be today with my current exercise program with my
current eating patent pendens.
And then you can compare the actual versus expectations.
Or I can give you my height and therefore you could derive these ratios of height to weight ratio.
That could make sense to you as opposed to just a blunt number 42 or 80 kills.
So having a perspective is very important.
And Trents is that kind of perspective that gives flavor to the numbers that you use in the business
world.
So pretty much an important topic.
If you want to understand your business performance or the KPI performance in real life we're going
to cover some definitions today and I'm going to give you the definitions from my vocab.
The way I understand things and the illustration on the right hand side will hopefully be useful to
refer to.
I've just whipped up this example quickly about the number of cars painted in the workshop during the
month of April and you can refer to it once I'm going to be giving you some definitions.
So the first one is trending trending is quite a generic term and I usually use it in the context of
having system producing some numbers some data it's something objective and something irrelevant to
the analyst.
So these blue bars that you see in the chart is effectively the KPI is trending in some sort of direction
and you can probably start guessing the direction by
using your logic and your common sense.
So trending is something that KPI does or a parameter that's baselining.
And the thing to look for on the right hand side chart is the dotted line baselining is a representation
of the past performance and most accurate representation.
So if you were to get a baseline without the actual data the blue bars you were you would be able to
describe how the past was in the best possible manner forecasting.
Forecasting is a process and it's a process of trying to set expectations of where the performance will
be in the future.
And it is usually referred to a cyclical type process.
In the business world we use monthly forecasts or forecasts quarterly forecasts annual forecasts and
so on and so forth as opposed to extrapolating extrapolating is a term that is referred to as an activity
or an analyst.
So extrapolating is trying to predict what the future performance will be based on your baseline based
on your observations of the trend based on your actual data and analysis of the data so extrapolating
extrapolation and the process of extrapolating is actually something else does.
So we got our definitions straight I hope and before proceeding any further I wanted to give you one
more definition which is of randomness.
So randomness is almost opposite of of the forecast and of trending randomness is actually the lack
of structure or system behind something whether it's data points events or whatnot.
What we are actually trying to do we are trying to defined and understand trends and understand some
models and systems behind the data when the data is totally random it is not going to be possible for
us to define by definition a model of the performance or behavior.
Randomness could be simulated but not modeled to the extent that it will be predicted with high accuracy.
So in the context of the Trents randomness would be almost the opposite of having a trend.
And I'm going to give you one more formula in this tutorial that would be useful for the like down the
track data that you have in the business.
Or you can get from the system is usually a sum of three things.
It is your trend.
If there is any plus your outliers.
Again if there are any plus noise so systems do produce noise this could be errors.
This could be misinterpretations and whatnot.
This could be things not related to the way things are and they can blur you.
You as an analyst when you are trying to understand what the trend is.
So quite important to understand that there are usually three components in your data set.
And to give you again the same example of number of cars painted in the painting workshop I'm going
to give you the reference to these three definitions.
So we talked about trend and trend is in fact the in this case you can try to look at the data and predict
the continuation of that line and kind of define your trend.
This the 18th of April that point is likely to be an outlier.
It looks like it's 20 or maybe a little bit less percentage points less than the usual performance of
the workshop and after drilling into the data you can find out that on that specific day there was a
fire alarm drill 3 PM and the workshop works from 9:00 to 5:00 p.m..
9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. So the abnormal event of the fire drill stop the production and therefore affected
the output which is number of course painted on that particular day as this event is not something that
is likely to happen in the future on a consistent and predictable basis.
We can say that the 18th of April is an outlier and excluded from these data set in order to derive
a trend or understand how the KPI performs.
There are other two data points.
The 10th and 14th of April they are slightly above the baseline level and if you were to drill into
these two data points you would find out that on both days there was rework the cars that were painted
we not to a quality standard they were returned into the workshop to do the work all over like from
the start however our system our computer has not been capturing these data separately and it was just
in the head of a manager that he knew that on the 14th of April for example the two cars were reworked.
Therefore the real number of number of cars painted as a now put ready for sale for production is actually
one hundred and thirty eight.
If you were to consider actually this sellable product at the end so this is an example of a noise something
that system has not captured as a result of the inaccuracy of the system and can blow your expectations
of how many cars are actually produced on a day or painted on a day.
I hope this was helpful.
And one last question before we wrap things up for this tutorial is sometimes a rhetorical question
that we will try to give an answer to how many data points do you need to build the trend and.
Well Carol we'll talk to you about a scientific answer that is statistical significance and the he will
give you an explanation and the definition of how to go around this question.
In this business in the business world there is a rule of thumb that we use to answer to answer that
question the data.
The number of data points is defined as sufficient.
If adding more data points is not going to change the decision or effect the conclusion that we're trying
to draw from the data.
It is potentially a vague definition and doesn't give us specifically we need three months of data but
it will serve you a good guideline in asking yourself whether you are analyzing enough data points and
asking enough questions to make a good prediction.
So for when we talk about production and if we were to come back to the example of our workshop the
car painting workshop to predict the end of the month performance it would be probably sufficient to
have 23 days worth of data.
And while excluding the outlier it would be probably 22 datapoints and understanding a little bit of
context what is going to if the performance is going to be affected.
In the last few days of the month it will be probably sufficient to derive a trend when we talk about
annual performance.
Usually look past years performance 12 months is going to is a good indication to derive the forecast
for the next year.
So this is a rule of thumb.
It is not a precise rule but think of it from the stakeholder point of view the person you're going
to be demonstrating and showing this outputs should should be confident in your data.
And if you were to produce more cover more data points in your analysis this is not going to give you
additional insights or change the direction of the decision that is going to be made.
That is it.
I hope the answer was clear or at least gave you some food for thought and until now we're going to
break up and I'm hoping to see you in the next tutorial.
Thanks for listening.