Hi everyone.
My name is Richard Warburton, and welcome to my course Java: JSON Fundamentals.
I'm an independent software consultant and co-founder of Opsian.
com, a low overhead production profiling solution.
JSON is one of the most popular formats for serializing data into
and is really commonly used by Java programmers,
especially for talking to front-end web applications.
Some of the major topics you'll learn about in this course are as follows,
what JSON is used for in the context of Java application,
how to take Java objects and produce JSON documents from
them in an easy and maintainable manner,
how to consume JSON documents and ingest them into Java objects,
what are the best practices of information
architecture for using JSON with Java.
By the end of this course,
you'll know how to use JSON in real-world Java
applications and be really productive with it.
Before beginning the course,
you only need to be familiar with core Java programming techniques.
No familiarity with JSON is assumed.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn JSON with the Java: JSON Fundamentals course at Pluralsight.