Hello, and welcome to this course on JSON fundamentals in Java.
I'm your host, Richard Warburton.
I hope you're as excited to be watching this course as I am to be producing it.
Now this is the first module, which is entitled, What is JSON?
Now just to make sure that you're in the right place,
I should say that I'm not talking about the actor who played George on Seinfeld,
the guy who played Marshall Eriksen in How I Met Your Mother,
or even the guy in Arrested Development.
We're not answering the question who is Jason.
Where answering the question what is JSON.
Now JSON is an acronym and it stands for JavaScript Object
Notation as it provides a language independent and human
readable data interchange format.
Now even though it originates from the JavaScript ecosystem,
JSON can be used for interchanging data between different
languages that aren't just JavaScript.
A particularly popular use case from the point of view of Java developers,
sending or receiving data between a Java server or a JavaScript web client.
Now were going to break out what I think are the three biggest
use cases for JSON within the Java world so that it's clear whether and why you should be using JSON.