The first aspect of JSON information architecture that we'll take a look at
is the distinction between implicit and explicit schemas,
and specifically, why you may want to use an explicit schema.
Before we go on to clarify the distinction,
let's ask ourselves what actually do we mean by schema?
A schema is a definition of the structure and content of the JSON
documents that you're producing and consuming.
So every JSON document that's produced has some kid of schema.
It has a structure which the code that produces and consumes it relies on.
Schemas can come into a variety of different forms,
but broadly we can think about them as being part of two categories,
implicit and explicit.
So implicit schemas arise in situations where the
producer and consumer of the JSON document.
They just make assumptions about the structure of the message involved.
So for example,
you may have a Java backend with a binding API that consumes
JSON messages and produces a Java class.
On the frontend,
you may have a Java script single-page application that creates ad
hoc objects that it posts to your Java backend.
Whenever a change to the schema of the document is made,
the developers need to update their respective code bases.
An explicit schema documents the schema in the abstract.
So that's to say it defines what the protocol is
outside of the implementing code.
That doesn't mean it has to be a text document that
bit rots or some heavy weight UML, if you've ever used that.
Explicit schemas when done right can still be a part of the code
base and integrated into the development cycle.
For example,
some schemas inforce systems that allow you to generate the POJOs
in Java that you bind to your classes with,
which reduces the amount of work and allows you to
update the schema in one place.
Implicit schemas are commonly used in software development,
but suffer from a number of downsides.
Firstly, they exhibit poor readability.
So if you want to understand what information is being sent between services,
looking at two different sets of code is a slow and
error prone way to grok what's going on.
There's no overview or easy summary that can help developers understand things.
Secondly, there's an unassigned responsibility here.
If a discrepancy occurs in the JSON between the producer and the consumer,
who's responsibility is it?
Is it the responsibility of the producing code or the consuming code?
The problem becomes even worse if it's a separate team who
maintain the producer and the consumer, for example,
a front-end JavaScript team and a back-end Java team.
This can result in finger pointing and undesirable
anti-social interactions between those two teams.
Finally, it's harder to maintain.
Every time you need to make a change,
you need to replicate the changes in two places and ensure
that they're compatible with each other,
that they need to work together correctly.
This is especially hard when you don't know whose
interpretation of the JSON is correct, producer or consumer.
Explicit schemas document the JSON API that's being used.
This can be as simple as having a text document or a
wiki page that describes the schema.
But a better solution is to use one of the software
tools for processing schemas.
That's because they do things like generate code
and documentation of your system, improving your developer productivity.
One increasingly adopted standard tool these days is JSON Schema.
That's the standard for describing JSON schemas that is language agnostic.
Unfortunately, the Java tooling support for JSON Schema,
at the time of recording, is less than ideal,
but I hope that it improves over time.
This is why it's also worth looking at Swagger.
Swagger is a more mature system for describing schemas and
generating APIs and documentation for them.
It can really save time, help develop a velocity, and reduce the amount of errors that creep into your production system.