Now, it's time for our second demo.
In this demo, you'll see how we integrate the binding API into a servlet.
Our servlet will do the same work as the servlet in the previous section.
That's to say it'll approve or deny the loan application,
but this time it'll use the binding style of API so you can see the
difference between that and the DOM style of API.
So let's do a little bit more of a real-world realistic example.
This is the same example that we did with the DOM API of building a
servlet that will approve or reject loan applications.
This time, however,
we're going to use the binding approach rather than the DOM
approach in order to evaluate the input.
So our servlet starts off by implementing the doPost method.
We have an ObjectMapper, which our servlet will use.
And we'll call.
readValue parsing the BasicLoanApplication.
class literal in as a parameter and it taking the
InputStream of the servlet request as its input.
So that will deserialize the JSON value we get sent and
give us a POJO from that JSON input.
We want to calculate the totalIncome of people,
so we can just use the streams API from Java 8 or
later in order to calculate that.
We'll take our loanApplication object,
we'll get the list of jobs that we have in there,
we'll stream them, we'll map each job into its income,
and just call the sum on that.
So that's the totalIncome of the person applying for a loan.
And then we get the amount that they want to apply for by giving the
loanDetails object and getting the amount out of that.
Then finally, we will evaluate that.
So if the loan is less than or equal to three times the totalIncome,
we'll give an OK for the servlet response and we'll tell them it's approved.
Otherwise, we will deny it.
So that nice and simple.
Let's see that code in action.
I have a little main method at the bottom that just loads
this up and runs it on a localhost port.
So, we'll just to remind you,
this is the same post-bank-loan script that we had in the previous section,
which is basically saying post a file to the localhost of port 8000
setting the content type as application/json.
So, this is just to prove to you that the servlet really works.
And I will provide a bank_loan.
json file,
which is the same one that we've been using all the way through so far.
Post it through.
That's approved.
I've also got my bad_loan.
json where the person applying for the loan doesn't have any jobs,
and thus doesn't have any income.
So if we post the bad_loan, we're denied. Servlet works.