Okay,
it's time to take the five different patterns of
transformation that we've encountered so far,
the Awkward Squad, and put them together in a complete demo.
We will write out an immutable version of our loanApplication class,
and define a customized version of it using the different patterns in
order to show off the power of Jackson's binding API.
So let's look through our trick here examples, our advanced binding examples.
So, these are situations where our basic,
just rely on the convention to work,
binding approach won't work anymore and we need to use a few annotations,
so a declarative approach.
We've seen some of the example annotations on the slides,
but I think it's helpful to walk through a more concrete example to see
why you would use these things and what circumstances.
So let's start off.
What I have here is an ObjectMapper and we've got a TransformedLoanApplication.
And the TransformedLoanApplication has a loanDetails object in that
has a LocalDate for its startDate and its endDate.
Now if you remember we saw from our first example, I used a string.
And I used a string because otherwise you get this exception here.
It says InvalidDefinitionException, java.
time.
LocalTime.
So this is basically telling you I don't know how to
deal with your LocalTime field.
I don't know how to convert that from a string into a LocalDate object.
What do we do?
Conveniently, you can register a module on your ObjectMapper.
Now a module is a set of different things that can be used with
Jackson to manage the deserialization approach.
We can, in fact, use a JavaTimeModule.
This is a built-in module that simply defines a bunch of
deserialization properties for different fields that are
included in the Java 8 date and time library,
which is where Java.
Time.
LocalDate is coming from.
We can see it works and that's the result of the toString on
the LocalDate object being printed back out.
But you can, in fact, create your own modules.
So I'm going to create a local variable called module here,
which is going to be a SimpleModule,
which is just a built-in implementation of the module interface that
will let you register deserializers in Jackson.
So we've got a LocalDateDeserializer.
You can implement your own deserializers as well,
it's just a matter of implementing an interface.
And we will instantiate that.
So if I just take the DateTimeFormatter and use the ISO_LOCAL_DATE format,
then I can add a deserializer to the SimpleModule to say
that anything of the type LocalDate,
you can use the localDateDeserializer to deserialize it.
Then I register that module, and again, it works.
If you just want the built-in Java date and time API,
you can just use that JavaTimeModule,
but it's useful to know that you can customize this and
implement your own deserializers should you want to.
So let's break down a little bit further.
We've got our TransformedLoanApplication.
So this parsing okay,
but I think what I'm going to do is simulate a few different problems
that you might encounter and how we solve them.
So for a start, suppose someone who is maintaining this class decides well,
name isn't a very descriptive field name,
so I'm going to rename that to applicantName.
And I'm going to rename the getters and setters as well.
I'm going to exclude string and non-code files, but I've basically done that.
So, that seems good.
It's still a name.
So we run our code and what happens?
Well, at run time, we get this exception.
It says look, unrecognized field name.
Not marked an applicantName.
We kind of saw this example earlier as one of the problems that you
might encounter with using a binding approach,
but here we're going to actually solve it.
So the way you solve it is you put a @JsonProperty
annotation and call it a name.
So if we rerun this code, we can see it now works.
Brilliant!
I put there on the field.
You can choose to put it on the field.
You can also put it on the getter or the setter as well.
That will work equally well.
There we go.
And we've got applicantName, Mrs Joan Smith.
So the next thing after renaming the applicantName is
I'm going to refactor my jobs field.
So it might be the case that we want to be able to look up jobs by name
rather than just have a complete list of the jobs.
So let's change that field to say a map from string to Job that's called jobs.
And we'll import the map.
Brilliant!
But the problem is we have our getters and setters here,
which are still using the old approach.
They're still using the list to get and set the jobs.
So let's modify this.
So we can use these getters and setters with the JSON to bind the
fields in and do a transformation from the data structure we see in the
JSON to what we're going to store internally.
So what I'm going to do here is I need to return the values of our jobs map,
which is a collection of job.
But our method for getJobs takes a list so I'm going to wrap that
up in an ArrayList so it's the correct type.
Then we have a setter for the jobs.
Okay.
So the setter for the jobs is a List of Job and that
needs to be converted to a map.
So what we want to do here is just use some of the nice Java 8 code
so we can just stream those jobs and collect,
and there's a nice toMap function.
So what are we going to do?
We're going to map them by the name, which is the title of the job,
and the other parameter here is a function to convert the value,
which we don't want to do so I'm just going to say
take that job and put it in the map.
Okay.
Now, if I go back to the main method here and rerun this,
we can see Part Time Developer = Job, Freelance Developer = Job,
that's the toString output of the map object and it's
being converted by the setters.
But let's evolve this a little bit more.
I don't actually want to call my getJobs and setJobs getJobs and setJobs
because it's not really modifying the underlying value.
What I really want to do is say something like getJobsJson and setJobsJson.
So if I run that code, boom!
We have a bunch of things saying look, I don't know about your jobs property,
I only know about jobsJson.
So again, to fix this problem,
we can add a @JsonProperty field saying jobs for our getter and our setter.
You might find this will work depending on what version of Jackson
you use for just one of the getter or setter,
but I'm going to use it on both here.
We're back to things working.
Lovely!
Now finally,
you might also want to have a getter for the jobs and the setter for
the jobs that just deal with the regular map objects.
And if you use this, you'll find with modern Jackson,
it just works out that even though those are getters and setters
because you have a named JsonProperty called jobs that actually
uses these getters and setters to do the transformation rather than
the ones with the same names.
So it overrides them.
If you want to be really explicit,
there's also a JsonIgnore that can be used and says definitively
just ignore this getter and setter method.
And that can, in fact,
be used on any getter and setter method if perhaps
there's data you want to hide.
Cool!
So that's our TransformedLoanApplication.
We've gone through a few different problems and
shown how we can get around them.
But, let's take a slightly different approach,
and this is an ImmutableLoanApplication.
So we've got an ImmutableLoanApplication here.
And the ImmutableLoanApplication is the same,
but it doesn't have any setters, only getters,
and it has final fields and the fields are instantiated in the constructor.
So, how does that work?
Well, first of all, convert that over to saying ImmutableLoanApplication.
And I'm going to rename that local variable and rerun this
code just to prove to you that it does work.
Boom!
Lovely!
It does.
Okay, so how does that work for the ImmutableLoanApplication?
Well,
we've got these properties here that we've annotated each of
the parameters on the constructor with.
So we've said the name is the name, the purposeOfLoan is the purposeOfLoan,
etc., etc.
Now, these aren't actually necessary.
If I remove one of them, and rerun this code, boom, huge exception.
Argument 0 has no property name.
So we don't really know what to do.
Okay.
Lovely stuff.
So let's put that back in and call it name.
Now technically, this JsonCreator annotation isn't necessary.
Some older versions of Jackson required you to have an @JsonCreator annotation.
Some older versions of Jackson required you to have a JsonCreator
annotation in order to say which constructor was to be used,
but that's not necessary anymore.
Okay.
It's sometimes still useful to have it there just to be
clear and just to make the convention clear.
But there we go, immutable Jackson deserialization. Brilliant!