So, again, we'll look at a more fully-fledged demo example for Jersey.
This will flush out and make concrete the ideas on how to use Jersey with JSON.
Again,
we will be using the bank application approval and denial service
for this problem so you can consistently see how it works in
different scenarios and with the Jersey API.
So let's take a moment just to explain how you would set up Jersey in a project.
Firstly,
you need to ensure that you have the right dependencies for Jersey in place,
so, grizzly, which is an HTTP container,
jersey-hk, which is an injection framework that binds Jersey together.
Now the jersey-media-json-binding dependency is the thing that says to JSON hey,
here's how you bind Java classes, POJOs,
into HTTP-based requests and responses, streams of stream-based data.
So, this actually uses Jackson under the hood.
So now we've seen the dependencies that you need.
You'd have to have these in your Maven and Gradle project to get started.
Here is just a little bit of boilerplate to get our
Jersey application booted up.
So firstly, you'll notice the ResourceConfig class.
So that's just a thing that tells Jersey hey,
when you're looking for HTTP resources to bind methods and
classes to look for which are annotated,
where do I actually find that stuff?
And the answer is you look in this package,
which is our integrating_json package.
We need to create an HTTP server, of course, in order to actually run the thing.
So that's where our factory method here goes.
It takes the ResourceConfig to say look,
this is the stuff we want to bind to that HttpServer,
and it takes a URI to bind to on the network side as well,
so localhost and our port, which is 8000.
Inside this main method,
I just want to keep the main method running until I hit
press any key and then it'll shut down.
We get the read in, which is just a way of waiting for any key to be pressed.
Where's the any key?
When we run.
shutdownNow at the end, it'll just shut the server down when we're done with it.
Well that's just kind of Jersey background.
Let's get to the actual JSON binding bit.
So in order to implement that, we need to build our class,
our BankApplicationController,
the path for the application controller that says hey,
what URL do you want to expose this on?
Again, we're just going to say put it on the root path for now.
It's a POST request so we need to provide the POST annotation,
and we also need to say look, what are you going to consume in that JSON body?
And that is the MediaType of APPLICATION_JSON.
Then we need to create a method.
So Jersey or JAX-RS has this Response class,
and that is what will be returned from our controller method.
Just like in Spring,
the parameter for the method needs to be the POJO that we're going to
bind to that's going to be deserialized from JSON.
Then we need to implement the body.
So just like before, we need a little bit of business logic.
Take the loanApplication, get its jobs, stream them,
mapToDouble on the AnnualIncome, and then sum up the incomes.
So that's our totalIncome, just like before.
Then we also need the amount of money to borrow, so that is loanApplication.
getLoanDetails.
getAmount.
And if the amount is less than or equal to three times the totalIncome,
we want to say look, we're going to approve your loan.
We'll lend you the money.
Take our Response, we return OK, saying approved,
and then we build that response up.
Otherwise, we return a Response with a status code that says SC_FORBIDDEN.
And I'm going to import that,
return the body of denied because that's where we're going to deny
the application just like before and build it up.
So different objects here to represent the response of the application.
And just to see it in action.
If I run the application main method, here that binds up nice and fast.
Much faster than Spring.
And if we send it a normal bank loan application, it's approved.
Lovely stuff.
And otherwise, it's denied.
Okay.
So it worked just like before.
And the key ideas here, just to recap, were annotation-based binding.
When you POST bind it to a method, say that you consume the APPLICATION_JSON, just put a POJO in as a parameter and the binding will take care of the rest.