Another interesting aspect of information architecture when it
comes to JSON APIs is how you represent errors.
The advice in this section is particularly relevant to when it comes to
APIs where JSON is being used in conjunction with HTTP.
That is to say that the JSON documents are the payloads in an HTTP
based request response communication system.
In a system like this, which is very common,
you've got a couple of choices as to where you encode your errors.
The first choice would be to use HTTP.
HTTP has a bunch of standard error codes with different defined semantics.
For example, the number 500 for an internal server error,
or 404 if the resource isn't found.
A successful HTTP request would be responded to with a 200.
This is a standardized error and standardized correct return values.
But on the downside,
it doesn't encode a message explaining what is wrong with the error,
and that might make it harder to debug things.
The other choice you have is to use a JSON document to represent the error
condition that's returned by the API when error is occurred.
This is flexible because you can put whatever information into
the error document that can aid debugging.
On the downside,
it's not standardized and you need to be careful to
provide debugging information that could not be used
maliciously by an attacker or hacker.
I think the best approach here between those two choices is to
encode the errors themselves into HTTP status codes.
My main reason for saying this is it keeps other tooling working correctly.
For example,
a web browser or a proxy is legitimately allowed to cache an HTTP 200 response,
but will not cache a 500 by default.
If you model errors as JSON documents with 200 status codes,
then they may be accidently cached elsewhere and this might
break retry logic from other services.
Even when returning HTTP status codes for errors,
it's still possible to use JSON documents in order to encode the
error messages as the payload of the response. And I recommend that you do this to make debugging easier.