Finally, let's talk about when we should use this style of API.
So in this course, we'll be covering three styles of API, DOM, binding, and SAX.
So it's important to understand when we would want to
use DOM rather than binding or SAX.
Now, in my experience,
there are two key use cases where a DOM API shines through.
The first is when you're integrating with unstable APIs
where the API will change relatively frequently and your
parsing requests from this API.
The second is API evolution,
where you have to support JSON payloads and different
client versions connect to you.
For example,
suppose you've got different Android clients who are
sending you JSON requests and some of those people aren't
updating their Android app version, but you still have to make sure it works.
Now in both of these cases,
the DOM API takes the work out of parsing whilst giving you
the flexibility to inspect the object graph and only pick out
the information that you need.
So it's very, very useful in that regard.
Now, finally,
it's worth saying that whilst DOM APIs are very nice APIs to use
for parsing and working with generic documents,
it's not the only choice.
In the next section,
we'll talk about the binding API and that's better
for regular simple applications. So I would say don't say with a DOM API, start with a binding API.