Welcome back to the advanced course on
Tableau. In the previous tutorials we did
most of the groundwork and created this
wonderful visual which will help us
identify which machines require
servicing and maintenance. Now, in today's
tutorial we're going to look at a few
quality assurance steps that we can take
to make sure that the insights that
we're going to be conveying are
definitely correct. For instance, I'll
show you an example, like here you can
see right away that this machine does
look like it requires maintenance. This
machine probably doesn't require
maintenance. This machine does spike over
the ten percent line it does look like it
requires maintenance but we'll talk
about that separately. But also here you
can see that these machines they're
green sr1 and sr4 a and the red
they do spike over the ten percent line
you can see that here and you can see
that here.
However it does feel somewhat not normal
like this spike doesn't feel that it is
entirely attributed to the fact that
mission the machine is underperforming
and requires maintenance it looks like
there might be a chance that this spike
is an irregularity just like this one
caused by the fact that we don't have
any data here and we don't have any
data here. So the lack of data for
these periods might somehow be causing
the spike and therefore we have to
investigate this further to understand
maybe we need to somehow fix our charts
so that these spikes go away and we report
only the true faulty machines or the
true truly underperforming machines that
require maintenance.
Alright so to understand this better
what's going on here and here.
Let's go to the data so here's the coal
terminal data and let's find one of
these machines. So let's start with this
green one for instance SR1 and this
happened at 12am. So let's go ahead and
find that one SR1 and if I just scroll
down so I might zoom in a bit so we can
see better, September 17.
There we go, SR1 so as you can see here
what's going on is that we don't have
any data
for September's 16th right? So it only
starts September 12, so basically what
we're seeing in our visual I'll just add
some rows here as we see all this blank
space in fact I'll just add a bit more rows.
So we're seeing this blank, this blanks
and there's a lot more blanks because is
there's basically 13, 14, 15, 4 days
missing so 4 times 24 bars are missing
or from this chart. So how does this spike
come to be. Well what's happening is
we're applying a moving average right
but we're applying the moving average to
idle capacity so let's perform these
calculations here as well and this is
actually the second thing that we wanted
to talk about in this tutorial how to
perform quality assurance on your Tableau
calculations.
Well basically we're going to recreate
the Tableau calculation now in our data
over here. So to start off with let's
recreate the table calculation somewhere
at the start. We'll say this is going to
be 0% difference right so how is
the percent difference calculated? We
have to take actual tons minus nominal
capacity and divide it by normal capacity and I'm
just going to copy this down a little
bit and then what we did is we took the
positive to send difference and we said
this is going to be the percent
difference times minus one. So just make it
positive and then we applied an
eight-hour moving average to the
positive percent difference. So let's say
MA here and what we're going to do is
let's say let's take this one for
instance, we'll say average of these bars.
So I'm going to select eight
values here, the first this current one
and the seven previous ones as you
remember in our data that's what we
did.
So there we go, that's our average. Now
I'm going to copy this up, so here you
can see that's our average for those bars,
here you can see that's our average and
I've copied here what is taking its
taking of the wrong values in fact if I
start copying further is gonna
incorrect reference because there is
nothing to take into account so the
these ones we can calculate a moving
average for these ones because we just
don't have enough bars to calculate the
moving average. So let's leave them for
now,
now let's copy this further down so as
you can see as I'm copying down the
moving average is running along with the
data and that's why it's called the
moving average so I'm just going to copy
it all the way down to our gap so it
went all the way down to 12th of September
and it stopped here. So now what will
happen if I copy this information or
these formulas for the 17th of
September and then I just gotta keep
copying them down like that. So obviously
this is calculated correctly. It's taking
these two values into account. This is
calculated correctly as well, however,
this this average is taking these blanks
and then the value into its calculation.
This this average is only taking two
values and then it taking six blanks. This
this next value here is taking three
values and it's taking four blank a 5
blanks into account. So as you can see,
the first eight bars here will be the
first eight averages that we calculate
or the first seven averages there will
be taking at least one blank value into
account their calculations. So therefore
the only kind of calculating correctly
and as you can see here we get the 0.136.
Let's see what we have in our chart.
On our chart we have 0.136, you can sit
over here so 0.136 how did we get that?
Well that is exactly because of the
blanks our average is actually equal to
the value on during that hour. So
therefore such an average is just
displaying the value of the percent
difference the percent difference
that we calculated for the idle capacity
for that specific hour and that's not
what we want. It doesn't fit our criteria,
it's not an average for 8 hours. In fact we
can calculate an average for 8 hours here
because we don't have the data. Similar
situations apply at the start, as we
discussed that you cannot
calculate the average because you just
simply don't have the data and the
similar situation applies here and here.
So here we just got lucky that the
averages were there,
idle capacity for that hours was very low
and therefore the average is low but
here in contrast we can see that the
idle capacity here was above ten percent
and therefore the average is above ten
percent. So we definitely don't want to
include things like this in our analysis
and we need to exclude them from this
report. So how do you do
that? First thing we want to do is want
to go into our formula so idle capacity
moving average and let's click edit over
here. Now we've got this window average
formula here, what we want to do is you
want to add a condition saying that if
there's not enough bars is not enough data
don't calculate the window average. So
how can we add that into our formula? Let
me bring it up again.
So there we go we're going to just add a
simple if condition, so we're going to
add another table calculation so we're
going to go into our table calculations
and we're going to find window which one
do we need? We need window count, this one.
So we're going to say if window count
here you also need an aggregation so why
don't we just use exactly the one that
we are aggregating? So we're going to say
if in our window,
we're going to calculate the number of
of these observations of or of these
values that we've derived in a given
window and that's windows gonna be
exactly the same as we're using here so
we're going to say, in this window seven
bars to the left and then include the
current bar right? If the count of these
values that have been derived is an is
equal to eight so if it is exactly eight
then only we want the calculation right?
So then we'll say then we want this
calculation so I'll just put a capital
if here right so that's the case else if
that's not the case then we want to say
no we don't want any values and then
we'll say and so what is going on here
we're saying calculate the number of
these values in the specified window,
there we go. So that's calculating them
the number of values in the specified
window. I might switch to excel that might
be easier to explain there, so we're
saying let's say for this bar for this
one here calculate the number of values
in this window so in this window there's
eight, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7. 8 and in that case, if it is
equal to 8 then return the average for
those bars otherwise return 0. You can
basically can replace the herd bars with
rows so in this case calculate the
number of values in these in this window
rows there's eight so return the average.
For this one on the other hand, what will
happen is there's a window so how many
values do we have in this window? We have
no no no no no we only have three values.
So on there's three values three does
not equal eight this condition will be
false
that means that this will not be
executed this will be executed and will
return all, so let's go ahead and click
ok and just watch how what happens to
this bar over here. You can see it got
cut off
so as the red one as the green was on
all everything at the start time is
going to press control zed for you to see
how everything returns and I'm going to
press control Y, to redo the calculation.
So basically we're getting rid of these
average that that are supposed to be
there because we don't have enough data
to calculate them correctly and that is
important,
by doing this as you can see we're right
away saying that this machine is no
longer and longer has an average that is
above the ten percent line and now this
machine also doesn't have an average
about ten percent of line and it's a
completely different. A report that we're
going to create in this case, we were
going to say this machine requires
servicing this machine this machine and
this machine right but if we do the
calculation properly it's only this
machine and this machine that look like
they require servicing and these three
don't. So that is an important step in
quality assurance. First of all,
calculating the moving averages
correctly because if you don't have
sufficient data you have to tell
Tableau not to calculate the moving
average on the certain bars or certain
rows
and finally also another quality assurance
check that since we've already got this
up and running what we can do is we can
take a random bar or a random row let's
say let's say 10th of September at
midnight and we can look at the average
here so 0.0342  and let's have a look
at what happened here at one-tenth of
September at midnight and we just want
to compare and make sure that the value
we see in Excel that the one that we
just calculated is exactly the same as
what we will see here. So there we go,
0.0034  what did we see in Excel 0.0034
so that means that our calculation
is correct and that's a good way of
conducting a quality assurance check on
your table calculations simply by going
back into excel and re-creating those
table calculations from scratch. It does
take time it is a bit of a tedious task
but you only have to do it for one of
your elements of your data so you
don't have to do it for all of your
machines just do it for one because it
works for this machine will work for the
rest of them but it will also save you
from errors and table calculations can
be complex especially when you're piling
many on top of each other like we're
doing now we already have two layers of
table calculations,
plus we've just added a condition so you
want to make sure that your table
calculations are correct. It's better to
spend a bit more time but get everything
right so that you report the correct
thing.
Ok so that's how you conduct quality
assurance for your table calculations
and that is how we fixed up all moving
average and this brings us to the end of
today's tutorial. Next time we're going
to start deriving insight from a
data. We're getting very close to punching
this report out and deriving this these
insights to the client, I look forward
to seeing you next time.
Until then, happy analyzing.