Hello and welcome back to the advanced
course in Tableau, and in today's
tutorial we're going to expand our
knowledge on LOD calculations and we'll
see how we can apply multiple fields or
multiple dimensions inside an LOD or
level of detail calculation. So let's
have a look at that and first of all
let's find out the reason why we would want
to do that. Well here we've got our
beautiful beautiful map that we've
created and it's showing us exactly what
we want.
So for every city it's showing the
normalized by state proportion that it
contributes to the profit of that state.
So it's it's quite a powerful
visualization but what happens if we
want to change this visualization, what
happens if we want to for some reason go
down to the level of postal code? So
we're so far we have country, state, city.
What if you want to make it even more
granular? We want to go down to the level
of postal code then what will happen to
this visualization right? So generally
like what you expect is that you will
see the same visualization, but instead of city,
you'll have postal codes and their
contributions to the whole profit of
that state. So let's have a look at that
I'm going to click this plus sign as you
can see no unfortunately not
unfortunately adding postal code into
our visualization completely messes up
the visualization. So why is that? What
happened here? Let's get to the bottom of
this.
Well now that we know how the level of
detail calculation works, we can trace
back what exactly happened. So if we edit
the level of detail calculation and look
at it here that the one that we're using
in this visualization you'll see that
we've got exclude city and then sum by
profit, right? So basically again let's
think in terms of relative and absolute
pathways on a hard drive so that little
trick that we talked about our
theoretical approach theoretical trick
that we talked about when thinking about
the level of detail calculation. So include
and exclude they are relative. They
exclude something relative to your
current visualization. So here what it's
doing is out of all of our dimensions to
the blue blue ones that we have here and
here we currently have only so all this
is green. These are not dimensions.
These are blue and these are dimensions
and you can see here we've got four so
what it's doing is it's saying if you
find a dimension called city excluded
from the visualization so take city
remove it and then calculate the sum of
profit right. So basically it's saying do this
and calculate the sum of profit but the
problem here is that that doesn't take
us to the level of the state. To it doesn't
take us to the aggregation level of
state because we still have the postal
code here. The postal code is still
keeping it and keeping us at that very
granular level even though we've removed
city. So how can we fix this? How can we
improve? Or how can we account for that?
Well what we can do is we can say
exclude not only city, but exclude coma,
postal code, right? So what this will do
is it will exclude city and postal code,
if it finds them from our visualization.
So basically, you'll do this takeout city, postal
code, city go back to the state level and
let's don't mind this this chart that we
have here. Basically it'll go back to this
chart because here we've got the level
of detail calculations instead of so
what we would do is but this has label
there. So there's our profit and remove
this other one as label. So you'd go back
to this chart with the profits because
we want the sum of profit. As you can see sum of
profit here and then it would take
a sum of profit from here. Let's put this
back and then it would go back to this
visualization and then apply sum of
profit. So let's give this a go. So let's
click OK here. As you can see it's now
fixed up and moreover if I cancel city
so if I close city and I mean remove postal
code so it doesn't matter if I have if
I'd if I wanted at the country, state,
city level of granularity. It works right?
So it works fine as it used
too. If I add postal code, it also works.
You will notice that not many cities
have different postal codes in our
data set. That's just a feature about
data set but if you look over here
you'll see that they are quite a few
there are a few that change so as I do
that there's if all is a few that change
right or if you look here you can see
that in Wyoming there's two cities here
one under each other to postal codes so
if i look at the data, we'll see that
this 82902 postal code or 82901,
and one is behind the other.
So zoom in a bit you can see them over
there so it works in both cases and you
can actually check so if we take Wyoming
and view data here you'll see that
we've got three possible codes and the
total of that percentage so if you add
these up it will add up
it should add up to a total of one
exactly. So it works perfectly fine and
this is a good illustration that you can
actually specify several dimensions that
you want to exclude or include so the
same would work totally fine for include
you can specify several dimensions in
your level of detail calculation so
let's have a look at it again and it
there it is exclude then the dimensions
that you want to exclude and the colon
and then the aggregation. So and again
if it doesn't find a dimension for
instance in this case we've got city but
we don't have possible code on
visualization, if it doesn't find this
dimension it will simply it can or this
command to exclude that dimension so
there's no conflict of that sort
happening here.
Alright so that's how you can include
several dimensions in your level of
detail calculation. Hope you enjoyed this
tutorial and I look forward to seeing
you next time.
Until then, happy analyzing.