Welcome back to the advanced course on
Tableau and in today's tutorial
finally the executive report is ready
and we're going to go through it.
However before we do, I would like to ask
you for a favor.
I know we're not finished with the
course yet but I would like to ask you
to leave a review.
It's very easy to do you just need to
click this button up in the top right
corner of your screen and select the
number of stars you think the course
deserves and perhaps type up a short
message for me if you like, if not,
select a number of stars will be
totally sufficient. I'll be really happy if
you can do that and the reason I'm
asking you now is that although we
haven't finished with the course yet, a lot of
students for whatever reasons don't get
to the very end of the course and
therefore forget to leave a review but
at the same time I would really
appreciate if you could give me some
feedback on how you felt the course went,
how I went for the materials and more
importantly your review will help other
students decide for themselves whether
this course is where their while or not.
So I would be very happy if you could do
that for me today and now let's get on
with the show. So I'm going to jump into
full-screen mode just like you would
during a presentation and you do that by
clicking f7 and so on this first page of
our storyline what we have is a summary.
Here we've got the five machines that we
were analyzing. A reclaimer one and two
and stack reclaim is 14a and 6 and we
are comparing the idle capacity in
percentage terms to the threshold of ten
percent and also what we're talking
about is the 8-hour moving average. So
what would you do with this first slide?
Well sometimes during the presentation,
this would be sufficient for you to
present your findings.
Perhaps you would just talk about what
you were able to investigate through
your data mining process and that
would be sufficient information for the
executives to proceed with the business
decisions. Here you would highlight that
machine number one has exceeded the
threshold several times and it does
require maintenance. Also, you would
identify the upward trend that you were
able to establish. Next you'd say that
machine RL2 is performing fine
and does not require any service add to
the stage. Machine
SR1 is also performing fine and
perhaps they would ask a question about
what this gap means and you would easily
explain it because we do know that this
gap was attributed to the fact that the
machine was working on another job. Then
you would highlight this trend in a
machine 4A saying that this is a very
important finding and even though the
machine does not exceed the ten percent
threshold and any given point in time
what in reality is happening, it is
coming near a very dangerous point in its
service life and that if a maintenance
is not undertaken and then it might
break down in the coming months. So
basically you're predicting ahead of
time using data that this machine might
break down in the next week or so and
you can already tell that just by
looking at this trend, something very
interesting, something that you would not
be able to find unless you looked at the
data. So this in itself demonstrates the
power of data mining and finally you
talk about machine SR6 and you'll say that
it did exceed the threshold but from
your further investigations into the
data it appears that this increase does
look like a planned increase. So it's a
sacrifice of visualization to increase
the utilization of machine RL2
because they are on one line. So and from
there perhaps you would want to still
published this report to let's say
Tableau server for the executives to
explore at their own leisure and that is
why we have the rest of these pages in
our storyline. So let's go through them
next you move on to the reclaimer so you
want to separate reclaimers from stacker
reclaimers in your storyline and you have
this traditional slide. Here you talk
about reclaimer one, so we've got a map
a very nice and convenient map over here
which tells us where exactly reclaimer
one is located and you've got the
transfer and you've got some verbiage or
some text explaining exactly what
happened to reclaim one. Now I won't go
through this text right now, won't read
through it but feel free to pause the
video if you'd like to read through this
text. This is my interpretation of what i
found in the data. Also, I have added a disclaimer
here because all of these findings they
are completely not really
related to DBCT. This is a mock-up
data set just to practice our skills in
Tableau, so just making sure that anybody
was reading this report is
definitely aware of that. So then we
move onto RL2, so you can see how the
highlighting changed and once again the
text changed. Then we move onto stacker
reclaimers. These are different machines
that can perform two types of tasks
by the way that's what the rails would look
like at a coal terminal then we talk
about stacker reclaimer one,
stacker reclaimer 4a and finally stacker
reclaimer 6. So it is a bit different
this type of presentation it is a bit
different to what we are used to
normally I am a strong advocate of just
pictures, just images, just graphs and so
you say the text you are the presenter
you are the focus of the attention of
your audience
the slides are there just to assist you
but when would you write up so much text
you would write up so much text in cases
when you are letting your audience
autonomously go through your report and
that is in this case if you're
publishing it to Tableau server and you
want to the executives to be able to
later go through this report on at their
own ledger and read what you had to say
sometimes sometimes you are required to
create reports that reports like that.
They can be in PowerPoint, they can be in
Tableau, they can be in other systems,
they can be online and there will be
times when you will be required to write
up text so it is also a good skill to
have.
So I really hope that you enjoyed this
section and picked up a lot of great
knowledge and skills and just as a quick
reminder, please leave a review for this
course if you have enjoyed the materials
so far and I look forward to seeing you
in the next section.