Hello this is Kirill Eremenko and welcome back
to the advanced course on Tableau and in
today's tutorial we'll be connecting to
our data set for this section. Now we
decided to devote a whole tutorial for
our connection process just because
we're going to be discussing quite a lot
of things. We'll be talking about creating
a dummy column for conducting and join
we'll be talking about conducting
multiple live joins at the same time.
We'll be talking about pivoting our
data and changing metadata and a
couple of things on top of that. So
there's quite a lot of ground to cover
and let's jump straight into it.
First of all we'll connect to our excel
file which is coal terminal. Now as you
can see here there are quite a few tabs
and as we discussed each tab is for a
machine so there's reclaimer 1,
reclaimer 2, stack reclaimer 1, stack
reclaimer 4a, stacker reclaimer 6 and
those are the machines that we need to
analyze. Now how we going to go about
this data? What are the options here?
Well I  wanted to mention that with
visualization often there are many ways
of achieving the desired result.
So we have a business problem to solve
and we have a question to answer but how
we get to that question and what the
actual visualization looks in the end
can vary and it depends on your personal
preferences and dependent approach to
choose and a lot of the time, the way you
choose you structure your data set will
dictate which approach you will be
taking. So let me give you a couple
examples what we could do here is we
could connect to just the one tab for
this machine and start analyzing it
right away so just have that one
connection and then we finish we could
connect to the next machine and do the
analysis again and the next machine doing
analysis again and so on. So that's a valid
approach that's one of the ways you
could do it. The other way you could do
it, you could connect to these machines
separately but then you could blend the
data inside Tableau. Another way is you
could connect to them all together here
and create some joins over here and
that's exactly what we'll be doing in
this. There are other ways as well,
I'll give you another example so here's
here's a the data set that we working
with what you could do is you could
some data manipulations in Excel and
then connect to your data and that
is also valid approach so ultimately
approach you take with data dictates
the pathway that you'll go upon what
your barcode embarked upon in your
visualization process and it also
depends on what you want to achieve on
how you want to get to the end result. In
our case, I'll show you one of the ways
that this problem can be solved and that
is through join. So let's jump straight
into it. How would you conduct a joint
here?
Well first of all let's try to
understand what we're trying to achieve.
So here's our data set and what we're
trying to achieve is we're trying to
join on this date time column and bring
everything into one big table like this.
So let me give you an example, just do
some manipulation in excel and I'll
cancel them out. So here we've got a
reclaimer 1 what we want to do is we
want to take reclaimer 2 and based on
the day time column bring it in here
like that and we want to take this
stacker reclaimer and bring it in here
like that and so you get the point, we're
trying to join all of our tabs on the
daytime column so we have one big table
like this and then from there we will
can create pivot and we'll adjust the
metadata and will create a data
connection that will suit on it,  but the first
step is to create this massive join, so
how would you go about that in Tableau?
Well the first thing that comes to mind
is why don't we take the one of the
tabs for the example the first tab and
use it as the master tab and then we
will join the rest of the tabs using
left joints to that tab and of course
we're going to join not an actual times
button daytime and then we can take
another tab SR1 for instance, and do the
same thing, right there we go.
But two things jump into mind in regards
to this approach right away first of all
it's doesn't look symmetric right? You're
using one of the tabs as the master tab
and the rest of the tabs are kind of
auxiliary tabs that are being joined to
it, so it doesn't look symmetrical,
doesn't appear symmetrical but generally
speaking that's not a problem. If, if
everything is else is correct that's a
completely valid approach and you can
conduct enjoying that way but the other
thing the more important thing that
comes to mind is
what if there is missing data in the
daytime column over here? As you can see
we're doing a left join, assuming that
they might be missing data in these
columns but here that all of the hours
are definitely present and so you will
never get a situation when SR1 has a
daytime that it wants to join to only
wants to use to join but that daytime is
not present RL1 but that might not be
the case. Let's look at our data what
you will see here is as I go through the
tabs you will notice that the number of
records in each tab change and you can
see that just simply by observing this
scroll bar over here as you can see it
will change when I jump from one tab
to another, that's by the way that's a
handy trick just to observe if the
number of rows in tabs is the same but
otherwise you can also see right away
that here the data starts from six of
September and everywhere else it starts
from first of September so we don't
there is no guarantee that all of the
data is present in every single tab for
the date time field and in order to
avoid losing any data you know join what
we're going to do is we're going to
create a dummy column that we will use
as our master column for the join and
this is how you do it, all you have to do
is create a new sheet and this one we'll
call timeline and in this tab I will
just create one single column and I'll
call it daytime and I'll just copy the
first row from here. So that is our very
starting point and we already know that
we're dealing with the whole month
September so we want every single hour
in September, so what we want to do is
want to take this value and we want to
add time and we just want to add one
hour so this is how you do it in Excel
and that adds exactly one hour and so
now if I drag this down, you'll see that
every time it adds one hour to the cell
before. So that way
what we can do is we want to get to
about thirty or thirty first, 30th of
September right? So there's 26th of
September, there's 2nd of October so we
just want to get rid of October we know
we're not dealing with October
and there we go, 30th of  September.
What we just did is we create a column
that definitely has all the values that
we need and one more thing that you
might want to do is copy the whole
column and paste special as just values so
you don't have those formulas in there
anymore.
Now if we save this and just go back to
Tableau, all you have to do is you
probably need to close Tableau because if
you update this it doesn't always pick
up the new tabs right away. So just if
you quickly close Tableau and open it
up again and now if we connect the
connection again, you will see that the
new tab has appeared timeline, now we can
use this tab to conduct our join, so
there's RL1, RL2 as you can see
automatically it's joining on daytime so
let's just add a few more in or will
actually hold on them in as there you
go.
So make some space and let's just make
them left all them left joins there we
go. So that is our timeline that is how
we connect your data set, so down here
you can see all the data that will
be working with and already there is
quite a lot of field now. What we want to
do is want to bring them all into one
format and what we want is we want to
date and we want them and just a value
so I value for the nominal or actual
tons and also we want of course the
description which machine that is for. So
first thing we want to do is as you can
see here let's go to the metadata so
here what you can see is that all of
them have an indication which sheet they
came from,
except for this nominal capacity and
these actual tons for RL1, so let's go
ahead. We can see that they're from RL1
here let's go ahead and just type
that in so that we don't lose this
information and that will be a bit more
convenient for us
good, now if we go back to the table, we
know we already have a date time column
which is this one which we are working
with. Let's get rid of all the other day
times columns.
So that day time we don't need I'm just
going to hold down control and select all
the daytimes I can find and if I right
click and press hide they'll, they'll go
away.
So let's see if we have any more looks
like we're only left with values now, all
we have to do is create a pivot and to
do that,
just select all of the value rows the
measures and right click and click pivot
and there you go it's as simple as that.
Now we have a daytime column, we've got a
pivot field name and we've got a pivot
field value, so once again we talked
about this in the basic Tableau course,
they should be you should be pretty
comfortable with this right now if not
please revise the basic course in
Tableau otherwise this is how we create
our data connection and finally we can
change the names of these fields in our
metadata. Let's change the field name, pivot
virtual names to machine and pivot field
values. We're going to change to tons
because we know that its measured in
tons.
Alright so that is our connection, let's
go back to the table as you can see here
we've got the day time,
We've got the machine which also
specifies whether it's actual tons or
its or it is nominal capacity and we've
got the measure. Hope you found this
tutorial useful and picked up a few new
skills and we'll pick up from here in
the next tutorial. I look forward to
seeing you then.