Hello and welcome back to the advanced
course on Tableau. In the previous
tutorial we built this beautiful-looking
visualization for country demographic
data and today we're finally going
to add the animation to see all of this
progress in action over the past 50-plus
years. So adding animations in Tableau
is actually very very simple. To start
off, we're going to remove year from
filter because we are going to build our
visualization or our animation based on
different year, so let's get it out of
filter and now we're just going to take
a year and we're going to drag it into
this tab which we haven't used before
which is called pages and once you drag
it into there, that pretty much builds
your animation right there. So you can
see a time line up here's and this is
actually a series of pages so for us
it's a timeline because we are using
year and bear in mind that the in this
case in our case year is recognized as a
string. It's not a date and you can tell
by this indicate over here which says
ABC and yet we're still able to create
this animation because Tableau does
require pages and pages can be
practically anything.
Well in our case, we are using years and
here you can control the animation you
can move zoom through the different
years and you can see how it's changing
as I click to the right or I can go back
to the left and that's changing
animation and also you can just let it
play by itself so I can just click play
and it will be changing slowly one step
at a time. You can control the speed you
can make it a change slower so here you
can see that it's changing very slowly
and that's if you want to analyze the
data in a lot of detail and finally
you can put on the maximum speed and
it's changing very quickly. So there you
go you can see how the animation works
very impressive isn't it? So that's how
the countries are changing and you can
look at individual countries for
instance this big red circle is China
and you can see it started over here
with fertility rate of 5.75 and
life expectancy of 43 years only
back in 1960 and and you can
see how it's moving through this grid
and finally it gets to 2013 where life
expectancy for fertility rate is 1.6 so
1.6 children per family and 75 years of
life expectancy, great improvement in
terms of life expectancy and this is
exactly what we were after. We wanted to
see how this what the tendencies or
trends are in the world in terms of
fertility and life expectancy. So the
other thing we can also see here is of
course population, you can see how the
bubble is growing for instance let's
look at the bubble China, you can see how
it's growing with time so it got much
bigger towards the end and that is
talking to the population of the country
and finally the other dimension that we
have here is the color which is telling
us which region these countries are from
and we've got Asia, we've got Europe, Latin
America, America, South Southern Africa,
Northern Africa and and so on, and in a
way what you have here on this
two-dimensional picture this is very
exciting actually on this
two-dimensional picture what you have is
five dimensions of information. You have
fertility rate, life expectancy right?
Then you have population which is the
size that's three, then you actually have
a fourth dimension which is the color
and that is which region they're coming
from and finally animation allows you to
add a fifth dimension to your visual and
that is the year so as you're
progressing through years you're you're
seeing the fifth dimension which is time
and that is pretty cool. So now we're
going to fix up just a couple more
things that we're going to fix up the
axis here so we're going to fix it at
eight and make it start at one and this
axis we're going to fix it at let's say
85 and we'll make a start 30.
And now if we move everything to left, it
kind of fits in a bit better so let's
play that again.
There you go pretty cool isn't it?
So as we discussed the nulls are
attributed to the fact that some
countries don't have data for some years
and you can check that in your actual
data sources so we're just going to
right-click and hide indicated so it's
not ruining our visual and let's play it
one more time. I'll show you another
quick trick here so we can say loop
playback and that way it will continue
playing out once it's finished it will
continue playing you don't really need
that in this visual but you might need
it in other visuals and just that's one
additional control that you can apply
here, so I'm just going to switch that
off and one more trick that I'll show
you here is you can play it backwards so
once it gets the end if you like you can
play it backwards and you'll see the
trends all going the opposite way and
one more thing that we might want to add
to this visualization is indication of
what year it is because people be looking
here not here and they might want to see
what year the visualizations currently
going through, so what we're going to do is
we're going to right-click and we'll
select annotate and will click area and
here we will say insert and here we will
say page name. So this is the name of our
page and we're going to insert here and
maybe make it quite large making a 72
and we don't want it black once again, we
want this color and make it bigger put
it in the top someone like that and we
want to get rid of this border. We don't
want the border so we're going to right
click format,
none there we go so let's see how this
changes maybe this is a big big let's
make it the next size down 48. That's too
small, so let's make this 64.
There we go, now let's see how this
changes as we play our visualization
that button there you go so you can see
that the year is changing and if you
want to analyze it in a bit of a more
slower version then you can actually see
every single year and other people see
the year and then they can see how the
countries are changing so they can
reference that here if they ever need to.
So that is how you create basic
animation in Tableau, that's that's the
first starting point for us. In one of
the next tutorials in this section I
will show you how to add advanced
features to this visualization to make
its interpretation more useful and more
intuitive for the people that are going
to be looking at it so that they can
extract more insights from it, and there
we go that's all for today. I look
forward to seeing you next time and
until then, happy analyzing.