Hello and welcome back to the advanced course
on Tableau and today we're going to
discuss the three types of the level of
detailed calculations that exists
in Tableau. Alright, so here we've got the
map that we prepared previously, let's
take profit and drag it onto color now
we've got profit which indicates which
is signified by the color of in this
case points because we've got cities on
our map and what we can do is we can
change the granularity or aggregation as
we discussed so we can just simply click
this minus button or just remove a city
and then we'll move to the level of
aggregation at the state level if we
remove that then our visualization is now
aggregated at the country level and as
you can see this is a total for the
United States so here we can zoom in
because we know we're dealing with
mainland US so you can see that's the
aggregation for the US. But we're going to
stick to the state and the city and
basically what do level of detailed
calculations allow us to achieve?
Well let's say you're working with this
visualization and here we've got the
level of detail of the visualization
which is the state level right so right
now we are at the state level and their
form that's how Tableau is summing
everything up, but what if we want to
actually perform some calculations at
the city level.
Yes of course, we can add the city into
our visualization by clicking this plus
sign or we can just drag city here into
detail same thing and what happens is
now we can actually see the different
cities here and we can perform calculations
here but what happens if we actually
want the visualization to stay at the
state level but we want to first perform
some calculations at the city level and
then display them at the state level.
We'll look at more specific examples
further in this section but let's just
imagine that scenario let's imagine we
want to perform some aggregation of our
data because we remember that our
data is actually at the order
item level so we've got many many rows
so even more than we have cities so what
if you want to aggregate these rows at
the city level. Let's say take the sum
or the average or count these rows at the
city level and then aggregation at the
level of the state.
How can we do that? Well that's what
level of detailed calculations are
actually for and we're going to discuss
the three types of level of detail
calculations and existing Tableau. So
let's go ahead and do that. Here I've got
a little presentation prepared three
types of level of detail calculations so
the three types are number one include
number two exclude and number three fixed. So let's
have a look at each one of them separately.
What does include a almost do? Well let's
say like in our hypothetical example
working on a map it doesn't have to be
my map by the way it can be any type of
visualization as you're creating can be
completely unrelated to geographical
data you just have some certain
measures and the measures that you
include in your dashboard, they are they
determine the level of detail of your
visualization but you might want to
drill in further without changing your
visualization to perform aggregation and
then display that on your visualization.
So which is using a map for simplicity's
sake so it's very visual it's very easy
to understand but again this can be
completely unrelated to geography it can
be any sort of measures that dimensions
that you're using in order to create
visualizations. That's just very
important to bear in mind that level of
detail calculations apply always. You can
always use them doesn't matter if you're
creating maps or not you're creating
something else. So in our case where
let's say we're working at the state
level and then we want to perform some
calculations at the city level for
instance aggregate our data at the
city level and then bring it back to
our visualization. So that's what include
allows you to do. It allows you to
include additional dimensions in your
calculation so not only on visualization bring
your calculation so
your visualization won't change even
though we're showing a new
visualization. Your visualization stays
like this and this is just what happens
in the background so include allows you
to go to a lower level of a higher level
of granularity or a low level level of
aggregation as you remember granularity and
aggregation are the opposites so include
allows you to go to a lower level of
granularity. So include allows you to go
to a higher level of granularity, so make
your calculation more granular for
instance go to the city level, perform
some calculation at the city level and
then bring it back to your visualization.
So all of this these two arrows and this
part you will never see them they will
happen in the background. They will happen in
your formula. Your visualization will
still remain at the higher level. That's
what includes allows you to and that's
why it's called include, it allows you to
include in this case we're including the
dimension which is called city. So our
visualization stays at the level of the
dimension state in our formula we are
including and as you'll see from the
practical side of things we're including
the dimension which is called city. Alright
so then we've got exclude, well exclude
does opposite. If you're working at a
level of aggregation such as city for
instance in this case and then you need
to for some reason go to a higher level
of aggregation also you want to lower
the granularity and you want to go to
the state level but you don't want to
change your visualization, you just want to get
some data from some from so calculations
at the state level and bring them back
right? So then that's what exclude allows
you to. Exclude in this case, we're going
to exclude the dimension which is city
which will give us just the same
visualization or this will give us the
same data set and the same analysis
that were performing but at the level of
the state and then we'll perform some
calculations in our formula and then
we'll bring it back. So in this case, all
of this on the left will be in the
background so your visualization will stay at
this
level of granularity whichever level of
granularity it was at and then you'll
just excluded the dimension temporarily in
your calculation perform that
calculation for instance you might want
to find out the sum of all of your
profits for each state and then bring it
back into a calculation right and an
obvious example here is that lets say
you have them profit for each city so
you can sum it up, you just just forget
about this left part. You can just, based on
this visualization you can sum up the
profit for every city and you'll get the
sum of profit for city but then you want
to divide it by the total profit for
that state in which that city is right?
So how'd you get that? Well you use a
level of detail calculation. You use
exclude, you exclude city in that
specific calculation so that will give
you this arrow. You will then this use a
sum function on the within each state in
that formula. We will see that as well in
action and then you will go back to your
original visualization. You will bring that
information back and you'll be able to
use it in your visualization so without
impacting the visualization itself very very
powerful and finally we've got fixed, so
what is fixed? Well here I've got just
the map based on the state level again
it's just this is just an example can be
at any level can be at city state
country war again your visualization
might not even include geographies it
might be a years it might be months it
might be gender it might be different
categories of products any kind of
dimension. This is very important to
understand and in this case what i have
is the data set, add to the level of the
state and what fixed means is it means
it doesn't this calculation which we'll
be using the fixed level of detail
calculation it won't care it won't rely
on the original level of granularity of
your visualization. So this is where the
calculation will happen, that's full stop so
you're not including or excluding
anything you just explicitly specifying
where at which level of granularity you
want your calculations be performed and
your visualization can be at
the country level. It can be at the city
level or you can even be at the same
state level. Doesn't matter, so it doesn't
matter from which actual visualization
you are calling this formula. It will
always be you'll be able always to be
able to call it with the same result
because you're explicitly specifying
where this calculation has to happen at
which level of granularity. The way to think
about fixed is kind of like a path on
your hard drive you know? So if you're if
you're familiar with program programming
then you can or basically any type of
computer work you can always specify a
relative or absolute path right? So
include, exclude are relative paths so
say your on folder x include means go into
a subfolder and find something in the
sub folder so going to make the
increase the granularity. Exclude means
going to the parent folder of the
current from your current location where
is fixed is the absolute path. You don't
fix doesn't mind where you are now your
folder X or folder Y, you're in the
parent folder or the child folder.
Doesn't matter, if it fixes like
specifying absolute path to your folder
where you want to find something. That's
kind of a very simplistic type of
analogy but it does drive the point home.
Alright so those are the three types of
level of detailed calculations and now
that we've done three, we can't wait to get
into the practical side and I look
forward to see you next time.
Until then, happy analyzing.