Welcome back to the Advanced Course and
today we're talking about combining set.
So in order to combine this obviously we
have to have more than one set and let's
go ahead and create another set.
Now remember that in order to be able to
combine two sets they have to be based
on the same dimension. So because our
first set is based on the ID dimension,
our second set is also going to have to
be based on this ID dimension. And we
already have a set that shows the high
shows us the high revenue companies.
Let's create a set that shows us the low
expense companies. Same thing as last
time, right click the ID dimension then
select create set and once against like
use all here and in condition we want to
say expenses but 2015 expenses be
careful of that doesn't matter which
aggregation we use because we are
working at the most granular level here
and and we want to say expenses are less
than a certain cutoff point and we can
see that our how our expenses range
actually you can see the range of values
here. There is a very convenient way you just
click load and it'll tell you the range
of values right away and let's say you
want to cut it off at under 5,000. No, 5
million and click ok. So once again we
didn't give it a name,
let's give it a name will say low
expenses, click ok. So there is our a new
set and now we want to let's just see
how it works by itself. So instead of
this set let's put the new set in here
and as you can see those are low
expenses.
Alright that's good, so but now we want
to see the companies that have low
expenses and also have a high revenue.
How do we do that? Well obviously we need
to create a set that combines the two
and when we combine two dynamic sets we
get a dynamic set in return.
Let's see how we can combine sets,
select one of the sets that you want to
combine right-click it and select create
combined set. Now let's give it a name
right away we want to call it target
quadrant because as you'll see
combining sets will break up our visual
into quadrants and the quadrant that we
want is the high revenue low expenses. So
let's select the other set that we want
to combine with, low expenses. As you can
see, we can only select from the assets
that are based on the same ID same
dimension. So we only have two of those
sets low expenses and top startups by
growth. We cannot select from the other
sets because they're based on other
dimensions. So we select low expenses and
here you have a few ways of combining
sets so first one is all members in both
sets that basically it's very very
simple to understand them they've got
pictures over here and we'll look for
the road through them just now. So let's
just click OK for now and let's replace
what we have here with target quadrant
and so as you can see we've combined the
high revenue companies with the low
expense companies and we haven't got an
intersect of them, we got like a union so
we're looking at any company which has
low expenses or has high revenue.
Let's go ahead and modify our set,
target quadrant and we click edit set
and here we can change it. So let's say
if we want that's what happens if we
look at this one
apply so that's basically all companies
that have high revenue but don't have
low expense, so we've excluded the
companies with the low expenses and if
we select this then we're looking at the
companies that have low expenses but
don't have high revenue but the one we
actually want is the ones only the ones
that are in both sets so high revenue
and low expenses.
We're going to click apply that's the quadrant
we get that's how you combine sets very
powerful feature the only thing that we
might want to change here is the
representation.
Normally, it's best practice for the
quadrant that you want to be in the top
right
and in order to achieve that result what
we're going to do is we're going to flip
this chart we're going to flip this axis
so if you right-click on the axis and
click edit axis, and then over here by
the way this is a hack Tableau hack, so
let's put a star here. Let's click
reverse and let's click ok. So simple as
that so now you axis goes has the
lowest value at the top then goes
downwards and which makes sense right so
expenses are actually negative even
though they don't have minus signs
it's a it's good practice to show that
as you go deeper down expenses are
getting greater so that means the best
companies are at the top it's like it's
like this is the cream on top of the
milk and the rest companies are heavy
because their expenses are high.
Another thing that we might want to do
here is to make this look a bit prettier.
We might want to go to format font and
let's give it our favorite font of 12 and
bold so that we can see everything are
really nice in here.
Ok so that's that don't forget to save
your worksheet workbook by pressing control
S or select where you want to save it.
That is how we combine sets. In the next
tutorial, we're going to talk about
another cool feature which is using
parameters to control sets and that's
really going to be a fun tutorial and I
look forward to see you next time.
Until then, happy analyzing!
I