Welcome back to the advanced course in
Tableau! Today, we will learn a new and
very important skill, we will learn how to
write our own table calculations and by
right i mean create formulas for our own
table calculations but before we do, it
has just occurred to me that I still
have not explained these gaps in our
visuals. You're probably sitting there
wondering when is Kirill going to
explain why we have gaps in our
visualization? What do they mean? Well
let's talk about that quickly for a
couple seconds, so what is going on here?
Well, you can see that this machine
doesn't have any gaps. This machine
doesn't have any gaps either and this is
because these machines are rl1 and rl2
they're reclaimers. So reclaimer one,
reclaimer two. All they do is always
they collect call and then they send it
off to the ship's whereas these machines
over here these are srs, sr1 4a and 6, SR
stands for stacker reclaimer and as we
were told in the assignment, sometimes
stackers are as told to stack whole
sometimes stackers are called told to
reclaim call. So basically what this
means is that this machine for the
start, from the start of the month
all the way up until somewhere around 13th
of September it was reclaiming call and
then it was told to go and stack coal, so
it was put on a different job and that's
why we don't have any data because
in our analysis were only analyzing the
utilization of reclaimers and then once
again it returned back to being a
reclaimer. Same thing happened here
it was so this machine was stacking cold
and was reclaiming called it was stacking
coal again those are reclaiming coal and that
is basically how you explain these gaps
and the why they're here and also why this
indicator is here. It has 312 null values,
that is exactly the reason that we don't
have any data for these machines for
those times. So we can now get rid of
this indicator all you have to do
is right click and click hide indicator
so that it is not bothering us anymore.
Okay, so that's great let's say this
worksheet and we'll call it analysis and
so what we have here is that sheet we
don't need anymore let's go ahead and
delete the sheet we don't need this
sheet anymore as well so let's go ahead
and delete that and now let's do some
more testing on our table calculations
so we learn how to create and write our
own table calculations. Very very
powerful skill to have
so right click that and click duplicate
sheets so we can have a copy of it and
we'll just rename this to table calyx
testing two. Alright off we go
what do we have here? We've got our table
calculation at the bottom we've got it here
so let's open it up.
This is a quick table calculation and we've
learned a lot and I mean like a lot a
lot about quick Tableau calculations. We
know how to create them, we know how to
work with them over here, we know how to
select which computation method we want
to use but now the time has come to
actually start writing this calculate
table calculations ourself to start
creating formulas for them. So we've
already started talking about table
calculation formulas and that was when
we looked at this table calculation that
we've saved over here as you can see the
formula was created for us is quite
complex but not worry we're going to
start small we're going to perform baby
steps to get to things like this and
let's create our very first table
calculation. So we're going to start from
scratch
we're going to right-click and will say
create calculated field and here we will
call it let's call it my first table
calculation and here what you want to do
is in the drop-down you want to select
formulas relating to table calculations
so that kind of limits the formulas are
looking at it's very convenient that way
and here they are. So let we're gonna
go through them in this tutorial and
understand the groups of formulas that
you have here and is the top ones are
very easy to start with they are
actually the simpler one so let's go
ahead and start
them. So what we want to do here is we
want to use this formula which is first
and what it does is return the number of
rows from the current role to the first
row in the partition let's go ahead and
just put this formula in here just say
first brackets and nothing else and as
you can see this options up, came up
here and it will allow you to specify
the direction of computation by default
it will normally be automatic so it will
normally go fall back to across and
let's see how that works out so I'll
click ok and we'll take this my first
table calculation and we'll replace it over
here and will also replace it over here
by holding down control. So what you can
see now is 0-1 minus 2 minus 3 minus 4
minus 5 and so on.
What is that? Well it is basically
telling us if this is the first bar
how far away is the every second bar
every next bar so let's go ahead back in
the table calculation. So if we click on
this formula it'll bring up the formula
and says returns a number of rows from
the current row to the first row in the
partition and here it even gives you an
example so as you can see it's negative
and that is because this is the top row
and as you go down through the table,  you
going further away from that row and
therefore that Tableau just works that way
that it's concerning them negative. Alright, let's
fix this up and change table calculation and
it's quite handy that the table
calculations already in there for us.
Let's see what happens with that as well.
So we're going to select Tableau
calculations and let's say index returns
the index of the current row in the
partition that's great let's put this in
here.
Okay, click apply alright so you see that
this time the table calculation has been
adjusted for us as I said you might want
to just drag it in here but if you see
that it has been adjusted for you then
there's no need to do that. So here it's
telling you the index which makes sense
right first second third and so on
let's go ahead and
click edit again index what else do we
have here. Table calculations last.
Well, it's kind of like first so there's
no point in doing that just just
calculates how much to the last row.
Lookup returns the value of the given
expression in the target row specified
as a relative offset from the current
row or you can use first and last to
specify an offset from first and last.
That's interesting let's look at look
up because as you remember lookup was
used you know idle capacity percent
calculation. Let's type it in here
look up and we want, what expression do we
want? Well let's say some of tons and
then we want offset let's say two. So two
bars away from the current one and we'll
click apply and click okay. So what is this
showing us? It's showing us the sum for
tons for two bars away from our
current bar. So there's our current bar
or that that's where we are now and now
two bars away would mean going to the
right going to this bar. So there you go
seven to eight seven to eight and for
this bar it's that bar for this bar it's
that bar and for this bar it's already
that bar. So it's two bars to the right.
That's good so as you can see the whole
chart kind of shifted to the left a
little bit. Right? So it would like from
this chart to this chart shift it to the
left by two bars.
Alright, great and that's now you can see
why the table calculations because you
are referring to rows and all these bars
actually represent rows.
So you're referring to
different rows from this row you're
able to call information from this row
from this row from row number four from
day number 4 you're able to call
information for a day number six which
is a separate row in this aggregated
table. So now if we go back to our table
calculation. We'll click Edit and let's look
at another one where our table
calculations.
Alright, so we did look up previous value
so it's pretty much just look at the
previous value nothing nothing special
there. Rank, so rank is also quick table
calculation you can find it there
it will tell you how this result. How this
specific row or row in your
aggregated table. Remember that table
calculations always remember this a
table calculations are working or being
calculated on an aggregated level. So
once your data has been aggregated
for this view then only the table
calculations are applied after that. So,
basically what rank will tell you how
does your aggregated row rank among all
other rows that you want to search among?
But we're not gonna go about talk about
rank right now running average these are
good ones. So running average, I never
understood that. Let's start with running
running a sum, right? So running sum, you
should be familiar of running sum
running some there it is. So running sum
of some tons right or and remember is so
if I specify just tons here, what am I
going to get? I'm going to get an error
why is that? Well because you can't say
running sum of tons is not being
calculated at the level of the data it's
not being calculated every single row
is having a data, is being calculated
at this aggregated level so at this new
table which is an aggregated table and
in order the aggregated table doesn't
have tons. The aggregated table only has
aggregate values and aggregated valves
are like some of tons, so let's let's
let's drive this point home. This sum of
tons is what you see here right?
So there you go, those are sum of tons.
Now you want to apply a table
calculation to those sums of tons right?
So on top of your aggregated table.
That's very important to understand,
that's how table calculations work. So I
want the running sum, sum of tons
click ok and this is exactly what we saw
previously remember when we did an area
chart feels like so long ago doesn't it?
We've learned so much and had so many
tutorials but that isn't that is a good
thing that means that we're going we're
being very thorough with these table
calculations and by the end of this
section you know pretty much everything
or at least eighty percent of what there
is to know about table calculations.
Alright, so we basically recreated the
quick table calculations for
running total and that was as simple as
using one for now. So let's go back into
our oops, wrong one.
There is my first table calculation, edit,
ok running sum what are the table
calculations that we have? Oh I promise to
talk a little bit about running average,
never understood that like why would you
want a running average like a moving
average is one thing or moving
average
where was it? We'll get to it in a second
but a running average, the way it's
defined here is in Tableau is returns are
running average of the given expression
for the first row in the program from
the first row in position to the current
also you can't control where it starts.
It will always start at the first row so
all these running functions they start
at the first row and up to the control.
So i'll show you the running average
just just for fun.
You'll see what it what it looks like so
click OK and always we talked averages
of representatives as line. This average it
because the further you go the more rows
that it includes right? So from here, we'll
include all of those rows from here
include all those rows from here we
could all rows. As you go further down,
its kind of stabilizes so all of these
if you even get bars that are like out
of the norm,
they won't they'll have less and less
impact as you go to the right.
Very rare you would apply something like
this. It has very limited scope of
applications.
Maybe in some specific kind of research
or specific industry task where you know
you're running average, otherwise it's
not something that you would be using
very often.
Alright let's go back in here my first
table calculation, so that's the running
average what else do we have running
average running count so runnings make
sense right?
Running counts basic accounting records
up to the current one that's probably a
good one to have a look at what I did
there is I double-clicked it.
There we go so that's better, so if you
that good
okay I think I lost I have an extra one
there extra racket, so running count is
basically number of records as it
increases. Alright so we're done with the
running ones. Let's move on to something
more interesting.
So script pool, we won't be talking about
this but all the ones that start with
script they're basically that allow you
to integrate R with Tableau. There's a
few more steps that you have to take
conduct, you have to load up a package
and R, you have to execute it like like
you have to set up your computer or your
server for in order to be able to work
with Tableau with R. But we're not going
to be worried about that right? Now we're
just going to continue of the rest
size so tell you how many rows they are
in your partition so it doesn't really
matter. So total, it gives you the total
so it kind of gives you the total for
all everything that you see so if we say
here total and we click OK you'll see
that the number is always the same
because it is it's just a total you can
you can just visualize it as one number.
Its total of this sum, so it's basically
the sum all this sum and it is 25
million tons in this case and alright,
so now let's move on to the
finally the fun ones at the end table
calculation.
Alright so here you see window and
window is often misinterpreted. Window
doesn't mean so let's let's look at one
let's look at window average right? Let's
replace this with window average, what is
window average do? Where is it?
There it is, so returns the average of the
expression within the window and window
is often confused and I was guilty of
this myself. When I was first starting with
Tableau, it's not the window that you're
looking at. It's not this window of
Tableau. It's not the window of your tab.
It's actually the window that you
specify so it's it's kind of like an
interval or a subset of your
rows that you want to work with. That's
all it says, so window is a subset overall.
So the window is defined as an offset
from the current row or you can offset
from the first and last rows. It started
and omitted the entire petition is just.
So let's say we want the window average
and let's say we don't want a window.
We'll just say the whole partition if you
leave it like this what will happen is
it will calculate the average for the
whole partition as you can see the
values same for every single bar. It is
847,625. So it's the average of the sums
or the average of the values you see
here. Now let's go ahead and change it
again and it's alright so window average
but now let's say I want the average for
a certain number of all bars relative to
the current bar. So sum tons minus 20, so
let's use the same example they have
here. So minus two is where I want to
start to two bars to the left of the
current one or two rows before the
current one and I want to end at the
final row so the current one so that
internals three rows 2 to the left and
then include the current one, click ok
and what does that remind us of. That
reminds us a lot of the moving average,
because it is the moving average. So what
are we doing here, we saying what is the
average for the window which is
construction of these three bars? So 520
plus 515 plus 518, if you take the
average of those three you'll get
517,661 and you you can check that on your
calculator if you like and then what is
going on in the next one over here, what
is that? That is the average for this
window. You see that's that's called a
window then this one is average for two
to the left and the current one for this
window.
This is average for this window and that
is how a moving average works and that
is why it's called a moving average
because as you move through your
data set as you move through your
timeline it moves with you, so let me go
ahead and change that quickly so if I
want to change this from let's say I
don't want to get to be a minus 2
anymore I wanted to be a minus 7, so 7
bars to the left and then include the
current bar as well.
What is that doing? So let's take this
one for example what it's saying is take
this current bar and seven bars left
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 so if you take seven bars and
include this one that is your window and
that 728,520 is the average for those
bars or for those rows. Now if I take
this one or let's say this one then the
window for this one is these eight bars
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 and the value here is 728,949.
So as you can see, as you move along your
window moves with you. You move window
keeps moving and that's why it's called
a moving average. So average of those
gets goes over there, average of those
goes over there and you can you also
have a moving average here in your table
calculations. So edit table calculation
or basically if you want to add we can't
edit that one. If you want to add it,
table calculation, quick table
calculation you, you do have a moving
average here but we did right now is we
recreated the table calculation.
Ok so this has been a very long tutorial.
We're getting to the end of it.
Those are table calculation functions. I
hope this is useful and now you know how
to create basic table calculations are
right formulas for them.
What we'll do in the next tutorial is we
will finally start applying all these
skills and knowledge we've learned to
our visualization to resolve the
challenge to find the answer to the
question that has been posted and I look
forward to seeing you in the next
tutorial.
Until then, happy Analyzing.