Welcome back to the advanced course on
Tableau. This is Kirill Eremenko and
today we continue with our section on
Tableau calculations. In the previous
tutorial we talked about the different
table calculations that you can create
yourself using the formula's provided
in Tableau and this is the table
calculation for a moving average which
we talked about in the previous tutorial.
So today we're going to do two things
first of all, we're going to take this
concept and we will apply it to our
analysis because that is exactly what
we're looking for. We're looking for an 8
hour moving average to help us determine
which machines need repairs and
maintenance and then we will recap on
how the moving average works just to
make sure that going forward we are all
on the same page and we fully understand
the concepts of table calculations.
Alright so let's go ahead and proceed to
our analysis tab. As you can see here
we've got the idle capacity in terms of
percentages of the nominal capacity and
we've already introduced our ten percent
line which will be our threshold to tell
whether a machine requires maintenance
or not. But this information is not
sufficient. As you can see every machine
at some point throughout the day spikes
above the ten percent threshold. So if we
were to use this chart as our criteria
then every single machine would require
service and maintenance. As the Simon's
jets the machines that require servicing
our machines where there is an
eight-hour period an eight-hour window
somewhere in this data set for that
machine where the average of what we see
here for those eight hours spikes above
the ten percent. So that means that we
need to apply a eight-hour rolling
average or moving average on top of this
data and analyze that.
So let's go ahead and apply it and then
we'll talk about it a bit more. So in
order to create this calculated field,
or this table calculation, I should say
we're going to right-click in the
measures and will create set say create
calculated field and this one will call
idle
capacity moving average. Now in Tableau
they're called if you recall if we go to
table calculations they're called window
average. It's the same thing as a moving
average as we discussed in the previous tutorial.
So lets just name ours moving
average. Now let's apply a window average,
I'll just double click on window average
here. What expression we're going to
apply to? Well we're going to apply to
this exact expression which we see here
and that is the idle capacity percent
positive. So let's type that in and now
we want to say how many bars to the left
to when to go of the current bar? How
many previous hours we want to take
before we include the current hour? We
want to include the previous seven hours
and then we want to include the current
hour as well. So in total that's eight
hours that we will be including our
calculation and that's all.
All we have to type in here and if we're
going to the default table calculation
as we discussed it's better to
explicitly specify our along which field
we want to calculate and in this case we
want to calculate across the table, so
not down but when we calculate from left
to right and that is the date-time field
and so we'll leave that as it is and
we'll just click ok and as you can see
here results are computed a long
date time click ok. So now if we take this
new calculation, we can replace the old
idle capacity percent pause with the new
calculation. So let's go ahead and do
that and there we go so right away we
can see a much better picture so what
happened here is now the results are
averaged out and instead of all this
sporadic, all these sporadic, all this
sporadic data for every single hour we
can see the average for every eight
hours in our data set and right away you
can already see some preliminary results
you can see that this machine does have
averages that spike over the 10 percent
line. This machine doesn't even though
the individual hours that spike over the
ten percent line. This one doesn't. Here we
can see some spikes but we'll talk about
these separately in a separate tutorial
these are irregularities
that appear because of the
moving average calculation and I will
show you how to deal with them in an
upcoming tutorial and this machine over
here also has an average so it does look
like it requires maintenance at this
stage. So but we'll talk about that in a
further tutorial, the purpose of this
tutorial was to show you how to apply
the moving average to our actual data
set and we've done that. As you can see
the result is completely different to
what we saw without the moving
average and now just to recap on how the
moving average works I prepared a small
two slide presentation which I'd like to
walk through to make sure that we are on
the same page in terms of how the table
calculation was performed and what steps
we took to get to this result. So let's
go ahead and proceed to that
presentation.
Ok so we started off our visualization
with a simple table like this which had
the time, the machine and the tons. I'm
going to put it on inside so we can
better visualize the chronological steps
that we took to get the final stage and
what we did to this table is we
visualized it and we visualize it by
aggregating it to a level of sum and now
of course we visualize the table at its
most highest level of granularity so we
plotted the tons for every single
machine at every single hour, so there
was no actual point in this sum. It didn't
change anything we were actually
plotting the values that we saw in our
Tableau but nevertheless this was an
important step because now for Tableau
this data has been aggregated even
though it has been aggregated to a
granularity of one. So basically that
same level of granularity as in as it is
in the data set so nothing has changed
for us for Tableau it perceives as data
as group aggregated and that means that
on top of aggregated data we can apply
table calculations. So then we applied a
table calculation which should stay the
percent difference from and we can't see
the fields that were also part of this
calculation. We can see that
nominal capacity because we hit them but
what we did is we calculated the
difference between the actual tons
processed and the normal capacity and
then divide by the nominal capacity so
basically we looked at the percent
difference from the nominal capacity,
there x minus one to invert our axis,
and so we ended up with a chart like this and
then on top of that chart because this
is still an aggregated calculation we
were able to play another table
calculation which was the window average
which we applied just now and then we
got this chart which we see in front of
us on, in Tableau now and the window
average this time was not applied
top-down, it was applied across as you
can see we have quite an interesting and
somewhat complex combination of
aggregations and Tableau calculations.
We've got an initial aggregation to the
level of sum then we've got a table
calculation that works top down or I
uses the machine field and then we got a
table calculation that works across the
table left to right or uses the daytime
field. So as you can see we're slowly
venturing into a bit more complex
calculations and an upcoming tutorials
we will actually learn how to refine our
table calculations and get rid of
irregularities using other table
calculations. So we'll build on this a
little bit more in the upcoming
tutorials and I look forward to seeing
you next time.
Until then, Happy Analyzing.