- [Kevin Bowersox] Thanks for watching this course
on Git Workflows.
Before we conclude,
I want to highlight some other topics that you might explore
and provide you with information about my other courses.
Now that you've learned about workflows
your team can use with Git,
I would recommend checking out two of my other courses
related to the topic.
The first is Git for Teams,
which will provide you with some additional strategies
your team can use to collaborate effectively with Git.
During this course,
we also touched on the need for strong automation
with a CI/CD pipeline.
If you're a Java developer,
I can teach you how to put those pipelines in place
in my LinkedIn Learning course,
Continuous Delivery for Cloud Native Java Applications.
If you just like my teaching style,
I have a few other courses on the LinkedIn Learning platform
that might interest you.
I can teach you about other topics like Microservices, APIs,
Java Collections, Spring, or GitOps if you're interested.
If you're just getting started with software development
or early in your career,
you might benefit from my latest course,
A Career in Code.
It contains strategies for advancing
within your software development career at all stages.
If you want to tag me when you post your course certificate,
I always like to interact with learners taking my courses
and enjoy reading your feedback.
Nothing makes my day brighter than when I hear from someone
who enjoyed a course.
So that's it for now.
Congratulations on finishing this course
and thanks again for taking it.
Now go put a great workflow
in place for your team and ship some code.