- [Instructor] When a team of software developers
collaborate on a project,
they need to agree on how to manage the project's code base.
This agreement, known as a workflow,
defines and standardizes how the team uses Git
to handle these common situations
that involve their source code.
So when we think about it,
teams use Git in a variety of ways.
A developer needs to move source code
related to a new feature
from their local repository into a shared repository.
From there, other developers on the team
can pull those changes
to sync their code with the shared repository,
which they'll need to do
before they begin work on a feature of their own.
A continuous integration system needs to integrate with Git
to build the latest source code for the project.
That way, it can be released to different environments,
like development or production.
Or, maybe a critical security vulnerability gets discovered.
The team might need to urgently deploy a critical hotfix.
A workflow provides all the developers on the team
with a consistent set of steps they take with Git
for these types of scenarios.
This helps the team collaborate better,
because for each scenario there's guidelines
or a recipe for what to do.
So, let's say you need to do a release.
A workflow determines which Git commands
you'll execute to perform it.
Or, maybe you need to develop a new feature.
You'll know what branch to start from
and where to merge your changes when you finish
since it's defined by the workflow.
So, you'll always know exactly what to do with Git,
and your teammates will understand what you're doing
because it's all agreed upon ahead of time,
so they'll know what to expect.
Having a defined Git workflow is essential for your team
to collaborate effectively on your code base.
It will make the flow of changes within your project
predictable and easy to understand for all team members,
which will help improve your team's development process
and overall velocity.
At the same time,
you'll avoid frustrating situations
that can arise from mismanaging your code.
Git's incredibly flexible.
It's really easy to create new branches,
and it provides us with advanced features
like tagging and rebasing.
So, your team could create a very customized workflow,
but before you go that route,
you should consider using
some of the established Git workflows
that are available to you.
They've been used by teams for years,
and are proven to improve your development process.
We'll be exploring them throughout the course,
but first we need to talk about the basic building blocks
used to create these workflows.
Let's start there in our next lesson.