- [Instructor] There are several elements
that work together to form a Git workflow.
Let's take a look at these building blocks
so that you're familiar with them.
The goal of a Git workflow is to make it easier
for teams to collaborate on a software development project.
So every Git workflow needs a shared repository
where the developers on a team can pull
the latest code base from or push their latest changes to.
This shared repository is normally hosted
on a repository manager like GitHub
that's used by the entire organization.
The organization might choose to use
a cloud-hosted repository manager
or they might run it on premise.
But regardless of where it's hosted,
it's the place where team members interact
with their team's shared repository.
When developers need to work on the code base,
they'll pull the code from this shared repository into
their local repository, which lives on their workstation.
It's their own local copy of the repository
that generally mirrors the code found
in the remote shared repository.
Here, in this local repository,
the developer will commit their source code changes
as they work to implement a new feature or resolve a bug.
Within these repositories, branches are created
and maintained to track different lines of development.
These branches typically fall into two categories.
The first are long-lived branches.
These remain open and are used
throughout the development of a project.
Long-lived branches are typically set up to store code
that's at different phases of development.
For example, the main branch is often used by teams
to store the stable code for a project.
It should always be in a working state, and often it holds
the latest code that has been released to production.
Develop is another long-lived branch that teams might use.
It's created by branching off of the main branch
and then used by teams to integrate the next version
of the code they plan to release.
So it's where the team merges all of their work in progress.
That brings us to short-lived branches.
These are branches that exist only for a short
period of time, which typically corresponds
with the development of a new feature or,
in special circumstances, the fix of a major issue.
The most common type of short-lived branch
is known as a feature branch.
As the name implies, a feature branch is created
when you need to begin development of a new feature.
As changes are made for the feature,
they're committed to the feature branch,
which is then merged back into another branch
and deleted once the feature is complete.
A hotfix is another type of feature branch
that is branched from the main branch
to quickly fix a critical issue.
We'll dive into the details of how it works later.
For now, just know it's another type of feature branch.
So those are the major building blocks you'll find
in most Git workflows.
When executing a Git workflow, you'll also use Git commands
like commit, fetch, merge, push, and pull to move
code changes between these branches and repositories.
You'll also be creating and approving pull requests
within most Git workflows.
It's a feature that's provided by most repository managers
that isn't native to Git.
A pull request allows other members of your team
to review your work before it's approved to be merged
into a branch on the shared repository.
So that's a quick overview of the parts and pieces
that make up a Git workflow.
Each specific workflow will describe what branches
should be established and how your code changes
will flow between them.