- [Instructor] Let's set up our shared repository on GitHub
to support the Gitflow workflow.
At the moment, the repository has one long-lived branch,
Main, and that's going to contain
a copy of our production code.
Now Gitflow requires two long-lived branches,
develop and main,
so we'll need to create the develop branch
so that developers can branch
their feature branches off of it
when following the workflow.
To create the branch,
just click in this text box and type the name develop.
That will be our branch name.
Then we'll click on this button
in order to create the branch.
Alright, there you can see it's created.
And now we have the two long-lived branches
that are required for Gitflow.
In Gitflow, these are very important branches,
especially main,
which contains the copy of our production code
that the GitHub action publishes the website from.
To protect them from being accidentally modified,
let's configure some rules on these branches within GitHub.
To do that, we'll click on the Settings tab,
and then on the sidebar,
you'll see the Branches option.
Click on that,
and then you'll notice
that we can apply branch protection rules
on the branches within our repository.
So let's click on Add Rule to get started.
The first thing we'll need to do
is provide the name of the branch we'd like to protect.
In this case, it's going to be main.
Now there's a lot of rules that we can apply,
but we're going to keep it simple
and we'll check this option
to always require a pull request before merging.
That way other members of the team
get the opportunity to review code changes
before they're merged into the main branch.
Now you'll notice it selects this option
to require approvals.
This is a good feature to put in place,
but since we're working by ourselves in the course,
we're going to go ahead and uncheck it.
Okay, now that we have our rule configured,
let's scroll down to the bottom
and click on the Create button
to put it in place on the branch.
We will need to authenticate
in order to have the rule put into effect.
Okay, so that's our first rule on the main branch.
We'll also need to put this in place on the develop branch.
So I'll just click on the Add rule button once again
and then I'll type the name develop here
and then click the option
to require a pull request before merging
and then uncheck the require approvals option.
And then I'll go ahead and create the rule.
Okay, that completes the configuration
of our shared repository for Gitflow.
And we can now safely do some development work
on new features.