- [Instructor] When practicing trunk based development,
the work for a larger feature
may be broken down into smaller pieces
that you're frequently merging into trunk.
For some features, this can mean
that parts of its code are merged into trunk
while other parts are still under development.
So those completed parts of a feature
that are merged into trunk
might get shipped to production in the next release
regardless of whether the entire feature is ready.
That might raise some concerns for you,
but a technique called feature flagging
makes it easy to handle this situation.
Let me explain how it works.
A feature flag is used to toggle
the availability of a feature in our software.
It allows us to deploy code
without making it visible to the end users,
or, if we'd like, we can choose to make the feature
available under certain conditions.
Let me give you an example.
Let's say you're working on an eCommerce website
and you've built a new filter
for the site's product catalog.
You might create a feature flag for the new filter
that allows you to toggle
whether or not the feature is displayed on the site.
While testing the feature,
you can toggle the flag on for non-production environments,
like development, to make it available
for the team to test and review.
However, in the production environment,
you might toggle the flag off
because it hasn't been thoroughly tested
and ready for use by the actual customers.
So, the feature would be in the production code,
but it hasn't been released for the customers.
Then, once the feature is ready,
you can just toggle the feature flags
so that the new filter becomes available for your customers.
When using feature flags, we draw a clear distinction
between a deployment and a release.
A deployment moves the code for a feature to an environment,
but doesn't necessarily make it available for the end users.
A release is when the actual feature is made available
which, in this case, is achieved
by activating our feature flag.
When using feature flags,
there's a number of strategies to choose from.
You can simply toggle the feature on and off
just like we discussed.
That's one strategy.
Another is to selectively choose certain users
or a percentage of them
that the new feature will be released to.
This approach lets you test out the new feature
with a small batch of users
to determine if it should be released more widely.
If the feature doesn't test well,
it can easily be turned off using our feature flag.
You might hear of this strategy
referred to as a dark launch.
It's used by companies like Facebook
to strategically ship an experiment with new features.
Implementing feature flagging can be as simple
as adding an if statement
and a configuration value in your project.
But, to get the most from feature flags,
you'll want to use a platform
that is specifically designed to manage them.
You'll find number of feature flagging platforms
that you can use like LaunchDarkly
or the open source alternative, Flagship.
These tools normally provide an SDK
that you can use to add the feature flag to your code
and a management console
where you can control the feature flag
from a user interface.
In our next lesson, we'll walk through a demonstration
of how feature flagging can be applied
to our small static website using LaunchDarkly.
If you'd like to follow along,
you'll need to create a free trial account
at launchdarkly.com, or, if you'd like,
you can just watch the lesson
to see how the concept of feature flagging works.