- [Instructor] Our website is kind of empty,
so let's work on a new feature
that will add some content to the site.
This will give us a chance
to see what the workflow looks like
for routine development work with Gitflow.
To get started, we'll need to clone our shared repository
to our local workstation
where we'll do the work in a feature branch.
To perform the clone,
we can click on the Code button within GitHub,
and here you'll see two URLs,
one for HTTPS and one for SSH.
You can choose either of these.
I'm going to use SSH.
Once we've copied that URL to the repository,
we can take that over to a Git Bash shell.
And here I'm going to paste that URL
after the git clone command.
And then once I execute the command,
the repository will be copied on my local workstation.
Now let's go ahead and we'll navigate into the repository,
and here we can start to create our feature branch.
Now the feature branch
is where we'll do our development work,
but you'll recall that it needs to be branched
from the develop branch
where the team stores its work for the next release.
So the first thing we'll need to do
is create a local develop branch
that tracks the develop branch on the shared repository.
Okay, we have that in place,
now we can go ahead and create our feature branch.
When naming a feature branch,
I like to prefix it with the word feature,
followed by my initials.
This helps if multiple developers are working
on the same repository
because you can sort by branch name
and it's going to group all of your branches together.
After my initials, I like to add a ticket number.
Now we're not working with a workload tracking system,
so I'm just going to make one up here, 123.
And then finally, to end the branch name,
I like to add a small description
about what I'm working on.
So let's just call this site-content.
All right, we can create our new feature branch,
and now we're ready to do some development.
So I'm going to hop up a directory.
And then here, I'm going to use Visual Studio Code
to open the folder containing our repository.
You can use any editor here
as long as you're able to make some small changes
to the files in the folder.
All right, inside Visual Studio Code,
we'll see our index.md file,
and there's the markup that we added to it.
Now within this file, we're going to embed a link
to a course on LinkedIn learning.
I'm going to use one of my courses,
but you can choose any course within the platform.
It's really easy. Let me show you.
All you need to do is navigate to the course of your choice
and then click on the Share button,
and you'll see this option for Embed.
This is going to allow you to copy some markup.
And if we take that over to our editor
and paste it within the file,
it's going to embed a video for the course on your page.
All right, with that in place,
let's go ahead and we'll save the file,
and then we're going to navigate back
to a Git Bash terminal.
Inside of this terminal,
I'm going to navigate back into our repository's folder.
And then here,
I'm going to stage the changes that we just made,
and then I'll commit them to the local repository
on our feature branch.
We'll just say that we added content to the site.
And now we're ready to push our local feature branch
to the shared repository.
To do that, we'll use the git push command,
followed by the origin,
so this is the shared repository over on GitHub.
And then we need to provide the name
of the branch that we're pushing,
so I'll type in the branch name
that we created for the feature branch.
And then we're going to add the -u flag.
This will set up tracking between our local feature branch
and the branch on the shared repository.
All right, let's go ahead and we'll perform the push.
And now we should find that feature branch over on GitHub,
so let's go check it out.
Over on GitHub, you can see that it's already picked up
on our new feature branch.
Let's navigate into the branches
for the repository to check it out.
So there we can see our main branch,
as well as our feature branch and our develop branch.
Let's create a pull request
that will merge our feature branch into the develop branch
where the team is storing its work for the next release.
To do that, we can click on the Pull request tab,
and then we can create a new pull request
by clicking on this button.
In order to create the pull request,
we'll need to indicate the branch
that we would like to merge into,
in this case, it's going to be develop,
and the branch that we would like to merge into develop,
which will be our feature branch.
All right, once we've selected those branches,
we can click on Create pull request,
and now we can provide some additional information
about our pull request.
Here I'm just going to add a description
that says, "We're adding content to the site."
Once I've done that,
I can go ahead and click on Create pull request,
and that will create the pull request
for other members on the team to review and approve.
Now we're working by ourselves,
so I'm just going to perform the merge myself
by clicking on this button to merge the pull request.
We'll then have to confirm the merge.
And once we do that, we'll have merged our changes
from the feature branch into the develop branch
where the team's shared work resides.
You'll also notice that we get the option
to delete our feature branch.
If you know that you're not going to be doing any more work,
it's always good to clean these up,
so I'm going to go ahead and delete that branch.
So that's the development workflow for Gitflow,
which is based on a feature branching strategy.
Let's move on from here
to look at how we can release these changes
in our next lesson.