- [Instructor] Throughout the rest of the course,
we're going to explore some popular Git workflows.
Some of these workflows will work better than others
in certain scenarios.
So you might be wondering how you'll know which workflow
is best for your team.
Well, it depends on a few characteristics of your team
and its development process.
So let's talk through them.
The first thing to consider is the size of the team
working on the code base, which in many cases is correlated
with the size of the project.
In a smaller team, it's easy to keep track
of what everyone else might be working on
simply because there's less people
and fewer lines of communication between team members.
So in general, smaller teams can benefit
from more streamlined workflows
that use less branching or perhaps no branching at all.
But as a team grows,
the number of lines of communication increase drastically,
and it's impossible to keep track
of what everybody else is up to.
For these teams, branching and pull requests
become essential features of their workflow
that help facilitate communication
that might not occur without them.
You'll also need to consider how frequently
your team ships code.
This is known as its release cadence.
Teams with a slower release cadence might deploy their code
on a monthly or quarterly basis.
So for them,
having more long-lived branches might be acceptable.
For teams that release daily or even several times per day,
having long-lived branches can be a problem
because there isn't as much time
to track what a particular branch contains,
and it can lead to merge conflicts.
Finally, you'll also need to factor in how much automation
is built into your delivery process.
More streamlined workflows depend heavily upon automation
and advanced CI/CD pipelines
that can safely build, verify, and deploy your software.
If you don't have these in place,
you're likely to encounter more issues
if you choose to adopt a workflow
that's designed to rapidly release new changes.
These are some of the general considerations
for choosing a workflow,
but each project will be a little unique in its own way.
So make sure you consider situational factors
when selecting a workflow, and don't be afraid to pivot
if something just isn't working.