- [Instructor] Throughout the course,
we'll be stepping through a number of workflows,
just like you would in the workplace.
To make it more realistic,
we're going to create a shared repository on GitHub
to mimic the shared repository
that your team would use for a project.
So let's walk through the setup of this repository
so that we can use it in our lessons.
Once you're logged into your GitHub account,
navigate to this dropdown below your profile picture
and click on Your repositories.
Here, we'll click on the green New button
to create the new repository for the course.
For this repository, we're going to use a neat feature
of GitHub called GitHub Pages.
It allows you to host static websites from a repository
right on GitHub using a tool called Jekyll.
By using GitHub pages,
we'll be able to visualize the changes that are made
within a branch on our shared repository,
which we'll consider the production ready branch.
To get started with GitHub Pages,
you'll need to give your repository a special name
when you create it.
It needs to be your GitHub username, then .github.io.
So I'm going to enter the name of my user,
then .github.io.
All right, once I have that in place,
I can scroll down to the bottom of the page
and create the repository.
So right now our repository is empty.
Let's go ahead and we can add a new file to the repository.
That way there's something in it.
We're going to name this new file index.md.
It's going to be a markdown file
that's used for the homepage of the site.
In the contents of the file,
I'm just going to add an h1 tag,
and here, I'm going to add the header,
Great LinkedIn Learning Courses.
Okay, so now we have some content on our site's homepage.
Let's scroll down
and we can commit those changes to the file.
All right, now we have a single file within our repository.
At this point, we can go ahead
and publish our GitHub page.
To do that, we need to adjust some settings.
So I'll click on the Settings tab,
and then on the left hand sidebar,
I'm going to click on Pages.
Here, you'll see that the main branch has been selected
as the branch to build our GitHub page from.
That's exactly what we want.
Let's go ahead and we'll click on this button
to add a theme for our site.
Here I'm going to choose the Slate theme.
So this will just add some styling to the site.
Once I've selected Slate,
I can click on this button to select the theme,
and now we're ready for our GitHub page to be published.
We can see that by clicking on the Actions tab,
and you'll notice that GitHub has created actions
that will build and deploy our page.
We can see them here, and they're already in progress.
Let's go ahead and we'll click on this action.
And you'll notice the build has completed
and the page has been deployed.
And down here's the link to the actual page.
This pipeline will be triggered
each time we publish new code to our main branch,
which will cause the page to be updated.
Let's go ahead and we'll click on the link
to our new page to take a look.
Excellent. So now we have our new site.
Throughout the remainder of the course,
we'll be working with this shared repository on GitHub
and a clone of it on our local repository.
These two repositories will help us simulate
the workflows we'll cover throughout the course.
Let's move on to the next chapter to see our first workflow.