[Autogenerated] Okay, let's begin discussing CLOUDFRONT.
Now.
For those who don't know, let's have a quick review.
Cloudfront is a global cdn offered by a ws for delivering
content faster via regional edge locations.
So it works together with our origins,
which will see here in a little bit to deliver
content at a faster rate via cashing.
Another neat factor is that it integrates with Route
53 seamlessly so we can use D.
N s resolution globally to hit our cloudfront distributions.
And then it also offers different cashing behaviors
and types such as Web in our MTP,
depending on the use case for your particular origin that you need,
and we'll look at both of these here in the upcoming clips.
Now let's go ahead and discuss cloudfront edge locations.
Now the back end of Cloudfront is what's called origins.
So origins are the content that we're trying to serve up to our
cdn that we have in place for people to hit.
You can see we have examples here on the right of a V B C with
a load balancer in some E c two instances,
and that's a single origin,
or we can even have a simple origin of a static site with an S three
bucket that holds contents for the clients to pull down.
Now,
another key factor here is that CLOUDFRONT is made up of
those edge locations that we talked about.
And these edge locations pictured here are going to allow
us to cash content locally in a location that's closer to
the client making the request.
So, for instance,
thehe mia applying here on the left up top is making a call to some D.
N s name.
It redirects them seamlessly to the nearest edge location,
and then they hit are streaming distribution that we have
with our ale B and E C two instances.
Now, if that bottom client made the same call,
it would hit the edge location that we see here.
And in this example, it's hitting a download distribution,
which we'll talk about, and it's just pulling that static site and contents.
But each of these edge locations are geographically close
to the client that's making the request.
It speeds up any cashing processing that needs to be done.
Now the A pack client on the bottom could also hit this streaming distribution
up top it would just go through a different edge location,
the one we see down here at the bottom.
So it would make it request to the same D.
N s.
Except for this time after the edge.
It would point it to our streaming distribution and hit that origin.
So there's a lot of configurations that go on here.
And don't worry,
we'll go ahead and walk through setting these up here in the upcoming clips.
I just want to give you a general overview of the
infrastructure and how it's architected.
Now, the next big use cases cloudfront restrictive access.
So this is a common scenario on exams within a W s where you
might be asked to go ahead and lock down access toe s three
buckets via cloudfront on Lee.
Now, this allows for several security benefits,
such as signed your l's and authenticated requests.
And what you do is you define an origin access identity, also known as an O A.
I.
And you assign that away i to a cloudfront distribution that is
permitted access to access s three objects.
So the permissions on the S three bucket are allowing on Lee this.
Oh aye, Aye, over here in the middle to access the objects in the bucket.
So if we have a client trained, directly access the S three objects,
it gets tonight because it's not coming through our cloudfront
distribution in our origin access identity.
Now let's go ahead and move on to some demos.
Now the first thing we're going to do is we're going to
create a cloudfront distribution.
We need to see how it works and what we need to do at a
bare minimum to get this stood up.
And then we'll look at setting up an origin access identity
for restricting s3 access to cloudfront.
We'll even look at some signed your l's as well as we go through there.
So let's go ahead,
will end here and then in the next clip will pick up in
the Consul and we'll start playing around with Cloudfront so we can see how it works.