[Autogenerated] Okay,
let's dive into creating a cloudfront distribution within AWS.
Now.
We just had a brief overview and a review for what Cloudfront is.
Let's just walk through creating a distribution,
some at the distribution page, which is the default dashboard for cloudfront.
And what I want to do is I'm gonna click on Create,
and that gives us our two delivery methods.
So if you recall back in the slides,
we talked about the two different types being Web in our TMP.
Now Webb is for any typical traffic, like a static site,
or if you're redirecting files via https,
then that's what you're gonna want to use.
You can see that you have to store your files in an origin.
What's well, look at here in a minute,
and that could be a bucket or a Web server,
depending on your application.
And we'll actually look at both here in the upcoming clips.
Now the other option is our TMP,
and this is strictly for streaming media files via Adobe.
So it's important to understand that this is a very
specific type of delivery method,
and a caveat for this is you have to store all of your
files in an Amazon s three bucket.
That's the Onley origin that you can have.
Now, this is a very popular test question for A W s.
So really get comfortable knowing the differences between
the two cloudfront distribution types.
So for this, I'll click on Web, and that brings us to our create screen.
Now the first thing we have is our origin domain name.
And this is essentially the origin of the data that we
want to set up cloudfront in front of.
So you can see here this is a list of all my s three buckets that I have
in my account And what I'll do is I went ahead and stood up a simple
static site in my Andrew es ist dot me bucket.
And before we continue,
let's just take a look at S three so I can show you what I've done here.
So when I go to my s three buckets, we see I have my Andrew s.
Is that me domain here?
And this is my bucket name and you'll see that it's publicly accessible.
Now,
what I did here is I stood up a static site that lives within my
s three bucket and under our bucket policy.
You see, we're allowing anyone to get objects within this bucket.
So if I go back here and they go to properties,
I go to static Web site and I go to this in point,
we'll get our static site.
Now.
I edited this simple site so we can show the origin that this is coming from.
So in this case were saying, Hey,
these files are from S3 and you'll see why I did
this in some of the upcoming clips.
It will become more relevant once we start dealing
with fail overs and routing policies.
So now that we see,
we have our bucket sights set up and that's the basis of our origin.
That's what I'm pointing it.
That s three bucket.
Now we can specify a path if we needed to.
Now the next thing we have is our origin.
I d.
Now the origin I d is essentially just a description, as you can see here.
So what I'll do is I'll say, Andrew ss dot me sight.
And that brings us to restrict bucket access.
So if you recall a second ago anyone from the public could
hit Rs three bucket in our static site.
But what we can do is we can restrict bucket access.
So anyone trying to get content from our bucket has to go through cloudfront.
Now, this is another important exam note.
So be sure to understand how this works were essentially focusing
people through cloudfront to retrieve our objects.
There are many security benefits around this.
So what's the like?
Yes for this.
And then, you see, we create an origin access identity,
which is what we discussed in that diagram in our slides.
So the origin, access identity?
Oh, aye, aye.
Is what allows us to access our content from our origin on the back in.
So cloudfront essentially uses this identity to
authenticate and get our content.
So I'll create a new one here, and we'll just call it access identity,
and then the name of the bucket will keep it the default.
Now, the next thing is pretty handy.
You can allow cloudfront to grant the reed permissions
needed on the bucket so we'll select.
Yes, and this is gonna go through an update.
That bucket policy we looked at and that brings us to our origin headers.
Now,
these air custom headers that you can add depending on your application needs.
So sometimes you might need a specific header that comes in on the
request that you use for determining workloads.
We'll leave this blank because we're just going to s three,
so it's not necessarily needed.
And then that brings us to our default cash behavior settings.
So this is where we set our cash behavior.
We can see we have our default path pattern.
So it's a star, which is basically everything.
And we can force a specific viewer protocol.
We can have both unsecure and secured.
Http, you can redirect http toe Http s or you can require secure http on Lee.
So for this demo,
I'll leave it the default and we get our allowed http methods below that.
So this allows even more granular control on what kind of methods were
allowing the public to make via our cloudfront distribution.
So depending on your needs,
a get in head might be more than enough just to get content.
But if you need a update, some stuff,
it might be good tohave get head options and then these put
post patch and elite Now leave the default and we see we have
field level encryption config.
Now, what this does is it allows us to encrypt at the field level.
On our private content, we see our cash methods.
So get in head, which are by default,
and we can actually set our cash based on selected headers
selection so you can choose the nun option,
which improves cashing.
You can cash all or you can white list certain cashed headers
and right below that we'd come on to object cashing so you
can use the origin cash headers.
Or you can customize them and not accept the defaults
which are here right below that, So you can see we have a minimum,
a maximum and a default timeto live, so use the defaults.
Weaken forward cookies weaken Do query string forward in cashing and a
n'importe note here is that query string for eating and cashing will slow down
your cloudfront requests so we'll leave this at none.
We can select smooth streaming if we're streaming live content, which we're not.
We're just going to be displaying some simple static forms
and then it brings us to restrict viewer access so we can use
Sign your l's or signed cookies.
Now we'll discuss this a little bit more in death in the upcoming clips,
but we can essentially restrict our viewer access even
further by requiring the viewers toe,
have a signed your ____ or signed cookie given to them for access.
They can't just use the default distribution.
I'll select no.
For now, we'll leave the compress automatically.
Default.
We'll leave the Lambda Functions,
which are Lambda at EJ functions that we can deploy.
I'll leave that blank,
and that brings us to our distribution settings at the bottom.
So the first thing we see is our price class,
and this is where we can specify where we want our edge
locations located so we can use on Lee U.
S.
Canada.
In Europe, there is all of those plus Asia,
Middle East and Africa, or we can use all.
And this is the best performance because it cash is everything
near pretty much everyone on the planet.
So I'll choose that we won't use an AWS waft Web a C L.
But you could attach one in front of our cloudfront distribution toe
help with Web application firewall mitigation And that's another exam
point that gets brought up a lot placing a waft rule on the account
in front of the distribution.
The next thing we have is our alternate domains.
So what I'm gonna do here is give my alternate domain,
which is going to be my Andrew estes dot me.
And we specify this because otherwise were only going to be
able to connect via the cloudfront domain name That's
provided and it looks like this here.
So I want to be reachable at Andrew s.
Is that me for SSL?
We can use the default cloudfront or we can specify a custom one.
Now,
An important thing to keep in mind here is that these
certificates within a CM have to be in us East one.
They cannot be in any other region for this configuration.
And I can almost guarantee you a question like that will come up in your exam.
So we select my ACM certain that I have from a W s in just a little background.
This cert here actually covers both my w w w and my route domain name.
So this one covers both.
We can set our custom ssl client support so we can do support server,
name, indication, which is the more modern technology.
Or you could do legacy.
And you can see that legacy is pretty expensive and
they're really trying to phase this out.
So we'll use the S and I We'll set our security policy as the default.
But you can see we have several options here.
And what's nice is a W s actually provides us a list of the ciphers and
protocols that are used based on the policy that we select.
So here at the top, we have our policy names.
And then on the left, we have our actual protocols and ciphers.
So this is a good matrix to see what is supported and what
you should include based on your needs.
So close out, we'll leave the default for now.
Weaken, specify our http version.
So I'll do the modern http to 1.1 and 1.0, we specify at a fault route object.
So, for this,
I'm gonna do index that html because that's the
default html document for our site.
Now we can turn on logging if we need Thio and we
just specify a bucket and a prefix.
So if we want a log requests through our distribution weaken,
do that and save it in S three for further querying via
some other technology or service.
Maybe like a FINA, I'll turn this off.
I'll leave enable i p.
V six on because we'll allow it.
I'll make sure it's enabled, and then I'll click on create and there we go.
So we just started creating our first distribution.
Now the current one is right here, the one that we're currently spinning up.
You can see a state of enabled,
and this will take several minutes for it to actually properly pra vision.
This is a good point to go ahead and take a break.
And then in the next clip once is this spun up will
resume looking at the distribution,
and then we'll also look at setting up a different origin from a load balancer as opposed to a bucket