[Autogenerated] Let's dive into this second module,
which is going to focus on implementing Brazilian
auto Skilling workloads in a W s.
Now in this module, we have a few learning objectives.
We want to understand how we can implement auto scaling
and multi availabilities own systems.
We want to learn how we can leverage load balancers within a W s.
So we'll look at the application load balancer offering as well as the
network load balance our offering and we'll explore the differences
between those in the demos that air coming up.
The last main objective is we want to learn the VPC considerations for
highly available systems when leveraging auto scaling.
So with that,
let's wrap up this intro here and in the next clip will dive in tow. Auto Skilling groups and their use cases.