[Autogenerated] Let's talk about stateless versus
state ful in a stateless architecture.
Er, we're not going to be focusing on storing data.
And what I mean by this is that our computer itself is
not worried about storing data locally.
You might share a common back in like a database or maybe
a no sequel database like Dynamodb,
but the compute itself is not storing data now.
Most of the time applications service one particular purpose,
which falls in line with a micro service approach.
You have one service that's extremely hyper focused on
performing one function with this model.
It allows us to have requests that are able to be handled by many
different service is within our architecture,
er and application, so we can route our traffic service to service,
depending on what we need.
And we do it quickly because we don't have to worry about
storing the data locally and passing it over now.
Another factor is it allows for quick deployments and recovery.
So since we're not storing data locally,
we don't have to worry about corruption in that aspect.
So for just a example, if we had a server go down,
we could easily spin one back up very quickly,
using a template,
and it will act as if nothing ever happened if we design it
correctly now that ties in tow auto scaling,
which is later in this course.
But I wanted to put that out there.
Lastly, containers are a great example and use of stateless architectures.
Usually when you're spinning up containers,
they're performing one particular function,
and they're not primarily storing that data locally.
You might have several containers spun up that connect back to a.
R.
D s database for storing any data, if that's even necessary now.
Staple, on the other hand, is where data is being stored.
So that's the biggest difference.
And because this is stored,
that means the stored data is very critical to the success
of the application and architecture.
An example of this would be a database,
so a database has to track its state meticulously and ensure that
there's no corruption going on with that state itself.
So the data is pristine now.
A downfall to this is that that state has to be shared between servers
or that same server needs to handle related requests so it doesn't
scale as easily as a stateless architecture.
Now let's go ahead and take a break here and in the next clip will start introducing A W s Lambda.