[Autogenerated] Let's go ahead and pick up where we left off.
Now we just looked at executing user data in our E C two instances,
and now let's dive into auto scaling groups themselves.
Now auto.
Skilling, which I have selected here,
is a free service to automatically manage E C to capacity on a per
need basis so we can automatically scale as needed.
Now there's two components to an auto Skilling group,
so let's walk through this.
The first is we have to create our launch configuration
and then using that launch config,
we create an auto Skilling group that references it
and we specify some other settings.
So let's go ahead and get started now.
The first thing we do creating the launch config is
similar to a normal instance launch.
So I'll click on select Let me go to configure details.
I'll give the launch configuration a name you can see.
We can specify spot instances if we wanted to,
we can give it a role, so I'll give it my s3 role that I use previously.
I'll go to advanced details and we get this same option here for user data.
So let's go ahead and input that same script,
and I'm using the one that pulls in our script from S3 and executes it.
And then we have the option to specify our I p address
type so it can be public or private, depending on their needs.
We can add our storage, configure our security group again,
and then we create our launch config.
Now the last thing is our key pair, which is normal.
And there we go.
We have now created a launch config for our auto Skilling Group.
So that's part one done.
And now we need to do Part two, which is create the group itself,
so I'll give it a group name.
We can specify our group size so we can start with one or however many we need.
We specify R V P C and then our sub nets,
so I'll just go ahead and spin this up in East to a an East to be just a demo.
This we can look at advanced details and what this is doing,
which will dig in later in the other clips,
is we can configure specific advanced networking information if needed,
as well as instance protection.
We won't talk about the top part yet because I'm going to go over that soon.
But instance,
protection is something we can set to protect our
instances from scaling back in.
Now I'm not going to select that.
I'll click on next, and now we can come up with are scaling Policy.
So the scaling policy is how we want our group to react upon
load so we can keep it at its initial size.
So it's always maintaining one instance,
or I can use scaling policies to adjust the capacity.
So we set a men in the max.
So let me do one into we give our group size and name,
and then we pick a cloudwatch metric type that we want to measure.
So what I can do is I can look at average CPU,
and when I hit 50 I can scale out.
So this is going to scale up to two instances now I can
give it a grace period for warming up, and I can disable scale in.
So if I wanted to scale out in stay, I can do that.
Here is well, now let me configure notifications,
and this is where we can add an s and s topic to send a
notification to Maybe a team of cloud admin is that need to know
when stuff is getting skilled in and skilled out.
Now, I'm not going to do this here,
but it's important to know that you can configure this
and then we'll configure our tags.
I'll leave those blank will review and then we'll go ahead and create.
And there we go.
It's created successfully.
So now, under auto Skilling groups,
we see we have our auto Skilling group name our launch config that
we used the number of current instances and then our desired
minimum and maximum so on the bottom here.
If I pull this up, we can see those details.
We can look at history we can look at scaling policies are instances that
are a part of this group are monitoring and then on important thing to
know is scheduled actions in life cycle hooks.
Now scheduled actions allow us to create a scheduled action to perform some
type of auto scaling action depending on what we need,
so we can scale down to a certain size or scale up,
and we can set the recurrence on how we want this to work.
So you see the options here.
So this is good if you have maybe a production workload that you
know receives a ton of traffic on certain days,
like maybe an e commerce site that receives an abundant
amount of requests during certain times,
like maybe black Friday.
So you can scale this as needed, depending on your needs.
And then we have our life cycle hooks.
Now,
life cycle hooks allow us to perform custom actions on
our auto scaling group Instances.
So a popular example that pops up on exams is that on
instances that are terminating,
you might have a life cycle hook that allows us to pull down our
data in our log files so they're not lost now.
Lifecycle hooks usually are tested over on the
solutions architect professional exam,
so you might want to get comfortable with him.
I'll go ahead and cancel.
Now let's say we want to change our launch config.
What can we do it?
Let's go to launch configurations and you'll see we don't have an edit button.
We can either delete or copy the existing one.
Now.
A W s does usually test on this.
So it's important to know that you cannot edit an existing launch configuration.
You can on Lee Copy or delete one and then use a
new one for Auto Skilling Group.
So if I copy this, you'll see we have the copy, so I will goto details.
I'll give it a new name.
Let's call this version two.
We'll go ahead and go to advanced.
I'll get rid of all of this all paste in our original script.
I'll skip to review because I want everything else the same and
then I'll create our launch config again.
So now I just created Version two of that existing launch config.
So let's go ahead and put that into place in our auto Skilling group.
So I'll goto actions at it and we specify our launch config.
Let me select version, too.
I'll click on save.
Let me go ahead and refresh,
and we can see our new launch config that we just created
and selected for our Auto Skilling group.
So what this is going to do is any new servers that spin up will
have this launch config as their config template,
so it's going to follow that particular script and user
data as opposed to the original one.
Now one last thing before we wrap up,
Let's go ahead and demo how auto Skilling Group can
help us recover automatically.
So if I go to my instances, I'll follow this shortcut here,
and I'm gonna go ahead and I'm gonna terminate this instance.
So now it's shutting down.
Let me go back.
All were fresh,
and what I'll do here is all pause the clip and then I'll
resume when this updates in the Consul.
Okay, here we go.
So now we can see are instances are set to zero.
And that's because we terminated our previous instance.
Now we have our desired set toe one.
So what this should do is spin up a new instance and recover automatically.
I'll pause the clip again, let this instance spin up,
and then we'll view it all right,
so I didn't even really have to pause the clip very long.
It's spinning up a new server and you can see down here it's using our
newer Apache Web server version to launch configuration,
so this automatically recovered our instance when it shut
down in the desired state was not met.
So a use case for this could be creating an auto scaling group,
even if it's just for one instance so that it automatically
recovers without having to have human intervention.
This is a super powerful service, and it's offered for free from a W S.
So be sure to study it and use it if you use E C two instances and
that brings us to a pretty good breaking point.
Let's take a pause here.
And in the next clip, I'm gonna talk about launch templates versus launch configurations.