[Autogenerated] Let's talk about elastic load balancing within AWS.
Now I'm at the EEC to dashboard here and under load balancing.
I want to select load balancers and let's click on Create.
Currently, there are three main offerings for us from a ws for load balancing.
We have application load balancing,
which is going to focus on that layer seven traffic in the routing.
Based around those rules, we have a network load balancer,
which is going to focus on the network layer,
and it allows for T.
L s offloading at scale.
And that's a common exam scenario that's brought up
on the solutions architect exam.
Now the final one we have here is on the right classic load balancer.
Now this is the legacy low balance or offered to us,
and it's not recommended that you use these if you can avoid it.
So for this demo will look at application load balancers
in the next one will look at network,
so let's click on create on application and this brings us to our configuration.
Now there's three main components to an application.
Low balance or set up.
The first is the load balancer itself, which is pretty self explanatory,
and you can see that here on the diagram.
But then we also have a listener which is listening for
traffic over the Internet or internally.
And then we have target groups that are assigned to
listeners for forwarding rules, and we'll walk through those here.
So the first thing we do is we create a load balancer name.
So let me go and give it a name.
We can choose if we wanted to be Internet facing or internal.
So if we want it to be public, we choose Internet.
If we want it to be private to R V P C, we can choose internal.
Now, Internet facing is pretty common.
That's what you see in a lot of public websites.
But a use case for internal might be some application that you're
hosting that need to be load balance within an enterprise,
but you don't want to allow access from the outside,
and then that brings us to our I p address type.
Now we can choose I P V four, which is self explanatory,
or we can choose dual stack now.
Dual stack.
For those who are not familiar with it means that it does
both i p v four and I p V six routing.
And this is another common exam scenario given to you by a W s.
So keep that in mind for this demo will do I p v four.
And that brings us to our listeners.
So our listeners, like I mentioned,
allow us to listen for connection requests based on protocol import
configurations so we can choose http or https and then specify a port.
Now, you can configure this to be a custom port,
but I'll leave it the default for now.
And we'll also just use basic http for this one.
But we'll come back through and at a secure listener later on.
So the next available thing that we have is our availability zones.
So this is where we get to select our multi ese routing that we want to do now.
This is how you can approach the ability to have auto Skilling instances within
several availability zones behind a single load balancer.
So if you split it in the two a z's on the back end and one of those goes down,
your load balancer can still route traffic to the other ese.
That's still up, so I'll go ahead.
I'll choose to a in to see.
I'll leave the default subjects that I have for my default
BBC and I'll go to security settings.
Now, if this was a secure listener, we would configure it here.
I'll go to security groups and we choose a security
group specific to our load balancer.
Now, to explain this, I'll use this diagram here.
What happens here is we assign a security group to our load balancer,
and then a best practice from architecture perspective is to
assign a security group to your internal instances or back in
compute that lives in your private subnet.
ETS and on Lee allow traffic from the load balancer security group
to your private instances via specific protocols.
So it follows the least permissive policy that a W s
preaches and we'll see that here in a minute.
So select my load balancers security group I go to configure routing.
And this is where we specify our new target group so
we don't have an existing one, So I'm gonna create a new one,
and I'm gonna call this Web server A and the next thing
we can choose is our target tight.
So, do we want a route?
Two instances based on instance.
Do we want the route specifically the eye peas?
Or do we want a route to a lambda function?
So this is another really neat feature that application load balancers offer us.
We can route traffic from a load balancer toe a lambda function on the back end.
It's really cool.
Now, the health checks will be a little bit different,
so you need to be aware of that.
But I'm gonna choose Instance for this Go.
We'll leave the protocol at http on the default port of
80 and then we specify a health check.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm eventually gonna use that same PHP page
that we use from before to get a status code from,
And I'm gonna use the basic http protocol Now if I
expand advanced health check settings,
we can specify settings for our health check so we can set
our healthy threshold are unhealthy.
The timeout that's expected to count is unhealthy or healthy.
And then the interval between checks and we'll leave that at 30 Now the last bit
here sometimes gets tested over and it's the success coats.
Now you can specify a single response,
or you can specify multiple values in a list or a range
of values with a hyphen in between.
And you can see those examples in this pop up.
So I'll just leave the basic 200 which is a status of OK,
and I moved to register targets.
Now this is where if we had instances running in R.
A.
W s account,
we could see them as long as they're within this region
and we could manually register them.
I don't want to do that here.
I'm gonna click next, we review it and then I click on Create.
So while this is provisioning,
let's just go to target groups and I want to verify our Web server.
A target group exists, and it does, as you can see here.
Now, how do we get instances to this?
Well, we assign instances or back in compute like a lambda function or an E.
C s container to a target group so it's not directly
associated with a load balancer.
It's directly associated with a target group instead.
So what I'll do is I'll goto auto Skilling groups and I have
one already created here for this demo.
Now it's using that launch template that we defined earlier,
and we're gonna set this to a desired instances of two.
So let's do desire capacity of two.
And then down here we have our health check type.
Now the default when you create a group is easy to, but with an E.
L B health check, it gives us more options and more flexibility.
So we'll choose an elastic load balance or health check will give a
grace period of two minutes and then I'll click on safe.
Now.
Another key factor to realize here is the Availability Zone section,
so you can see my auto Skilling Group has us east to a end to see which
is what we configured for our load balancer back here.
It spans across to a and to see.
So let me go back to auto scaling groups and let's go ahead.
I want to edit this one more time and I want to scroll down to target groups.
So this is where we can add our auto scaling group to a
target group for a load balancer.
So I select Web server a I'll click on safe,
and that should start attaching it to our target groups once they're spun up.
So if I go to target groups and I go to targets and
pause this clip for a little while, we'll see that they start to register.
And now we see that the targets are registering in.
The registration is in progress,
and that shows is two instances that belonged to our auto Skilling group.
So let me go ahead and pause the clip while these spin up in
register and when they're successful and healthy.
All resume.
All right,
so that only took a couple of minutes due to the
health check thresholds that we said.
And now our targets are showing up as healthy and they're
in two different availability zones.
So now if I go to load balancers and I copy this D.
N s name here and I go to it, we get our Apache page.
So that's awesome.
Now this is going to one of those back and instances that
we configured for Auto Skilling Group.
So if I go to that PHP info page, we get this.
Now if I refresh enough,
we should see this internal I p change that lives here
and there you go with one refresh.
We're now hitting the other instance.
So if I refresh this a couple of times,
that should swap back and forth and it iss so that's how we
can see that are instances are receiving traffic based on
load from our load balancer.
Now we'll go ahead.
This is a good place to take a break and then in the next
clip will pick up where we left off and will add a secure listener to our load balancer.