Hello and welcome back to the course on Tableau.
In today's tutorial we will look at what special files are and how we are able to connect to them in
tableau.
Jones is all that you are not an expert if you are.
Feel free to take a short break.
Sit back and enjoy the presentation.
Now the idea of this tutorial is not to make you an expert on special falls but at least to be able
to know your way around the different types and how to use them not Tableau allows us to connect to
four different types.
The first being shaped falls.
We also have map info tables keyhole Markup Language or came out and the geo Jason fall.
Let's have a closer look at shortfalls however now shape files was developed by the environmental system
Resource Institute and is one of the more widely used types with inside files.
We have a few manatee files that needs to be included in the package.
Firstly we've got the HP file which is the shape format.
The S H x your shape index format and your db file which is your attribute format.
Now we don't need to know the details of these fields or these files but at least be aware that all
three of these needs to be present in our structure or in our folder to be able to use it within tableau.
Now they might also be some additional information that is supplied with the file and it can be any
of these fall types in there.
But as a minimum be sure that all three of those files are required to be used within tableau.
Now we have a similar pattern on the map in the tables where we have four different fault ups which
are required.
There are also a couple of alternative files and before came Al and Jason.
We just have one required File Type Two able to use this with Tableau.
Now working with Max in tableau we know there are three different types and some of these might seem
familiar from earlier on in the course.
The first type is the polygon map which is also referred to as the fold map where we have polygons depicting
the shape and or the outline of a specific area on the map and then we can use our dimensions and measures
to color those.
This the whole polygon then we also have a point map where we actually use the latitude and longitude
points within a map to point out where certain things are located and we can enrich that obviously with
our dimension as measures in terms of color and sizing and a few other attributes.
Lastly we have the line map which connects different points on your map to be able to show direction
or actual distances between points on your map.
Now we also know that tableau has some built in geographic roles that we can work with in Tableau and
we can define these as city country or state zip codes as well.
We even have airports and some other area codes that we can use but these are also quite limiting and
they might also be the occasional time when you might need to use geographic roles outside of what's
available with Tableau.
Examples of these might be school districts dams or parks where we need that additional spatial data
not from tableau ten point two onwards tableau has made it possible for us to connect directly to customers
spatial files to draw these shapes out on the maps but these are obviously limited to the four types
which we have just referred to.
So how does this work.
Now it's very easy you just need to obtain the spatial falls from an authority or an open data platform.
And this could also be from some of your cities or local government institutions that generally supply
a vast number of these different shaped files and what we need to ensure there is that we do have the
required fields for the types that are being supplied.
So once we have we are connecting to this tableau will then analyze the files and make the files available
to be used within tableau then the tableau basically transform the Falls using the latitude and longitude
information and creates a very important new field which we haven't seen before is the geometry field
and the geometry fueled basically acts as an alias for the underlying data that is able to draw the
lines or points or polygons even on our maps.
So generally the shape files that are supplied by these institutions also contain additional information.
So when you are looking for specific data or say have a look when you connect to the spatial files what
else is available in there for analysis before searching for it on any other platform.
Now the data that we are looking at for this specific case was obtained from the New York City open
data platform.
And if I just open up the folder you'll see that we have four files in there.
Firstly we have the debate file the shape file and the s h x file.
Lastly we also have the project which is additional information.
But as we know we at least have the three mandatory files that we need to use the spatial files all
the other the shape files for this specific format.
But this opens a blur and see how it works in practice.
So we'll start off by adding a new data source.
And again we just look at our data source types and we can just select the spatial file when we go to
or when we navigate to our folder.
We'll see that tableau is only looking what it looks for the couple of types there.
But we have the shape file and that's what we'll select to connect there and immediately tableau connects
through it and draws through all of the information that's within these contained within these files.
So what's important for us is in this specific case will be the name field or the name three you want
one which will rename a bit later the borough in which it is fitting back to the case study we need
to do something with the borough.
And lastly the geometry.
So there'll be some cleanup necessary here but this is the important field that we spoke about that
contains and we know what kind of shape or what kind of point will be drawn and we know that this is
the alias that connected to the information in the background to know how to draw this.
The latitude and longitude because you'll do You'll notice that all that information is not captured
in here.
All right.
Just to see what it looks like we'll just open up a new sheet and go and look for the geometry image
over there.
Once you drag that into your map immediately it draws all of the different box as one object.
By the way so let's quickly put in the name into detail to make them individual.
There we go.
And you can see all of the different box and public spaces within New York.
It will be drawing and you can see there Central Park which we need to exclude for our best case study.
And all of them.
And if you scroll in as well you can see how the shapes are exactly the same as the actual box within
this city.
So quite a lot of public spaces and public box with in New York City.
And that wasn't for this lecture in the next material.
We'll be connecting the spatial files to our PBF data in preparation to solve the business challenge
inching our way forward to the final result.
I look forward to seeing you the next time.
Until then happy analyzing.