Hello this is Carol.
And welcome back to the course I'm tableau.
And today we'll be connecting our data source to Tableau.
So I'll bring up Tableau and this is the data source that we're talking about office supplies.
So we downloaded in the previous lecture and normally throughout this course I won't be spending a lot
of time on connecting to a data source because as you'll see it will become kind of a quick thing for
us.
We'll be doing it pretty much on the fly.
But today I thought I'd stop on it specifically because we did rush through it kind of lost time and
I didn't have a chance to show you around the connection manager interface.
So let's go ahead and do that as soon as you open tableau here on the left you have a column called
Connect and it's got different types of files as you can connect to so last time we did an excel file.
But this time if you have downloaded the CSP file a as few files actually considered a text file because
it's basically text delimited by commerce.
That's why it's called CSC comma separated values.
So let's click on text file and now we will select our file here.
Office supplies those yes we will open it up and right away we're redirected to the connection manager
for this data source.
And let's have a look around here.
So on the left here you've got a directory where the file is located and at the bottom here you've got
only one file currently.
That's because we only have one file in that directory.
Later on through the course you'll notice that when we have more files of the same type there will be
more.
There will all be listed here and you'll be able to select from them.
So here you've got a window where all the files you have selected are located.
So what does that mean.
Well that basically means that you can select many files so I can show example now I can drag another
one of these into here and right away something happens.
Tableau is trying to find a way to connect these two files and basically join them.
But we won't do that now.
So we'll just click the Red Cross here and cancel that.
We will talk about joining data further down in the course but just bear that in mind that your data
that you're working with in tableau doesn't all have to come from one file it can come from many files
or it can come from many tabs in a file or it can come from different types of files.
But once again we will talk about that later on at the bottom here you've got a preview of your files
so certain rows and columns of the files just so that you can have a look and see what you are dealing
with.
And in our case we do have the order date which correctly here has been identified as a date so you
can see this icon.
That's a data icon then these are have been identified as text and these have been identified as numbers.
And here are some more controls which we will talk about in further sections of this course.
And up top here also an important part of the connection manager the live or extract connection.
Once again we will have a separate lecture on that and we will understand what the difference is.
And when you would prefer to use an extract for now let's just leave it at life.
So everything looks good over here.
Now we can proceed on to the dashboard so we just have to go here and we'll talk about all this in the
next section.
I just wanted to show you here that we have a data column and here we've got our data source.
So this little icon is an icon that is used to illustrate a database.
If we right click on it and click View data you will see our data just as we saw in the previous window.
The columns can be rearranged here that that is that happens that's that's totally normal.
But this is like a preview of the data it's just as we had before.
So that's pretty much it.
That's as easy as it gets to connect to a data source.
And before we finish up this lecture I just wanted to show you one more thing.
So if I want to connect to more data sources I can always go here and click.
Just go back to the data source connections over here or you can just go data.
New data source and connect from here.
So if you want to connect to another data source you just click this icon over here.
But what we are looking at now is the types of data sources that tableau can work with.
So as we read discussed there's Excel there's a text file which includes a suite files.
There's access databases.
There's now statistical files.
You are able to connect to statistical files and as you can see here these are SAS files SPSS files
and even our files for those of you who are interested in statistical modelling with our.
Let's have a look what else we have.
We've got Tableau Server files we've got Microsoft.
Microsoft tells a field server so we will have an example of this in the course there's Maya skill databases
for online use his oracle.
And there's lots of other different types of servers here.
So if you are doing for instance Hadoop and big data analytics then you've got two pivotal green plum
databases Postgres skill and even have SAP HANA here.
So as you can see tableau guys are constantly introducing new connection to connections to Tableau and
trying to keep up to date with the technical trends.
So that's just even if you don't use any of this just good thing to have you know kind of in mind to
know that tableau is not this to a little become obsolete one day.
It's always changing and always adapting to the market and what's happening.
All right.
So that's it for today's lecture.
We did connect very quickly we just had a lot of discussions about other things going forward in the
course connections to data will be much faster.
So there you go.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.