Welcome back to the course and tableau.
And in today's tutorial we're going to install tableau on our computer.
So when do we need to install tableau.
Well the only thing that it will need is a browser.
So let's go ahead and bring it up and where you'll need to proceed to is w w w dot tableau dot com.
Now you have two options here.
You can install Tableau and get a demo version of tableau.
That's of course if you don't have a full license of Tableau already.
If you have a full license of tableau really then you can proceed with the first option and then use
your license.
Otherwise if you don't have a full license you can either use a trial version of Tableau they provide
a 14 day trial or you can use Tableau Public which you can get at public dot tableau dot com.
So we're going to start with option number one and then I'll explain a bit more about Tableau Public.
Now what we need to click is the try and now button up at the top once we click that here we can download
our free trial.
And in order to do that we're going to need to enter our e-mail and let's for argument's sake put an
email Test one two three at each email dot com and click download free trial and now as you can see
your tableau installation has started downloading.
So I'm going to cancel this one because I really have tableau installed on my computer.
And also you will notice that there are a couple of versions so the version that's been downloaded is
the one that has been recognized for my computer that's a 64 bit Windows version if you need a 32 bit
version for Windows you can get it here or if you need the Mac version you can get it here as well.
But normally the website will recognize the correct version that you need and download that one right
away.
So there you go and once you have downloaded the installation package just in so tableau select the
14 day free trial and proceed with the prompts.
After that you will get an icon on your desktop.
Now if you want to proceed with the Tableau Public version then you'll need to go to public dot tablet
dot com and tell the public is absolutely free.
So it doesn't have any limitations in terms of the amount of days that you can use it for it's a completely
free software.
It does have a few slight restrictions for example you can cannot create extracts and you cannot save
files directly onto your computer you'll have to save them onto the public tab of public server.
But that is not a big hurdle in terms of completing this course you will be able to totally complete
this course.
I've done it myself.
I've created the most complex physicians in this course using Tableau Public.
And you can totally do that as well.
The public is a very convenient tool it is free.
And it is often used by people like journalists and professions where they're not facing any sensitive
data where they just want to create some really interesting visualizations that they want to share of
the world.
So telling the public is a great option.
I often get asked What is the best way to take this course.
If the tableau trial has expired or if somebody decides that the trial is not long enough Tableau Public
is a great option to complete this course so select one of those to either select tableau I'll be using
Tableau the full version throughout this course or if you like to follow along exactly then select the
tableau full version if your trial has expired or you just want something that doesn't have a time limitation
golf table public and you'll be able to follow along with 99 percent of this course as well.
And once you've installed tableau you'll get a desktop I can just like this one so if you double click
it that'll bring up Tableau and this is what it looks like inside.
And this is where we'll get to the fun stuff and we'll proceed with that in the further tutorials of
this course.
I can't wait to see you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.