Hello and welcome back to the course on tableau.
And today we will continue with the analysis of the demographics segmentation of our member base or
customer base for this bank.
So here we've got the gender chart that we created previously.
It's a pie chart.
And by the way with pie charts people don't really like them in an in analytics in possessions and that
is the case when you have like more than three or four elements to a part pie chart gets very clever.
In this case we only have two male and female.
So I think it's okay to create a pie chart but it's up to you.
You're more than welcome to substitute with this.
This will for different viz. if you think that pie chart a pie chart is not the best way to go here.
So we're going to change the name here to gender and we're going to create a new tab.
And this time we're looking at age.
So this is going to be interesting because we have age here and we want we want to see how many people
the age of how our member base is distributed across this age across the different ages.
So if we take age and graph drag it into columns and you see take some of age right away.
But if we change this from a measure to a dimension so it's not an attribute dimension.
So basically disaggregated and take a number of records and drag it into rows.
You'll see this curved line here.
So it's basically telling us how many people they are in for each individual age.
So for 35 years old there's 163 people for 36 years old hundred 183 people and so on.
But this is not exactly what we want and even if we change to a basket not really what we're looking
for we don't want every single age demonstrated here imagine if our ages weren't given in integers so
in whole numbers what if they were given in floats or doubles so basically if we had in our database
in our data sets or if I'll just go here told us that if in our data set we didn't have twenty one but
twenty one point five and thirty four point three and thirty point four and so on this it wouldn't work
if this doesn't look as good but it wouldn't work even as good as that.
So we need to do something about it and this is where we talk about creating bins and basically breaking
up our ages into different groups so five ways let's say for instance five year bands from 15 to 20
from 20 to 25 and so on and seen how our membership is distributed across those bands.
So let's go ahead and do that very it's very simple to create bins or groups for a variable in tableau.
So as long as it's a measure it basically it's a numerical variable.
All you have to do is you have to right click on the variable that you want to create bins for and then
you go to create and you create bins.
Simple as that.
And size of bins in our case is going to be five because we want five year bands and we'll leave it
as age bin click OK.
And as you can imagine age bin goes into dimensions because now it's no longer a numerical variable
it is a categorical variable we've broken up our data into categories and now we take age bin and drag
it into columns and we take total number of records or no records and drag it into rows we get a beautiful
distribution which tells us how a member base is distributed across five year bands.
So in 15 to 20.
So 15 is inclusive 20 is not inclusive in 15 to 20.
There is 54 EC of 54 records meaning 54 customers 20 to 25.
There is 108 to customers than 400 two in a new one and so on.
If you want you can add the if you press and hold control and you drag some number Records label you'll
get the number at the top.
But we don't want the number at the top right now.
What we want is we want to change this to a table calculation and it is useful sometimes in a distribution
to know the total.
So how many in total people there were in a certain age band but what we want right now is we want a
percentage and why we want a percentage why do we not curious about the total is because this chart
is going to work together we've found map in a dashboard and our map already has the totals so our map
already has the absolute number and that's why we changed gender to a percentage and that's why we're
going to change this to a percentage as well because we don't really need to know the total twice we
don't need to know it in the map and in the breakdown it's more useful here to know the percentage.
So we're going to click this dropdown as we did previously.
Quick table calculations and here will do percentage of total and void.
Right away.
It has changed from a absolute figure to the percentage of total.
So what we want now is we want to hide this label at the top edge.
We don't need this.
We want to change the name of the chart to age distribution or distribution by age probably better by
age and now in our worksheet we want to format it so if we write.
Oh actually first we're going to change this.
Edit access and here percentage of total number records percentage of customers.
And now we want to right click on anywhere in the chart click format and we will change this to keep
it consistent 12 and black or dark bold and to finish off what we're going to do is we will take some
number of records which is a percentage and drag it into color.
So now we can see the dark blue.
And there you go we've got a beautiful distribution here ready to go into our dashboard which will create
very very soon.
That's all for today.
I look forward to seeing you next time when we will continue with our analysis of the segmentation.
And until next time happy analyzing.