Hello and welcome back to the course on tableau.
And in today's material we're talking about data blending is a very exciting.
And at the same time controversial topic in tableau.
And that's because data blending is often very underestimated.
It is a feature that is not often used but at the same time it is very powerful and should be used more
and moreover at the beginning it might be a bit difficult to distinguish between joining data and blending
data.
But don't worry.
Today we will clarify all of that and we'll put everything back in its place so that you can comfortably
use and take full advantage of these powerful features both joining and blending data.
So to start off if we're going to need a browser.
If you go to Super dot signs dot com slash Tableau and then you scroll down to section number five a
joining and blending data just download the very first file which is airline comparison.
So we'll just say that there we go.
And now just bring this file up airline comparison.
And as you can see here we've got two tabs the first tab has revenue for our airline number one and
it's split by period financial year 2015 and financial year 2016 and is split by multiple regions.
And the second tab has revenue for airline number two.
It is also split by year and region.
As you can see airline number two operates in less regions.
And another thing to note is that in the first tab the year is called period and in the second tab the
year is called the year.
So you'll see why that's important in a few minutes.
So I'm just going to close that and we're going to open up a new tableau workbook OK.
And now we're going to connect our excel file airline comparison.
There it is.
We're going to connect to the first tab here.
So that's done.
Now we're going to create another connection and it will be to the same excel file but now we will connect
to the second tab.
Now if we go to our sheet one you will see here two data connections and they represent the two different
tabs in our Excel workbook.
So what we're going to do now is we'll start visualizing airline number one.
We want to see how the revenue is split by region for instance.
So we'll ignore a year for now we'll just assume the revenue for the two years.
And as you can see here it's broken down by region now and we can see how the revenue changes from region
to region.
Now what we want to do is we want to add airline number two to this visualization.
So if we go to the second data source right away Here you can see this orange line on the left and you
can see this link icon which tells us that tableau is prepared to blend the data for us now.
And so this is where we get to the topic of blending what is a blend.
Well remember how previously in one of the tutorials before this we created a joint for our daughter
so here in the data source we connected some different sources of data like for instance like that we
put in another element of data here and we create an inner join and then.
So we prepared all of the data before we actually worked with it in our workbooks.
Well now we haven't done that but at the same time Tableau allows us to do that on the fly.
Why while we're working with our workbooks and that is called data blending and blending is kind of
like a smart joint.
So let's have a bit more of a play around with it and see how it works.
What are we going to do now is we're going to drag revenue for the second airline also into our columns
and right away.
Now you can see that we have two elements in our business session.
We've got the first set of bars and the second set of bars which represents the second airline and also
it's important to note that here in our control panel we've got two main elements.
So this these controls are for this airline and these controls are for this airline and these bars.
And also you can control all of them through this feature here so let me just show you an example if
I want to change the color for instance I can change the call for everything or if I want to change
something for this other bar chart.
So we're just one of them.
For instance I want to make it a line chart and Santa Barbara.
I can't do that and then I can go into the second bar chart.
I can change something else as well I can change the color here if I want and things like that.
So we'll just cancel those changes because we don't really need them.
But keep that in mind that you can control these separately if you need to.
And if you need to control them together then you just need to click this all feature over here.
So what happened here.
Well tableau knows that it can.
It needs to join the two data sets in order to visualize them because as you can see here we're using
region from airline number one and revenue from airline number one but revenue this revenue comes from
airline number two and that's why it's marked with this little database with a orange I can have on
it and so tableau needs to somehow aggregate revenue from airline number two at the level of region
of airline number one.
So how does it do it.
Well tableau knows that it needs to blend the data meaning that it needs to join the two data sources
and how does it do it.
It goes through the region variable here and that's shown using this link.
So it's basically telling us that tableau has performed a left join from between the datasets airline
number one and airline number two on the field which is called region.
So it's kind of a join on the fly.
So that's that's great.
And the way region was picked up is because the name is the same.
So region here is the same as region here and that's how tableau understood that it needs to join on
the regional field.
But what we actually want to do is we want to visualize not only by region but also by period.
So by year.
So if we go back to airline number one and we take a period here and we drag it into our Rose you'll
see here financial year 2015 financial year 2016.
So now one more thing we're going to do is for this chart on the left we will take some revenue will
hold control and will drag it into labels and we will just format that quickly so that it's not it's
not in the millions.
So there's less numbers currency and just want millions.
There we go.
And then we will take this revenue and drag it onto the label for this chart.
And now we will formatted here as well.
Currency just in millions.
And now for the whole dashboard we will format it and tell it to be 10 and bold.
Okay.
So hopefully you can see that a bit better now.
Now what's happened is after we dragged period so I'll just perform that again.
So I'll take a period out and I'll drag period into rows.
You can see after a drag period intros the first airlines data was split into two periods.
So here you can see Africa 10 million and have record 8 million.
Asia 20 Asia 16.
So it is working here.
But at the same time the second airline it's not been affected by the period variable.
It's basically what it did is just duplicated the data for the full data set instead of splitting it
into two separate periods.
Why did that happen.
Well because tableau does not know how to connect how to connect to this period variable hub to connect
the second data set to the period variable.
Now that's because we haven't established that connection.
So we can fix that very easily if we go to Data added relationships.
Remember how we talked about joining or multiple fields.
Well here we've only joined on region.
You can see that that was picked up automatically.
What we're going to do now is we're going to join on multiple fields.
And now instead of going just joining a region we're going to join on period and year here.
So if we do that click OK you can see right away.
This has been adjusted so what that did is now Tableau is joining these two datasets on two fields.
And this is exactly what we talked about in that example with joining when you need to join multiple
fields if you don't join in multiple fields when it is required then you will duplicate values and you
will over inflate the observations.
So in this case what happened is tableau joined on two fields and there was a period a region and year.
Now the reason why tableau didn't pick it up originally was because year has a different name.
So what we'll do now is I'll show you how else you could fix that problem.
So if we go to edit relationships and we take period out so we'll just put it back to automatic click
OK.
You see we have that problem where the values are some tier and the value of some tier and some have
been split.
Now what we can do is we can just go to one of these datasets sets.
So here we've got period.
So how about we go to the second dataset and we will here change the name.
So we'll rename it instead of a year we'll color also period.
And what you'll see is that tableau automatically right away picks up that this should be a connection.
So now tableau knows that the names are the same.
So therefore it is joining the data on those two fields.
Well one more thing you should know is that if you take a period out of your viz. right away tableau
no longer needs to join on that field it does know that there is a connection here but it won't be joining
on that field and that is because it's that field is no longer part of your visualization.
So you can manually switch it on if you want or switch it off but it doesn't really affect the resolution
in this case because it isn't participating in this visual.
And so what that does is that tableau actually creates this join on the fly.
And the way tableau does it is a bit different to the way we were doing it manually.
Back here in data sources when we were creating our own joint the way tableau does these blends is it's
actually instead of joining the data at roll level it will first send queries to each of the datasets.
It will aggregate them.
So here you've got airline 1 and airline 2.
It will aggregate them to the level that is required at the current level of granularity of the results
station and then it'll only join them.
So in our case for instance before joining the data it goes into airline in the into the airline one
data set and it looks at the data it aggregates it to the right level so in our case it's the region
level and then it goes to the airline to data set it aggregates the data to the region level as well
and then it brings back the aggregated values and joins them.
And that is what data blending does.
So it is a very very smart left join and you can also see that it is a live joint because here one table
is the primary table the blue one and the orange the airline to table is actually the secondary table
which is marked with an orange Mark.
And that from there you can see that it's a left join because here you can see all of the regions which
are present in airline in the airline one database.
And here you can add their join to the airline to database and therefore these two are blank because
they're not present in airline two.
So.
And finally joining blending blending is actually done on a per sheet basis.
So if I create a new sheet here you can see right away there is no more blue or primary and secondary
secondary data source which means you can create a brand new blend and let's have a look an example
here.
If we start creating the blend with airline two you will see that it will become the primary data source.
So if we drag region into rows and now we drag revenue into columns and also revenue into label and
make this a bit smaller what you will see is that when we go to airline one it has become now the secondary
for this sheet it is the secondary data source.
And if we take revenue and drag it into columns here what you will notice is that there is no longer
six rows.
Actually before we do that we have to fix something up because some revenue is this revenue has been
copied for both of the sheets and that's not correct.
So that can be a mistake.
We need to take our revenue from here and drag using control revenue.
The correct revenue.
And so you can see that it's got the database I can.
So what you can see here now is the important thing is that there is not six rows but only four.
And that is cause there's only four regions present in the airline one data set and it's the left join.
Oh sorry.
In the airline two data said because airline 2 is our primary table and this is a left join.
So there's only four regions present in the airline two data set.
And if you recall when we talked about joints when you do a left join every everything that doesn't
match get discarded.
So in this case North and South America got discarded from the final resulting table and that is because
blending is a very smart.
But it is a left join.
So that's pretty much it.
That is how blending works in tableau I realize that this has been a rather lengthy tutorial but it
is important to understand how blending works and we went through everything that is included in a blend.
So we talked about the primary the secondary tables we talked about how to add our own elements to the
joints or in this case period and region.
We talked about how the the blend actually works that it first aggregates the data and then it only
joins the data in your final result.
And we also looked at why the blend is actually a left join and how you should be cautious of that when
you are creating your viz..
So that's all for today I hope you enjoyed the tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.