Hello this is Carol.
And welcome back to the course and tabla.
And in today's tutorial we will learn how to export our worksheets as images for other files.
All right.
So we've got this beautiful report that's ready to go.
How do we put it into a document like a PowerPoint or a word document and so on.
So one way is to take a snapshot and I knew a friend of mine.
He didn't know how to export and he kept taking snapshots we just take like a print screen of this report
and then you stick it into your file.
Well that's not the proper way to do it.
There's definitely a way to export files directly from tableau.
And today we're going to learn how.
So right away.
This is a worksheet as we discussed.
So if you go into worksheet and you go to export your image you can copy the image.
So I'm just gonna close that because there's no way another way of doing it a bit faster.
You don't have to move your mouse all the way out there.
This is one of those tips and tricks.
So if you right click and you go copy you go image you get the same menu.
So there's there's two ways to export.
So we all we need right now is the view the title and the college and so we don't need the caption because
we don't actually have a caption We haven't created one for this chart.
We'll talk about captions further in the course there they're pretty easy.
So we'll take caption art and we'll talk about this menu in a second as well.
So we'll just copy.
Now let's bring up the document so let's say I want to export this image into a Word document.
So here I've got a Word document prepared.
The annual bonus report and I want to put the image in here.
So what you need to do is obviously control B.
Or just right click and paste.
And there you go.
So there's your image here.
So that's the image it blends and renewal.
But what do we see about this image that is all right away.
Not good.
Wrong.
Well we see this name over here.
So what went wrong.
Why.
Where did it come from.
Let's go back to Tableau and find out if I click on Tableau.
You can see that there is no name here but sheet one.
Sounds familiar doesn't it.
That's the name of the tab here.
So that we remember when we exported the image.
So if we go to right click and then when we go to copy image here it says title and title is actually
the name of the tab.
So you either have to click title or just change the name of the tab.
And so let's do that.
So I'll go to the name of the sheet.
I'm going to call it the annual bonus
analysis and now I want to see it here as well.
So I'll go to worksheet and I'll click show title so here now I can see the annual bonus analysis name.
And that also gives me the power to change and format it.
So if I click here and I click format title as you remember our formatting pane pops up in the left
and I can actually do that.
Sorry this doesn't allow you to change the size of the text.
So we're going to have to work on this a bit.
You need to double click on the title to be able to format the size of the text.
In this case it's 12 it's bold so it's it's all right it's the same as the rest that we have here.
So just if you do need to change the format that's how you do it.
So just click that.
And now we can right click copy image um view title Cole legend copy.
Now let's go back to our document.
Delete that and paste in our report.
OK so here now you can see annual bonus Report analysis at the top.
And that's good.
So that's pretty much ready ready to go.
You add some text for the executives and it's ready to be presented.
The only thing is if you want a bit more space social on this chart to be a bit bigger than you want
region at the bottom.
And that where your chart can expand to the right and that's where we'll try to now.
So we'll right click right click copy image and color legend.
So but here we'll put the college in at the bottom.
We'll choose that one.
Go back here and paste.
And as you can see the college is at the bottom and the chart has a bit more space.
So that's the other way you can do that.
So that's pretty much done.
And so that sums it up for us for today.
I just wanted to tell you that we still haven't saved our workbook.
So make sure you do so you go to file save as and obviously you know for this workbook Section 1.
Just make sure you keep it saved because tableau doesn't actually order save your work and you want
to keep it for yourself for the future and that is it for this section.
I hope you enjoyed it very easy introduction to tableau that was an easy dataset but it did help us
get our head around a lot of things.
And we talked about navigating tableau creating First calculate field adding colors labels doing formatting.
So all of that together that's our base.
We're going to take that forward in the course.
But before you do proceed with the next lecture Do not forget to do the quiz.
It's right under this one.
It will help you make sure that you've covered everything that we talked about in the section.
I'll look forward to seeing you in the next section.
And until next time be analyzing.