Hello and welcome back to the course on tableau.
And today is going to be a very quick tutorial.
We're just going to create one more charge for our segmentation dashboard.
And this chart will be a tree map.
This tree map will be working with the job classification variable in our data.
So let's go ahead and create a new tab.
We will call this tab job classification.
And now we will start creating our tree map.
So let's take job classification drag it into our workspace and let's take a number of records and drag
it until workspace.
Now if we use the Show Me functionality we can select tree map from here.
And once we do that you can see a tree map has appeared.
It is funny how it's called a tree map.
I know it's it's actually boxes.
There's no trees here but nevertheless it's a tree map.
So what we want to do now is get rid of this color that's been determined by the total number of records
in each box.
And instead of that rule to jobless classification hold control and drag it into color.
So that's our tree map let's just make it look good.
Now to start off with if we're right click somewhere here and we'll click format change this to bore
or 12 and bold.
And now I also would like to change the colors.
Let's go into colors and change them up a bit.
So blue color can stay blue.
Other let's make our green and white collar.
Let's make it gray.
We can't really make it white because our background is white.
But let's make it gray.
So there is our tree map and now we'll just save ours worksheet.
And that's pretty much it.
That's how you create a tree map there.
Pretty easy to create.
What else you could do you could drag this into labels as well if you wanted to but we're not going
to do that at this stage.
So we're done with all of our worksheets which is great.
In the next tutorial we will finally start creating our super powerful dashboard.
I'll look forward to seeing you then.
And until next time happy analyzing.