Hello and welcome back to the course on Tableau.
In the previous tutorial we created this beautiful visualization in front of us which allows us to compare
the actual sales of the different departments of a store to their target sales.
And today we will finish up with blending and what we will do is we will talk about how to create a
calculated field within a blend and what that means is how do we create a calculated field that requires
starter elements from both of the tables which are being blended.
Now I feel that this is an important topic that I should share with you because you will be creating
a lot of calculated fields along the way.
When you work with Tableau and when it comes to creating calculate fields within a blend it's a bit
different.
There are certain specifics that you need to be aware of.
So I just wanted to make sure we cover off this topic so that you're not in for any surprises along
the way when you are working with Tableau in your role.
So let's get ahead.
Let's go ahead and get straight to it.
Here we've got our charts and what we will be looking to do is for each one of the departments we will
want to look at the difference between the actual sales and the target sale.
So we want to create a chart which will be taking every single bar and subtracting the target and seeing
whether basically the bar.
The remainder of the bar is above zero or below zero and that will allow us to very quickly see how
the departments are performing now because adding another chart will increase the size of this worksheet.
We might want to consider taking these departments and looking them at looking at them separately so
that it's not too cluttered because we already have.
Basically right now we have six charts on this worksheet.
We've got the targets which are in gray in the background and we have the actual sales which are these
bars in the front.
So if we add another chart for every single one of the departments I'll take it to nine charts that
might be a bit overwhelming for the user.
So we want to take care of the user and that's why we're going to kind of simplify this chart a little
bit and we can very easily do that by taking the category out of rows and putting it into a filter.
So that's we're going to do we're going to take category and drag it from rose to filter and right away
we've got this filter settings that come up we're going to click Okay.
And what that gives us is quite a crazy chart right away because we are looking at everything at the
same time.
What we will do is we will take this and we'll click show quick filter.
Now I'm going to reduce the size of the chart a little bit so I can zoom in and so that you can see
the filter at the same time.
And we're going to reduce the size of the bar so that's just for for us.
Okay.
So that's what our chart looks like.
Of course we don't want to see everything at the same time we're trying to get away from that.
So first of all we're going to customize or change this filter to a single value list and then we'll
take out that all our value so we'll take we'll go customize show all value take it off.
And now we can simply click through our departments and we'll see the chart for each one of them which
is great.
Now at this point which you might be seeing is something different and not a worry I'll be able to help
out right away so perhaps what you're seeing looks something like this for it after you've taken category
out of the rolls and you put into filter what's happened is now when you click over from the different
three different departments you see the total target for all of the departments of the individual target
and that can happen.
That just means that what you did by taking category out of rows is it's just a filter now so it's no
longer a level of granularity of The View and Tableau no longer aggregates the data at that level.
It ignores that level of granularity when it's doing this blend and why that happen is because perhaps
in your some of target in this control window when you in the previous tutorial when you removed a category
from color to make the target Grey you didn't put it into detail but you rather just removed it completely.
So right now what's happening is for this chart this great chart in the background here if you look
at the look at the worksheet right now you will see that category is nowhere to be seen as a level of
granularity.
Ignore it as a filter because a filter just filters data but you target your categories not in columns
it's not in rows it's nowhere to be seen in this control panel.
And what that means is right away tableau no longer knows or no longer regards category as a level of
detail and will not aggregate at that level it will ignore it you can fix that once again by taking
category back into the rows right away as you can see now the categories correct.
And you can click through but we didn't want to do that.
We wanted to keep category just as a level of granularity but were fired actually been in our chart.
So we'll take category out of here and we'll just drag category into the detail just make sure it's
there.
It might be there if you if you'll put it there in the previous to term might be ready there and that's
where you're seeing everything correct.
So just make sure that that's the case because this kind of shows that when tableau aggregates the two
separate data sources it only looks at what is and what fields are in the view for that specific data
source and you can check that for through this control panel or here so for sales or for Target and
so on.
So that's how we get our chart to be filtering bull by the different department which is good.
And once again we have to make sure that the access is synchronized which which is a great thing.
So we can visually see right away what's happening and now we're going to create our calculated field
which will be working across the two data sources in the blend.
So we're going to go to the primary data source.
We're going to find our field that we're going to use which is sales will right click that and we will
choose create calculated field.
So here we want to take sales and we want to subtract the actual target to see whether the sales are
above or below the target.
So we'll call this a calculated field what should we call it meets or to excess of target.
Let's try that size of target.
And now we will go to sales targets so the new the other data source the second one and it will take
target here and we will subtract.
So we will actually first of all we'll put a minus sign because I want to subtract and I will take target
and we'll drag it into a calculated field right away.
You can see two things happen.
First of all the sales targets the target has this prefix before it which indicates a data source.
So it's telling us that this field is coming from there and it's basically just the way for tablets
to know which secondary data source this field is coming from and for you also to be able to tell that
very quickly when you look at the calculation next.
You can also see that there is a sum here.
So why there's some appeared.
Well that is quite it should be intuitive by now because you know that or we know that this blend is
happening when by tableau aggregating the data first so as we discussed tableau sends separate queries
to these data sources it aggregates the data to the correct level of granularity then it brings it back
and it joins or plans it here in tableau.
So that basically basically means that there will already be an aggregation when this calculated field
is being performed or being derived.
So that is why this summer's here on this here you can see the calculation contains errors and that
is because you're trying to or we're trying to subtract an aggregated field from a non aggregated field
that is easily that can be easily resolved.
We're just going to put a sum around sales here as well.
Woops There we go.
So some sales minus the some of the target another field is valid and we click OK which is great.
Now we can start using it.
So let's go ahead and drag excessive target onto our Rose right away you can see a new field appear
excess of target.
Now if we go to the control for exits of target as you can see here in this whole view for this new
field there is no category where whatsoever except for in the filter.
And that means that category is not being considered as a level of granularity for this specific chart.
The one at the bottom.
So we need to fix that and we're going to do that by taking category and just dragging it into detail
right away.
You can see that the chart has been corrected.
And now if you click through it is actually showing you the difference between the charts the bar chart
and the area chart in the background which is correct or exact.
It's exactly what we wanted to see.
So now we'll just make it look pretty.
All we have to do is color it properly and we'll just take excess of Target and drag it into color so
by holding down control and right away you can see Tableau is smart.
It's selected the colors for us.
So anything above is blue.
Anything below is orange.
And now we can really start doing some analysis around this perhaps before you start doing a loss.
You might want to formatted a little bit so you go into format you change the worksheet to say a 10
or maybe a twelve depending on how much space you have.
You make it bold as you can see all everything has been adjusted.
And once again this is a personal preference you might want to color it a bit differently.
So there we go we've got we've got the chart pretty much prepared.
Now we can do a bit of analysis so I'll just make this a bit bigger so we can see a bit more the filter
here for instance is being cut off a little bit perhaps maybe let's make it a 10.
Yeah that looks better.
So what we want to do is we want to just see how the departments are performing right away.
You can see that the what is this furniture department had a few quite a lot of bad months.
If we move to office supplies you can see that they have much less bad months only one two three four
five six seven eight nine ten eleven months below target in the one two three four years and the technology
department has quite a few bad months but recently they've been doing a bit better.
So based on that information you can really start making some assumptions or preliminary conclusions
you might say that the furniture department the way they say is set their targets might not be the best
way because they're the they're constantly underperforming and not meeting their targets.
Perhaps this department manager should revisit the way they're setting the target.
So far it's been just constantly increasing month to month over the past four years.
Perhaps it's time for a change technology department is setting a targets once per year and that is
met perhaps they're not accounting for some seasonality effects as you can see there's some orange bars
clustered together so and here like some 0 bars as well so that basically means maybe there is a seasonality
effect that they're not taking into account and maybe throughout the year the target should change based
on how their customers are purchasing or how their stock is being adjusted and the behavioral patterns
that they're observing and looking at the office supplies department you can see that they have the
least months when they've not met their targets.
And basically means that their way of setting the targets for the months which are reviewed.
So these targets are reviewed quarterly seems to be the best approach currently and perhaps that manager
can explain to other managers how he is doing it and what his secret sources.
So that's awesome.
One more thing that you might want to do is perhaps because these two axes are aligned you might just
want to right click here and just unsure header so get rid of it and that will save you some space because
pretty much it's the same axis.
And here you can just rename it so added axis and just call it sales slash target apply.
Okay.
And that way you're saving space on the right which was not really being used for anything important.
So that's how we create calculated fields across blends.
A very important topic because you will find yourself in situations when you will need it.
And now you're totally prepared for it.
I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.