Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization and marriage headed for.
And today we will run a more precise optimization of this particular set of parameters or of this cluster
of sets.
Start with our 9.
So in order to do that you need to right click Set and prepare amateur's.
We can run the tests just to see the result and what we want to do now is to go into text properties
and uncheck start our meaning that we will keep it constant.
We will not change it and it will.
It will be nice for this optimization that will follow.
And now we want to check if.
Which of the sets around these particular parameters very in very close proximity to them.
Is the best one.
So what are we going to do is we going to optimize around these parameters.
And this is technique that is very often used in optimization.
So we are going to start at 6 move step 1 and go up to 10.
That means that will check the values for a min limit of 6 7 8 9 and 10 and 8 is in the middle.
And thats exactly what you want.
And also I would like to stress once again for those of you who are using a five digit broker that in
this particular expert vizor the easiest way to make your make it work for a five digit broker is to
multiply mean limit take profit Stop-Loss everywhere in your settings by 10.
So to be eighty thousand three hundred and same thing would apply in the Start step and stop values
.
So take profit.
We know its a hundred in this particular set.
We want to optimize around that.
So we want to go start at 90.
Step two and go to 110 and that puts a 100 in the middle and that will give us 20 steps from 90 to 100
.
Its five steps from 100 to 110 thats another five steps.
Stop-Loss here is 30 so we want optimize from 20 step up to about 40 and you can do smaller steps you
can do step 1 and do that for example or Fehmi period.
So 17 is put in the middle.
So will start at 16 will step 1 and will go up to 80.
So that will give us a more precise optimization We'll find out exactly which parameters are the best
to start our line in the vicinity of these products that we have.
So going to click okay optimization and will just go kick start the optimization is much faster now
because there is a lower number of parameters and will go Siggraph.
Very interesting graph.
Sometimes they can be quite amusing and there we go.
The results so let's see what the best set of parameters is.
As you can see start our has been moved to the back because it's no longer an optimized parameter.
And then we have the optimized parameters here so many people it is a take profit is 106 plus 28 a filter
.
True and a period 71.
So what are we going to do now as we roll right click Set and parameters start and we'll just check
out the graph gross graph hasn't changed much.
But if you look at the profit then you can see that there is maybe one trade difference because 3000
here the next those 2356.
So it does change a little bit.
And if you want to get the best results for your expert wiser then sometimes it's worth optimizing around
the parameters you've set.
It won't really help you if this that original set that we used was curve fitted set.
So it wasn't a true set that will survive in market conditions.
But if in case it was then we can maybe improve marginally improve your result.
And if you're trading large volumes that can be something that you'd want to do.
So we go ahead and save that and we'll save that as simple system set 6 9 9 b for example.
So that's all we have success.
I think that's enough just just have a look.
We have six sets I think that's enough for now.
What we want to do next is run all forward tests and pick out the best ones out of these sets.
So we'll do that next tural and I hope to see you then.
Until next time hepi training