Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization Ameritrade for as you can see from here in
the previous tutorial we talked about the two dimensional surface analysis technique in MT 4.
And today we will talk about exploring optimization results into Excel and further analysis there.
So let's jump straight into it.
If we go to the optimization results tab you'll see the set of optimization results which I have from
last time.
And originally there will always be ordered by Profitt cells just illustrate that that's how your results
come up after the transition is complete.
First what we want to do.
Or want to order them by pass so the first passes at the top then just bear in mind that if you did
have Skipp useless results checked when you ran the optimization you won't see the negative results
here.
In this stage right now we want to export all of our results to Excel so that we can analyze all of
them there.
So if you want to follow along like that just make sure this is unchecked and just rerun the optimization
if you do check it.
Next what we're going to do is we're going to call a click copyable or just press Alt A on the keyboard
.
So do that.
After that you need to open a blank Excel workbook like I have here.
Then right click and click paste that'll paste your results into Excel.
The only main drawback that you can see here right away is that we don't have headers in this Excel
spreadsheet so we're going to fix that and we're going to right click on the first column and click
insert which will give us a US first row and click insert which will give us a blank row.
And now we're just going to make this smaller.
Will type in the headers manually.
Unfortunately you do have to type and type them in manually but you cannot.
You probably only need to there once because you can always just copy them across to your other workbooks
.
We analyzed the results.
So I'm just going to do that.
So I have populated all of the headers and now we see the next abnormal thing it's these this column
full of zeroes.
This started occurring from one of the recent builds aventure for all.
And you can either just give it a name such as empty or did it all together and that's exactly what
I'm going to do.
So I'm going to click here and click delete.
Now one other thing I like to do is if you select all of your cells and then just by clicking up here
in this corner over here and then you double click on any one of the column dividers the cells the columns
will automatically will order size.
And then maybe if we make this one a little bit bigger that allows you to see all the contents of the
cells.
And finally the last challenge we have before we can move on with analysis is these values of the parameters
are present in the workbook.
However there the both the name and the value of the parameter are in each cell and we don't want that
we want the names of the parameters to be up here and the values to be here suits best suit would be
very similar to what we have for ratio's because they have the names up there and the values in the
cells themselves.
And it's easier to analyze that way.
So in order to do that we're going to do the next procedure so we just copy the name of your parameter
and place it into the top of the cell so we're going to populate up here.
We're not going to just type in the name of the parents and we will type in their parameter equals name
of parameter and why we need to do that.
I will explain in a minute.
Same thing for this take profit.
So we're going to type that in.
So we've populated the top row with these equal parameter name Eco's Param name and some just going
to show you a very efficient way of getting these values out of the cells or just keeping the values
in the cells and getting rid of the name of the parameter.
So just highlight the role that you want to do that for go to dadda and here select text to columns
and indexical them select delimited then unselect tab and select other and then other just put an equal
sign and click next.
And then when you've got this first column select is selected do not import Culham skip that will skip
this column and then with this general column just keep it as general.
It's all good.
And as you can see what that will do is it will split your column at the equal sign and that's why we
were putting the equal sign in for the Herro as well so that it would be able to split as well and we
get rid of this Barbul keep this part.
So now we're going to click Finish.
And as you can see here we have many people who are at the top and the values down the bottom.
So now we're going to do that for the rest of the columns.
All right so I've done that same procedure first the columns it took less than a minute.
And now we have all of our optimization results separated and we can very easily analyze them in Excel
.
So what are some examples of analysis would be we could first of all we could add it filter up here
So in the same daughter ribbon just click filter and that as a filter.
And here we can now easily not like what we were able to do back in the intro for we could we could
sort by told trades largest to smallest So that's a maximal smallest the largest or sort of a profit
factor but that was the limitation to what we were able to do is actually going to make this a bit more
appealing visually.
Put that in the center so that there was a limitation on what we were able to do but now we can do much
much more.
And especially if you're you've got basic Excel skills you'll find that you can do quite a lot of cool
stuff.
For example if I want to now sort by the parameters Let's say I want to sort by stop loss.
Now I can do that right.
I can sort from the lowest to the largest of the largest the lowest or if say I want to only look at
certain limits.
I want to look at four and five in my analysis and then I also want to look at take profits that were
the lower take profits I want to see 10 15 20 25.
I don't want to see anything above that.
And I've got them there and now I want to order about profit large the largest to smallest and I can
see the large profit here then say for example we don't want to do anything with these because these
were not optimized so metric for always puts the pyramid as it did optimize in the first place.
And that way you can do that for example.
Now if I want to see all parameters with profit factor say here if we go to conditional formatting and
we do color scale we do color scale like that we'll see a color scale showing the most profitable and
the least profitable results or favorable results in terms of profit factors are the least are over
here and you can see how they gradually increase like that.
And because it's ordered by profit but that was ordered by total or let's get rid of the mid limit limitation
and that's ordered by total trade say largest to smallest and you can say for here we also add a color
scale.
But in this in this case we say let's use a blue and red color scale you can see that there are some
negative ones here.
And then there's a chunk of good green profit factors.
And then as this drops off you see a mix.
So even with a low number of total trades is a high number of profit factor or high value of profit
factor and then very very low trade.
You see this anomaly that they are proud they are very high profit factors at 31 trades.
So you kind of can do very interesting visual analytics here and you can create charts and just basically
do any of that Excel analysis.
You are familiar with or have knowledge of how to do and that can significantly speed up the process
of analyzing optimization results.
So that's all for today in the next term I'll show you one specific example of how to benefit from this
and that's how to calculate the recovery factor and that's a parameter that is very important in trading
.
But it is actually not represented in any of the meditator four reports.
So we'll look at that next time.
And until I see you on that Tauriel happy training.