Hello hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization in meditator for so Louis quick video.
I wanted to show you how to set up your terminal so that the expert or adviser can actually perform
live or demo trades.
So here I've got a demo terminal open in front of me and I've got a simple system version 7 here somewhere
.
If I just drag it onto the chart then you will see that one side you know set of my inputs and everything
is good here.
When I click OK here the simple system I can has like a frowny face and that means that the expert adviser
is not operational it's not working.
And so now we're going to rectify this issue.
So I'm going to ride click and I'm going to remove the expert adviser.
Now there's two things that you have to pay attention to.
So first of all this button over here this arbitrating when it's red that means it's off.
If you click it mate makes it green.
Now trading is on and there needs to be green but that's kind of the the very quick switch when you
just installing the extra adviser you have to go into the settings of the terminal and fix everything
up there first.
So we're going to go to Tools Options up at the top here and we get this window pop up.
And usually it's on like on the first page you need to go to the expert advisors tab and this is what
it looks like in the recent builds of a trader for us so we're talking build seven hundred and sixty
five plus I used to look very different but this is the most recent one.
So here you have to click allow automated trading and that's basically this is pretty much the same
as clicking this button.
So when you click this button at the top the red green one it will trigger this checkbox.
But in here within the checkbox we have to set up our own preferences so the first one is disable automated
trading when the count has been changed.
I recommend keeping that on on because if you've changed your counting your terminal which I don't recommend
doing.
But if you have then probably you don't want the same expert advisors running on that other account
as well disable automated trading when the profile has been changed.
Yes I I also keep that one on even though I don't normally change profiles at all.
But just in case.
Disable automated trading when the charge symbol or period has been changed.
I also like to keep that on on and that is because if your expert advisor is designed for the already
time frame and you accidentally switch to the daily time frame you want to make sure you expedite and
wiser is switched off.
Once again that's something I don't recommend doing ever changing the charts a when expert advisors
are running on them.
But if that happens by accident you're probably better off if they spurred wise it turns off.
Otherwise it can make a lot of mistakes lot of imports.
So if your expert advisor is running using DL else then you should switch Hassan and I will switch it
on.
Most expert advisors or simple expert advisors like simple system don't use deal else but you'd rather
have this on in case you do want an expert or wiser deal else on so that you don't forget to turn this
option on when when the time comes and allow web requests from list the Jor-El's.
I don't really use expert advisors that go too suddenly or sometimes that happens when your expert advisor
tries to find out news or CRN algorithms that are proprietary and are hosted on web so I usually don't
switch to sun unless I specifically see that in this tractions of my supervisor.
So now we click OK.
As you can see our trading is enabled.
It's very simple to switch it off switch it back on.
You don't have to go back into the settings anymore.
Now your terminal is set up.
I know you just click click drag your simple system expert vizor you put in all your settings as you
like click OK and there you go.
So now simple system version 7.0 is running and there is a smiley face and that some That's a good thing
that means that the expert adviser is ready to roll.
Once again just make sure that you are always aware of the state of this button.
If it's red that means your expert advisers have been switched off and they're not making any trades
at the moment so I hope that was helpful.
I look forward to seeing you on the next Tauriel.
And until then happy trading