Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on backtesting and optimization.
And today we've got a new version of simple system out and I wanted to share it with you and tell you
what it's all about.
So if you go to the original page where you download simple system for example dot com slash simple
hyphen system and scroll down you'll see that the latest version now is not 5 point 0 or even 7.
It's eight point nine.
And if you go down to the download section you will be able to get the new version here.
So there's a few details about what's new.
But I wanted to bring to your attention the most important new adjustment or a new model that I have
added to it.
So let's go ahead and look at that.
And here I've got a four digit Broecker account open and I've got the simple system in strategy tester
at the bottom.
Now a lot of the stuff we haven't talked about yet at this stage of the course you will get to see it
further through the course but bear with me just let's focus on the parameters of this new expert advisor
.
So in this simple system version eight point nine you can see that you're able to enter the variables
over here so they start out with a limit take profits stop loss and so on.
And also you'll see that there's a new parameter which was added in Version 7 which is trail value.
But nevertheless after you've done your optimization backtesting which we'll talk about further.
Of course you'll have a set of parameters that you're ready to use with this expert adviser and let's
for instance run this expert advisor and see what results we get.
So I'm running on the period of the last three months so from in February March and from April 2015
to July 2015.
And so if I run that you will see that there our graph and this is a result result that or a set of
parameters are pretty much got off the top of my head.
It's already shown some good results.
Further Of course you will see how to get even better results with this expert adviser.
But for now we're going to focus on is our type of account.
So this broker this account is a four digit account and you can see that here in the market watch me
window you can see that all of the prices are 4 digits or for the yen currency pairs.
There are two digits.
Now what happens when you move over to a five digit broker or if you even if you start off a five digit
account right away.
So let's open one up here I've got as you can see here is a different account and here I've got five
digits in all of my currency pairs and three digits in the yen currency pairs.
And this is a different broker.
This is roba for X dollars for X for you so here you can see the difference right away there's an extra
digit in all of the currency pairs.
And this has always been a under-water stone that has tripped up a lot of algorithmic trading traders
because once you move on to you New onto this five digit type of account your expert adviser might not
be able to handle it.
And here if we enter the same exact parameters so I'll just open these to this window first so if I
go to setting's expert adviser parameters here they are.
And if I go to my five digit window or five digit account and go to the parameters you will see that
they're pretty much the same except for a change of startHour because there is a time shift between
the two brokers and once again that's something we also cover in this course.
But for now what we're looking at is that the main parameters take profits stop loss minute people who
are in exactly the same as in the four digit account.
Now let's go ahead and run this and see what we get.
So if we were on this now on the same time period same currency pair same timeframe and we look at the
result and it's a complete loss.
So why does that happen why when we move from a four digit account to 5 digit account why do we get
this change.
Drastic change in results.
So here you can see this is the original graph the end result of all back tests and this result of a
back test is completely negative.
But also what you can see is that on this chart the stop loss or the stop losses like for instance here
that's a stop loss and take profits for instance that that looks like a take profit over there.
They're much greater than the ones on this chart.
And what that is telling us is that their experience Wiser's not correctly recognizing the parameters
we're inputting.
That is because expert Wiser's think in terms of points rather than Pipp So here we're putting 4 1960
just as we were in the four digit account.
But in the 5 digit account is recognized as 4 points so four of those last of the last decimal of the
currency pair.
So what we normally would have to do to correct this behavior is to change all these parameters and
multiply them by 10.
So if you go ahead and do that.
So all of the parameters relating to points including all Trel value is not used here so we don't have
to multiply but we would have to multiply it if we were using it.
So if we are now an expert advisor you will see that we're getting pretty much the same Charsadda exactly
the same but that is due to differences in quotations and historical data between the two brokers.
But once again we're not focusing on that what we're focusing on is now that we have corrected the behavior
of the wise and is recognizing our parameters properly.
Now that is kind of a headache to always remember to multiply your parameters by 10.
And if you worked with expert advisors between four digit and five digit brokers before you will know
how you sometimes you might forget to do it or sometimes you know you'd always have to remember to do
it for all of your expert advice if you don't want to be doing that all the time.
So a smart expert advises have these things coded in them.
And finally simple system has become one of those areas and you can see I've added a module which is
called Auro handle five digits.
And now we'll just turn everything back to the original values of the parameters so for 1960.
And if I change the handle digit from false to true you will see that nothing changes here but the behavior
of the expert was all changed so first off we will keep it at false and we'll have a look and see that
it could be behaving incorrectly.
And now we will change it to True and see what happens.
So I'm going to change it to true.
OK start.
And as you can see the expert advice has adjusted its behavior.
It recognizes that it is working on a five digit account.
Moreover this is actually a very smart module.
It doesn't only just bluntly multiply everything by 10 or something like that.
Like other expert devices would have.
This one is a smart one so you can keep it on true even on a four digit account like we're going back
to the four digit account now.
And if I switch it on here so if I go down you can see it's actually switched on so for a four digit
account if it's off you'll get a good result.
You'll get the parameters recognized properly recognize properly.
And if we switch it on you will still get the same results so there won't be any unnecessary multiplication
by 10 or adjusting of parameters because the expert adviser actually knows how to recognize a four digit
account from a five digit account.
So all you have to do is keep this parameter or this module on and be careful it is on by default in
this expert advice so that is very important for you to be aware of.
You keep it on by default and then you can always from now and specify all the parameters in four digit
mode you don't have to manually multiply by 10.
And moreover you should be careful because if you already have a saved set of parameters for your 5
digit account so if I go back to the 5 digit account here.
So let's say for instance you already have some primers saved for a five digit account.
If you load them into this new expert advice they will probably be already multiplied by 10.
And also you will have this automatically set to true so that will mean that if you're launching expert
like that you will double up and your stop loss and take profit will be out of whack.
So be careful of that.
Make sure if you move on to version eight point nine or simple system that you either re reset your
variables in four digit mode or you switch off this new module by default the new module is always on
.
So that's the main change in system simple system.
Eight point nine.
Now when you're trading on a five digit account you can not worry about multiplying all of your parameters
by 10 because the expert Yser can do that for you.
And that module is on by default.
Hope that it was helpful.
Hope you're enjoying simple system let me know in the common section of what you think.
If you have any sort of recommendations for using this expert adviser going forward or any ideas for
new modules for expert advisor this this idea actually came from one of the students.
He also wanted this for five digit recognition so always open to new suggestions.
And I look for see you throughout the course.
Until then happy trading