Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome to the sixth tutorial on testing and optimization and meditator forth in the previous tutorial
we discussed the available models in this empty Four strategy tester.
And those were the every tick control points and open prices models.
And today we will be looking at the strategy test to report.
Assuming that you have run a back test the report can be found in the report top down here.
And what we will do is right click on the report and we'll save as report.
And this allows us to export the report as an issue mail file.
We will give it a name which reflects which expert adviser was tested.
So a moving average report for example and we'll save that.
And as you can see Mecir 4 has really brought it up as a file in a browser.
I'm going to zoom out so that you can see a bit more of the report at the top here we have some statistics
around the test.
Then we have the chart and then we have a full list of all of the trades that were conducted.
You can reference this list if you need to find out something about a particular trade.
Now we won't be discussing this particular report because I have a much more interesting report prepared
for you.
I'll just bring that up now.
And Azumanga.
And as you can see from this report right away from the chart it is a profitable report and I think
it will be more interesting for us to discuss this profitable report rather than that unprofitable one
from the moving average pre-packaged expert adviser.
So the system that was used in the back test for this report is called simple system version 2.0.
And this is a proprietary algorithmic trading system which we will get to know very intimately in the
next section of our course and you'll be able to download this for Robert or you could you can copy
the code if you like and we'll be working very closely with this expert advisor we'll be optimizing
it back backtesting it forward testing it and making sure that it gives us results like this which are
profitable and we can actually use on our accounts for trading.
Let's go ahead and discuss this report.
We won't be looking at the actual trades that were conducted because we're more interested in the statistics
up here.
I will zoom in so that you can see the text a bit clearer and we'll start from the top and we'll work
our way down through to the bottom.
So at the top we have the name of the strategy the server where the test was conducted and the build
of the trading platform.
The mix is the symbol the financial instrument and the timeframe on which test is conducted here in
brackets the dates are the dates that the trader chose for the back test.
And then these dates of the actual dates when the test was in fact drawn.
Sometimes the dates can be a bit different to the one specified because there wasn't sufficient data
.
For example I asked the test of your own from the second from the 23rd of February but the test was
actually ran from the 24th of February and that is possibly because there wasn't enough data for the
23rd maybe because that was a weekend or something like that.
Next the model is one of those three models that we discussed in the previous tutorial in this case
I chose every tick model the parameters is the parameters list of parameters for the trading system
.
This line will be always unique to every 4 x robot.
And in this case simple system takes five parameters which we will discuss in more detail in the coming
to Charles Barsoum test.
There was a total of 4000 hourly bars in this specified six month period.
The number of Tick's model was just over 4.2 million ticks.
And the modeling quality was 90 percent which is very good mismatched chart errors is 0 which is also
a good thing.
If this number is just about zero then that's not really a big deal.
It just means that there were some irregularities in the data.
The initial deposit is starting balance of the test.
The spread is then spread on which test was conducted.
In this case it says Current theory meaning that I chose the current spread however I would like to
warned you that you should be careful with when choosing the current spread because sometimes brokers
increase their spreads for the weekends.
And if you're running your test on the weekend then you can find yourself in a situation when you're
running a test for spread of seven for a currency pair that on average during the week has a spread
of four so you always have to consult with the brokers website to understand what the average spread
is.
But in my case I heard of three seemed reasonable for the British pound dollar currency pair.
Next the total net profit is how much money you earned or the system earned in the during the back test
.
And it is equal to gross profit minus cross loss.
So as you can see from the chart the starting balance was around 10000.
And the final balance was around twenty thousand.
So in this case the net profit is the difference between the ending balance and the starting balance
so this earn profit is the total net profit the profit factor is the next parameter oh the next variable
here so let's bring up a formula and see how the profit factors calculate and the formula for profit
factor is gross profit or gross loss.
So in our case it would be this gross profit of $25000 to buy $15000 Gross last gives us a proper five
to one point seventy one.
Generally in your trading systems you should aim for a profit factor above 1.5.
And if your profit factor is below 1 then the trading system is making a loss expected payoff.
The formula for expected payoff is a net profit divided by a total number of trades and this is pretty
straightforward as expected prior payoff just tells you what is the average net profit per traits in
our case it's $10000 to divide by 115 trades gives you approximately $93 of net profit per trade.
The absolute drawdown Apso drawdown is by how much your balance curve went below the initial balance
.
So as you can see here the lowest the Bhasker curve has ever been is just $894 below the starting $10000
deposit maximum drawdown is the maximum of all of the drawdowns which are present in your balance.
So our drawdown is considered between the maximum in your balance curve and the consecutive minimum
will get Baskar.
So this in this for example is a drawdown.
This is a drawdown.
This is a drawdown and this is a drawdown.
And in this case it appears that this is a maximal drawdown and the total value of this drawdown was
approximately $3000 which represents 14 percent of that balance at the top of that peak relative drawdown
.
It's the same thing but backwards total trades is self-explanatory.
Short positions that's how many short positions we have and that's how many what percentage of them
we won.
Same thing for long positions profit trades.
That's we had a total of sixty eight profit trades and that was 59 percent of the total number of trades
we had similar for last trades.
Largest profit trade just tells you the value of the largest profit trade in dollars.
Same thing for a large US last trade.
Average same thing.
Maximum consecutive wins and then profit of money.
So we had a maximum of seven profits in a row and they brought us around $3000 and maximum we had consecutive
losses was six and they and we lost $1700.
The next line is the same thing.
But backwords finally the average consecutive wins is the average profit in a row and consecutive losses
the average number of losses we had in a row.
So there you go that's how you read a strategy test to report.
We'll be working more closely with some reports like this when we're talking about which parameters
we should focus on how to evaluate the effectiveness of your trading strategies in the coming tutorials
in this course.
So that's it for this tutorial.
Don't forget to click Subscribe if you're watching on YouTube and I hope you'll consider going to WWE
for Expo.
Dot com as subscribing to my new newsletter here as well.
And until next time have the.