[Autogenerated] Hi,
my name is not steal and welcome to my course building
multistep applications with a W.
Let's step functions.
Modern applications are becoming more and more small.
Independent media service is that fit together to make up
the applications that we see today.
Feeding all these service's together monitoring and tracking their
progress is a very involved and complex task.
Learn how AWS step functions work and how they can help us build large,
complex, multi step work clothes that are easily debug and visualize.
Some of the major topics that we look over in this course include
creating step function were close with many different steps.
Setting up error handling and retry logic using activities toe
add logic that runs on our local environment,
monitoring work for performance using cloudwatch events and
finally learn about security and best practices when it comes
to building step function were close.
By the end of this course,
you'll know how to take your existing micro service's and create multistep work.
Clothes that are easy to visualize and monitor howto have called that runs
on your own environment and make it part of your cloud.
Were close using activities and how to debug work
flows in development and production.
Before beginning this course,
I recommend that you are familiar with creating London functions and
having some basic no jail skills to get the most out of it.
I hope you'll join me on the journey to learn how to create
work flows with the building multistep applications with a W Step functions course at lower side.