[Autogenerated] our company.
Club romantics, like many other companies,
is trying to break down their systems into smaller pieces toe,
help them better manage and understand their business logic much on their e.
P I.
A logic has been converted to either a serverless
function or a smaller micro service.
These now helps them easily.
Main Thing called across different functions but presents
another problem when it comes to coordination.
In a lot of cases,
one several dysfunction needs to be continued by another
function in order to complete a larger task.
Let's take an example off sending a PDF report for clients.
We generate a beauty every board encrypted,
depending on the client requirements and sanded by our email.
Now we could have this process all in one step, generate and creep and sent.
If any of these steps failed, the entire process fails,
and if you only wanted to generate the report,
we couldn't do so.
We would need to have a dedicated service.
Just to generate The report on Ideal solution is to have them
separated into smaller independent service.
Is that individual tasks?
Ideally,
we would have a serverless function or a service to generate the pdf
wantto and creep hand an email service to San a maze.
This way we could scale each independently or have them a server
less toe on Lee pay for when we are using them now that have
broken down our logic into smaller pieces.
There is the matter of coordinating them.
We need detain them.
So once the report generation has completed its past to the increase in step
and after encryption is passed to the email step managing these viacord wild
doable it's very complicated and proved to errors.
We have to think about error handling, retrial,
logic and progress tracking and also down the line.
We might get other requirements, like sand,
a file using other means other than email,
like chat integrations or SMS.
All these is already becoming complicated.
With a small process like ours.
Imagining a large process with multiple steps becomes
quite unfeasible and hard to manage.
That is where AWS step functions come into play.
Step functions is a service that enables us to easily orchestrate multiple AWS
service is that can fit together to accomplish a larger task.
We can have a process with multiple steps.
Each step.
Output can be used as another's import,
and we can build work flows that integrate as many
service's and steps as we require on.
We can arrange them accordingly without writing any
called or having to redeploy.
Our service is when the work flow changes.
Step functions provide us with a lot of crucial functionality
that we would otherwise need to be ourselves.
We have error handling automatic retrial failures,
triggering and tracking steps,
manage the execution order and finally visualize the work
flows in easily to understand diagram When it comes to
orchestrating large scale complex diagram.
Step functions have a lot of benefits over self implementing.
We can easily create complex work flows that could have a lot of
steps coordinating a 100 step workflow on our own.
Other than being time consuming,
it's very hard to do and let alone maintain and watch for errors.
Step functions gives us an easy way to create,
visualize and provide detailed information on each step.
Execution on.
When a step fails,
we can easily see which step failed why and what's
the state of the entire process.
At any given time,
AWS step functions can wait a long time from going from one step to another.
We can easily configure away,
period between two stabs or wait for the next step to
start until an outside factor intervenes.
For example, if we have a payment system and we are going to do a refund,
we can set it.
So if the amount is more than $1000 we can decide to
have a human approving the step.
Execution would halt, and until someone approves or denies the request,
the workflow will not continue forever.
Another benefit is not having worked for logic on the business
logy when he had worked for logic to applications that are
supposed to handle business logic, it makes things complicated.
Changing one requires changing, rather using step functions.
Devil opens the design work.
Clothes don't have to know much about the inner
workings off the service is they use.
They only need to know the possible errors that are thrown,
the input and the output to design the workflow successfully.
And another benefit is that step functions can run in parallel.
We can have multiple parallel executions off the same work
flow as well as we can have parallel executions off a subset
of steps within our workflow.
Tow it, period over a process faster.
Managing these complexity on our own environment would be
very complicated and time consuming.
This was just a brief introduction into AWS step functions. We'll dive deep into different topics in the cliffs to come.