[Autogenerated] as with any other business workflow,
and our handling is crucial.
When an error occurs, we have toe.
Either we drive the action or call some other business
service in case off specific errors and with AWS step
functions and or handling is very easy.
We can define our air or catching logic in each off our steps and
decide what to do when a specific error occurs,
which in most cases is to move to another state based on the error type.
For this day more,
we are going to use the work for we created in the previous clip for a report,
generation workflow and at an ER,
handing and retry logic to our steps in case something goes wrong.
We are going to use the errors toe at branching logic.
Poor workflow.
Let's not forget to our workflow and added the definition.
Clicking on the edit button will open up the workload
definition where we can edit it toe, add error,
handling four steps.
We just need to add a catch property,
which is an array off error handling logic for which state toe point,
when a specific error occurs for our demo,
we're going to add some error handling in the email step.
If it fails,
we're still going to go toe gene up step so we can clean up
the generated PDF files For the email step.
I have created a domino lender function,
which throws an email sending failure exception regardless off the input.
We are going to use these to simulate a failure on our
email step to make things easier.
Let's go be the function Aaron and change in our workflow now that
our e mails that points were right Lambda function.
Let's add our error handing logic on the email step.
Let's add a catch.
Property for the error equals value.
We need to specify email sending failure,
which is the error that we're throwing from our ____ Yolanda function.
And for the next date, we're going to specify the cleanup state.
So even email fares to sand.
We're still going to clean up our files.
Also, one more thing that we need to do is specify a result value.
So we met.
The exception results into a variable.
Otherwise it will override the entire state machine out.
Let's name it emails sending error.
Up to this point, we are only handling a specific error.
Email sending failure in case another type of error occurs.
We won't move to the cleanup.
State step functions also provide us with task state errors
that we can use to handle task failures,
which is more high level than handling the underlying
service errors like London functions.
In our case, here are all the space that we can use for error handling.
We have states that old.
This is a wild card and can be used to catch all errors.
Next, we have states that run time.
This error means that the execution failed because often
exception that could not be processed.
For example, when we try to apply an input or output path on Al Jason payload,
this error cannot be retried and will always cause the workflow to end in error.
Next,
we have states that time out an error coast when the task
grant's longer than the amount it's allowed to.
We also have staged the past failed.
This is used to catch tasks that failed their execution and
finally we have states that permissions.
This error occurs when a task fails to execute.
Some called you do not having all the needed permissions in our workflow.
On the email step,
we're goingto also use the states that all which will act like a catch all
options and catch any errors that we did not handle previously.
That safe and execute our work floor and see what happens to start our work.
The execution.
We're going to use the same payload as we did in the previous clip.
We are going to pass the data in a property called report Options,
and we need to specify a client email, email,
subject, female body and should increase.
In our case,
it does not matter if we said the shooting crew property to true or false.
Since we only care about the email step,
let's execute our floor and see the results as we can see the image step failed.
But the cleanup step was executed regardless.
And if we check the email step details,
we can see that it's hard to say it's called error,
which means the error handling took over and the
workload execution was successful.
For our email step, we want to retry in case the email standing face email,
standing feels for so many reasons,
so we want to try at least three times before we call it a failure.
We're trying in AWS step function.
Work clothes is also very straightforward.
To add retrial logic,
we need to use the retry property similar to the catch property.
We need to specify the error time we are looking for.
Next.
We want to specify the amount of time we want to wait
before starting the retry process.
We also can specify the number off a tense we can retry.
The default value is three, and finally we have a bank all free.
This is a multiplier used to increase the interval
between replies in this example.
The first we try,
we look her after 10 seconds and the second we try will occur 20
seconds after the 1st 1 And if we had the third,
that would be 40 seconds and so on on a work floor,
we wanted to try on Lee.
If the emails that frozen error email sending failure,
let's add our retry property.
The retry property can be specified together with a catch property.
After the retry has finished, the catch will take over them for the error name.
We need to specify the same error we did in the CAT state email.
Sending failure, image sending can take time.
So foreign interval That's put it as 15 seconds.
We also want to try to send the email three times.
So in the Mexican property, we need to specify the value to to retry attempts.
Plus, the original run makes three and finally for the bank off.
Great, let's set it before.
If the first attempt fails,
let's wait one minute before we try to send the email again.
Now that we have set up a retrial logic,
let's save our workflow and executed again.
And after the workload has finished running,
if we look at the execution history,
we should see that the workflow was executed three times.
We can see that the first retry has started 15 seconds
after the original run had failed,
and if we compare the first retry with the second to retry,
they should have 60 seconds in between.
And indeed, they have 60 seconds in between.
One was started at four away and the other at 409 after
which the cleanup step was start.
That's all for catching errors,
enhancing retrial logic in AWS step function work flows.
It's a very powerful way off making work through decision based
on errors to make our work close more robust.
Using this knowledge,
try throwing different hair types and making different decision.
Using this workflow or your own work clothes that you have desired, we'll dive into other interesting topics in the clips to come.