[Autogenerated] step functions provide us with a lot of useful features,
but like many other service, they have their limitations.
We'll go over some of those limitations.
In this clip, a workflow has a maximum one year execution time.
If an execution continues for more than one year,
it will fail with a timeout error.
Most work clothes will not run for a year.
But if by any chance your workflow has an outside input
factor and that is not results within a year,
your work for, well, time out.
And if we're using express work close.
They have a maximum lifetime off five minutes.
But since they're used for high event, read were close.
They're meant to run for very short periods of times and not likely to time out.
A workflow has a 25,000 history limit to guarantee the execution off.
All steps and their order step functions start the history of
each execution after completion off each state.
The execution history includes all the information that we see here.
All of these execution event history can only go up to 25,000.
For most cases.
This will not be an issue if you do have very long running executions
that may reach such higher number of state transitions.
You might need to consider splitting your work floors to stay under the limit.
Or we can add logic to our workflow.
So we keep track off the execution, he 30 and when the limit is reached,
we can start a new execution when we use activities were continuously
pulling for available tasks to complete the number of conquering requests
that we can have for a specific activity East 1000.
If we exceed this quarter,
we will get an error that says the maximum number of workers
concurrently pulling for an activity task has been reached.
One of the limitation that we have is a payload size that we can
make a request against an AWS step function.
This payload is said to 32 kilobytes.
If we have a pay look that is more than 32 kilobytes,
then we should use something else to story.
A good candidate is Amazonas three.
Once we start appeal it there, then we compare the file air in between steps.
These will help bring down the pale outside significantly,
and if we happen to have sensitive information going
in as input into different steps.
Then we could encrypt that information industry so
no unauthorized people can see.
Now let's look at what happens when we pass a payload
that is more than 32 kilobytes.
As a payload, I'm passing in a property that says more than 32 kilobyte,
which is a _____ payload out of generated.
Once we started execution, you should get a mirror, and indeed we get an error.
The value of input is more than 32 kilobytes.
We get this error using a console.
You I and if we were using other means off triggering our workflow,
we would get a similar error message.
When building your workflow,
Try to keep this information in mind so you don't get any surprises while running your work clothes on production.