[Autogenerated] hi.
In this clip,
I'm going to look at some of the best practices when it
comes to building step functions.
First, we have time out.
Time outs are very important in any type of obligation,
and step functions are no exception.
If there is an obvious run time, there's something should take to run.
Then we should limit our steps to that amount of time.
We should make something timeout, a common practice.
So if something goes wrong or we have some sort of Lupin are code,
it's your time out so we could investigate quickly.
While in development.
Time out won't be much use to US scenes.
We mostly run tests on a controlled environment,
but in production they could be invaluable.
We could easily identify failed jobs by the time out
status and also save some resources.
In the meantime, in a complex work floor,
the payloads for some steps could become quite large.
We should avoid using large payloads, and instead we could use,
for example,
Amazon simple storage or a database to store their
data and move it between state.
So instead of passing a payload,
we could pass a file I D or a database I D Errors will always happen
something sometime we'll go wrong being that the code that we wrote or
a network issue or in AWS service issue,
for example,
sometimes aws some the functions can experience transit service error,
in which case it will throw all 500 a roll call.
It's a very good practice toe handle errors on the workflow level based on
which we can either make a decision to go to some cleanup step where we can
clean up previously generated files and undo any actions that we might need
to undo or terminate the workflow.
And also based on the aero time.
You can also retry failed steps.
For example,
we can retry steps that are prone to errors that can benefit from a retrial,
for example, e mails sending or other network related desks.
The Get Activity task.
FBI is designed to provide a task token on Lee once,
if a task talking his drop while communicating with an activity worker.
A number off get activity task request can be blocked for up to 60 seconds,
waiting for a response until get activity task times out.
So it's very important that the task token is received
properly and there is no communication issues.
And finally we need to to the correct work.
So type step Functions offers a standard work slow as a default work.
So type with the option to choose express were floors we need to to
stand that were close when we need long running,
durable and auditable work flows.
Or we need to choose express work flows for high
volume event processing work floors.
State machine execution will behave differently
depending on which type we select,
and the type of truth cannot be changed afterwards.
Make sure you spend some time to decide if your workflow
should be expressed or standard so you can get the best
performance out of your work.
Slow to continue this further.
Try applying this information to our previously created work
clothes and update each accordingly if needed,
so you can get a better handle on the different aspect off work. So desire