[Autogenerated] throughout this module we cover how to create real life
scenario workforce with many steps and decisions.
We learn how to best perimeter's between states,
how to parse the input and output and how to use a past A to
transform the state machine output so we can offer I different
variables based on different decisions.
Even the best code sometimes fails.
We learn howto add error handling to our steps so we can handle
cold failures and make decisions based on them.
We also looked into adding retry logic to our steps so we could
retry tasks that can benefit from a retrial.
Aji, for example,
timeout errors or network airs workflow are no good if we don't
have an appropriate way off starting them.
We looked at different ways.
We could trigger our work flows what through a step by step on how to
use an AP I gateway to trigger our work clothes and allow easy FBI
access that can be integrated in any application.
We learn how to optimize our work,
slows by identifying steps that are independent and run them in parallel so our
work flows can run with optimum performance running cold When a serverless
function might not always be possible or even desire.
We learned how to use activities to run tasks somewhere else on our own
environment and connect them to our work clothes,
which would open up A lot of possibilities for integrating in
house service is with step function work,
folks.
I hope this has given you an understanding on how to build step function works,
those that have multiple steps with input and output parsing error handling,
retrial logic and with steps that can run on our own environment.
You can start by putting his knowledge to use by creating your own
work flows with different steps and activities. Thank you for watching.