alright let's talk about interfaces now
there isn't a lot to say about them
because they're not much different from
Java now of course all the syntax
changes apply to them all the stuff that
we've seen in the way that you declare
class is but other than that there's not
a lot of difference but let's take a
look at them because there are a few
things I want to say about them so we're
gonna declare an interface called my
interface let me get rid of this error
first for the data class so we'll say
interface my interface and that's pretty
much all there is to declaring an
interface now of course you will never
see parentheses after an interface name
you'll get an interface may not have a
constructor because you never actually
create an instance of an interface so
having a primary constructor wouldn't
make sense now let me declare a sub
interface that extends my interface I'll
call it my sub interface and just as his
classes you just extend an interface
like this by using a colon and then
following it with the super interface
name now is there anything here that is
a little surprising or perhaps what you
wouldn't expect just take a look at this
for a minute
so my sub interface is extending
interface now if we go up to classes
where we had something else extend
something you'll notice that we had to
use the open keyword here otherwise
nothing could extend something well you
don't have to do that with interfaces
they they're just extendable by default
so we didn't have to explicitly declare
the interfaces being open okay so let's
add a function to my interface we'll add
a function called my function and it'll
take a string parameter and it'll return
a string and well do the same thing for
my sub interface it'll have that should
be a lowercase M it'll have a function
called my sub function and it'll let's
say up let's make it take an int you
know int and let's have this one return
a string as well
now we could have my sub-interface
override my function that would actually
work katli wouldn't complain you could
put open here and have it override it
down here but you know it's an interface
so obviously there wouldn't be much of a
reason to do that okay so now let's have
the something class implement my sub
interface so we'll come up to something
and just as with classes you just put a
call in and say my sub interface and now
of course we're gonna get an error
because we haven't implemented the
methods in my sub interface so I'm going
to have IntelliJ do that for me
so I'll just right-click go to generate
I want it to implement methods and we
have two methods we have two well it
says methods but two functions we have
to implement one my function in the
parent interface and then my sub
function in my sub interface so we'll
click OK and we get our two functions
with the override keyword there and two
bodies with two dus in them now of
course a class can extend more than one
interface and also it can extend a class
and also implement an interface so let's
go up to laser printer it's extending
the printer class I'm going to put this
on a separate line and we'll also have
it extend the my interface class so
there we go and of course by doing that
we have to now implement the function in
my interface but rather than do that I'm
just going to remove this I just wanted
to show you nothing earth-shattering I'm
sure you would have figured that out by
yourself but now you've seen it now
interfaces can have properties and these
properties don't have to be abstract you
can even provide accessors for them and
sub interfaces can override the
accessors so let's go ahead to my
interface and let's add a property to my
interface so we'll say Val number and
we'll make it type int now at the moment
this is abstract because we haven't
assigned it an initial value and you'll
see now that the something class and the
something else class because it's it
sense of something class they have
errors because there's no concrete
property definition in them and the
property definition and my interface is
abstract so let's go up to the something
class and we'll make the property
definition concrete so we'll say
override because we're overriding a
property in the interface and we'll say
Val number and did we make that a
shorter an inch we made it an int okay
so let's make it an int and we'll give
it the value of 25 and now you'll see
the errors have gone away because now
the class contains a concrete
implementation of the abstract property
defined in my interface which of course
is the parent of my sub interface okay
now let's add a concrete property to the
class so we'll say Val number two int
and we want this to be concrete so we'll
get a give it a value of 50 and you'll
see that we have an error and the error
is property initializers are not allowed
in interfaces so this is one area where
interfaces differ from classes you can't
use property initializers within
interfaces so if we want this to be
concrete and we can make it concrete how
would we do that how would we want it so
that this is going to our interface
we'll return a particular value unless a
superclass overrides it well we have to
use a custom get so I'll indent here and
I'll say get and we can return whatever
we want here so we could say return 45
or we could do something like return
number times 100 or something like that
so now this is a concrete implementation
and you'll see that we're not getting
any errors up in the something class
even though it doesn't declare a number
to property and that's because this is a
concrete property so it's all taken care
of and the in the interface now if we
wanted to we could override it here
number two int and we could return
something else you know 25 again that's
perfectly okay but in this case we want
to let the interface handle that
property so we're not going to declare
it and that's really all there is to
interfaces I have one last thing to
mention though you'll recall that when
we were discussing classes we talked
about a backing field that you can
access within custom sets and gets using
the fields identifier
well properties in interfaces don't have
backing fields and so the set and the
get can't access a backing field so if
we come down here we can't do something
like field times 100 you'll see that we
get property in an interface cannot have
a backing field so this differs from
from classes where you can access the
backing field for properties using
within the custom set and get properties
and interfaces don't have a backing
field so obviously the field identifier
isn't going to work so that's something
to keep in mind when you're designing
your classes and interfaces all right
that's all for inheritance I'll see you
in the next video