OK so we learned in the last video that generic types are erased at runtime.
Now as you've seen you can still cast to a specific generic type though you might get a class cast exception
when you run and you can also use A-star projections and tasks to check whether a variable is an instance
of a specific type of collection.
Now the same holds true for function parameters because generics are a rased at runtime when a function
accepts a parameter with a generic type.
There is no way at runtime to determine which type it was invoked which is for example.
Let's say we have a function that wants to iterate through a list and return all the elements of a certain
type in the list.
So let's write a function that would do that sort of thing.
So we'll save fun get elements of type and it's going to accept a list a list of any and it wants to
return a list of T.
So the way that we would call a function like this is we would do something like vowel and we want big
decimals only equals and we'd say get elements of type and we're going to call this with big decimal
because we have to tell the compiler what type we want back when you have a T in the return type.
Then you tell the compiler this way that hey this function is of type Lisp big decimal.
I want this to return a list of big decimal and then we would pass in let's say a mixed list here containing
a bunch of mixed objects.
So now it's right.
The function body.
So we'll save our new list is going to be immutable list of T because we want to return the type of
lists that we were asked for and will say mutable list of.
And then we'll say for every element in the list that was passed to us if element is of type T add it
to the list
and at the end of course we'll return the list.
We turn the list to sell.
All sounds great.
Only we can't do it.
Actually I want to return new list here.
OK so this all sounds great but we can't do it.
We'll see we have an error here saying cannot check for instance of Eraste type T.
And so we have the same problem here within the function the runtime the JVM has no clue what t is.
So you can't do this it can't check because it doesn't know what t is.
As the error message says the instance the type is erased at runtime so it's not there for the JVM to
check.
Now back when we looked at functions we we touched on inline functions and we said that one scenario
that benefits from inline functions is when the function has a lambda as a parameter.
Another scenario for inline functions is when they have a generic type as a parameter because inline
function parameters can be what's called reified.
Now what does that mean.
Well reification is a Koplin feature that prevents the type from being erased at runtime.
If you declare a function as in line and a type parameter as a reified then you can check the generic
type at runtime.
So if we inline this function now we declare the generic type the type parameter here as reify then
we're going to be able to check the type at runtime.
So we're going to use reification to get around this error and we have to do two things in line the
function and reify the type parameter.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we'll declare the function as in line.
That's step 1.
And then instead of just t We're going to say reified T.
And you'll notice that when we do that we no longer have an error here.
So let's go ahead and test this function.
So we'll say Vau we'll call it mixed de-list and we want this to be a list of any and we'll say list
and we'll put a string.
We'll put an integer we'll put a big decimal.
Twenty two point five.
We'll put a I don't know what do we know.
What else do we want to put in here we'll put another string fall let's say and we'll put in another
big dust and all minus some weird number.
So now we've got two strings.
You've got an integer and we've got two big decimals and we're calling our get all elements of type
function and we're saying we want this function to return as a list that just contains the two big decimals.
So let's print the list we get back to see if indeed our function does that so we'll say for item in
big decimals only print the item.
Let's go ahead and run
and we get a list with our two big decimals.
So by inlining this function and declaring the parameter type here as reified the type is no longer
Eraste at runtime and we can actually do this checking now.
So let's go ahead and change this to a string to make sure that it's actually not just working with
decimals and will run again.
And this time we get our two strings.
Now there's a shorter way to write this function.
In fact we probably wouldn't even write it this way because there's a collections function that will
do this type of thing for us but it shows how by reifying the T parameter we can get at the generic
type inside the function.
The type is interfaced at runtime.
So you'd want to do this sort of thing when you need to check the type within a function.
Otherwise there's absolutely no reason to use reification.
So you only want to use reification if you need to check a type inside the function.
Now you can't mark classes properties or non inline functions as reified.
So you can't do something like this.
You can't say class something and then say you want this to be a reified t that doesn't work it'll say
only type parameters of inline functions can be reified.
You also can't use the T to create a new instance let me get rid of this.
So inside our function here we can't do something like this.
We can't say oh vowel c of type T equals t because it's going to tell you right away you can do that
type parameter T cannot be called as a function.
So you can't create new instances of type T within the function.
And the reason we're getting this error message that says it cannot be called as a function is because
the compiler isn't even considering that we might be trying to create a new instance where it just assumes
that we're trying to call a function.
Now there are a few other restrictions on the use of reify parameters.
I'm not going to go through them but the compiler will always let you know when you're trying to do
something that you're not allowed to do with reified parameters.
But as I said the only reason you want to use reification is if you want to check the type of T within
the function.
So if you don't need to do that don't use it.
And remember that in order to use a reify type parameter you have to inline the function.
This only works with inline functions.
OK so that's it for reification.
Are in our next video we're going to start looking at what's called variance.
And some people find this a difficult concept so hopefully the examples that we look at are going to
make it clear.
I'll see you in the next video.