In Kotlin, there's a way to declare a
class and define an instance at the same
time, and this is where the object
keyword comes in. Now there are three
typical use cases for the object keyword,
the first use case is singletons, the
second use case is what's called
companion objects and the third use case
is object expressions. So let's take a
look at each of these. Now you're
probably familiar with the singleton,
it's a common design pattern in Java,
we use it when we want one and only one
instance of a class during the running
of an application.
So in Java what we typically do is we
declare a class, it has a private
constructor and then the outside world
gets access to the single instance that
the class creates. And it gets access to
this instance using a static method.
Now when you want a singleton in Kotlin,
you'll use the object keyword because
there can only ever be one instance of
an object class. So when you declare an
object class, you're saying you want one
and only one instance of the class.
So let's suppose that this application that
we've been working on that has a bunch
of printer classes in it, let's suppose
that this application is for our company
and that company wants the same
copyright message, the same tagline etc
on all of its communications. Now, we
could have a company communication
singleton that contains functions that
return all the different bits of
messaging the company application might
want to use, so let's create a new file
for our singleton in the project.
So we'll right click on the package and
we'll go to new Kotlin file or class,
by this point I hope you've realized that
it doesn't matter if we choose file or
class or interface because choosing a
type from the drop-down just means that
the IDE will save us some typing, but we
want to create an object class here.
So let's select object from the list and
we'll call this company communications-
communications there we go.
Ok, so now we have a new file
and it's the IDE is included the object
keyword, that's the first thing to learn
about object classes, you use the keyword
object to declare them, you'll notice
there's no class keyword here,
it's just object. Okay, so now we can go
ahead and add properties and functions,
but we can't have any constructors
because an object declaration declares
and creates an instance at the same time.
So having constructors wouldn't make
sense, so we're going to add two
functions one that returns the company's
tagline and one that returns a copyright
statement. So for the copyright statement
we'll get the current year dynamically,
we won't hard code it. So we'll say val
current year equals year dot now dot value,
don't need a semicolon we're not
writing Java. And then we'll add a
function get tagline and the tagline for
this will be our company rocks. And then
we're going to add a function to get the
copyright line and the copyright line
will just be copyright and we'll use the
unicode character for the copyright
symbol and we'll add the current year,
our company all rights reserved. Now one
thing I didn't point out here is that
we're using java's year class and we
don't have to do anything special to do
that. You'll see we've imported Java dot
time dot year, so once again you can just
most of the time just use Java
seamlessly from Kotlin without having to
do anything special. Okay, so I'm going to
add a main function to this file, even
though we've got one in printer just so
I don't have to keep going back to
printer to run. So let's add main and
we're just going to print out our tag
line and our copyright line so print line
company communications dot get tag line
and print line company communications
dot get copyright line. So we're calling
the two functions here and as
you can see, when you want to use an
object declaration, you use it the same
way that you use an instance of a class,
except you use the class name. There's
only ever one instance of the object and
it's created the first time the class is
used. So the one instance of the company
communications object is going to be
created here on line six the first time
that we want to actually use an instance.
So essentially, we have a singleton
object called company communications and
this is how you do singletons in Kotlin.
You'll see there's no constructor here,
so nobody from the outside can actually
create an instance of this class, the one
single instance is created the first
time you use the class. Let's run just to
show that this works and as you can see,
I ran the other main function, so I'll
run from here and now we get the right
main function, so we see our tagline and
we see the copyright line that we created,
Now object declarations can extend
classes and implement interfaces, so if
you want it to create a singleton that
extends another class or that implements
an interface, that would be fine but this
is all there is to creating singletons
and Kotlin. Just create a class with
objects in front of it and then go ahead
and use the properties of the functions
using the class name. So that's the first
use case for the object keyword is when
you want to create a singleton.