We've seen how we can use covariance to preserve subtyping.
Now we're going to take a look at what's called contravariant.
So we're going to start with an example.
So I've carried over just the Rose and the flower classes from the last video so I'm going to create
an interface called Flower care so interface flower care of tea.
And it just has one function called Prun and that function will prune a flower.
So now I'm going to add back the garden class I didn't carried over because I want to do something a
little bit different with it so I will say.
Class garden and it'll be of tea flour and it's going to accept a flower's property which is a list
of tea and it's also going to accept an instance that implements the flower care interface so Val flower
care and that'll be of tight flower care of tea.
And then the garden is going to have the pink flower function.
It takes an eye and that will return to the ice flower in the garden.
OK so now let's go out to our main function and let's create a Rose Garden now in order to do that.
Now we're going to have to pass a list of Rose and we're also going to have to pass an instance flower
care of rose so let's create the flower care instance first.
So we'll save Val and I'll call it roast tender equals and we're going to make this in a not anonymous
instance so we'll say object and we want it to be of tight flower care Rose.
And then of course right now we're going to get an error because we have to implement the function in
the interface.
So we'll go ahead and do that.
We'll say override fun Prun and we're going to take a rose and we'll just print out.
I'm pruning a rose so that's it.
And now we can create our garden so we'll save our Rose Garden equals a garden of Rose and we're going
to pass a new list of roses solaced Rose.
Rose our poor little garden only those two roses in it.
And then of course we'll pass the rose tender.
So that's all fine that all works.
So now let's add another function to our garden.
We can pick a flower.
We're taking a flower care instance so let's use it for some things so we'll say fun.
Ken flower and it'll also ask you what flower you want to tend to apparently tending to the entire garden
would be a little bit too strenuous and it'll just say flower care or prune and pass along the flower
that you want pruned.
Actually that should be flowers I flowers by.
So you can pick a flower and you can tend to a flower and tending to the flower means you're going to
prune it.
All right so now let's turn to two of our roses so we have a Rose Garden up here and we'll say well
attend to one of our two roses.
We don't want to overexerted our garden here so we'll say Rose Garden Daut 10 flower and will tend to
the first rose.
Now if we run at this point
we'll see I'm pruning a rose.
So what's happening here is we've created a rose garden and our garden has two roses in it and we've
passed the rose tender and so here in the garden class when we call 10 flower it's going to call you
see flower care object that we passed in to invoke Prun we passed in this anonymous instance and it's
implementation of Prun just prints out I'm pruning a rose so far so good.
So we also want a daffodil garden now so let's go ahead and create a daffodil garden of course and we're
going to have to create declasse so we'll say class daffodil.
And it also extends flower fullfil Yes.
Daffodil that looks better.
And then we'll do the same thing for the daffodil garden that we did for the Rose Garden and we'll see
how daffodil tender and again will create an anonymous object of flower care except this time we want
a flower care of daffodil
and we'll say override fun prune flower.
But this time it's going to be a daffodil and this time we'll say prune line.
I'm pruning a daffodil and that should be flower care.
I'm just wondering why the compiler screaming at me and it's because I had flour rather than flour care.
OK so let's now tend actually we have to create our daffodil garden first and then we'll will tend to
it so will say daffodil garden equals garden daffodil and we'll make this garden we'll give it Daffer
Dale we'll give it three flowers
and we're going to pass our daffodil tender and I need a closing bracket here.
OK.
So that's all fine.
And now let's tend to a flower just like we did with the Rose Garden.
So dark little tender dot can actually daffodil garden rather top ten flower and will tend flower number
two this time.
So let's run
.
And when we tend to our Rose Garden we're pruning your rose and when we tend to our daffodil garden
we're pruning a daffodil.
Now everything's working but if you look at this code let me just close up the console for a minute.
If you look at this code this is repetitive.
And what would happen if we also wanted a daisy garden and a lily garden etc..
We don't want to have to be repeating code like this for every possible type of garden that we might
have.
Now we can't do anything about creating the different types of garden because there are different instances
and we can't really do anything about calling 10 flower but if we look at our anonymous objects here
so this rose tender here and this rose tender here or daffodil tender in this case they're doing the
same thing in both cases they're just printing out a line of text so it would be nice if we could just
use the same object.
But right now we can't.
If we try to pass the rose tender to the daffodil garden the compiler is going to complain.
Let's try it.
So let's change this two rows tender instead
and the compiler says no I'm expecting a flower care daffodil this is a daffodil garden not a rose garden
so why are you giving me a rose flower care instance.
Now we could try creating a flower tenderer and you know use that for both roses and daffodils.
Let's try that.
So I'm going to switch this back to Daffodil for now.
Daffodil tender.
And then let's go up here and we'll say about flower tender.
So this is the all mighty flower tender and be an object of flower care except this time it will tend
to a flower because after all both roses and daffodils are flowers and we'll say override fun prune
flower this time you want to flower and this will say print line capital F for that flower and this
will say print line.
I'm tending a flower.
OK so we've got a flower tender now.
It'll take flower care flower.
Let's try passing it to our Rose Garden.
So instead of a rose tender we'll say Well go ahead and use a flower tender and we can't because it's
going to say you have a Rose Garden.
I want a flower care flower.
Now I think this might be a little bit of a bug here because you can see found at Lake throws its hands
up and says I don't know what I found.
I think it's probably a little bug in intelligence right now but we know that what it's it's doing this
because it's saying that the type of flower care that you pass has to be T.
So if t is a rose and I want a list of rows and I want to flower care of Rose I will not accept a flower
care of flower even though Rose is a subclass of flower.
So we want the team matching the matching of T.
Here we want it to be a little more relaxed.
I mean roses and daffodils are both flowers so a Rose Garden a daffodil garden should accept a flower
care instance that cares for flowers.
So this is where contravariant comes in.
Contravariant is the opposite of covariance.
When we use covariance we're preserving the subtyping when we use contravariant.
We're going in the opposite direction so we're starting at a subclass and we wind to accept instances
of that subclass or any of its superclasses.
You can remember that we were doing the opposite with covariance So rather than saying we want to accept
a flower and all of its subclasses were saying we want to accept a rose and all of it superclasses.
So when it comes to contravariant we're looking up the inheritance tree rather than down the inheritance
tree.
Now some people have characterized this as flipping the inheritance tree upside down and so in this
case Rose would become the super type of flower that always makes my brain hiccup because I'm thinking
but Rose isn't a super type of flower so I I find it more intuitive to just say you're starting at a
point on the inheritance tree and if you want to accept that point in anything above it then it's contravariant.
And if you want to accept that point in anything below it then it's covariance.
But for you maybe the notion of flipping the tree on its ear essentially and making subtypes become
super types maybe that's more intuitive for you.
So how do we make this happen in code.
How can we say in this case that when we're given a subclass of flour we also want to accept flour.
Well when we discussed covariance we discussed the in and out positions and we said that covariant types
appear at the out position.
So maybe it won't be a surprise to you that contravariant types use the in position and we know that
parameters occur at the in position so let's do the following down here in flower care.
We're going to say all right we want you to be contravariant because t should accept whatever T is in
any of its superclasses.
So if we have a garden of roses we want it to accept a flower care of flour because flour is a superclass
of Rose.
So we've just made our interface contravariant by adding in before the type So we're saying here that
if we that we will accept any types that have T in their inheritance tree.
So if t is a direct or indirect superclass of a class then the class will match T.
So now we can create one implementation of flower care for flower and both the rows and the daffodil
gardens will accept it because flour is a superclass of rows and it's also a superclass of daffodil.
So a garden of Rose will be perfectly happy with a flower care a flower because we've made the flower
care type contravariant and therefore a rose garden will accept a flower care a flower.
So first let's go back to the flower care a flower that we created instead of just printing out.
I'm tending a flower.
Let's make it say something more specific so we'll say I'm tending a pen I'll open up an expression
and we'll say a flower name.
Now of course we don't have a name property in the flower class right now so we'll go down and fix that.
So we'll say the flower takes a vowel name as the string.
And now of course our subclasses are going to complain because they're saying now the primary constructor
actually wants something.
So for Rose we're going to pass that Rose and for a daffodil we're going to pass it.
Daffodil So now we'll use a flower care flower for both gardens.
We've already done it for the Rose Garden and you'll let me go here.
Did I change it.
No.
So you'll notice that for the Rose Garden it's no longer complaining.
The error went away.
So let's also change our daffodil garden here so we'll say we want to pass in the flower tender now.
And that's not complaining either.
So let's run
and we'll see.
I'm tending a rose and I'm tending a daffodil rather than I am pruning so for sure we're calling this
implementation.
That's what we're passing to both of our gardens and you can see now that the roast tender and the daffodil
tender are not used and we're no longer repeating ourselves now.
We could go ahead and delete the rows tender and delete the daffodil tender because we no longer need
them.
We don't have to create a in an instance of flower care for every single possible type of flower.
So that's contravariant.
Just as with covariance using contravariant comes with a price.
Remember one where we make something covariant.
We can no longer write to it.
I guess it won't come as any surprise that when it comes to contravariant we can't reheat them we can
only write it so we can only use contravariant classes as parameters.
We can't use them as return types of functions because the return type is in the out position so we
can't do the following if we go back down to our interface which is now contravariant.
We can't do something like fun pick T because the compiler is going to say nope type parameter T is
declared as in but occurs in the out position so we have the opposite situation now compared to something
that's covariant.
Now why this restriction.
We went through that with covariance So why do we have this restriction for contravariant.
Let me just comment that out.
Well because if we didn't have this restriction we could run into the following situation if we could
implement pick.
So pretend that we can implement this function that the compiler is not giving us an error.
If we could do that we could write code like the following and obviously this is not going to compile
but just to show you we could save Val flower tender and I guess I'll call it too because we already
have one equals object.
Flower care flower and will say overbright fun prune and for the prune will take it.
Flower equals print line.
You know I'll just say I'm tending a flower because this is just for illustration purposes.
And now we'll say all right let's override pick now.
Obviously we can't do that but pretend we're overwriting pick.
This returns a flower and we'll say we return flower or some random flower.
We're getting this error because there's not actually a pick function so I'll just take this out just
so we don't get an error.
And then down in our garden class instead of 10 flower or rather pick flower just returning flowers.
We could change this to use our flower care so we'd say we're going to do flower care dot pick and we're
going to pick a flower flower care this won't work because we can't actually implement flower care pick
in the flower care interface but pretend we could.
So if we now come up here and we say we create a rose garden so.
Val rose garden too and we're going to pass it.
We're going to create a garden of Rose and we'll give it a list of just one flower and then we'll pass
it our flower tender too because that will work.
And then we say Rose Garden to dot pick flower let's say zero.
If we come up to here we're not going to get a rose.
We're actually going to get some random flower.
In fact this would work if I save Val.
Rose Rose equals this works.
Nothing.
Nothing fails here and we're asking for a rose but because we've created this garden with a flower tender
too and pretending that we could implement this pick we could return any type of flour from here.
We're returning a flower some random flower we're not returning a rose.
So the problem is if we were allowed to do this sort of thing when we're dealing with contravariant
interfaces and we do something like this we're not guaranteed to get the type that we want.
It's always ok to treat a rose like a flower but it's not okay to treat a flower like a rose.
And so that's why it's OK to accept contravariant types as parameters and act on them because it's OK
to treat a rose like a flower.
We know that an instance can always be treated like one of its superclasses.
So it's fine to treat a rose like a flower but the opposite isn't true.
You can't treat a flower like a rose it might be a rose but it might not be.
So once again using contravariant it comes with a price so that's covariance covariances contravariant
you can use them when you want them matching for tea to be a bit more relaxed.
You use covariance when you want subtyping to be preserved in other words t will match T and all of
its subclasses and you use contravariant when you want to match T and any of it superclasses.
And as I said before I've seen contravariant described as flipping the inheritance tree for a class.
So in the flower case when we use contravariant we'd say Rose becomes the supertype of flower.
But the way I look at it is which way are you looking at the inheritance tree.
If you start with a class do you want to accept a class and all of its superclasses Well then you're
dealing with contravariant So you want to accept a class in all its subclasses then you're dealing with
covariance So when you started a point on a tree are you looking up the tree that's contravariant.
Are you looking down the tree that's covariance.
I find that more intuitive but you might not.
So when you're dealing with covariant and contravariant what you're actually doing is widening a generic
type to include either a class and its subclasses or a class and it's superclasses.
Now what we've looked at so far for both covariance and contravariant is call declarations site variants
because we're doing it when we declare a class or an interface.
So here we've made the interface contravariant and we've done that on the interface declaration.
And here we've made what we did in the other project we made garden covariant by including out when
we declared garden.
So we made it covariant by including out on the class statement and that is called declaration site
variance and you don't have declarations site variants in Java in Java you only have use site variants
and you have the same thing in Katlin and that's what we're going to look at next.
I'll see you in the next video.