Alright, the third use for companion
objects is object expressions which are
essentially anonymous object, so you use
them where you'd use anonymous classes
in Java. So let's say we have the
following interface, let's say interface some
interface and it'll just have one
function must implement that accepts an
int and returns a string. So that's our
simple interface and now we'll add a
function that accepts some interface as
a parameter, so we'll say fun want some
interface and I'll take a parameter si
and whatever instances passed has to
have implemented some interface and all
it's going to do is print out printing
from wants some interface and what it'll
do is it'll call the must implement
function inside the interface and it'll
pass it 22, the implementation will take
22 and do something with it. So we can
use an object expression to call this
function, so let's do that from the main
method, let's come up here and we'll say
wants some interface and so this function,
as we just saw once an instance that
implements this interface. So we're going
to create basically an anonymous
instance using the object keyword.
So we'll say object and this object
implements some interface, will open up
curly braces and will override the
function must implement. Now here, I could
hit enter or select this and IntelliJ
will generate the function definition
with a to do body, but I want an
expression body for this function I don't
find a block body, so I'm not going to do
that, I'm just going to type it out.
So must implement and this function takes
an int and we're going to return the
string this is from must implement
implement and what this function will do
is take the number that's passed to it
and multiply it by 100, so nothing
nothing or shattering. So what's going to
happen here is this is an object that
implements must implement, so it's going
to be passed to this function and this
function is going to call the must
implement method with the value 22,
so the value of 22 is going to be passed in
here and so we're going to multiply 22
by hundreds, so we expect to see the
value 2200 printed. Let's run and sure
enough, we see that we're printing from
want some interface and then this is
from must implement, so we're getting
print line here and this is the value
that it's printing, so it's printing the
string being returned from this function
which is this. Now, a couple of notes here,
first of all when you want to use an
object expression, the instance that's
created isn't a singleton, so even though
you've used the object keyword here,
the instance that's created here is not a
singleton, it's used and then it's
discarded. And so if we were to call you
know if this was inside a function body,
that you were calling a lots of times
you'd be getting a new instance every
single time. So it's not as if one
instance is created here and then it's
kept forever, if you use an object
expression for the same class again or
the same interface in this case, then
another instance will be created. Also,
unlike in Java the object expression
inside here can access variables from
outside it, local variables and these
variables don't have to be final,
in other words they don't have to be val
variables, they can also be var variables
so let's give this a shot, we'll say var this is
mutable, in other words it's not final
and we'll give this the value of 45 and
then in here
now I do want a function body, so let me
add some curly braces here. So in here
I'm going to say we need to return this
now, it returns a string and I need to
add the return value here and in here
I can go you know this is mutable plus
plus and I'm not going to get an error
here even though this is accessing a
variable outside it and this variable is
not final, so if I print this is mutable
here, I don't know why IntelliJ imported
a class here from Java code, that's why
these errors are coming up, so we'll get
rid of them let's run and now we'll see
46 printed for this is mutable, so the
object expression was able to access
this variable even though it's not a val
variable which is essentially saying
it's not final. Now you can assign object
expressions to variables and they can
also implement interfaces as we've seen,
but not only that they can implement
multiple interfaces, which you can't do
in Java, so if we had another interface
that we wanted to implement, we could
actually tack that on, I'm not sure how
useful that is, because most of the time
you're going to be doing what we did
here and calling a function that just
wants a parameter of a single interface,
but you can do it.
Okay so you've seen the three use cases
for the object keyword, you can use
object when you want to create a
singleton, you can use object when you
want to use companion objects and when
you want to have private constructors
and you can use object when you want to
create anonymous instances.