OK so you've seen declarations site variants.
Now we're going to take a look at you site variants.
So let's say we have a bunch of car classes going to declare the car class here and I'll want to extend
it so I'll declare it is open.
So open class car and then we're also going to have Ford and Toyota classes all say class Toyota and
that extends car and class Ford which also extends car.
And now let's write a function that copies one list of cars to another this is a pretty trivial function.
But I am going somewhere with this so will say fine copy cars and this function once a mutable list
of car for the source and it also once a leader will Mr. list of cars for the list of cars for the destination
and then it will say for car in source and each car to the destination.
And that's it.
Nothing earth shattering So all this function does is takes the source list and copies it to the destination
list.
So let's call this function from within the main function.
So we'll say Well cars one equals mutable list of.
And we'll give this a few cars.
So we'll say car car and then we'll save all cars 2 equals and I'm going to take this one because we're
going to give it an empty list.
So we'll see a beautiful list of car and it'll just be an empty list and then we'll see coffee cars
cars one cars two cars one and we don't get any errors no problems no errors.
But now let's say that we want to call our copy car's function and do the exact same thing for Fords.
So I'm going to copy and paste this.
But this time I'm going to say that we want Fords.
And so I'm going to give it a couple of Fords here Ford and Ford and we'll take Fords to here.
And we want to amenable this to Ford to come back and will copy Ford's one to Ford's too.
Well as you might have guessed from what we've covered with generics so far we can't do it because generic
types are invariant.
So the compiler is complaining.
It wants a two readable lists here.
Once immutable list of car for the source and a mutable list of car for the destination and we're providing
it with a mutable list of Fords and it doesn't like that.
And as we've covered in variant generic types are invariant.
Now we don't want to have to create a copy car's function for every type of possible car that we could
have.
And all the tricks that we've looked at so far such as covariance contravariant specifying an upper
bound in the function signature while they're all there to help us avoid this bloat and repetition.
They let us relax the invariant taping or somewhat say to widen that so that we don't have to write
a different version of a function like copy cars for example for every time we want to do something
with a different type we can use one function for related types.
So instead of using car let's use T in the copy car signature so we'll say OK let's use t so fun t.
Copy cars and we want immutable list of T here and a mutable list of T here.
And that works.
We can now call this function for both cars and Fords now because Fords are cars.
We also want to be able to do this.
We want to be able to say copy cars and we want to copy our for it's into our cars too but we can't
do it because he has to be the same for everything.
So the source type and the destination type have to be the same and here they're not we're passing immutable
list of Ford for the source but we're passing immutable list of car for the destination but we should
be able to do it because we can do this.
We can say Val cars three and we'll make it immutable list mutable list of car and we can give it a
mutable list of Fords.
That's not a problem because Fords are also cars.
So if we can do this why can't we pass do this.
Why can't we say well hey we're copying Fords to list of Fords to a list of cars so we should be able
to do that.
So just like we can add any type of instance to a list of any we should be able to create a list and
assign it to a list of its superclass type and we can.
But how can we get a similar thing to work for our function so that it lets us do this so we can give
it a forward list and say copy this into a list of car.
Now setting an upper bound won't help us here because T has to be the same if we set an upper bound
if we were to add an upper bound here.
Car is going to want you know it's still going to want source and destination to be both be car or both
b Fords or both B.
Toyota's but let's try it.
So we'll say you know we'll take car or any of its subclasses here.
But as you can see it doesn't work.
So let's take a closer look at our function here and let's say that we only read the original list and
we only write the destination list.
So this function doesn't change the source and it doesn't read the destination.
So think about this.
Where have we heard that before that if you do something you can only read but you can't.
Right.
Or if you do something you can only write but you can't read.
Well that sounds like some of the restrictions around using covariance and contravariant.
So perhaps we can use covariance and contravariant here just with an individual function rather than
doing it at a declaration site like on an interface or a class because we meet the requirements for
covariance and Koncz of variance.
The destination list is only written so that sounds like it could be contravariant and the source list
is only read.
So that sounds like it could be covariant.
So in this case we want the original list the source lists to be a car or any of its subclasses.
And that also sounds like covariance.
So we don't write the original list.
We only read it and we want the t here to be able to be a car or any of its subclasses.
That's covariance.
So let's try adding out to t here.
Let's try making just this one parameter here covariant and see if that helps us and boom our error
went away.
So now we can pass a car or any subclass of car to the copy car's function as the source of the coffee.
So what we've done here is we've used use site variants because a car class and its subclasses there
are not covariant.
We have not made any car class or any of its subclasses covariant.
So we're not using declarations site covariance we're using you cite covariance.
We're making a parameter type covariant and we can do this when the implementation of a function meets
the requirements for making something covariant or contravariant.
Now as I said this could also be in.
That would work but we don't really need that here.
So I'm going to take that out now doing this sort of thing you cite a variance in contravariant.
Or rather you cite covariant and contravariant is also called type projection.
And as I said you can use the same technique to make something contravariant and you can do the parameter
types so as we've seen.
But you can also do it with function return types.
Now a good use for this is when you're working with a third party class that's invariant and you want
to write functions that use instances of the class any covariant way.
Now you say variants is equivalent to wildcards in Java.
So in Java we can do the following.
I'll just do that down here.
It'll cause compiler errors but we can do something like this in Java.
We can say extends car and that's covariance because you're saying you'll accept anything and it's subclasses
so you'll accept car and anything that extends car.
Now you wouldn't want to create a list variable of this type because you wouldn't be able to add anything
to it because remember you can't write to a covariant instance.
So you wouldn't in Java code use this as a variable type but where you will see it a lot in Java is
in method declarations and then in Java the following corresponds to contravariant is if we say lefse
super car that's contravariant because here you're saying all except Carr and any of its superclasses.
But once again you wouldn't want to use this to declare a variable of that type because you wouldn't
be able to read it.
So where you're going to see the use of wildcards like this is in method declarations because Java doesn't
have declarations site variants there are classes in the JDK that use generics and use say variants
on all the methods in the class in cotland if you want all the methods to be covariant or contravariant
you just use declaration site covariance or contravariant the way that we did it with our garden class
and our flower care interface.
But in Java you'd have to do it on every member Massad and that can make for some cluttered class and
interface definitions.
All right so that's covariance and contravariant both declarations site and you site.
And that's it for generics.
I'll see you in the next video.