Welcome to the Kotlin for Java
developers course. Thank you for
investing in the course and give
yourself a pat on the back for investing
in yourself. In this course, you're going
to leverage your Java knowledge to get
up to speed quickly with Kotlin, so that
brings us to who this course is for.
This isn't a beginner's programming course.
I assume that you have some experience
with Java, so I won't be going over basic
concepts like what is a variable,
what does encapsulation mean, what is a
conditional statement etc. We're going to
hit the ground running, so if you've
coded in Java, this is the course for you.
Now you don't have to be a Java expert
and know everything there is to know
about Java because frankly few
developers do, but you do need to know
more than hello world and you should
understand object-oriented concepts like
encapsulation, polymorphism, inheritance
and obstruction, all that good stuff.
Now if you don't know any programming
languages, if this is the first
programming course you're taking or if
the only Java program you've ever
written is HelloWorld, you should take a
Java course before you do this one and
I'd recommend Tim Buchalka's Java
master class, if you've taken Tim's
course and you've at least watched the
master class beyond the introductory
topics, then you know enough to take this
course. Now if you don't have experience
with Java, but you do with another
object-oriented language and so you
understand object-oriented concepts,
you'll probably be able to muddle along
in this course. So let's go over what
we're going to cover in this course.
First I'll tell you a bit about the
Kotlin language and then you'll watch
me convert a Java application to Kotlin
to give you a taste of the language
then we're going to go over some quick
differences between Kotlin and Java,
for example you don't have to use semicolons
at the end of statements in Kotlin, I bet
you'll all be crying over that, we'll
also code the classic hello world
application because let's face it,
it wouldn't be a programming course if we
didn't do that but on top of that just
that simple application will allow me
to point out a few key differences
between Kotlin and Java and after that
we're going to look at variable
declarations in Kotlin because as you'll
see, they're quite different than the way
that you declare variables in Java, after
that we're going to take a look at data
types in Kotlin and we'll also see how
Kotlin protects against null pointer exceptions.
You might have heard that you can't get
a null pointer exception in Kotlin,
that's not quite true but it's pretty
hard to get them. After that, we're going
to take a look at the object-oriented
topics, we're going to look at classes
and how you declare them, we're going to
look at methods and functions, yes
functions, we're going to look at how
constructors are handled in Kotlin this
is one area where it's very different
from the way they're handled in Java and
it does cause some developers some
difficulty when they first start working
with Kotlin, so we'll look at primary and
secondary constructors will also look at
enums, we're going to look at the
singleton in factory patterns and how
you code those in Kotlin and other good
stuff, then we're going to take a look at
loops I say loops but really it will be
focused on the for loop because the
other loops are pretty much the same in
Kotlin but there has been a significant
change to the for loop in Kotlin from
what you can do in Java. Now related to
this is a feature in Kotlin called
ranges, so we're going to take a look at
them as well. After that we're going to
take a look at lambda expressions and
also collections and generics.
Now lambdas and collections aren't that much
different from what they are in Java but
you can do more with them in Kotlin.
Kotlin has enhanced lambdas and
collections. Now for generics, we're going
to cover variants that's both covariance
and contravariance and again this is
another topic that some developers find
it hard to wrap their head around,
so we're going to spend some time on both
of those concepts, yes so as I just said
we'll be covering generics and under
that topic, we are definitely taking a
look at variants. Now after that, we're
going to take a look
at i/o more specifically file i/o because
this is where Kotlin has added some
convenience functions that we can use
when we want to read files in particular,
it's kind of focused on enhancing
reading text files, so we'll take a look
at that and then we're going to look at
Java interoperability. Kotlin has been
designed from the ground up to be
interoperable with Java and so you can
call Kotlin from Java and you can call
Java from Kotlin .Now most of the time
when you do this, you don't have to do
anything special but there are cases and
areas where you do have to do something
a little differently or where you might
want to influence the behavior of the
Kotlin compiler when you know that
you're going to be mixing Kotlin and Java
and so we're going to take a look at all
of that and there are going to be
challenges along the way where you'll
get a chance to practice what you've
learned. Now at the end of the course,
we're going to revisit the code that I'm
going to convert in the next section,
so we'll revisit the Kotlin code, the code
that I write as I convert the Java
application because by the end of the
course, you're going to understand all of
the code and you'll also be able
hopefully to explain it to somebody if
they were to ask you what the code is
doing. So as you can see we have a lot to
cover, so let's get started.
I'll see you in the next video.