now we're going to take a look at lambda
expressions now lambdas themselves don't
differ that much between cotton and Java
the syntax is pretty much the same so as
usual we'll just focus on what's
noteworthy about Kotlin now lambdas in
Kotlin have to be within curly braces
and you can store them in variables
there's nothing new there but you can
also call them directly using the run
function so let's take a look at that
I've already created the usual project
and package etc so inside the main
function we'll say run and then we're
going to run a lambda so we'll open
curly braces and we'll say print line
I'm in a lambda and that's it so this is
a library function that will run lambdas
for you and if we run the application
we'll see I'm in a lambda so this is a
quick way to play with lambdas and and
print them out and see what you'll get
alright so we often use lambdas with
collection so let's create a collection
to play with we're going to go into
collections in more depth
after we've covered lambdas but for now
we'll just create a list that we can
play with and we're going to use our
familiar employee class so I'll go ahead
and declare that first so class employee
and we'll have a first name property
that will be string a last name property
that will be a string and we'll also add
a start your property which will be an
int and we want all of these to be
selves
there we go okay so there's nothing new
here we've seen our employee class
before
so now we'll create a list of employee
I'm going to comment out the run I'll
just leave it here if you download the
code you'll be able to see it and we'll
say Val employees equals and we want a
list of and let's create a few employees
so we'll say John our usual employees
John works a lot a lot of companies here
John Smith 2012 and we'll have Jane
Wilson and she started with the company
in 2015 we'll have Mary Johnson
then she started in 2010 and finally
we'll have Mike Jones and he started in
2002 all right so now we'll use lambdas
with some of the collections functions
as I said we'll go more in-depth into
collections after we've covered lambdas
so let's find the longest-serving
employee so the way that we can do that
and we'll print out the answer here is
we can say employees and then we can use
a function called min buy and this
function wants a lambda and so we'll
give it a lambda and we'll say e for
employee e dot start here so what we're
doing here is we're passing a lambda as
a parameter to the min by function and
we're saying that we want to find the
employee with the minimum start year
because that will be the longest-serving
employee that'll be the one whose work
at the company the longest so the lambda
takes one argument this will be review
but just to make sure we're all on the
same page the lambda is taking one
argument that we've called E and for
every e so for every element in the
collection we will become that element
and then we're going to look at the
start year and the min by function we'll
figure out
the lowest start year so obviously under
the covers this will be a loop because
every employee and they'll in the list
has to be examined now we could have put
the lambda inside parentheses so we
could have gone like this and that works
you'll see we don't get any compiler
errors but that's a little bit more
difficult to read the rule is that you
can move a lambda outside the
parentheses when it's the last parameter
in the function call and in this case it
is the last parameter because it's the
only parameter but if men by took two
parameters and the lambda was the last
one we could still move the lambda
outside the parentheses but if the
lambda isn't the last argument if men by
took two arguments in the lambda was in
the first position then we would not be
able to move it outside the parentheses
so this is something to keep in mind
when you write your own functions that
take lambdas if you want to be able to
write the lambda outside the parentheses
and make sure you make it the last
parameter don't make it the first
parameter or another parameter that
isn't the last one so I'm going to move
this back outside the parentheses
because it's clearer so let's run this
now and that's not very helpful
we haven't overridden the to string
method the employees dot min by function
is returning an employee but we haven't
overridden two strings so we're getting
the usual reference now I could override
to string but I'm going to take the easy
route here and just change this to a
data class because all it's doing is
storing state and as we know with data
classes we get a nice two string version
for free so now that I've done that
let's run again and now we'll see that
our longest-serving employee is Mike
Jones he started in 2002 and everybody
else started after him so we have found
our longest-serving employee now we can
make this print line statement a lot
more concise let me put a line a blank
line here so you can see it better so we
can make this even more concise
and rlm that we're not specifying the
type of e because the compiler can infer
it now there will be cases when the
compiler cannot infer it and so you'll
have to specify the type and when you
have to do that you would do it in the
usual way using a colon and then the
type so we could do this and that's the
exact same thing so this is just saying
that the lambda is taking an argument of
type employee but in this case the
compiler can infer it so we don't need
it now as you've seen we have the
special it parameter that we've used
before and we can also use it here when
there's only one parameter and the
compiler can infer the type we can
simply use it we don't have to declare
the parameter like we're doing here
because the compiler will understand
that it is the parameter to the lambda
so we can make this even more concise by
just changing this whole thing to it and
because there's only one argument the
compiler knows that this is actually the
argument to the lambda so if we run now
we'll get the same result okay so let's
talk about scoping lambdas can access
local variables as long as they're
declared before the lambda when you use
a lambda within a function they can also
access the function parameters so let's
try these things out we'll use the run
function for this
so we'll say var num equals 10 and then
we'll say run and inside our lambda
we're going to add 15 to num and then
we'll print line num let's go ahead and
run and we'll see that num is now 25 now
this was trivial but it does show that
you can access local variables from
within lambdas but more importantly
because that's not different from Java
num is a var not a vowel so it's mutable
but we can still access it from within
the lambda now I've mentioned this a
couple of times before this differs from
Java where you can only access final
local variables within lambdas and
anonymous classes I mean how many times
do we write code in Java and then when
we compile it we get the error that
we're trying to access a local variable
that isn't final so we don't have to
worry about that in Kotlin now I also
mention that the local variable you're
trying to access has to be declared
before the lambda so if I comment this
out and then I say you know are num
equals ten obviously that's not going to
work because the compiler is only going
to actually know about this variable and
generate this variable after the lambda
so obviously the lambda can't access it
so let's put things back to the way they
were all right so now let's try using a
function parameter in a lambda so for
this we're going to write a simple
function so we'll say fun use parameter
[Music]
and we'll take our list of employee ie
and we'll also take a number an integer
and then we'll say employee is dot for
each and for each employee will print
line the first link the first name and
we'll also print line num obviously this
is a really really dumb example but just
wanted to show you that you can access
function parameters from within lambdas
however we can't change num because
function parameters are Val variables so
if we do something like this we'll see
that right away we get Val cannot be
reassigned so when you're referencing
function parameters from within lambdas
you can't change them but you can use
them now I've mentioned member
references before so let's briefly
revisit them you can use a member
reference in place of a lambda
expression when all the lambda does is
access a property or when it calls a
top-level function that doesn't take any
parameters so let's take a look at some
examples let's go back to when we're
calling min by and we can see that all
we're doing inside the lambda is
referencing a property so this is one
Kay
where we can replace the lambda with
what's called a member reference so
instead of doing this we can do the
following we can say employee start here
so once we use a member reference at
that point we do have to put the member
reference inside parentheses so we can't
have this outside parenthesis and as you
can see all we're doing here is
providing the class name and then the
property that we want to access and this
is called the double colon right here
and if we run now we'll get the same
result Mike with who started it in 2002
so let's try a function now I'm going to
write another really simple function fun
top-level then all this function we'll
do is print line I'm in a function so if
we want to use this function in our
lambda now we'll just use our handy run
again I'll comment this out so we'll use
our handy run function to do this so
we'll do say run and now we need to put
this inside parentheses and because it's
a top-level function we just used a
double colon right off the bat and then
we call top level and you'll see that
there's no parentheses here because when
you do this with the top-level function
it can't accept arguments in fact right
down here you'll see it's asking for a
block with no parentheses it'll it can
have a return value but no parentheses
so let's run this now and we'll see I'm
in a function now one syntax isn't
better than the other so it's up to you
which one you want to use you might be
told what to use if you're working for a
company and they have a style guide you
might be told you know when you can use
a member reference use a member
reference or you might be told not to
use them but one form isn't more
efficient than the other form okay
that's it for this video and the next
one we'll start taking a look at what's
called lambdas with receivers