All right so let's touch on a few things you need to be aware of when calling Java from Cartland.
Now we've seen that when we want to use a Java class we can just go ahead and use it.
I've gone ahead and created a car class in Java and if you take a look at it.
Doesn't that look verbose.
Now compare to the car class that we've sometimes worked with in Kallen and we haven't even implemented
to straightening or equals.
And this code looks really verbose now.
Anyway this isn't doing anything special We've got the color model and year fields and then we just
have a constructor that initializes those values and then these sets and gets.
So let's go to Scotland file now and let's create an instance of this car class so we'll say vowel car
equals car and we'll make the car blue and we'll make it a Ford and we'll make it a 2015 model and you
can see that we can do that in tele automatically added the import for us and we can treat it like we
can treat any cotland class from just looking at this code you wouldn't know whether you're dealing
with a Katlin class or a Java class.
Now we've already touched on a couple of places where you do have to be aware that you're calling Java
one of those is when a jab at method once a primitive array went.
Remember you have to use one of the Courtland's special primitive arrays to pass to Ajab a method that
once a primitive array and then we saw that some access modifiers are mapped to different modifiers
in Java and you can review the video on access modifiers.
If you've forgotten what that's all about and you want details.
So now let's take a look at other stuff.
You need to be aware of.
And we're going to start with no liability.
So as we've seen CANTLIN protect against null pointer exceptions Java doesn't Java doesn't have any
builtin protection.
So how does no civility come into play when mixing Cartland with Java.
Well intelligence has the noble and at nocte no annotations.
They serve as documentation only.
There is nothing that's enforced.
However when something is annotated with nullable or at not all the implementation should enforce it.
There's nothing in Javid to enforce it but the implementation should enforce it.
Still Katlin uses these annotations as a hint.
So if it sees the at nullable annotation then it's going to map the item in question to a nullable type
and if it sees the at not no and station and it maps it to a non nullable type.
Now when we say it maps it it's a matter of how is the compiler going to treat it.
Remember that when you're using Java from a Cartland file it's to Cartland compile it it's going to
be compiling that file.
And so if it comes across the code using a an instance of a Java class it has to know.
Well can I assign that instance to a non nullable type or can that instance only be assigned to a nullable
type.
So Cartland uses the non-liberal and at not know all annotations as a hint when they're there.
They don't have to be there.
So let's try this out.
We'll change the set color methods so that the parameter has the not null annotation.
So let's go back to our Java file.
So down here on set color we're going to say that we do not expect this parameter to be no.
Now let me just take this out for Max.
I want to show you something when I started typing it.
You'll see that not all comes from or just brainstorm annotations so this is actually an annotation
from the that you can use in the ID.
It's not a calling annotation and it's not a Java annotation so I'll add that back now.
So here we're telling intelligence and this disk where we're telling rather the Cartland compiler we're
giving it a hint we're saying that color shouldn't be knol.
But again nothing will enforce this absolutely nothing's going to enforce this.
This is kind of like a documentation for humans and it's a hint to the compiler.
And if we go to the top we'll see that we now have an import for Oregon check brains annotations and
there are other code bases that contain similar annotations and the Cartland compiler does recognize
some of those.
Obviously it recognizes the jet brings annotations because Katlin you don't check brains owns Katlin
but it also recognizes these annotations in some other code bases.
So now go back to our job of file or our Cartland file rather.
And let's do the following.
We'll say car dot color equals green.
And then they'll both say print line car and you'll see here that we're using the same syntax for fields
in Java classes as we do for properties in Katlin classes.
So right now if we run this
we'll just see the reference for a car instance because we have an overwritten two string here.
I'm going to use intelligence's generate method to generate a two strenger generate functionality rather
to generate a two string OK.
So now we got a nice two string method and let's run again.
And we'll see now that we can see our car.
OK so we had changed the parameter for some color to say or added the annotation rather to say that
we don't expect this to be no.
So let's go back to call Java our Cartland file.
And now let's change this to no.
Now we don't get any compiler errors because what we're doing here is perfectly legal.
But if we run we're going to get an illegal argument exception and it's going to say that the argument
for the act not all parameter must not be null.
So by adding than not no annotation to the parameter this check has now performed at runtime the compiler
has generated code so that this check will be done.
So let's remove the annotation and run again just to show that we're not going to get this runtime exception
without the annotation.
And we don't and we can see that the color is now now and we obviously don't want that.
So you know this is a case where it's good to use the annotation and that will stop the Cartland code
from from setting a the color of the car to.
No.
All right so now let's try out the at nullable.
So let's say let's set this two at nullable now and there is a number of annotations there is one in
a a sun package here.
But we want to jet brains one.
Now we obviously wouldn't want this but it lets the compiler know that nulls are OK.
So back here in our Cartland file We're still setting this to knowl and before when we set this to not
know we got a runtime exception.
But now if we run again
we'll see that we don't.
So.
So we didn't get an exception when we don't annotate at all and we don't get one.
If we tell the compiler that oh it's fine if this is null.
So these annotations are just aids for us and the compiler.
And as you saw when something isn't supposed to be know the compiler will generate code so that if it
turns out to be null at runtime an exception will be thrown to alert us.
But somebody has done something they're not supposed to be doing.
So that's one way Cartland tries to protect against Nalls when it's mixed with Java.
But the onus is on us developers to add the annotations.
Now as I mentioned there were using the jet brains annotations here but there are other code bases that
have annotations defined and Katlin also pays attention to the Java X and the Android Knol related annotations.
So what about return types.
Well let's call the get model method on our car and see what class we get back.
Let's go back to our Java code.
I'm sorry our Cartland code.
I'm actually going to change this to green.
So we're not doing something of noxious.
So now we'll say VAR model equals Kardon model then we'll say print line model dot Java class to see
what we get back.
Let's run
and we'll see that we get each Avodart that string now is Cartland going to treat this as nullable or
not.
Nullable Well let's assign normal to model and see what happens.
Model equals no.
And we'll print line print line model.
So let's go ahead and run
and we'll see that we could assign a novel.
And so the default free Java type that isn't annotated with anything is the nullable type.
So let's see what happens if we declare model with a non nullable types so let's go up here and say
let's try to force this to be a non-null of all types and we're going to declare it as a string and
you'll see that right away down here we get an there that we can assign all to model.
So you can treat values coming from Java as non-global and protect against null pointer exceptions in
the Cartland code.
Can we declare a model as a nullable type.
Well we can but now we can't use the Java class property because this is an exclusively Cartland type.
And so we can no longer ask for the java class.
There is no equivalent to this class in Java.
And so I'm going to comment this line out and run
and must see that everything ran fine and let me just remove the question mark and run because I don't
think I did that before.
Oh I'm not going to be able to do that now because then also.
OK so when you get a value from Java that isn't annotated you can assign it to a novel or a non-global
type.
Now let's go back to our Java code and let's annotate the return value of get model with not no.
So we're going to say that the return value model shouldn't be No.
And if we go back here we'll see that the CANTLIN code is still fine.
So it's always OK as we know to assign a non knowable value to a nullable variable.
So this is a nullable variable and it's always OK to assign a non-null level to a nullable variable.
But you can't do it the other way around.
So now let's go back to car and say that this is nullable
and then we'll come back here and we'll remove this.
And now right away we get an error and that's what we would expect because we can't assign a nullable
type to a non-negligible variable.
It doesn't work.
So once again when it comes to protecting against Nalls if you want to help the compiler and you want
to get help at runtime it's up to you the developer to properly annotate your Java code when it makes
sense to do so.
I mean we don't have to use these annotations.
We can just go ahead and leave them off.
But then of course all bets are off in the Cartland code and you're not going to get any help from the
compiler or any help at runtime.
So what happens then when the Cartland compiler doesn't have any information about whether a type is
nullable or not.
Well in that case the type is what's called a platform type.
And as we've seen it means that you can use it either as a nullable or a non nullable value.
Now platform types can't be created in Katlin We can't declare a variable in cotland that can be used
as nullable or non-knowledge all you're either a string which means your non-null level or you are a
string questionmark which means you're nullable you can't be Bogues a string question mark can store
both nullable and non-bailable values but the type is in that case would be nullable So a type cannot
be nullable and non-null leval you either have to question mark or you don't.
So platform types can't be created in cotland.
They can only result when you're mixing Cartland with another language like Java.
So when you have a platform type the compiler uses the exclamation mark in the typed name.
So if you ever see an error message that contains a type followed by an exclamation mark then you're
dealing with a platform type.
So let's see if we can make one happen.
Let me comment out this whole block because it's filled with errors now and will save roud color.
It equals Carr-Gomm color.
Now we know that's not going to work because colors are a string but if we have her over the error we'll
see that it's a type mismatch it wants an int and it found a string exclamation mark.
OK so when it comes to no lability if a java method isn't annotated as get color isn't.
You should do the usual null checks within the Cartland code before using the return value.
The compiler is not going to do any checks for you and that's it for this video we'll continue discussing
what you have to watch out for when calling Java from Katlin in the next video.