So before we get into what data types
are available in Kotlin, let's get one
thing out of the way, everything is a
class. There are no lower case data types
as there are in Java, but apart from that,
you're already familiar with the
built-in data types available in Kotlin,
because they're the same as in Java, so we're
not going to spend much time on them.
I mean think about this, we're writing
Kotlin applications that are targeted to
the jvm and the jvm understands a
certain set of built-in data types and
so Kotlin has the same set of built-in
data types. So we're going to create a
new Kotlin project and add a package
and file as we normally do. I'm going to
go through this fairly quickly. I'm going
to go to file, new, project and I'm going
to call this project data types.
I'm going to open it in this window and I'm
going to expand the project navigator
and create a package and I'm going to
call this package academy dot learn
programming dot data types and I'll
create a file called data types as well.
And now, I'll add the usual main method
and we're ready to go. So let's start
with integer which as I've said several
times , is the default data type for
whole numbers, just as it is in Java.
Now you've already seen this, so I'll just
remind you that you use int for the
integer data type and because int is the
default when you want an int, you don't
have to specify it in a variable
declaration when you're assigning an
initial value. Obviously, if you're not
assigning an initial value, then you have
to specify it, otherwise the compiler
won't know what type you want, but if
you're assigning an initial value and
you want it to be an int, you don't have
to include the data type, so we can do
something like val my int equals 10 and
that will give us an integer variable in
this case and immutable integer variable
with a data type of int. Now there's also
byte, short and long I'm not going to
waste time going through these, because
you know these from Java. I'm just going
to mention two things, the first thing is
that the L suffix for longs is also used in Kotlin.
So you go val my long equals 22L and that
works. If you take the L away here, you would
actually get an int, because the compiler
is going to see 22 is an int. So if
you're not going to specify the datatype
here, you have to say L, if you specify
the datatype, then 22 at this point will
be a long. Well let's take it out and just
use L, it's shorter and in Kotlin,
you always always try to write things the
shorter way. Now the second thing I'm
going to mention is really important,
because it's different behavior from
Java. So listen up, Kotlin does not
automatically widen numbers. Now what do
I mean by that? Well in Java, we can do
the following, I'll type this out in Java
even though the compiler is going to
complain, just so we can quickly look.
So in Java, we'd go like int my int
equals 10 and then we go long my long
equals my int and that works in Java.
Java is not going to give us an error,
but let's try the same thing in Kotlin.
Now before I do, that though the reason
Java is not going to give us an error of
course is because my int can fit into a
long variable, so Java just automatically
converts this to a long when it assigns
of value, not a problem.
In other words Java automatically widens
the integer, but Kotlin doesn't do that.
So let's try to do the equivalent thing
in Kotlin, let's try to assign my int to
my long and you'll see we have an error
for two reasons, first of all I'll have
to change this to a var but we still
have an error now and it says type
mismatch requiring a long and it found an
int. So we can't do the same thing that
we did in Java, there's no automatic
widening of numbers in Kotlin.
Now, because of that and Java has the same
methods but they're even more important
in Kotlin now, every datatype has two
functions that convert to the other data
types. So in order to fix this error,
we just have to call the two long
function on the integer and now the
error goes away, because this function
converts the value to a long and long on
the right-hand side matches long on the
left-hand side so we no longer have an
error here. So let's look at another example,
we'll declare a Val variable called my
byte of type byte and we'll assign it
the value of 111. Now here of course,
we have to specify the datatype, because if
we don't, 111 can fit into an integer,
so the compiler is going to assume you want
an integer, if you don't specify that you
want to a byte and let's declare a var my
short and we'll make it a short and then
we'll go my short equals my byte and
again, we're going to get the error
saying that we have a type mismatch,
because once again in Java, Java would
automatically widen the short, the byte
to fit into the short but Kotlin doesn't
do that. So we have to go 2.2 short and
call the two short function and now the
error goes away. So keep this in mind
when you're working with numbers.
Now, there is one exception to this and that
is numeric literals. Kotlin will
automatically widen literals, so this is
only a problem when you're assigning
numbers that are inside variables, so for
example we can do the following,
val another int equals five. Now we've been
doing this all along, we were doing it up
here, we were doing it up here because
here, you know 10 doesn't need an int,
this could fit into a byte. So could this
this obviously does and that's okay,
because we're assigning it to a byte,
but here, by which could fit into a byte
where the compiler is going ahead and
creating an int variable for us,
so that's an exception
obviously, compiler is not going to
complain here about that, but if we this
was a variable and it wasn't an int
variable then the compiler would
complain. So for numbers stored in
variables, you have to explicitly widen
the value when necessary, and you do that by
calling the appropriate to datatype
function. Alright, so let's briefly
touch on floating point numbers,
everything I've just said about the
whole number types applies here, now just
as in Java, double is the default data
type, so you don't have to specify in
variable declaration. So you can go do
something like var my double equals 65
point 984 and this will give
you a double value. And if we wanted to
prove that, we could say print line my
double is double, this should be a
capital D and let's run and we'll see
that we get true. So the compiler is
assigning double here and I suppose
we've never actually proven it for int.
So let's do that print line default data
type is and we'll do this inside a
string template and we'll open up an
expression, my int is int and let's print
that and we'll see that, you know default
data type is true, I suppose I could have
put integer in here.
Okay now you can use the F suffix with
floats, just as you do in Java.
So you could say val my float equals
eight thirty eight point five four eight
nine, whatever I don't even know if
that's what I said F and when you do
that, this is now a float it's not a
double. Let's print it out to show that.
Let's say this is a float and we'll open
up a string template, my float is float.
Let's run and this is a float and that's true.
And as with whole numbers there is no
automatic widening, so if we say my
double equals my float we're going to
get an error here, type mismatch double
on the left hand side and it wants a
float and of course we can just go to
double and that would take care of the
error. So that's a very quick whirlwind
tour of the numeric types most important
thing to keep in mind, I think from this
is the difference in behavior when it
comes to variables, the values are not
automatically widened when you're
assigning them to a wider data type.
You have to explicitly do the widening by
calling the appropriate two data type
function. Alright, so now let's take a
look at the char data type, so we can say
val char equals and let's make this b
nothing new here, the compiler can infer
the type if it sees a single character
literal and single quotes like this that
knows it's going to be a char, but if we
want it to, we could be explicit and say
char, that works too but we don't need it
and we try to be concise in Kotlin.
Now in Java, we can do something like the
following and I'm going to write Java
code here, so we'll get errors you can
say char my char equals 65 and semicolon.
Now what that does is it assigns
whatever character corresponds to the
value of 65 in the character set that
the application is using now for utf-8
and I believe in ASCII as well, that's a
capital A so if we were to print it out,
we would get a capital A. Let's try to do
the same thing in Kotlin now, so I'm
going to delete that and I'll say val my
char equal 65, now can you see right away
why that doesn't work? The compiler is
going to assume that by 65 you mean the
integer 65, so that won't work so let's
explicitly tell the compiler we want a
char and it doesn't work, it'll say the
integer literal does not conform to the
expected type char, so you can't assign
numeric values like this to char
variables, like you can in Java and a
concise way of saying that is you can't
treat characters like numbers in Kotlin.
Characters have to be treated like characters.
So, if you wanted to do something like this, what
would you do? Let's say you had the
number 65 and you want to get the
character that corresponds to the number
65, this is the way we could do it, we'd
have to convert it, so we'd go val my
char int equals 65 because this is going
to be the int type and then we'd say
print line my char int dot to char and
let's see what that gets us, let me run.
And you can see that the character a was
printed, so if you've got a character
literal as a numeric and you want to
actually get it into a char variable,
Once again you've got to explicitly do
that, there's no automatic conversion
done for you.
All right, so how about boolean?
Well, there's nothing remarkable about boolean,
the only thing I'll tell you about it is
val my boolean, I'll make this actually uppercase
and it's boolean, in fact as you might
have guessed we don't need the boolean
here, but I wanted to show it to you so
we can take that out and just say true,
and of course there's false and that's
all there is to boolean, so that's all
I'll say about them. And that's it for
the primitive data types, we've seen the
Kotlin types that map to Java's
primitive types, but one of the key
features of Kotlin is that it's
interoperable with Java, which means that
you can call Java methods from Kotlin
without having to do anything special,
but what happens if you want to call a
Java method and it once a primitive type
is a parameter, like let's say it wants a
boolean parameter but it wants the
primitive boolean type? It doesn't want
the boolean class. Well let's try it out,
we're going to add a Java class to our
Kotlin project, I'm going to put it into
a separate package but because it'll be cleaner.
So I'll just right click here new,
package and we'll call the package
academy.learnprogramming.java
code and then inside this package,
I'll create a new Java class and I'll call
the class dummy class because this class
really is going to be a dummy and we're
going to add a very silly method in here,
it just takes a boolean and then
depending on the what the boolean is,
it'll print one thing or another thing.
So we'll say public string is vacation
time, it accepts the primitive boolean
called on vacation and it's going to use
the ternary operator, which as we've
learned no longer exists in Kotlin, so it
will return on vacation and if that's
true, it will return the string I'm on
vacation, but if it's false it'll return
the string I'm working and that's it,
very very simple, but it wants a
primitive boolean, so what do we do if we
want to call this from Kotlin? Well let's
go back to our Kotlin file, so we want to
create an instance of the dummy class
and call is vacation time and we don't
have to do anything special, we can treat
the Java class just as we would a Kotlin
class and just to make things a little
bit more complicated, we'll pass a
boolean variable rather than a literal,
I know that's not all that complicated but
rather than doing it the absolute
simplest way, we'll decide a variable to
the mix. So we'll say vow vacation time
equals false, so we're not on vacation
and we'll say val on vacation equals
dummy class, so here I'm instantiating a
dummy class instance and then we want to
call the is vacation time method and
we're going to pass it vacation time.
Ans let's print the result.
Now you'll notice that we have no errors
anywhere here, so let's run. And we get
the string I'm working, so it looks like
we successfully called the Java method
that was expecting a primitive type
without having to do anything special
and in fact that's correct, you don't
have to do anything special and the
reason for that is when it comes to the
primitive classes, the Kotlin classes
actually compile to the primitive types
under the covers, so when the Kotlin
class- this class is compiled this
vacation time variable is actually a
boolean with a little b that's what
it gets compiled to and that's why
there's no mismatch when you need to
call a java method that wants a
primitive. Now how about if it wanted
boolean big B boolean, would that work?
Let's change this to a big B go back to
data types, doesn't look like anything's
changed here so let's run and it still
works and that's because of course Java
has its boxing and unboxing, so that all
works just the way it does in Java where
there's boxing and unboxing that goes on
for you. Okay so before we leave this
topic, I just want to talk about the any,
unit and nothing classes, these are three
important classes in Kotlin. Now the any
class is sort of like the object class
in Java, it's the root of every Kotlin
object, it includes function definitions
for two string hashcode and equals.
So, let's take a look at the class by
declaring a variable type any and then
doing a control b to go to the source
code, the declaration for any.
So I'll just say val anything is of type any and
then here we'll right-click and we'll
say go to the declaration and here you
can see that here's the any class and
it's got function definitions for
equals hashcode and to string and you'll
see that there's nothing in here. Also,
one one interesting thing here that
we've already covered it'll say that
note that equals equals operator and
Kotlin code is translated into a call
for equals, when objects are on both
sides of the operator and not null and
that we saw that before, when we were
looking at structural versus referential
equality. So it says the any class is the
root at the call in class hierarchy and
every Kotlin class has any as a
superclass, so this is the any class.
Now, the unit class is equivalent to void in
Java, void isn't really a datatype, it's a
way of telling the compiler that a
method doesn't return anything, Kotlin
uses the unit class for this purpose.
So, if you have a function that doesn't
return anything, then you can declare it
as returning type unit, but unit actually
exists in Kotlin, it's not just you know
a way of telling the compiler that
nothing gets returned.
It's a singleton and we're going to
cover those later, so if a function
returns unit, it will actually return the
singleton unit instance and this is an
important difference between Kotlin and
Java. In Java a void method truly doesn't
return anything, but in Kotlin a function
that returns unit, actually returns the
singleton unit instance. And finally, we
have the nothing class and there's no
equivalent for this in Java. This is
going to sound strange, but nothing is a
subclass of every class, which means that
you can use nothing wherever you can use
any class, so why would you do this?
Why would you want to use this nothing
class? Well, one common use case would be
when you know a function is never going
to return, like for example if a function
intentionally contains an infinite loop,
you can tell the compiler that you don't
expect this function ever to return by
having the function return type b
nothing, so that's one use case for it.
Anyway, that's it, I just wanted to
briefly touch on any, unit and nothing
because you're going to see them, but
that's it for the built-in data types in Kotlin.
I'll see you in the next video.