Alright, so I said we'd cover loops in
this section, but we're going to spend
all our time on the for loop, because the
other loops haven't changed in Kotlin.
So all the other loops the while and
do-while loop, they have the same syntax
and behave the same way as they do in
Java. So there you go, we've covered the
while and do-while loops, but now let's
talk about the loop that has changed in
Kotlin, the for loop. So I've mentioned a
couple of times already that the
original for loop isn't available in
Kotlin. So in Kotlin you can't do
something like this, you can't do for int
i equals 0, i less than 10, i plus plus,
you know do something, we're getting
errors here and not just because this
syntax would be bad, it's because this
form of the for loop does not exist in
Kotlin, instead in Kotlin for loops use
what's called ranges. So what is a range?
Well a range is an interval that has a
start and an end value, you can use them
with the for loop and you can also
assign them to variables. So let's do
that, I'm going to get rid of this for
loop here and I'm going to say val range
equals 1 to 5, the range operator is the
two dots the start and end values are inclusive.
So the range includes 1 and also it includes 5.
So essentially numbers that are greater
than or equal to 1 and less than or
equal to 5 are within this range. Now, you
can also have ranges of chars and
strings, because both of them are
comparable. So let's define a char range,
char range, var range equals and
we'll say we want to range from a to z,
so that works or we could say val
string range and we'll say we want to
range abc to xyz and both of these work.
So any type that's comparable, can be
used in a range. So as I said, those
values that are included in a range are those
that are greater than or equal in the
start value and less than an equal than
the N value. So the type used in the
range has to be comparable because of
the in operator you use the in operator
to test whether a value is in a range.
So for example, we could say print line 3 in
range, so here we're testing whether 3
belongs to this range, we could say print
line q in char range, print line ccc in
string range, but we could also do
something like this print line cccccc in
string range. So let's run and see what
we get for these and we'll see that we
get true for all of them, now these are
probably obvious, this one we get true
because it's less than xyz, because x
is greater than c, so this string even
though it's longer, is less than xyz
and so it belongs to the string range
we've defined here. So let's try another one.
We'll say not up here, but down here
we'll say print line and let's try
siz z in string range and what do you
think we're going to get for this one?
Let's run and of course we'll get false
now, because that is greater than xyz.
So it's not less than or equal to the N
value, therefore it's not in this range.
Now, of course there are range functions
that you can use to create other types
of ranges, for example let's say you want
to range from 5 to 1, rather than from 1
to 5. Well, you can do that you can say
val backward range equals 5 dot down to 1.
Now you might be wondering why you
can't just go like this,
val let's just call it r equals 5 to 1
because you'll see here there aren't any
compile errors, but let's try testing
some values with that one, so
print line let's say five in r and
let's run this and we'll see that we get
false and the reason we get false is
because this is going to compare five
against the start value and the end
value, so is it greater than or equal
to the start value? Yes. but is it less
than or equal to the N value? No, it's not.
So this creating a backwards range like
this doesn't work, it doesn't give you
what you want, you need to use for a
backward range five down to one and then
we'll say print line five in backward
range and let's run now and this time we
get true. So if you want to create a
range that's in reverse order,
essentially you've got to use the down
to function, Now you might want a range
that looks something like three six nine
twelve fifteen, in other words you want
the step to be three, so rather than a
range going one two three four five or
each value in the range, is basically
incremented by one, you might want each
value in the range, each subsequent value
to be incremented by a different number.
And you can do that, so first you define
the range, so we'll say val step range
equals and we want to start at three to
fifteen, if we want to go three six nine
twelve up to fifteen and then we'll say val
step 3 equals step range dot step and we
want each step to be three. Now, you can
also reverse an existing range meaning
that you can switch the start and end
values, but you can only do this with
numeric ranges. so this won't work with
all types of ranges, so we could say val
reversed range equals range dot reversed
and in fact, when it comes to some of the
functions we've looked at like the step
two down to and reversed, you can only
really use them with numeric types and
char, you couldn't use them with strings
or you can't use and let's say you have a employee
class and it implements comparable you
can create a range, a regular range with
a low start value in a higher end value,
but you can't call step and down to and
things like that, because the compiler is
not going to be able to figure out what
you want. You can actually do a lot of
things with ranges though and let's take
a look at what you can do. So if we say
step range dot to see what IntelliJ
suggests, you can see that there's quite
a lot of things that you can do.
So you'll want to take a look at the range
documentation at some point to see what
cool stuff is available to you but let's
change this now to our string range to
see what what's available on a string
range and you'll see that it's a much
shorter list, there's not as much stuff.
So as I mentioned, when you're working
with numeric ranges or char ranges,
you can do quite a bit with them but outside
of that, you can still do some stuff I
mean you can test if it's empty,
you can test if it contains something
but there's not a lot else you can do
with string ranges and other types of
ranges. So while you can create ranges
with any comparable type numeric ranges
are the most powerful. So loops are where
the in operator comes into play, we've
seen in in here and let's print out some
of the ranges that we created, so we can
actually look at them. So we'll go back
here and we'll say for i in range we'll
print line i, so what we're doing here is
we're saying for every value of I that
belongs to this range, go ahead and print it.
So let's run this
and we'll see that we get one two three
four five printed. Now, I'm not going to
print this one out because it would be
quite long, but let's print out our step
range and see what we get for that one
for let's call it n in step range and
we'll print line n so let's run and
we'll see that we're getting 3 4 5 etc.
down to 15, but if I copy this in fact
I'll delete it from here, so we're not
printing things out twice put it here
and now print the same range except this
time, we've said that we want steps of 3,
let's print that and now we'll see that
we get our 3 6 9 12 15 and let's print
out our reversed range, where we reversed
this range up here and we'll see that we
get 5 down to 1. So this is a very common
form of the for loop, so instead of doing
the following here, instead of saying for
int i equals you know 1 in this case,
i less than I guess it would be 6, i plus
plus, go ahead and print the value of i.
This is the equivalent we're saying for
i in range and you don't have to assign
the range to a variable, we could have
just put it directly in here and we get
the same thing 1 2 3 4 5. So this is the
form of the for loop that's used in
Kotlin, that replaces the original Java
for loop. Okay, now I said I wasn't going
to print the string range, but let's
let's go ahead and print it. Let's see
what we get for this, so we'll say for
let's say s in string range
and we'll print line s and you'll see
that we can't do it.
It says the for-loop range must have an
iterator method and the string range
does not have an iterator method,
so there's no iterator method defined on
the string range. So you can't loop
through strings like this, it doesn't
really make a lot of sense when you
think about it, because as we've seen
they could be any arbitrary length, so
what values actually belong in here.
There's actually probably an infinite
number of values that belong to this
range, so this range doesn't really make
a lot of sense, but when it comes to
strings, you can access them in loops in
the following way, if we have a string
str equals hello and we want to print
out the individual characters in this
string, we can do the following for c in
str print line c, because the string
class has an iterator defined on it and
if we run, we'll see the individual
characters h-e-l-l-o printed for hello,
so when you're using the in operator
with the for loop as long as what's on
the right hand side has an iterator
defined for it, you're good so we saw up
here that we can just use a range
directly in a for loop we don't have to
assign it to a variable first, well the
same thing goes for some of the other
things that we did.
So let's print the numbers from 1 to 20,
So for let's say num in 1 to 20 print
line num. Now we know that we're going to
get you know 1 2 3 4 all the way up
to 20 printed out, we don't need to run
this. So let's say instead though that we
wanted to do this in steps of 4, so we'd say step 4.
So that's how you do it, if you haven't
created a range as follows and assigned it
into a variable. So if we run, we'll see
that we get our 1 2 3 4 5 and then we
get 1 5 9 13 17, because we print
the one and then we add 4 to it and get
5 etc. we can't- if we add 4 to 17 were
then outside the range, so it stops at 17
when we're using a step of 4. Now one
thing to note here is you'll notice when
we assign the range to the variable, we
use the name of the variable dot step 3
when we wanted to range with values
incremented by more than one, you can't
do that here by doing dot step so we
can't do dot step 3 for example, you'll
see that that doesn't work. So if you
haven't assigned the range to a variable,
you have to do it the way I showed you.
Step 4, okay so if we want to use a range
directly in the for loop, how do we go
backwards now? How would we go from 20 to 1
rather than from 1 to 20. Well, we do
the following, for i in 20 and let's just
go down to 15 and then print line i,
so here we're saying we want to start at 20
and we want to count down to 15, so if we
run, we'll see here we're starting at 20
and we're counting down to 15. Alright,
we can combine functions, so let's say we
want to go from 20 down to 10 let's say
and we want to do it in steps of 5, so we
can just say for i in 20 down to 10 in
steps of 5 print line i. I'm going to
comment out these two for, so that what
we see comes up first and I'm going to
run and now we'll see we go from 20 to
15 to 10, so we're going from 20 down to
10 in steps of 5. Okay, so what do you do if
you don't want to include the last
number in the range? As I mentioned
earlier, the end value and the start
value are inclusive, they're included in
the range, you can use the keyword until
so you can do something like the
following, you can say for i in one until
ten print line i and so what this will
do is it will print the numbers 1 to 9,
it will exclude 10. So let's try this out
and we'll see up here that we get the
numbers 1 to 9, we don't get the number 10.
Now the start values and end values
can be variables, they don't have to be
constants, so for example we could do
something like val s equals goodbye and
we can say val s range equals, let's say
0 to s dot length, so you could do
something like that and then if you
wanted to loop over the string, you
wouldn't want to include s dot length, so
at that point, you could use the until
keyword to loop around the string of
course, you don't really need to do that
with strings because they have an
iterator, so earlier on I showed you
I guess I deleted it, here yeah earlier on
I showed you how you can just loop
around a string, so you wouldn't need to
do that, but you can probably think of
situations where you'd want to do
something like this and exclude the last
index. Okay, so as you've seen you can
create ranges outside loops and assign
into variables, you can also create them
in the for loop itself, as we're doing
here and here and I guess we took out
the for loop where we're just doing a
plain old 1 2 5 for i in 1 2 5, ah here
it is so the only thing you should do is
pay attention to the difference in
syntax, because when you're declaring a
range outside a for loop, for example you
can do things like calls dot down to dot
stuff etc. when you want to do the same
thing inside the for loop you use a
different type of syntax you actually in
this case they're using them like
operators so rather than functions you use
them as operators and you can do that
with some functions, we haven't covered
that but you can declare functions as
being operators and then use them like
this. Okay, so let's now look at how to
loop over an array, we saw one way
already when we covered arrays, we can
use the in operator with them, so I'm
going to comment out all this stuff
so that we're not going to see these things
print it over and over again and then
let's- didn't mean to do that, let's come
down here make some room and then we'll
declare an array, so we'll say val
seasons equals array of and we'll have
spring summer winter and fall and then
if we want it to loop over this array,
we just say for season in seasons print the season.
Let's run, then we'll see our four
seasons printed. Now, I'll mention here
that there's also a not in operator that
you can use to test whether something is
not within a range, for example we could
say val not a season equals and we could
say whatever not in seasons and then
we'll say print line not a season,
don't know what is an extra blank space here
and then we'll run then we'll get true
because it's true that whatever isn't in
our array. We can do the same thing with
a regular old range of course we could
say val not in range equals 32 not in
one to ten and we're going to expect
this to be true, let's run and we'll see
that yes 32 is not in the range of one to ten,
the in and not in operators also work with
strings as we've seen, well let me define
a string first val str I'll use our
usual hello string and we can say print
line e in sdr and print line print line
e not in str and of course we'll expect
true for the first one and false for the
second one, which is what we get.
Now arrays also have an extension function
that makes them easy to iterate over
when you want to use the array index in
some way. So we've got our seasons array
and let's iterate over this array using
the index within the for block,
so instead of just doing a plain old for
season and seasons let's change this for
loop and we'll say for index in seasons
dot indices and then what we'll do is
say we're going to print line I'm going
to open up an expression here and say
seasons index is season number index,
so it's happening here is on each iteration
of the loop, the index of the current
element will be assigned to index.
So let's run and we'll see that we get
spring a season number 0 summer season
number 1 etc. because in this expression
we're substituting seasons index so when
index is 0, seasons 0 is going to be substituted here etc.
So if you want to do something with the
index within a for loop, this is how you
can do it and if you wanted to get at
the value of course, you just use seasons
indexes we're doing here. Now you can
also use the for each and for each index
functions which work with arrays and all
collections in fact. So we can also do
the following seasons dot for each and
we'll print line it.
So this is actually a lambda and
inside the lambda, we refer to each
element using it. So that's one way we
could do it and if we wanted to get at
the index as well, we can say seasons dot
for each indexed and I'm going to use a
lambda here so I'm going to say index
and value and we'll print line value is
season number index. So here I'm getting
it both the index and the value and I'm
using them inside the lambda here.
So we'll run this and here's our first loop
up here and then here's our for each
printout spring summer winter and fall
where we're just printing each the value
of each element and then following that
is our for each indexed where we're
saying spring is season number, so we're
basically doing the same thing that
we're doing here. So here's two alternate
ways of getting it the index and
printing what we want to print,
this one's more concise than this one here.
So one final word before we leave loop and
this is something that applies to all
loops, not just the for loop you can give
them a name, so let's say we had a bunch
of nested loops like the following so
we'll say for i in one two three then
we'll say for j will print line
will print line the value of i in here.
So we'll say i equals i and then we'll
say for u in let's say one to four and
let's print line j,
then let's have for k in five to ten and
we'll print line k. Okay, so we've got
three nested loops here and let's run.
I'm going to actually comment out these
things now, so that we're not getting a
bunch of seasons beforehand and now
let's run this, so we'll get what we
expect to see, quite a few things printed
out so we start with i being one and j
being one and then we get our inner k
loop going through its values, we come
back out to j which is now two we get
all the k values and that's going to
happen until j is four and let me see if
I can find that.
And here we start i equals two so up here j
is three and then j is four and then we
go back out to the the outer loop and i
equals two, so nothing earth-shattering
going on here. Now let's say that we want
to stop looping within this k loop when
k is seven, so when we hit seven we want
to stop looping. So let's add a test for
that and a break statement, so down here
I'm going to say if k equals seven break
and that's fine, but let's say that when
we break, we also want to short-circuit
the j loop, because right now if we run
we'll see i is 1, j is 1, k is 5, 6 oh we
hit 7, so now we break but then we go out
to j and let's say we don't want to do
that when we break here, we will actually
want to go right back out to i, we don't
want to continue executing j so how
would we do that? Well what we're going
to do is we're going to give the j loop
a name and then the break statement,
we'll specify that we want to break at
the j loop. So to give the j loop a name,
I'm going to come here I'm going to call
it j loop and follow that with the at
sign. So this loop now has a name called
j loop and then down here I'm going to
say I want to break at j loop, so when k
is seven, I want to break out of this
loop here. Obviously, I'm going to break
out of here as well and I want to break
out of this loop. So when k hits seven,
I want to go back out to i, so let's run
now and we'll see that we hardly get
anything printed now because i is 1, j is 1
k is 5 6 7 oops
I want to go right out here and so we
skip all the rest of the j, we don't see
2 3 4, we go straight out to i equals 2
and then the same thing is going to
happen, j is 1 we're going to hit 7 in
the inner loop and we're going to break
straight out into i, so you can use names
like this on any type of loop and you
can use- you can specify where you want
to go when you specify break and this
also works with continue, if we change
this to continue, I can't type here
continue, so now what we're saying here
is we're not going to break out of the
loop, we're going to continue with the
j loop, so when we hit K equals 7 we're
going to go back out to the j loop.
Now using name loops and jumps like this can
lead to spaghetti coding, so it's not
something you want to do unless there's
no other way to do something, but
I wanted to show you this because you
might see it in code examples or you
might see it in code that you have to
modify or maintain that you didn't
write, so if you see this sort of thing
that this is what's going on, it's giving
the loop a name and then you can
reference that name would continue and
break statements. Alright, that's it for loops.