In this video, we're going to take a look
at the if statement. Now, I could also say
we're going to take a look at the if
expression, because in Kotlin if can
evaluate to a value, so that's the big
change in Kotlin, the big difference
between the if in Java and the if in
Kotlin, but otherwise the if statement or
expression depending on whether it's
returning a value or not is pretty much
the same as it is in Java, so this is
going to be a shortish video. Now I
mentioned when we went over quick
differences between Kotlin and Java that
the ternary operator doesn't exist in
Kotlin. And now maybe we can understand
why, because the if statement can return
a value in which case it would be an
expression, we don't need the ternary
operator because the if can act as a
ternary operator, it can do the same
thing. However this is probably perhaps
you know one of the few instances when
Kotlin can be more verbose than Java.
So let's take a look at an example I've
already created a project and the usual
package and everything else, so we'll
just jump straight into the main
function here and let's say we have var,
num, int and then we'll say if some
condition and we don't know what that is,
this won't compile but we'll save some
condition num equals 50, otherwise num
equals let's say 592. So in Java we could
write the following, we could say num
equals and then we have some condition
question mark 50, otherwise 592 and
that's pretty concise and that's using
the ternary operator. Now we can be more
concise in Kotlin as well, I've written
this out to be rather verbose instead of
writing it out like this, we could say
val num equals if some condition 50 else
592 and this would
actually work. So what I'm going to do is
I'm going to comment out all this stuff,
I want to show you that this will
actually work, so I'm going to go val
some condition equals, I don't know let's
say 69 is less than 22, this is a really
dumb example, but I want this to be able
to compile so that you see that yes
indeed we don't get any errors. So this
would be the equivalent of the ternary
operator. As you can see, it's a little
bit more verbose than what we would
write in Java, but not you know
excessively verbose, but this is why we
don't have the ternary operator in
Kotlin, because the if can now evaluate
to a value, we can just write this.
Now what if you want to do more with the if
or else block? Well, that's fine as long
as the last statement in each block is
the return value, if you want one.
You don't have to have the if return a value,
we can still use the if as usual, you
know if some condition, print line
something else we move this up here
print line something else. So you can
have an if statement that doesn't return
anything, but if you wanted an if
statement that's an expression that does
return something and you want to do more
than one thing in the effort else block
you can do the following, I'm going to
comment this out and I'm going to say if
some condition then we're going to print
line something and then we're going to
return the value what did we have 50 and
if it's some condition isn't met then
we're going to print something else and
we're going to return the value 592 and
that would work. If I said val num2
equals and then here I'm going to print
line num2. When we run, we should see in
this case, we're going to see 592 printed
because our condition is 69 less than 22.
So let's go ahead and try running that
and we'll get 592 and something else printed.
So, when you want the if statement which
would make it an expression to return a
value, when it returns a value it's an
expression, you put the return value as
the last statement in each block or you
can do something like we did up here.
If all you want to do in the if and else
case is return a value. So let's go back
to this if statement and let's try to
remove the else block and see what
happens, so I'm just going to comment it out
and right away we see errors and the
error says if must have both main and
else branches, if use is an expression
and you can understand why that is,
I mean if we do- we want to use it as an
expression, we want to assign it to
something or even if we don't and the
condition isn't met, then what would we
assign to num2? There's nothing to
assign to num2. So when you want to use
the if as an expression, you have to
provide both an if and an else there has
to be some value, you need both branches.
Now if you're just using if as a regular
old if, you don't have to do that. I was
looking to see if I have one and I don't
think I do, let me uncomment this and I'm
going to just copy and paste it and
we'll take this out so we're not
assigning it to anything and we'll
remove these guys, so we're not
evaluating the if to a value and then
we'll comment out the else and in this
case, we don't get an error because it
doesn't matter if the- if there's no else.
This isn't evaluating to anything so
it's fine to just go ahead and just have
an if branch. Now because if is an
expression, we can use it anywhere you
could use a value for example instead of
assigning this to num2 and then printing
it like I'm doing down here we can just
print it. So I can just say print line
and I'll print the if statement because
this now or expression rather because
this now evaluates to a
value. So let's run. And we'll see the
exact same thing we saw before, 592.
We can use it in a string template if we
want, so I can say the result of the if
expression is and dollar sign open up
curly braces, I'll have to add a curly
brace down here and add a closing quote
and we'll run and we'll get the result
of the if expression is 592. Sow notice
that we're nesting curly braces here and
the compiler isn't getting confused, just
like it doesn't get confused any other
place that you nest curly braces,
so that's not a problem, so if we went up
here and we said instead let's change
this to 20. Now we should see our if
branch executed and we should see 50 as
a result. And we do, and we see something
printed now, rather than something else.
And we're also seeing something printed
from one of our other conditions down
here now, so we're seeing two some things
now because some condition is passing
here as well, so basically because if can
be an expression, we can use it as I said
wherever an expression can be used.
So, you know we can assign it to a variable,
we can pass it to a function as we're
doing with print line or we were doing
with print line before we change this to
a string template. So essentially when
you write an if statement so that it is
actually an if expression because it
evaluates to a value, you can use it
wherever you would use a value, but you
don't have to use it as an expression,
you can use it just like you normally
have, just like we do down here,
we're not setting a value at all we're
just saying that you know, if the
condition is met do something and we
don't need this to evaluate to a value.
Now, could we assign this to a variable?
Let's give it a shot. We won't be able to
actually in this case because I don't
think because we don't have an if so
we'll go val x equals and I'll say no,
you don't- sorry we don't have an else so
it'll say no, so let's add an else
print line something else and we'll see
that this works. So what type do you
think X would be? It's probably going to
be unit. Do you think it'll be unit?
Because unit basically means nothing, right?
So let's print out the type of X, print X
dot Java class, that will give us the
class. Let's run. And indeed we'll see
that in this case, the type of X is the
unit, so the compiler knows this isn't
going to return anything, so X gets the
value of unit, there wouldn't be any use
doing this, but I just wanted to show you
that you can do it and that the value
that's returned from this if expression
is essentially unit. Okay that's it for
this statement and expression.
I'll see you in the next video.