(electronic chime)
Alright, so now I'm going to convert
the text adventure application from Java to Kotlin.
Now this is meant to give you a taste of Kotlin
compared to Java, so I'm not going to explain
in detail what I'm going because everything I do
is covered in the course.
In fact, at the end of the course we're going to revisit
the converted application and by that time
you'll be able to explain all the code
and also understand why I made some of the choices I did.
So grab your favourite beverage, sit back,
and just watch.
Now if you don't understand anything,
just mentally file away your questions
and wait until you've watched the videos
later in the course that cover the topic,
because as I said, everything I'm going to do
in this video is covered in the course and a lot more.
So don't worry if you don't understand anything right now,
just file away your question
and it will be covered in the course.
So I've already created a Kotlin project
and we'll go over how to do that in the next section,
and I've copied our two data files into it.
Now I have made two changes to the locations_big.txt file.
The first change I've made is I changed the delimiter
from a comma to this weird looking quote.
I don't know actually what this symbol is called,
but it's located on the same key as the tilde
and that's usually in the upper left corner
of an English keyboard.
Now why did I do that?
Well I did it because descriptions can contain commas.
And when I do the conversion I don't want to use a scanner
to read the file and to parse the input.
I want to be able to use a Kotlin extension function
and we'll cover extension functions in the course
and I want to be able to use one of those
to read in the data.
And then I just want to use the string.split method
to actually get the two pieces of information.
But if I had kept this delimiter's comma
I wouldn't be able to do that because a lot of the
descriptions have a comma in them so that would
obviously throw a wrench into the whole process.
Here's one right here with a comma in it,
so if I use string.split and then didn't go through
the hassle of having to rejoin all the tokens
after the first one together, I'd be cutting off
my descriptions prematurely.
So I decided instead to go through and change the delimiter
to something else.
So I just wanted to point that out to you
that in the locations_big.txt file
I changed that delimiter.
I don't have to do it in directions_big
because none of the pieces of information
will contain a comma, so I just did it for this file.
Now the second change I made was I changed
you are sitting in front of a computer learning Java
to you are learning Kotlin, and I think that change
is self-explanatory.
So with that out of the way, let's get going.
So the first thing I'm gonna do is create a package
for my Kotlin code, Kotlin uses packages
just like Java does, so we'll say
Academy.learnprogramming.,
and I'll call it text adventure.
And them I'm going to convert the location class.
You'll recall that this class stores
the information for the location.
So I'll say new common file or class
and I'll just call that location.
Now I'm going to create what's called a data class,
so I'll say data class, I'm going to call it location,
and we have three properties in our location class.
We have the location ID which is an int,
we have the description which is a string,
and then we have the exits map.
I'm going to declare two of those properties up front
as part of this class's constructor,
and I'm going to declare the exits map separately.
So I'm going to say val, locationID and that's an int.
I'm going to say val description and that's a string.
And then inside the class I'm going
to declare our exits map.
I want this to be a mutable map
because we want to be able to add exits to it,
so I'm gonna say mutableMapOf, the key is the string,
the direction letter and the value is the location
destination ID.
So now I'll do what we did in Java and when an instance
of this class is constructed, I'll add the Q exit
to the map.
So I'm going to do that in an init block
and I'll say exits, Q, because the direction letter
is the key, equals zero.
That's the destination location ID.
And then the only other thing I have to do in this class
is add a function that adds an exit to the map
as we're reading our data files.
So I'll say add exit and this will accept
the direction which is a string
and it also wants the destination location ID,
so I'll say destinationID and that's an int.
And then what that will do is exit and we want
the direction here, so that will be the direction
as the key equals, and the destinationID.
And that's it for the locations class.
So I'm doing exactly what we did in Java,
I've declared the three properties.
I'm adding the Q exit to every location,
and then there's a function here that accepts
a direction letter and a destination ID
and it adds the destination ID to the map
with the key of the direction letter.
So that's our location class.
Alright, so now let's convert the locations class
and you'll recall that this is a class
that reads in the two data files, creates all the locations
instances and adds all the exits.
So let me add a new Kotlin file for that,
so I'll say new Kotlin file or class
and we'll say locations.
And in this file I'm just going to create
a top level function called readlocationinfo.
So function readlocationinfo, and it's going to return
the map with all of the location instances.
So it's gonna return a map and the key will be
the location ID and the value is the location instance.
Okay, so the first thing I'll do in here
is create the map, that will eventually return.
So I'll say val locations equals and once again
we want it to be mutable 'cause we're going
to be adding to it as we read our data files.
And it's a mutable map of int and location.
And then I'm going to read the locations_big.txt file
so I'm gonna say file, locations_big.txt
and then I want a reader,
and then I want to do the following
for each line in the file.
I want to use the string.split method
to get the two pieces of information
that are on each line, the location ID and the description.
So I'll say IT.split and the delimiter is the funny
quotation mark that I changed it to.
And then we're going to create our location instance,
so I'll say val location equals location
and the first token is the location ID,
so we'll pass that first and the second token
is the description.
However, I do need to convert this to an integer
because right now it's a string.
So if we go back to our location class,
it wants the location ID and the description
and in our tokens array, the first token
is the location ID and the second token is the description.
And now I need to add this location instance
to our locations map.
So I'll say locations and the key for this
will be the location ID.
So I'm gonna say location.locationID equals
and the location instance we just created.
And that's it for reading our locations_big.txt file.
We've read in all of the lines, we've split each line
into the location ID in description
and we've created a location instance
and we then added that location instance
to the locations map.
So I'm now gonna use the same technique
to read the directions_big.txt file.
So I'll say file, directions_big.txt
and I'll want a reader and I'm gonna do something
for each line in the file.
In this case I'm going to again use the split method,
so IT.split but this time it's a comma that's the delimiter.
The first token is, we go back to our directions.big,
the first token will be the location ID
of the current location.
The second token is the direction letter
and the third token is the destination location ID.
So with that in mind we can now add the exit
to the location, so the first thing we have to do
is look up the location instance in our map.
So we'll say locations which is our map,
and we're going to use the current, the first token,
the current location ID to look up the location.
So we'll say tokens zero and we have to convert
that to an int.
And now here I'm going to use an operator
that's not familiar, but just understand for now
this has to do with Kotlin protecting against nulls.
And then I'm going to say add exit,
and the first thing we want to pass is the direction letter
'cause that's the key and the second thing
we want to pass is the destination ID
and I need to convert that to an integer.
So once again we're looking up the first token,
is the current location ID, so we're using that
to look up the location instance in our locations map.
And then we're calling the addExit function
which wants the direction which is the string
and the destination ID.
So it essentially wants tokens two and three
which are tokens one and tokens two,
and so that's what we're passing it here.
And so that's it, we've read in the directions_big.txt
and we've added each exit in that file
to the appropriate location.
So all that's left now is to return our map,
so let's go ahead and do that, return locations.
And that's it, we have now converted
our locations.java file.
Now looking at this and looking at location
I think you'll definitely agree that this
is more concise than the Java's location class
and you might be looking at this and wondering
how are we gonna access any of these properties,
there are no sets and gets and get to that in the course.
And this is also more concise, I think it's neater.
Now part of it is I'm not using a scanner,
but I do think it's a lot neater.
We can tell pretty much at a glance what's going on here.
So now all that's left for us to do is to convert
the game logic.
Oh but just before we do,
one thing I want you to notice
about the locations file is we don't have
a class in here, so obviously it's possible
in Kotlin to write code that is outside a class.
Alright, so now we'll convert the game logic
and I'm going to add another Kotlin file to that
and I'm gonna call it main.
And the first thing I'm gonna do
in here is add a main function
and I can do that by typing main and pressing enter.
And now I'm going to call the read location
info function that I just wrote to get all the data.
So I'll say val locations equals readLocationInfo.
And so we've now read in all our data
and then we're going to declare the loc variable
that always has the ID of the current location.
And just as in Java we're gonna set that
to 64 initially.
Now I'm gonna add an infinite loop
just like we did in Java.
And the first thing I'm going to do in this loop
is look up the location instance
for the current location ID, but I'm gonna do
something a little bit differently here.
So I'm gonna say val location equals locations loc
because this is a map, if we go back here,
this is a map of int and location where this is the
location ID and this is the instance.
So back here I'm saying I want the map entry
that maps to whatever is in loc, and that's going
to give me the location instance.
And I could stop there but I'm not going to.
I'm going to assign a default value
if this turns out to be null.
So if we do the lookup in the map
and we get a null back meaning there's no entry
in the map with the key loc.
I want to assign a default value to location.
Now this should never happen, if we've successfully
read in our data files this should never happen
but Kotlin doesn't know that, so if I don't protect
against a null here, if I don't protect
against location getting null I'm gonna have to do
something special throughout the rest of the code
to protect against nulls and I don't want to to that.
So instead I'm going to assign default value
if this turns out to be null, now there would
be nothing wrong with doing this special stuff
throughout the rest of the code,
but it does clutter the code.
And in this case I'm pretty sure this isn't gonna be null.
So I'm going to use what's called the Elvis operator
and you'll learn about this operator in the course
and I'm going to say if this turns out to be null,
so you look up the entry in the map
and there's no location instance with this key,
then assign this instance.
I want you to assign a location instance,
it has an idea of zero, and the description
for that instance will be sorry,
something went wrong, so the game will terminate.
I'll actually pull this back a bit
so you can see it.
Okay, so after that we're gonna go ahead
and print out the description, so we're gonna say
println, println location.description.
And so that's going to print out the description
for this location and if something did go wrong
this would be the description that would be printed out.
Then we're gonna check for the zero location
which is the quit location.
So if location.locationID equals zero.
And in that case just as in the Java application
we want to break out.
And once again if by any chance this default gets assigned,
I gave it zero because at this point we want to break
out because obviously something has
gone wrong with the game.
If the user doesn't want to quit, we'll print out
the available exits, so we'll say print available,
let me get rid of that dialogue there,
available exits are,
and now we're going to loop through the exits
for the location instance.
So I'm going to say location.exits.keys.forEach.
Remember that in the exits map the keys
are the direction letters
and that's what we want to print out.
So here I'll say print, we're gonna say dollar sign
I-T comma, and you'll learn all about this in the course.
So no we printed our exit so now we want to wait
for a direction from the user,
so I'm gonna say val direction equals readLine,
we want to read from the console.
Again, I'm going to use this operator here
and you'll learn about this later in the course,
it has to do with protecting against nulls.
And I want to upper case whatever the user gave us.
And then once again here I'm going to use
what's called the Elvis operator to assign a default
just in case this whole thing does evaluate to null.
And I'm going to assign a default of Z
because I know that there's no direction
that has the letter Z, so I know that this
is going to be invalid when we test the direction
that came back, and we're gonna do that right now.
So we say if location.exits.containsKey direction,
then we have a valid direction,
so we're gonna go ahead and get the location ID
corresponding to this direction, so in this case
it will be the destination location ID,
and we'll assign that back into our loc variable.
So we'll say loc equals location.exits
and we're gonna look up the direction
and this will return us the destination location ID
which we assign to loc.
Now you'll notice I have an error here
and once again this has to do with nullability.
I'm gonna add two exclamation marks here
and for now just understand that this is my way
of telling the Kotlin compiler that I am absolutely
sure that this is not going to be null,
because we've already looked up the key
and there's no reason if the exits map contains the key,
then I am 100% confident that it also contains
a non-null entry.
So this is my way of telling the Kotlin compiler look,
don't worry about nulls here, I'm telling you
that this is never going to be null,
otherwise I have to do other special things
which is why I was getting the error there.
Now if the exits map does not contain the key,
then the user has given us an invalid direction
or this evaluated to null for some reason,
so my default value of Z was assigned.
So in that case we're gonna say println
you can't go in that direction,
which is exactly what we did in Java.
Now in both cases we'll loop back up to the top
and the first thing we're gonna do is look up the new
location instance, which is the destination location
for the direction they went in.
And we rinse and repeat.
Now I think you'll agree 'cause we're finished now,
we're done, I think you'll agree that Kotlin
has its own flavour and it does seem to be
a little more concise, especially in these two classes.
And you may have spotted a few other things,
for example, I'm not using semicolons at the end
of lines in any of this code.
I pointed out that we have a function outside of class
and I pointed out a few places where we are having
to do something different because Kotlin
wants to protect against nulls.
One of its guiding principles is safety,
so I'm doing something different here,
I'm doing something different here,
and I'm doing something different down here
and also here.
I pointed out a point here where I'm doing something.
And we're gonna cover all of this in the course.
As I said at the end of the course,
we'll come back and we'll revisit this code
and at that point it's gonna look really straightforward
to you and you'll be able to explain
everything that's in this application.
Anyway, let's run.
I mean I've converted it but don't take my word for it
that this actually works, so let's run.
Okay, and we get you are at a complex junction,
a low hands an knees passage from the north
joins a higher crawl from, I still think that should
be crawlspace, from the east to make
a walking passage going west.
There is also a large room above, the air is damp here.
So let's do what we did in Java.
We'll go up, alright, now we're in a large room
full of dusty rocks, there was a hole in the floor,
there are cracks everywhere and a passage leading east.
Well let's go east.
Now we're in a dirty broken passage,
and to the east is a crawl space,
to the west is a large passage, above you is a hole.
Let's go up just for fun.
Now we're in a low north south passage at a hole
in the floor, and the hole goes down to an east west
passage, well that's where we were before
and at this point I'm gonna quit.
And it says you are sitting in front
of a computer learning Kotlin.
Alright, so our application works.
I hope you're excited about getting started with Kotlin.
In the next video I'm going to show you how IntelliJ
can convert Java to Kotlin for you,
and then we're going to get into the wonders of Kotlin.
I'll see you there.