As we've seen a few times now, Kotlin
provides shortcuts to avoid boilerplate
code that's always going to be the same,
so here's another change that can make
our code look neater. You can define
constants outside classes, how many times
do we write static classes filled with
constants in Java, perhaps not as often
once enums were added to Java, but before
then, we did it quite a lot and we
probably still do it quite a lot. Now in
Kotlin, you can have top-level constants,
just as you can have top-level functions,
so you don't have to declare a class and
fill it with constants. Let's add a
constant to our access modifiers file,
and then print it just to show how to do
this, so just under the package name
we'll say val my constant and we'll make
it 100. Now, of course constant should be
val variables you don't want them to be
changed, you want them to be immutable so
they're going to be val variables and
I've used uppercase for the constant
name as is conventional to do in Java.
Now, this is an int constant, we didn't
specify the type, so the default datatype
for a whole number is going to be int.
Now, we can use it as we'd use any other
variable, we'll print the constant from
the main function, so I'll do this right
at the top, I'll say print line my
constant, nothing earth-shattering here
if we wanted to we could have used this
within a string template, so we'll just
run and write at the top here, we'll see
100. So that's really all there is to
defining a constant, you can- you don't
have to create a class if you wanted to
find a bunch of constants, you can just
put the constants right at the top of
the file. Alright, so before we move on to
taking a close look at functions, you
need to know about data classes, this is
a special type of class that you might
want to use if the main purpose of a
class is to store state. When I converted
the text adventure application for
Kotlin right at the top of the course,
used a data class for the location data
because all the location class did was
stored information about a location,
it didn't do anything else. So if you
have a class and essentially it's all
it's doing is storing state, I mean it's
basically fields and setters and getters
and nothing else, then that's a good
candidate for a data class. Now when you
use a data class, you get some extra
functionality for free from Kotlin. So,
we're going to create a data class
called car, I'll just add it to the
existing file and our simple cars will
have three properties, the color,
the model name and the year. So let's come
here and this time I'll say data class
rather than just class, otherwise the
syntax will be the same, I'll call it car
and we'll give it a string property for
the color, we could use you know RGB
values or something, but let's keep
things simple val model and we'll also
make that a string and val your which
will be an int and we'll need curly
braces. So, as I mentioned to create a
data class, you start the declaration
with the word data. So what's different
about this class compared to a regular
class like employee? Well, we get some
functions for free, data classes come
with a nice two string function, a custom
implementation of the equals and
hashcode functions and a copy function.
now if you don't want the default
implementations of any of the provided
functions, you can add your own and
they'll be used. For example, if you
wanted to implement to string
differently, you just override the two
string function within the data class
and then your version of the two string
function would be used. Data classes also
get everything they need for a type of
declaration called a destructuring
declaration, we haven't covered those yet,
so don't worry about that now, I just
wanted to mention it. Now, data classes
have to meet certain requirements, first
of all the primary constructor has to
have at least one parameter and all the
primary constructor parameters have to
be marked val or var, you can't just
have a regular old parameter for the
primary constructor, like for example
with regular classes, you can see here
full-time doesn't have val or var in
front of it. It's just a regular
parameter, we're not declaring the
property in the primary constructor
signature. Also, data classes can't be
abstract, sealed or inner classes we're
going to cover inheritance later on and
that's when we'll discuss abstract and
sealed classes, just know for now that
they can't be abstract sealed or inner
classes. Now you can define properties
within the data class that aren't in the
defined in the primary constructor, but
when Kotlin generates the equals and the
hash code and everything else for you,
it won't include those properties,
it doesn't take those properties into
account. So it's best to declare all of
your properties within the primary
constructor signature. Okay, getting back
to our car class, let's see what's
printed out when we call the two string
function on an instance. I'm going to
comment out everything else, so that
we're not getting confused here and then
we'll say val car equals car and this
car will be blue, it'll be a Toyota and
let's say it's a 2015 model and then
we'll say print line car, let's see what
comes out. Alright, so we'll see that
right out of the box, without having to
override the two string method, we have a
very nice print out, we've got color
equals blue, model equals Toyota and year
equals 2015. Now if this was a regular
class of course, all we would have seen
here was the reference, the instance
reference but with a data class, you
getting nicer to string method, right out
of the box. Now, if you didn't like this
to string method, you could override it
in the data class and output something
else, now to show that this is a lot
nicer, let's uncomment these two lines
here and I'll just print
emp rather than printing out the name.
Let's run and you'll see the difference
now, so this is the nice two string out
of the box that we get from the data
class and this is the regular old two
string method that just prints out the
instance reference for a regular class
that isn't a data class. So let's try the
equals method, you'll recall that when we
use the structural equality operator
which is the equals operator and Kotlin
it's calling the equals function under
the covers to do the comparison, so let's
try this out with the employee class
first. So we have an employee called John,
let's create another instance and two
equals employee and we'll also call him
John and we're going to print out
emp equals emp2. So let's have a look at what
that gives us, now we're going to expect
false and the reason we're going to
expect false right now, even though these
two are structurally equal is that we
have not overridden the equals function
in the employee class. So right now, the
dot equals function is just going to
compare the two references and of course
they're not going to be equal because
we're dealing with two distinct
instances, so let's run and we get the
expected false. Now let's try the same
thing with car, so we'll say val car two
equals and I'll just copy this
declaration here and now let's print car
equals car two. Now just like with the
employee class, we haven't overridden the
equals function inside car, but let's see
what we get and in this case you'll see
that we get true, even though we haven't
overridden equals, because when you're
working with data classes, the equals
function is one of the functions you get
for free. Now once again, if you wanted to
override the equals function, because
let's say you only wanted cars to be
equal for some strange reason if they have the
in color, then you can do that you can
just go ahead and override the equals
function in the car class and you'll get
what you want to get, but if you want
equals to do what it normally does and
you get that for free, you don't have to
override the equals function here, you'll
see this class is still totally empty,
yet we have a nice two string function
and also we have structural equality
working the way we want it to work. Okay,
now I mention that you also get a copy
function for free in data classes and
that lets us make a copy of a car
instance. So let's give that a shot, let's
say val car 3 equals car dot copy and
then we'll print line car 3, see what we get.
Ok, so now we have a car that structurally
equal to car, the first car we created so
car 3 is structurally equal to car.
All the values have been copied over into
the new instance, now that's great but
what if we want to copy the car instance
but we want to change the year to 2016
and keep all the other values the same?
Well, that's not a problem we can do the
following, we can say val car 4 equals
car dot copy and then in here we can say
yeah, we want to copy it but this time
you want the year to be 2016. So keep all
the other values the same except for the
year, set that's 2016 and then let's
print out car 4, we'll run and we'll see
that we have a car instance here,
the color is blue the model is Toyota, but
this time in the year is 2016. So all we
have to do is specify what we want
changed, if we also wanted to change the
color, we could just add that here, we
could say oh, we want the color to be
green too, we don't want it to be
whatever it was blue. Let's run and now
the new instance has green it's still a
Toyota and the year is 2016.
So the names that you use in here of course
have to match your property names.
Now, you'll notice that because we're using
the names the properties could be in any
order down here in the primary
constructor signature, we're expecting
the color first and the year right at
the end, but up here we actually
specified the year first and the color
second and that's because we're using
name parameters and so there's no
confusion. Alright so that's a taste of
data classes, so they're great if you
have a class that's basically storing
state information and not doing anything
else. So remember in here, you've got all
of your gets and sets and you've got
an equals function, a hash code function
a to string and you've got a copy
function and all you had to do is write
two lines of code and one of them is a
closing brace, so that's Kotlin at its
best in terms of removing boilerplate
code, there's nothing in here.
Alright! I'll see you in the next video.