All right it's time to practice what you've learned in this section.
We're going to spend most of the challenge looking at Java calling Katlin.
But our first challenge will be about Cartland calling Java.
So I've created an Employee class in Java and if you download the starter project and the resources
you will get this class typed in for you.
So unless you really really feel like it you don't have to type it in again.
And as you can see it has four fields.
First Name Last Name Start and salary last three years and then it has a constructor that accepts the
first name last name star and just assigns those values and it initializes the salary last three years
field.
So now I'm going to go over to a Cartland file that I created and it's in a separate package.
And right now there's nothing in it.
And so I'm going to add the main function and I'm going to type in the following code and this code
will be in the starter project.
So I'm going to save Val.
Employee equals employee.
And the first name will be Jane the second name will be Smith.
And she started in the year 2000.
So we have the first name the last name and the start your.
So then I'm going to say employee Daut last name equals Jones.
Maybe she got married.
Maybe she changed her name for some reason.
And then I'm going to say employee Daut salary salary last three years equals.
And I just want to check the spelling of that to make sure I got it right.
So salary last three years equals we're going to say array of.
And we'll say fifty thousand dot.
Twenty five.
Fifty four thousand Daut.
Sixty and fifty six thousand eight hundred forty two.
So what I want you to do for your first challenge is to make this code compile so do what you have to
do either in this class in this file rather or the Employee class or both to make these two lines compile.
So when I say make the code compile I don't mean you can't change this code you've got to just somehow
make it compile.
But you know you can change this code.
You may have to change this code but what you essentially want to do is assign Jones to the employee's
last name and assign this array to the salary last three years.
So pause the video and give it a try OK welcome back.
Well we have a couple of problems here so let's go through them one by one.
So the first problem we're getting is cannot access last name.
It is private in employee.
So what do we do in Java when we want to allow the outside world to set the value of a private field
while we add a set method so let's do that I'm going to have intelligence you do it for me.
So all right click can say generate I want a setter and I want a sweater for the last name.
That's great.
But if we go back to the file the call in file will see that it's still telling us that it can't access
last name.
And the reason for that and maybe you are expecting it to fix the problem but the reason for that is
if we want to use the dot notation to access a Java field we have to have a set and a get.
So let's add a get here.
Have intelligent do it for me again.
So I want to get this time for a last name and now if we go back we can see that we can do it.
So if you want to be able to access a Java field using the Courtland's syntax employee Daut the field
has to have both a set and a get.
Now you might have done this you might have said employee set last name Jones and that's how you fixed
it and that's fine.
That works too.
But you'll see that if we hover our cursor here the IDE is giving us a hint it's saying use the property
access syntax which is what I usually say is the dot syntax.
So it's saying you know you could access this directly like you can access a property.
So it's giving us that hint because it knows we have a set and we get in the Java class so it knows
that we can access it that way and that's the more Cartland way.
So I'm going to put it back to that.
But if you came up with this if you added the set and you'll see now it's saying the get isn't being
used so if you went ahead and added a set and then changed it to this that works.
And if we comment out the get
You'll notice that this still works.
So we only need both a set and a get if we want to use the dot notation or the property access syntax
and you'll also notice we're not getting that hint now because now that we only have the set we can't
we cannot access it like we can access a property.
So let's uncomment this because we'd like to kind of do it do more Cartland way and we get the hint
back now and all change that back to.
Well same point you got last name equals Jones.
OK so that's one problem down.
So now we have the second problem and we can solve this error message in the exact same way it says
cannot access salary last three years it is private while we know how to fix that.
Now let's come in here and we'll add a set and a get for the salary last three years so I'll have intelligent
you do that for me.
I want a getter and setter for the salary last three years.
Q And now this problem goes away but we still have a problem which is devalue we have a type mismatch
and it says that the method wants a floater range we now know that that's a platform type because it's
got the Exham exclamation mark there but it actually found an array of double.
So if we go back to the math that we'll see that at once a primitive float array.
And as we learn we have to do something special in cotland when the method in Java once a primitive
array.
Right now we're trying to pass a big a array of double so we can fix the double problem by adding F
to the end of all of our literals here.
So now it's saying while you have an array of float remember that when it comes to floating point double
is the default sum unless you have the F suffix floating point literals are considered to be double.
So now that we've added the suffix to all of our literals we know we have a float array but it's a big
a float array and you can't pass big a Erase to primitive Java arrays.
We have to pass one of those special primitive type arrays and there are two ways we can fix this.
We can convert this big a array to a float array by saying to float array.
And that takes care of the error.
So here we started out with a big a float array and we've converted it to one of the special primitive
type arrays.
But since we know we want to do that anyway and we're not using this array anywhere else the second
way we could solve this is let's just start with one of those special arrays to begin with.
And so instead of array of we can just say float array of.
And that fixes the problem for us.
And now our code compiles so we're done.
That's challenge number one down.
OK so that's all we're going to do for a Cartland calling Java.
There are other things you need to be aware of but they're more along the lines of You need to be aware
of them rather than you must do something if you want to make this happen.
So let's switch over to calling Katlin from Java now and to do that we're going to start with a java
project.
So I'll say file new project.
I want a Java project so that's good and I want idea to create the main method for me so all select
this command line app template and I'll call this Java calling cotland and this package name is fine.
Call Katlin from Java.
That's what we're doing.
I think I use the same package in the video about this and that's probably remembering that from there
so I'll click Finish and I'm going to open this in this window.
All right.
So we've got our main class and our main method and now I'm going to create a package for the Cartland
code.
So all right click here saying new package and I'll call this cademy.
Learn programming dot and I'll call this Koplin code.
And then inside all creating Cartland file and I'll just call it CANTLIN code.
Now right away we're going to get the message that Cartland isn't configured and we know that we just
have to come down here and I'm going to select as Cartland Java module because I'm targeting the JVM.
So I'll click on that.
I'm going to accept all the defaults and the ID will add Katlin into this project and we now have Cartland
configured and we're ready to go.
All right.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to add to the employee class that we had in Java but
I'm not going to include the salary last three years field in the in the Koplin version so I'm going
to say class employee raúl first name in that string file last name is a string and vowels start.
And that's it.
And then I'm going to add a top level function.
I should mention here that the there's a starter project that will have all this code typed in for you
so you can type along with me if you want to reinforce the concept so you can just download the starter
project.
So I'm going to add a top level function called Say hello to Java.
It's going to take a name that's a string and all it's going to do is print line Portlands says hello
to Java and name.
And now I want to add an object class and I'm going to call the object challenge.
And this is just going to have a function called do math that takes two parameters X in line.
And all this does is adds x x and y and then multiply that by X minus Y minus Y.
And finally I'm going to add a function to the Employee class.
So we'll do that down here in a safe fun takes default.
And this is going to accept a parm one which is a string and Part Two Part 2 which is a string.
But this will have a default value of default.
And then inside the function it's going to print line.
Actually I need to double quotes here.
Form One and Part Two.
OK.
So let's pop over to our java file now and in our main method.
Let's write some code.
So I'm going to say Katlin stuff.
Daut.
Say hello to Java and I'm going to pass the name student.
You can pass your own name if you want semi-colon.
When I say employee employee equals new employee
John Smith and he started in 2010
and then I'm going to say employee start your equals 2009 let's say when whoever typed in John made
a mistake.
So we need to update the start you're going to say Challenge don't do math you math 5 and four
and I'm going to say employee got takes default and I'm going to pass it.
Our big one now as you can see there are quite a number of problems in here.
And your mission if you decide to accept it is to make this code compile.
Now there are two ways you could do this or you could do something in the Katlin file to make all this
code compile or for most of the cases you could update the Java code you could change the Java code.
I want you to only change the Cartland file.
So make all this code compile without changing it.
You should only have to make changes to the Cartland code file.
So good luck with that and I'll see you in of it.
All right welcome back so lets go through these one by one.
So the first one Cartland stuff.
Say hello to Java.
Well the compiler is telling us it can't find a class called Cartland stuff and that's because when
the CANTLIN compiler generates a static class for all the top level items it will call that class the
same name as a Cottman file.
So in this case the class will be called Cartland code Caity but we want to refer to that classes as
stuff.
So what we need to do is we need to tell the Cartland compiler that when it generates the static class
to call it Courtland's stuff rather than Cartland code Katie and the way we do that is by using the
JVM name annotation So let's add that.
And remember this goes above the package so we'll say X-File JVM name and we want to call this Koplin
stuff.
So now what this will do is it will tell the compiler that when it generates a static class for the
top level items to call it Cartland stuff and if we go back to our Java file we've now fixed the first
problem and you'll see that an import has been added up here as well.
OK so that's one down.
So our next problem is it's telling us that Star has private access in Academie don't learn programming
Katlin cocotte employees so let's go ahead and look at what's going on here.
First of all we have two problems because right now the star year is a vowel and so we need to change
that to a VAR but we'll see that that still doesn't fix the problem.
And the reason for that is we have to tell the CANTLIN compiler that we want this property to be able
to be accessed from Java using the dot notation like we're doing here.
So the way that we do that is we use the at JVM field annotation.
So let's go ahead and say that JVM field and if we head back to main That's our second problem taking
care of.
So our third problem is that it's saying a non-static method cannot be referenced first from a static
context.
No what's happening here is at the moment the hotlink compiler is only generating an instance method
for do math.
It's not generating a static method.
So we're saying that we want to access this method in a static way so in order to force the Codling
compiler to generate a static version of this method we have to annotate this with the JVM static annotation.
Do that G B and static.
And now if we come back to our file we fix that problem.
So now what will happen is when we add this annotation the Cartland compiler will generate both a static
and an instance version of this method.
So now we're calling the static version of Do mass which is what we wanted.
All right so our final problem is we have an error here and we have an error because the compiler is
looking for a method that takes two strings but our Takes default method and Katlin has a default value
for the second parameter.
The second parameter is optional.
So how can we make it optional in Java.
Well when you have optional parameters in Katlin the Cartland compiler only generates one method under
the covers and that method has both parameters.
It requires both parameters and we don't want that we want a method that will just take the one parameter
and in order to make the Cartland compiler generate all possible versions of the method we have to use
the at JVM overloads annotations so let's do that.
And so now we're saying to the compiler don't just generate a Takes default method that requires part
1 and part to generate one that takes both and generate one that just takes part one.
If we go back to our file we've now fixed all our problems.
So that's wonderful we manage to fix all our problems without touching this code which was a challenge.
But as I said you could have done it by making changes to the Java code when I'm going to do is I'm
going to control C
control the to copy all of this.
I'm going to comment this out and now what I want you to do is you want to do the same thing in here
you make copies of everything that we did small comment that out and
you go to the end here you'll like that and I'll comment this one out and I'll do the same thing here.
Comment that one out and I'm going to comment this out as well I guess I commented out the wrong one
for some of these
because when I want you to do if you haven't guessed isn't going to want you to fix it in the Java code
now.
So I'll take out that I'll take this out and I'll take this out.
And then we should be back to the situation of nothing compiling and we are.
So what I want you to do now is I want you to fix this.
Just touching the Java code.
So don't touch the Katlin code and I'm not going to be mean.
I'm actually going to comment this one out because there is no way for you to fix this one in a Java
code.
This is the one case where you can only fix it in the Cartland code by using the JVM overloads.
So I'll actually remove these guys remove that one and just put it back to what it was.
So fix these three just by changing the Java code give that a try and I'll see you in a bit.
OK welcome back.
Well to fix this one as I mentioned when we went over the other solution the Cartland compiler is going
to be generating a class called Cartland code Caity.
So we're going to use that filename Koplin code and you can see it suggested to us.
So there we go.
We fix that one to fix this one.
It's already Vark because we want it back.
I didn't want to change this code but we can just then call the set method and we can just say employee
Daut set start year.
And what did I say 20 2009.
Well whatever I said so that fixes that one.
And for this one this isn't really a fix.
You can't call this statically.
But I wanted to leave this one in because you can call the instance method and you can do that by using
the instance Daut.
Now depending on what this method is doing you might not want to do that.
In our case it's fine because all it's doing is a calculation.
But if this function was referencing a static property let's say and accumulating a value every time
you called it then you would not want to be calling the instance version you'd want to be calling the
static version.
So there is no fix in the Java code to calling the static version.
If you don't have this JVM static then you're not going to.
There is no static version of the method that's going to be generated.
So you're not going to be able to call it.
But if you don't mind calling the instance method then you can just use instance.
Now we have an error here because now the Cartland stuff import is invalid.
So I'll just comment that out but otherwise everything's fine and let's try running the main method
and we get Cartland says hello to Java and student because that's the only thing that's actually printing
anything here.
So I guess it's up to you how you want to resolve some of these things when you're calling call in from
Java you might want to use a set methods and get methods if the rest of your code that's referencing
Java classes let's say is using Santon get.
And if you don't care what the name of the cotland class is you can just go ahead and keep it as the
default name that the compiler is going to generate.
And as I said this one you have to think about it it's going to depend what the function is doing.
So there were two ways we could have fixed most of these.
Only one way for this one and for this one it would depend on what you were doing.
There wouldn't be a fix if you wanted to access it statically if you did want to access it statically.
You'd have to do that by adding the JVM static.
Now one more challenge for you.
For this function here if you wanted Koplin to throw an illegal argument exception whenever null was
passed for parm one what would you have to do.
So positivity you and think about that for a minute what would you have to do if you wanted Cartland
to throw an illegal argument exception.
If Java calls takes default and passes a null for one paused the video and gives some thought to that
OK welcome back.
Well the answer is nothing.
You don't have to do anything because string is a non nullable type.
You've already told the Cartland compiler that you don't expect now.
And so if we call it from Java and we pass and all the compiler will already be generating the checks
that it does to make sure that this isn't null so let's give that a shot will say employee dot takes
default.
And because I don't think does this version have JVM overloads us so we can just pass.
No it isn't and that will compile but what will happen when we run.
Let's give it a try.
And boom we get the illegal argument exception parameters specified as non-null.
And you'll notice that we get that online 20s so we get it as soon as we call the method.
We don't actually have to reference it if I comment this line outs and how this parameter isn't being
referenced at all.
And I run again we're going to get the same thing happen because what happens under the covers is when
this function is entered the compiler generates a check to make sure that this isn't Knol and if it
is it throws the exception.
Now if I had a question mark here to make this nullable and we we run we won't see the exception.
And if I can comment this out and run again we'll see that we get null and default printed.
So you don't have to do anything special if you want Katlin to protect against Nalls when there's not
supposed to be an all when you're calling from Java.
If you're using non nullable types you're going to get the usual protection and that's it for this section.
I'll see you in the next one.