Ok, so now we're going to look at an
important behavioral difference between
Java and Kotlin, and that's in the area
of referential versus structural
equality, so we're actually going to
start out by looking at some Java code
so that we can be sure that we're all on
the same page. So, I'm not going to make
you watch me type in the java code,
because you already know Java, so I've
already done this and basically I've
created an employee class in Java. I'm in
a Java project here and this is
a .java file. I've created the equivalent
employee class that we've been working
with over in Kotlin so it has a name and
ID and they're both private,
the constructor just as a usual constructor.
And then I've written a quick and dirty
equals method to compare two objects and
see if they're equal, obviously I should
also be overwriting hash code etc., but
this is just for demonstration purposes,
so I've just done a very quick and dirty
equals method. So now that you've seen
this, I'm going to switch over to the
main class, it's going to make use of the
employee and so here all I'm doing is
creating three instances of the employee
class, the first one has a name of Mary
and an ID of one and the second and
third one both have a name John and ID
of two and that's intentional, because
we're going to be looking at equality.
And then down here, I'm printing out the
result of four conditions, in the first one,
I'm comparing employee one to
employee two, using the equals operator.
And we're going to expect false because
the equals operator is actually checking
for referential equality which means
that it's going to return true if the
instance on the left hand side is the
exact same instance as the one on the
right hand side otherwise it's going to
return false and employee one and
employee two are two separate and
distinct instances, so we expect false
and the same goes for employee two
equals employee three, because the
employee two an employee three are not
the exact same instance.
However. when we call the
.equals method, we're still going to
expect false for the first one, because
the two instances have different
contents, in other words they're not
structurally equal, but we're going to
expect true when we call the .equals
method to compare employee to an
employee three, because they are structurally
equal, both of the names are equal to
John and both of the ID's are equal to 2.
So, let's run this to make sure that our
guesses are right, so we're expecting
false, false, false, true. And that's what
we get, false, false, false, true. So, in Java
the equals operator is checking for
referential equality and the .equals
method is checking for structural
equality and you probably already know
this, but just in case I wanted to make
sure we're all on the same page before
we go over to Kotlin, so let's do that now.
Ok, so we're back in Kotlin and let's
go down to our employee class, obviously
it looks a little different than Java
and we have to write a lot more code in
Java this class is actually doing what
the Java class is doing except,
of course it doesn't have the equals method
So, let's implement the equals method now
and I will make you or rather function I
should be saying, however I will say this
in Kotlin often when functions or
members of classes they're called methods.
Honestly, the terms tend to be used
interchangeably, but if a function is
actually a member function then it's
often referred to as a method, I'll use
both terms because I have one foot in
Java and one foot in Kotlin, so it'll be
wherever my brain is at the time,
calling the equals function a method
but here actually isn't incorrect, so I'm
going to make you watch me type in the
equals method, because you're learning
Kotlin and this is another good way and
code along with me. Now we haven't
covered functions yet, so bear with me.
I'm going to start with the override
keyword because we're overriding a mess
in the superclass for this class fun,
which you've seen before, which is what
we use to declare a function and then
the function name and then I'm going to
specify the function parameters. So in
this case, we're going to take an object
of type any don't worry about this
question mark and the function is going
to return a type of boolean so right now
we have an error, because the function is
not returning anything, so I'm going to
make this a really really naive
implementation of equals just so you
don't have to see me type in a lot of
stuff, I'm just going to say if obj is an
employee so that's basically doing an
instance of, then I'm going to return
true if the name of this instance is the
same as the name of the object that was
passed in and the ID of this instance is
the same name as the ID that was passed in,
now that's a really naive
implementation, but it'll work,
it'll serve our purposes. Of course, I've also
got to return false here in the case
that the is test fails so this is doing
the same thing it's not as safe, well
actually it is because we're using
something called a safe-safe type here
and we'll get into that later, but
basically this is checking for
structural equality, so with that in mind
now that we have our equals function,
let's do the same test that we did over
in Java. So I'm going to go back here and
I'm going to put this at the top of the
method, just so we can see it right away.
And I'm going to say val let's call it
employee, we already have an employee
on and stuff, so I'll just call,
I'll stall them out val employee one equals
employee and we'll say Mary and we'll
give her an idea of one, we'll create our
second employee John,
and he has an ID of two and then
of course, we want the exact same thing for
our third employee -John,
and he has an ID of two and now we want
to test our for condition, so we'll
print employee one equals employee two,
we'll print employee two equals employee three and
then we'll use the .equals method
like we did over in Java, so we'll do
employeeone.equals, employee two and
employeetwo.equals(employeethree).
Ok, so these were the same test that we did in
Java. Now, in Java we got false for the
first one, because they're not the exact
same instance, we got false for the
second one, because they're not the exact
same instance, for the first .equals
we got false, because they're not
structurally the same either, the two
instances don't contain the same values
for all the fields, but we got true for
the fourth one, because these two
instances are structurally equal.
So, let's go ahead and run this and see what
we get printed out and I think I'm going
to uncomment everything that we have
here or comment it rather, so that we'll
just see the one thing printed. Alright,
so let's go ahead and run. Ah! we didn't
get the same thing we got in Java,
in Java, we got false, false, false, true but
here, we're getting true for the second test.
So the equals operator is when it
compares employeetwo and employeethree.
It's telling us that oh those two are the
same. So here is a very important
difference in behavior between Kotlin
and Java, in Kotlin the equals operator
checks for structural equality when it's
comparing instances, we're actually
repeating ourselves here, because
this operator when you're doing a
comparison between instances actually
just defers to the dot equals method.
And so, we're actually doing the same thing
twice and because this is Kotlin,
we would want to write it like that because
it's more concise. So of course,
that raises the question, how do we check for
referential equality? I mean this is all
great we can now check for structural
equality just by using the equals
operator, but how about referential
equality? Well, that's where the triple
equals operator comes in, so instead of
using a double equals, I'm just going to
copy these two copy and paste these two
lines here, we're just going to add
equals to each of these and now we are
checking for referential equality here.
So, if we run now we're going to expect
to see the same results we saw in Java.
And we do, so we're now getting false for
the first three conditions and true for the last one.
So, again this is a really really
important difference that you have to
know about, because if you're used to
checking for referential equality using
the equals operator, you're going to have
to remember that you can't do that in Kotlin.
That in Kotlin, this is equivalent
to calling the .equals function and
you'll want to use the triple equals
when you want to check for referential equality.
So, let's have another variable
called employeefour and we'll assign it
employee two, so now these two should be
referentially equal, because they
contain the reference to the same
instance, so if we now use triple equals
to compare them, this should be true.
Let's give it a shot, and we do get true.
So when the instance on the left hand
side is the exact same instance as the
instance on the right hand side,
the triple equals operator will return true.
Now, how about not equals? Well, there are
not equals and not double equals, I guess.
That's the equivalent of the
triple equals to use and so let's give
those a shot. Let's see if employeefour
is not equal to employeetwo. And what
else can we check? Well let's check
whether employee four is not exactly the
same as employee two. And, we'll do one
more or a couple more.
We'll try employeetwo not equal to
employeethree and we'll try employeetwo
not double equal to employeethree.
So, let's look at these and see what we'd expect.
Well, employeefour not equal to
employeetwo should be false because we
know they're exactly the same instance,
employeefour not referentially equal to
employeetwo would also be false, because
they are the same instance, so both of
these are going to fail. Now is employeetwo
not equal to employeethree?
This should also return false because this is
checking for structural non equality and
they're structurally equal.
However, employeetwo not referentially equal to
employeethree should return true,
because employeetwo and employeethree
are distinct instances, so in this case
we're expecting false, false, false and
then true. So let's run and that's what
we see for the last four conditions
false, false, false and true.
Alright, what does this mean? Well, in Kotlin you
never have to explicitly call the
.equals method when you want to test
whether two instances contain the same
values, which means whether they're
structurally equal, you can just use the
equals operator. And when you want to
test whether two instances are in fact
the same instance, you use the triple
equals operator and keep in mind that
you can use not equals and not equals
equals to test non equality.
So, that's it for this video.
This is an important difference between
Kotlin and Java so keep this in mind as
you're working with Kotlin.