Okay, so let's just go over a couple of
more sort of minor but important
differences between Kotlin and Java.
First of all the bit operators, there's
been a minor change there, I'm just going
to make some room here and type in some
code that we're going to delete. As you
know in Java, you can do something like
this. Well you wouldn't need val let's
just go. Well, I'll use Val here so the
compiler won't report an error. You can
go zero X zero zero one zero one, one
zero one whatever and you can do val y
equals zero X one one one one zero one
one zero one one and then you can do
things in Java like X or Y, X and Y.
You can see that the compiler here is giving
us some errors and it's because these
operators don't exist you, actually spell
them out in Kotlin. So you'd go X or Y and
you'd go X and Y. So you can see we're
not getting the errors now we're not
assigning them to anything, but we're not
getting the errors and you know you'd
use X or so for the bitwise operators
you spell out the operator rather than
using a symbol. So that's one difference to
be aware of. The other thing we're going
to discuss in this video is casting.
Casting and type checking.
So in Kotlin, if you want to check
whether a variable is of a certain type,
you use the is operator rather than
instance of. So let's try it, we'll say
val something and we'll make this as
type any which is sort of kind of like
object in Java but not not exactly but
it can hold any Kotlin object, so we'll
assign employee four to that employee
four that we created in that in a
previous video and then we say if
something is an employee and then we go
ahead and do something. So as you can see,
instead of saying if something instance
of employee, we say something is employee.
So when you want to check the type of an
instance, you use is. Now, of course
there's also there not is, so you can say
if not is employee that works, so the you
know the coding here would be executed
if something was not an employee, so you
can do that as well/
Okay so let's stick with is though and
let's say okay so you want to do
something with employee, maybe get the
name, so you want to cast it now in java
of course, we go employee something in
Kotlin we say val new employee equals
and we say something as employee. So this
is how you do a cast in Kotlin, you use
the as keyword and you say I want to
treat this variable as this class. Now
you're going to see that no cast is
needed, hold that thought for now and
then we could do something like, you know
print line new employee dot name and
that would work. Now you'll notice this
is all grayed out, as I said as employee
and I said hold the thought and it says no
cast needed and the reason that no cast
is needed is because Kotlin has a notion
known as smart casting, after you've
performed an is check which we're doing
up here, you can then go ahead and treat
the variable as if it has been cast.
Now, underneath the covers the compiler is
doing the casting for you so once again,
this is sort of a syntactical saying
where the compilers doing some extra
checking and generating some extra code,
so we don't actually have to type it,
because this is very common in Java,
right? Where we'd say if something is
instance of employee and then if it is
inside the following block of code we
cast it and then we start using the cast,
the casted variable essentially.
So, because it's so common Kotlin has smart
casting and so we don't actually have to
do this, we can just delete this line
actually. I'll comment it out actually
and we can then just get rid of that and
just go ahead and use something,
and we don't have to actually cast it, so
after using the is check after the
compiler has verified that an instance
is in fact of a particular class, you can
go ahead and start using it as if the
variable is of that type. Now this
doesn't work if you change the value to
something other than it's been employee.
Like, if you do this and then you come in
and say oh let's say something is now a
string, you're going to see two things,
first it can't be reassigned so let's
change that to var, just so we don't have that
particular error, but you're going to see
now that you can't refer to name so the
compiler is saying excuse me,
you've now reassigned this variable.
You've changed the value, I can no longer
guarantee that something is an employee
and so you're not allowed to access it
like that anymore. Now, this would work if
we've said something is employee one,
let's say. The compiler smart enough to
see that oh, you're still working
with an employee. Because inside this
block of code, essentially the compiler
has kind of typed something as employee.
So as long as you're still assigning
employees to it, it's fine, but the moment
you decide you're going to assign
something else to something, at that
point you can no longer use it as if
it's an employee, for obvious reasons.
So this is known as smart casting and this
is yet another way that Kotlin cuts
down on the amount of code that we have
to write. See in the next video.