Friends here our concept is a WK or oc command.
Say before going to work with AWS or oc command.
Let me show you the differences between a grip with Cut command
and AWPA command so that you will come to know the importance of AWPA command.
Let me explain that.
Suppose I want to find V HTTPD version,
then I can run this command and I can see my output here as to dot-dot-dot for one.
But I want to display exactly this version.
I don't want this to these remaining information.
Then you have to apply filters.
The very first one,
I am applying grep Fader.
I'm gripping a line
which is having version because we don't know what is the version we're having here.
It may be any version based on Apache which we install on our host.
That's why first-time trying to filter the first-line.
Yes, we are getting that first line.
Now.
In this line, here he how your version.
Now if I assume our line as some fields,
then somewhere some field,
you will get your version.
And just before your version you how slash.
Now I am assuming field separator,
column separator as slash so that this entire thing is the foster column or foster field.
Then the main thing is secondary lot second column.
So by applying cut command,
I am taking field separator as a slash,
then you are information is there in the second field?
Yes, we are getting.
But if you observe the output,
it is having parenthesis as well.
I want to remove them,
then try to apply once again,
you are cut command on this output by assuming space as the fields operator.
Because between these two spaces there,
if I assume the field is operator,
then I can say that this is the first official or foster
column and this is a second field or second column.
Now let me try to apply once again our cut command.
But here I am taking field separate address space so that our first release,
our worst hand information.
That's fine.
Now, instead of grip with Cut command,
I can directly take AWPA command.
And by using that also I can get this information.
Let me show you that with step-by-step.
Suppose I am running first HTTPD hyphen v,
then you are getting your output.
None. Here.
I'm applying a WK command.
First, I'm trying to get the line in which we have a version.
Then let me print that.
So these are syntax, but don't worry about syntax.
We have a detailed discussion for that.
Now you're getting first-line C in your cut command.
You can assume some fields operator,
but that fields operator always a single character.
But whereas in AWPA command,
you can provide your field separator with first hyphen.
Yet, here we are using hyphen D,
but here you have to take iPhone5 fields operator.
And these fields operator,
you can write some pattern,
a pattern that presents multiple strings.
Know what I'm doing here is I'm assuming space,
space or slash as my fields operator.
You know, from your grep command somewhere used.
We use square brackets inside that we heard in some year and B.
Then what is the meaning for that,
either a or B, the same way.
Here, I mentioned my fields operator inside of square brackets.
First argument some space.
Then how given slash?
The meaning for the days fields operator is slash or space or both.
Now if you observe in your output here there is a space here,
there is a space here, slashes there.
So you would aid obligate command.
We take two characters at a time to separate your information.
Now, this is foster field,
this is second field.
This is third field here space is there,
here slashes then, but we are given both to,
that's why first failed,
second field, third, fourth, fifth.
Now let me try to print fifth field.
So if you want to print a fifth field here,
you have to take, sorry, four to field.
You have to take dollar for.
Now. See, there is a did I miss?
Yeah, I missed one more single quotation here.
I've opened here single quotation,
but I misread that politicians are important.
Let me close with quotation. Now see the result.
In shut off writing this a lengthy command,
instead of using two different commands,
instead of using two times cot command.
By using simply AWPA command,
we are able to get our required information.
But here, if you want to use a WK command,
you How to good with patterns,
how to create a patterns we already discussed about patterns in our Grip command.
Same rules are applicable here to write your patterns.
So this is the difference between your cut and AWPA Command C.
Instead of using grep command to serve some lines directly,
we can use a WK command by writing your sum such string.
So here we can get pattern, right,
the same pattern you can right,
between these two slashes.
The way how we discuss with Grip command,
same patterns we can write here also.
And we can also write patterns or feel separate Roosevelt such
that we can write our time number of fields,
number of fields operators.
So that is the advantage.
And so if you have a W get command,
then why we are,
why we explained about Cut command previously.
If you want to get characters,
then you how to use Cut command only.
In AWS command always you have to,
you will get fields only.
But in cut command we can get fails as well as characters.
So from now onwards,
if you want to get some characters,
foster two or some number of characters,
then go with Cut command.
But if you want to get fields, go with it or leaky,
so that you won't get confused. Ok, fine.
Now let me go and work with you or a delicate command.
First thing we know,
Cut command is going to work on each and
every line to get characters or feels the same way.
A delegate comment also is going to work on each and every line.
But here line is called record.
Line or row is called a record.
And we know columns,
columns are nothing but feels in your cut command and here also.
And you can use this cut commands or AWPA command as a Linux command.
And also there is a separate scripting language is there with your AWPA combined?
That is the advanced level.
So there is a separate course for that AWPA study.
Anyway, I will also give you some information how to write your academic history.
But for time me, forget about AWPA scripting.
A delicate scripting easily exactly or shell scripting, Bash shell scripting.
Ok. As I've don't just assume that AWPA is a command,
but do we help scripting as well?
Now let me do the simple syntax for your edit locate command or oc command.
Awpa.
Options. Options are always optional.
So just now we have given hyphen your fear.
This is option on here.
We didn't provide that option.
If you want, you can prove and otherwise you can skip.
Then in single quotation,
you have to provide some selection criteria and some action.
Action is there in the curly braces.
This action is always with the print and the selection criteria is optional.
So if you want, you can provide,
suppose here I have given selection criteria as some such string.
Not only such a string, you can also put some condition as well.
Ok, now, so this is the syntax we use ANOVA command line.
But instead of providing your output from a command badly,
if you have a SAM file, you can port your file also here.
So now actually you are having different types of options for
your AWPA command there like hyphen,
Yeah, just to provide fields operator,
just know we used that.
And other than that, we have two more options,
but we'll discuss them in a delicate scripting part.
Not no. Then selection criteria,
it may be a pattern or condition.
Pattern is nothing but with what string you want to
search in the file or in the output condition,
we can get some condition here itself.
I can apply that.
Suppose if you are sure that your information is there in the first lane.
Now instead of writing one,
I can write line number means number of
records or the number for your record is first-line.
See that same you are getting.
So you can write either pattern or condition. That is the condition.
Work on only first-line amines.
Record number for your record, first record,
first-line, Nazi. Then action.
So Anwar, matching pattern or on your satisfied condition,
what are the condition you are writing in your AWS command on that?
What is the action you want to perform for 3000?
Some logic that is always with the print.
I mean in your edit wiki command,
but not in your Angelica scripting.
So as a beginner,
don't worry aboard does scripting just try to concentrate on a Duplicate command.
Now, let me explain that first thing.
Very simple, eta, locate command ease simply AWPA, action, input file.
Actually it's always with the print statement. See that?
Suppose, let me take some file.
This one, I will create some way,
some demo dot TXT.
Before that, let me commend when let me nullify that.
I'm writing something like column one,
column two, column three, column four.
Let me write once again column one.
Now I am giving tab space, column two,
tab space, column three.
Let me take only two lengths snowballing.
Now.
A WK start with single quotation,
curly brace directly or action.
So I want to print only Foster Field first column from each and every line.
Then printed $1.1.
$1.1 means first column, foster field.
Then provide your demo 2.txt.
I mean, you are a file on which you want to perform this action C
that you are getting column one from those two lines.
Actually, if you observe your content,
which is there in your file,
first tip, row, first record is subreddit with spaces.
But second record or second row or second line is operating with a tab.
So by default, AWPA will consider tab also as a space.
So now you can say
that default delimiter default to feel separator for AWS command easiest space.
Be clear for Cut command default.
Fields operator is pap.
But here, space and a tab will also consider as a space in your AWPA command.
That's it. Now these are very simple one.
In case of default,
separator is there with the word file to separate your fields or columns,
then no need to write any field subarea directly
can perform your action in which really want.
That's a.
Now, let me see.
Suppose this is the common output.
Now I want to get first afield from those two lines,
then AWPA brink, $1.1.
See what you are going to get.
You're going to get servers, server because default separate resists space.
Now here space is there,
here also space is there.
Then there is Foster Field,
second field, the center up to the start of it.
This is for the field. So in second line, first, second, third,
fourth, because he has spaces that fifth,
spaces that sixth. That's it.
Now let me try to print a six,
the field in first-line we don't now 63, then you will get empty.
But in second line we have a sigma field.
You are getting that.
That's it.
Right? Now.
You have some default variables with your comment or end of leaky command.
There.
Just now we have seen $1.1, $1.6.
Likewise you how $1.2 dollar infinity.
Suppose if I take c,
what you are going to get a WK print $1.
I'm providing input file.
I can provide input file on.
I can apply an obligate command on the output by using pipe bend symbol,
let's say demo dot txt output,
they are going to get entire file, not only $1.
If you remove that by default there is knowledge 0.
That's it.
So whenever if you take a W get command,
print $1 R without any variable name here,
if you simply use print,
it is going to print n-type content.
But if I take $1.1,
it is going to print Foster Field, foster column.
Suppose if I want to print first two column and third column,
then take $1.1 comma three so that you are going to get first, third, right?
And by default the output fields operator is also a space.
Be clear.
So if you want to get other fields operator,
you can get from our advanced level scripting.
I will show you our Diane. I mean,
let me show you that but don't get confused.
If I write that, you may get confused.
Let me write it.
Begin to write some script here.
Output fields operator equals two.
I want to get suppose, underscore.
Say that, but don't get confused with this one.
Again, we'll discuss that in our AWS crippling part.
Fine.
So first thing I want to get first third fees.
Yes, you are getting now I want to reverse
my third first feed while displaying in output.
Then write it in the I'm in first as $1.3.
There.
It's very, very important this point,
how to reverse your fields using AWPA command.
It is possible with your AWPA command.
Okay? No dollar TO second than you.
How some n naught it will print line or record number c.
Let me printed there so that you can understand.
So how many records are lines are there in your file?
Only to suppose if I write N r c 12.
So I want to print entire file with line numbers.
Then first n naught means see whenever
you free AWPA command is working with the first-line. Nr is foster.
One.
If it is working with second line, n naught is two.
So automatically it will increase and will display the value.
We know $1 means entire phi.
Now I am printing entire file with line numbers.
There is one more variable called m. So it will print how many fields are there,
how many columns are there in each and every line?
So at the ending, I'm printing.
You can also write at first,
but just I am writing at the end C,
there is a first-line.
How many fields are there?
Three fields. Second line,
how many fields are the three fields?
Let me add some more fields.
In third, I'm writing column one,
column two, column three,
and column four, and I'm writing column one.
Now for records we are having let me print them.
In first record.
Record means you are lying in first record we held three fields.
This is second record in second decoder also 3.
Fourth, third record for fields.
Fourth record one field.
Know logically I can print some information here.
And the first thing, if I run this thing,
you're getting your output right. Now.
I want to print last field from each and every line.
C.
If you want to, suppose if I write simply $1.3 here,
you will get from first-line,
you'll get Column three from third line triggered column three.
But this is not the last field, this is the last to fail.
But you know, if you observe here
automatically you were NF is giving the number of fields.
Now if I write it dollar enough,
dollar, NF Beatley or without inevitably do the count.
But dollar enough means whenever if it is working with the foster feel sorry,
foster record enough will replace with the three so that this will become $1.3, $1.3.
This you will get.
And whenever if it is working with the third row,
third record, how many fields are there for?
So this value will be get by using NF.
But far enough we are writing dollar then dollar,
NF means dollar for dollar forming fourth column.
So automatically you will get lost a field from each and every record by using dollar NF.
Just simple logic.
And one more logic.
Now, this is useful,
but the second thing is just four logically, it is useful.
You can understand, I want to print from first record,
first to fail from Second Record,
second feet from third record, third field.
Then you can use inner Because if you observe another line numbers, now let me do that.
Simply. I'm printing only dollar in NOR,
so that from first to record you'll get foster
field from secondary God, you'll get secondary.
Third record, third, fourth record for the field,
but you don't have for the field in the fourth regardless, we are getting an empty.
That's it, guys.
This is the simple way to understand the uses of AWPA Command C. As of now,
I have given the very basic AWPA command,
and this is simply part one.
So we have advanced level advocate scripting that we'll discuss after some concerts.
Because this edge obligate command I want to use in some simple shell scripts.
That way. That's why I have given here.
Okay.
Okay guys, thank you.