Friends here our concept is operations on strings.
So these operations are very,
very important while working with the real time scripts,
especially while working with the path.
Now let me go with one by one.
The very first one is how to find these string length.
Let me explain them with a simple shell script.
See, suppose very first line,
I'm writing bin bash,
I mean shebang line.
Then let me define a variable called shell.
Simply I store in a string called shell into a variable called my name.
Now you know how to display variable value.
You can use either this syntax or you can use dollar curly brace.
You will have variable name.
Both will give the same result.
Now, just provide the exclusion permissions
for that and see the content of before running your code.
Now see there is a what are giving same result.
Now in the second syntax,
I'm using hash before you were variable name starts. Now see the result.
What we are getting, we are getting length or fewer variables means the data,
which is their newer variable.
Because of this syntax,
we are getting the length while we are getting phi means.
In this variable we have a data called shell.
So in that shell we have 5K characters.
That's why it is giving phi.
Suppose if you are string consists of space. Space.
Space is also a character.
I'm giving one space then some letter called S. Now forced to see your core ones.
Now observe the output in your string, in your variable,
in your string, you have Sheldon space then yes, finally,
seven characters, Yes, you are getting that C. Instead
of directly displaying your length of a string,
you can assign that into your variable as well.
Let me take my variable called mine, named length.
Friends here I have taken a variable names such a way
that it consists of all four beds and underscore.
You can also how numbers in your variable.
Fine.
Now, if you want to assign the length of your string into a variable, simply,
you can follow this syntax,
whatever we are using to display that we can assign and be available as well.
Now let me display word length of a string with respect to variable as well.
My name length.
So inside of this variable, what is there?
The length of your variable?
So actually what is the your variable value shall yes,
that means this is string length we stored into this variable and we are printing that.
No, let me save this and run it and see the result. Yes, it's working.
Now I am doing one thing for second eco command, echo command.
Simply, I am writing Hash before starting you what line?
See whenever if you place hash symbol before starting you what ln, x shebang line.
While executing your core shell will skip this line simply you are shall.
We'll assume that that is not the part in your code.
So actually, hash symbols are used to commend a code.
So to write some comments,
we can use hash symbols.
Now let me save this c you are core first and let me run that and absorbed output.
We are getting the output from this line,
not from this because that is commented simply you are,
shall we assume that that is not the part in your core?
Suppose if you want to come in multiple lines,
suppose I want to commend all the lines,
then for all the lines, how to write hash symbol.
So instead of writing hash symbol for each and every line,
you can also do one thing that is this syntax you can follow to come into multiple lines.
Suppose I am writing my comment one.
Then up to this, I want to comment,
I don't want to execute all these codes,
then you can follow this syntax.
So because of this syntax,
what will happen means whatever the lanes which are there between these two lines are,
those lines will skip while executing your code.
Now we don't have any lines to execute because whatever the lines were having,
all those lines are there between these two symbols.
Between these two lines?
That means this code is commented.
So while executing your code, you are shelled.
We'll skip the lines which are there between those less than,
less than and some name and the name.
Now, if I run now,
there is no output because there are no lines to execute.
Actually we how, but we commented them.
That's a fine.
Now the next operation is how to join two or more parts.
That is nothing but concatenation of strings.
Just assume that a how to park in my hand.
One is path one.
That party is suppose I am taking valid bug,
but you can take anything.
And I'm having one more path called path two.
And this is HTTPD.com.
Now I want to get complete path for the file.
So if I join this path at the end of this path,
then I can get complete path.
Of course you need a symbol asthma.
Let me do that.
Suppose I am writing a variable called HTTPD con for filing,
but I'm taking lengthy variable him just to understand, but don't undertake this,
lend the variable name C. I can write,
I can write simply dollar path one.
Then immediately I can write dollar path to let me sale These.
Yeah.
If I display that, they can understand, right?
Yeah. Let me just say that a CFO display our print
that HTTPD underscore con for underscore file.
Let me save this and run this.
So before running, it's better to see your code as well.
Now see the result, what you are getting.
What happened? Yeah, I miss to close with the quotation.
So that is another. So I started quotations but I forgot to close that.
Now. See your core.
Now I'm running that.
See the output, what you are getting.
You are getting root A-T-C, A-T-C,
last HTTPD slash conf,
then immediately are getting hit gdb.com,
but you need some slashing.
Well, right? Then I can do in this way.
See here.
Here I can write curly brace,
non-native codebase vertically conveyed slash.
So I am substituting faster path then sludge directly I am writing,
then, I'm sorry, shooting second path. Now see the result.
What we are getting very,
very important adding to part C,
that is, you're getting valid path now.
Now, if you are getting confusion here,
you can also use curly braces.
First two-part slash, second part,
I'm shooting first two path than I am placing slash directly,
then I'm shooting second path so that I'm getting
complete path for this HTTPD con file path.
So this is the way how you can add one.
I'm in two or more than two paths.
If you want to add one more path,
just RD here by substituting that variable value.
That's a fine.
Now I want to come into the center core,
a second particle then, right?
See if, if you want to line,
if you want to comment line by line for each and every line,
you have the right hash symbol.
At the starting of each and every line you had to write Hashim.
But I want to come into all these four lines at a time,
then you can follow or less than,
less than I'm writing might come into two.
And how many lines you want to come in after that, right?
You were come into to name this name and this name must be same,
then only these lanes will come and otherwise you'll get an error.
Now, we don't have any code to execute our shell script.
Because whatever the core we are having that we come into.
The next one, converts strings into lowercase or uppercase.
But it's simple.
First, let me open your shell script.
I'm writing a variable called Again,
my name shall suppose I want to convert this into uppercase.
Then ACO, first-time displaying output.
The uppercase info E, dollar.
You need curly braces here.
My name to capture or to anchor symbols.
But now let me execute and see the content.
You are getting your data in terms of capitals, right?
So because of this gap symbols,
instead of displaying directly with the echo command,
you can also store this result in b, a variable.
And one more thing guys,
let me write that first.
Echo dollar, my name.
So my intention is suppose if I run our core,
you are converting your data into capitals.
But the virginal data is not converting into capitals only while displaying.
Your data is converting into capital.
So now, if you want to store that connoted data in the variable,
you can follow this syntax the same way how we stored the length India variable c.
Now I am defining my name
in uppercase equals two.
Dollar, curly brace, you were variable.
Then to encode symbols that say,
same way my name,
yeah, learned of conditions there.
My name is lowercase equals $2, curly brace.
My name two commas.
That's it.
Now.
It can display ACO upper data.
Simply, I am writing dollar, your variable.
What is your variable? My name,
upper in that Uppercase data is stored now.
Then echo lower data.
So dollar, my name lower in that our data is there.
Again, offer that I am printing your original data.
It won't change.
Only it will modify your data and we'll store it that this result.
But because of this operation,
you are original data.
This is, my name is not modifying.
That is very, very important.
Now see the content first and run that and
see the output you are getting in capital and small.
You may get confused here.
So already original data in terms of Miletus only, right?
I will do, I will take combinations capital and small so that it can understand.
That's it. Now see that they are getting capital small,
uneven ordinal data is there as it is.
And that data we are seeing with the help of this,
is the way how we can convert our data into lowercase and uppercase.
Next one is uses of DAR name and base name on strings or paths.
Actually DA and name and base their mother commands.
They will work on parts.
The first command DIR name.
So it will strip BAR removes last component from filename ot from the puck.
Let me show you this on command line first.
Suppose if I take BAR name, ETC,
HTTPD, con hatred ebay.com C That isn't what it is giving.
A DC tripping or removing the last content from your path.
Then it is giving the remaining data up to this.
Now, same thing I am applying for a baby named command.
These two commands are very, very important.
C there is a, it is giving Now the last content which is there in your file.
Now these two datas,
if you want to store in a file,
India variable, yes, you can now play with the dollar parenthesis.
But before that what I will do is first time you stored the data into a variable called
suppose HTTPD, pot, fight.
No need to take this lengthy variable name I'm taking just for
your understanding purpose. That's it.
No, engine off directly are playing on
this path I want to apply on this variable you are command.
Then the IR name.
Don't directly, don't write directly where variable name you hard to write with a dollar,
then only the value which is there in the y variable will be substituted.
That's a, suppose if I remove dollar,
then there is no use.
See there isn't.
So take dollar the same way you can take based name as well, based name.
In case if you are parties taurine,
some variable, then base name,
dollar that variable so that the data which is there in this,
that will be replaced in place of this entire data.
That is nothing but this, ETC.
Cough up to that.
See there is no,
you can store the result into your variable as well.
First, let me write a shell script for that already we have a shell script.
Let me open that. Now. Let me comment this code now.
So base if you want to practice, remove this comment.
Foster command, second comment, third,
comment, and practice with the quote,
I will share this court.
My commend. Three.
Now I am writing here.
Now our core.
Suppose I am taking a path called this one,
but I want to get HTTPD constant,
whom means up to this.
Then I am taking one more variable,
HTTPD con home equals to C. If I want to apply command on command line,
I'm doing BAR name, dollar, our variable.
But this is a command,
this command output I want to store into this variable.
Than if you remember.
We had a discussion on this US dollar parenthesis are backstage.
Both will work.
Fine.
Now let me take only HTTPD config file I want to get.
Then dollar parentheses, base name,
then you were variable.
What is your variable?
This easy one variable in that your data is there,
actually, whatever the path is there.
Now let me print HTTPD con footpath file.
So complete path, I can print it with the help of let me remove $1.
Then echo HTTPD con for home.
We stored that in the variable called HTTPD underscore con funders for home.
So he applied to understand the uses of Bayes name on BAR name,
then HTTPD con for file,
HTTPD underscore, underscore file.
And that's it. Let me see the content first.
So these are the lines we are going to execute now because remaining all are commented.
Now I'm running that.
See the result.
Yes, you are getting what gel path from this because of the DAR name command,
we are getting this part and basically we are getting this one here.
That's a fine.
Now with the base name,
we have one more advantage. Let me show you that.
Suppose base name, I'm writing EDC, HTTPD.
Hey, Khan.
He actually built.com. What is the output you are getting?
Simply what HTTP.com file.
But in that file, I want to
strip.com then provide in the way that it is going to get only HTTPD.
So simply base name will strip or
remove directory name and also a suffix from the file names,
not prefix, only suffix.
So in this entire thing, what is the suffix.com?
So if you, if you know what is the suffix and if you want to remove that,
then after base name, you can,
I mean based name, then you are path,
then provide a suffix in him so that that will be removed from your file.
The result will display very, very, very important.
While writing scripts.
Let me write this in script as well.
So that will be clear for us.
Suppose I'm storing that HTTPD con for file without suffix.
Without suffix dies I am taking lengthy were able in just to 41 understanding,
don't take that lengthy variable name way lighting.
You want realtime scripts.
So simply you had to write these anti-doping.
Then our dn, just write.com.
That's it.
Now let me print that.
So last literately, I'm printing your variable.
I'm not adding any extra message.
If you want write, you can write it.
Now see the last output.
Yes, we are getting only hits to the beauty.
That's a fine.
Then next string slicing or extracting portion of a string.
C.
Before this already we know Cut command with Cut command also we can slice out a string.
Suppose I have a shell,
let me directly printed that shell.
Yes, you are getting r.
You can store that into a variable and you can print it that both,
these both are possible, right?
Echo, dollar, my name.
No, on this output I can use Cut command directly
cut based on characters I need Foster character.
I need a second character.
I need second to some fourth character, yes, you are getting.
This is also slicing operation on your strings.
And this resulting can directly assigned to
any variable because this entire thing is a command,
then just write x equals $2 parentheses inside that this enter command.
That is one way to slice he was doing.
So I have given this because already we know Cut command with iPhone C option.
Other than that, when also having one more way.
Let me do one thing first.
Suppose we have a shell.
This is just assume that our string,
whenever, if you assign that string to any variable,
immediately ever shall, we'll assign some positions for this,
some numbers for that number is by default 12.
Likewise, it will assign 34.
Likewise it will assign,
suppose you've held shell scripting,
suppose shelf space, scripting spaces at 567.
Likewise, he was telling me la sign some numbers.
Right?
Now let me write this on a notepad,
then will explain about this.
Suppose I am writing a variable called my name equals to shell.
Whenever.
If we assign in this way, immediately, you will,
shall we'll assign some numbers for your characters which are there in your string.
S.
Number is 0, heads one.
Likewise, it will assign the numbers,
and these are called index numbers for clustering C that,
yes, he's there at very first, that index each GO,
Hetchy is there at second position, but Index is one.
Now based on this index potions also,
you can slice your string.
Now let me write a separate shell script for that.
So string slicing operations, dot SH.
So I'm writing separate shell script.
Let me write my name equals to shell,
not only shell, let me take some lengthy string shell scripting.
And first-time directly displaying the virginal string which is there in your mind name.
And here guys, for slicing operations,
you need curly braces.
That's the reason I told that.
It's better practice to take always curly braces for your variable Nim.
There is no wrong in that.
But sometimes you have to use mandatory.
That's why make a habit that always use curly braces for your variable.
Now, I'm displaying in this way my name,
column G. Then echo.
Echo, dollar, my name, colon 1.
First, see the output for this.
Provide the exclusion permissions here.
Then see your core ones.
Then run your code and see the output C.
Because of this, you are getting that
is directly or displaying your variable value directly.
You are getting uneven infrared colon 0,
you're getting complete thing,
complete, you are getting.
But if I write one you are getting from which onwards?
That means if I write in this way colon with
the gyro printed the string from index 0 onwards up to yen.
One printed the string which is there in your variable.
From index one.
Index one means HMO S E is index 0.
Hattie's at one. Now.
Now what I am doing is I am writing one more thing.
Let me do that.
First.
My name, colon. Two, I am writing,
but immediately I am writing one again with colon.
Then what is the meaningful that you can understand by observing the output?
And I'm hurting One more thing,
my name colon, I'm writing to.
Then after that I am eliminating colon with the three. Now let me run this.
First, observe the output.
Let me open your script.
Now I'm running your script C,
that is because of this complete string.
Even because of this also are getting complete string because print from index 0 onwards.
Now here, one, print from one index onwards.
That's why we are getting H-E-L-L-O scripting bring from T2,
but get only one character.
That's, that's the reason they're getting ie index is to
know From yon words get you a string.
But I'm applying a condition that is,
print only one character.
That's why you are getting only E. Now,
print from secondary index,
that is from E, but only three characters.
That's why we are getting three. So this is also one more way to slice.
He was string and friends.
These operations are very,
very important while writing your realtime scripts.
Please do practice on this any way I will share our scripts.
You just go through that and do practice. Ok. Thank you.