Friends here, our concept ease input with command line arguments.
So he already we know how to provide an input for your shell script using 3D command.
Now instead of read command,
you can also use command-line arguments to provide an input for your shell scripts.
Now let me explain that
these command line arguments are also called as positional arguments.
Why we will see, see command-line arguments or simply values or
arguments on which are provided
while running your shell script on your command prompt itself.
Let me explain that with a simple shell script,
I'm taking shell script name as command line,
always dot-dot-dot H. Now let me write the very first line as user bin bash.
Then, see, suppose I am trying to display the value of y.
That is done away. Anyway, we know that dollar y is not defined in our shell script.
Then if I run that,
let me provide the execution permission for our script.
Then see your core ones.
Now run your code.
You're getting an empty line because y is not defined
anywhere that we are getting, output is empty.
Now, there are some special variables in your shell strip.
Let me printed them. $1.1. I'm printing in a different lines.
$1.2, $1.3.
Actually, you should not take variable name as 1-2-3.
C dollar y means y variable.
You are printing the same NBA $1.1 min,
one variable value you are printing.
But we know that we should not take our variable name starts with a number.
And here I have taken directly our variable names has 123.
That is not correct actually,
but these are some special variables for your shell scripts
and which are defined with your shell script with your shell.
Fine.
Now, first to see your code. And I'm running.
So you can get the output is empty because nowhere that values are defining,
Yes, you are getting three empty lines.
Say that. First empty line,
second thought empty land.
Now while running my shell script,
I am passing some value with the space shell script name space some value.
Now see the result. You are getting the first output.
Now, $1.1 means after your shell script name,
if you pass some value,
if you pass only one value,
then that is delta one.
If I pass first value,
then second value with the spaces be clear.
Then $1.1 needs this.
$1.2 is this one.
Likewise, you can pass any number of values.
Now see the result. We are displaying only 1-2-3.
So after, immediately after your shells taped name,
this is $1.1 inside of your script.
This is $1.234567891011 up to infinity you can provide.
And to be clear, all values must be separately with the spaces.
Right?
Suppose if we have a data and in that if you always spaces,
then you have to write your entire data inside of a quotation.
Let me take the very first as shell scripting. Now see there isn't.
Shell scripting entire thing is then quotations.
So that's why this is the first argument.
If you don't provide quotations,
then Shelley's first argument,
scripting is second argument.
So $1.1 is shell scripting.
So there isn't, you have to be clear on that. Ok.
So these are called command line arguments for your sheltered.
And we're also calling them as a positional arguments because if I change the position,
if I read scripting here on shell here,
the position is changing that.
So these are the positional arguments.
C.
If I write scripting here on shell here,
then one becomes scripting.
$1.2 becomes shell.
But if you want to get delta 1S shell,
you have to read the very first actual position is important.
Fine.
Now, let me open your script once again.
I am defining, I want to display one more value
called dollar G O D is also very, very important.
Now am running or shell script by taking this data.
Now see that isn't dollars zero,
you are getting script name itself.
So in this entire format,
be clear on this.
In this entire format.
This is inside of your script.
You can access your script name with the help of dollar row.
And the first value which you are passing offer
your script name can be accessed with a $1.1.
Then two, likewise, you can take any number of arguments on your command line.
So based on that, jihad to access inside of your script with the help of God,
one dot-dot-dot U3 and position is important.
Fine.
Now, let me go with one more thing.
Suppose how many values we're passing, 12345678910.
Yeah, I want to print,
suppose some tenth command line argument.
Then you have to take a CFO, $1.10.
Now let me observe output for this.
So if you observe in your command line,
what is the tenth argument? First account it.
This is one, this is 2345678910 is AB, right?
So before running your script first to see the content of your core,
now run your script. Observes output.
You are getting the output for ten,
the command-line argument as shelled 0,
but it is AB,
but you are not getting that.
Whenever if you print command line argument
for greater than or equal to ten or two digit command line argument,
then you had to write that command line argument inside of curly braces.
Otherwise, it will consider like $1.1 then 0.
So $1.1 means first command line argument.
Yes, you are getting that,
then Gero is printing as it is.
So if your command line argument e is greater
than or equal to ten or two digit command line argument.
Then take curly braces,
even for your single-digit command-line argument.
Also, you can take curly braces, but not required.
Now let me save it and run it and see the result.
There is no difference with 23.
Even though if you take curly braces for your single,
I mean, what does it command line argument,
no problem, but for two digit command-line argument,
you have to take curly braces.
That's fine.
Now, I want to find how many command-line arguments or passing to us script.
Now first let me comment this code.
So I'm using multi-line comment to comment our code.
Know simply I'm displaying the number of command line or domains,
or simply with dollar hash.
Now first let me run your code without
any command line arguments and see the result you're getting 0 because I'm
not passing any command-line arguments of that our shell script.
Now I'm passing one command line argument, the counties.
One, I'm passing two counties to, I'm pausing.
Suppose three numbers, three command line arguments, three, that's it.
Now, suppose if you want to print all the command line arguments at a time,
the OL command line arguments
or simply I can use dollar at the rate.
You are also having one more syntax for this.
That is dollar stock.
C.
There is a small difference between duller and duller direct,
but as of now there are same that defense I can explain while working with the loops.
So up to that, you had to wait.
What is the difference between dollar,
Stalin, dollar at the rate?
Now, I'm running a shell script and I'm not passing anything.
So I'll put easier empty because you're not passing any command line arguments.
Dollar upgrade means, or dollar star means as of no.
All the command line arguments which we are parsing for our script.
Suppose I'm passing three command line arguments, yours,
you are getting more good for your 1 stock. Right?
Now.
Then what is the use of these command line arguments?
We know that just to provide input.
Suppose we how our script to install Tomcat.
Now, previously we work in this way.
No, let me remove this seed directly.
If you want to pass your version number,
we are opening our script and we are passing our version number here.
But if you don't want to edit,
then we're commenting this line.
Then we are commenting this first line,
I mean Tomcat, what line?
Then with the help of read command,
we are reading the version number of waves running JavaScript.
Now, even if you don't want to provide your version number of the running us strip,
then before running your script itself,
you can provide the required Tomcat version by using your command line arguments.
Simply I'm taking your variable required Tomcat version equals $2.1.
Then let me save it.
And I'll see you a script first.
So the required value we are assigning $1.1
value delta one means command-line argument first command line argument.
So before that, remove your concat mine.
Now see that I am running our shall skip.
And by providing command-line argument as our required version,
nine dot 0 dot 27, any version number.
Now it is going to work.
That's it.
So this is the best uses of command line argument.
So before running your shell script,
without opening your shell script,
if you want to pass your required values for your shell script, yes,
we can pass, we can provide input for our shell script using command line arguments.
And suppose if you are not passing any command-line argument,
and inside of your script actually you are taking your command line arguments, right?
And if you are not passing, then it won't work.
It will do some errors. Let me run.
Now.
I'm not passing any Watson and I am running,
you're going to get an error.
So how to handle this?
We will discuss that in our for the sessions.
That is actually advanced level concept.
We'll discuss that.
Okay guys. Thank you.