Friends here our concept is case statement.
See this case statement is very useful to design some menu-driven scripts.
First, let me show you the syntax of your kids statement.
These are simple syntax of your case statement.
So if you observe here,
here we are starting the case.
Under here we are closing the case statement.
And there is some variable.
Suppose you are giving this variable from input side
or somewhere from the output you are getting somewhere in your core.
And we have here different options here.
Be clear on that.
Suppose if this value mapply with this one,
then these lines will statements means number of lens you can write.
And at the end of all the lines.
Lastly, hot right to semi-colons from each and I'm in,
in each and every option.
So simply, if you are,
this is a variable.
You may provide it from input side,
or maybe you are getting from because of some logic inside of your code itself.
If this value mapply with this one,
if these two are equal,
then this logic will exclude.
Suppose there is no match with
the very first option then will compare with the second one.
If there is a match with the URL option and this option two,
if both are equal, then this logic will execute.
And remember that suppose if very first option is executing,
then remaining all will skip.
Suppose if there is no match with
the first option and there is a match with second option,
then these seeds anyway,
it is not going to exclude and remaining Minsky.
So in that way you are case statement will work.
Let me explain this with a simple example
so that you can understand the uses of your case.
Suppose I want to design a simple calculator.
Let me design that simple calculator dot SH.
I am writing the very first line as user bin bash.
I want to read two numbers.
Let's say the very first number is I'm taking enter num one.
We can take anything.
I mean, you can print anything and I'm storing that in the variable called a.
Then read iPhone P, enter num two.
Then I want to store that into a variable called be.
Fine.
The next thing, actually my intention, nice,
I need to find either addition or subtraction
or multiplication or division or something like that.
But I don't know what user required.
Suppose if user requires addition,
then I will take that with as options.
See that I'm writing one more 3D command. Entry.
What option? And here I am giving optional suppose
one for addition to FOR subtraction.
Then I'm giving three for multiplication.
You can also design this in a different way.
I will show you that. Then for four suppose division.
That's it.
Now whatever the user is entering that I am taking as a variable call option,
not only option, you can take anything.
Userinput requests something like that.
You can take, I'm taking variable as option.
Now let me read a case statement.
So whenever if you start a case statement,
you have to under with a reverse character of your case studies,
ESC is C. Then here based on R2,
based on user option,
you have to execute some logic that way here,
just select option in.
Then let me write,
suppose because why I am writing here,
one means you are valid options for the user is either one or two, or three or four.
That's why just right here, 1234.
Then if the user enters one than just I am writing in this way,
Ico, you selected addition.
So I am writing one more, one more line.
The addition of a and b is,
guys, we know how to perform
simply integer arithmetic operations with parenthesis, right?
Simply I am writing a plus B, let's say.
So.
Yeah, one more parenthesis.
See whenever if the user enters one,
then case will take action based on that.
So this is one because user enters 1.8em storing into one.
I mean, OPT that won't be DBS.
Substrate in dollar OBD means one. So this is one.
That's why inside of this case,
wherever one mapping is that that logic will execute.
And under these are the last line
you had to write always to semi-colons, but is the syntax.
Then user may interest to also because we are giving options 1234.
Then I can write a code you selected.
So you can add any number of lengths.
That's why just I am writing two eco statements,
not only a Coke, any logic you can write here.
You selected subtraction. That's it.
Then let me write the subtraction of Nala 3a.
And dollar b means yes,
and B is dollar to parenthesis E minus b.
That's it.
So at the end, just right to semi-colons,
user may enter three also,
because we are giving us options up to four.
So you've selected multiplication, touch it,
echo the multiplication of dollar 3A and B
is going to be then ending with two semi-colons, then fourth option.
So here I am writing echo you selected division,
then echo the division of,
let me take dollar aa width b, e.
Yet division width B.
That's it.
Suppose by mistake if user enters are then 1234,
then I want to display something like invalid option.
So invalid option always is like with the stock or default option.
A co, you selected invalid option, that's it.
So now before executing your code,
just try to understand how your case will work
anymore faster to read statement just to read every a and b values.
Then third, we are giving some information to the user.
In third statement that is, one for addition,
two for subtraction, three for multiplication or division.
Just imagine that user is entering for this line
to two means two will store in into this variable called OPT,
then that we are substituting in our case statement.
So net then dollar OBD means two for two varies the mapping here.
So this logic will exclude that's it.
So once it is executed remaining all will skip.
Suppose if user enters ten,
then this value is $10, OPT is ten.
Is there any match with ten?
No, no.
If there is no map with you or given value,
then star will execute.
Star means actually all.
If there is no match with all four,
are whatever the offense you are having,
then by default star will execute.
That's it. Now let me run
simply by providing execution permissions for your shell script.
I'm entering number for number six.
Then I wanted to find the addition.
Then just provide one. You are getting the result.
Let me rerun and provide numbers and I'm giving invalid option called nine.
So in that way your case will work fine.
Right?
So based engine operating in this way,
if you want to decorate here,
you can write in this way also.
You can able to understand that just to follow this,
let me comment this line first.
So just for decorating your own,
put them. So I am writing.
I will write whatever the way you can design for calculator.
Just I'm decorating notebook.
Select. Otherwise I would do on day one.
Addition, subtraction,
multiplication.
It just your interest and how you're going to design your own ICO for division.
Then here I can write, read Ivan p.
Please select your option from above.
Then take OPT.
So here also, if you wander degrade once again,
you just write in this way.
Now let me save this and run it.
See the output for phi option to subtraction.
Yes, you are getting.
Now c.
Suppose we are opening our core and we are running, while running your code.
If you want to clear your screen,
then when he first a command,
just write C LAR,
you know the purpose of CALEA or command.
So the very first line I'm writing CLEA, clear screen.
See that while running your code he was clean, will be cleared.
That's it. So now for some cap hash that is invalid options you output.
That's it. It's working fine.
So now you can understand the syntax.
So this option may be from the input or maybe why writing some realtime scripts,
you will get that option.
Because of some logic,
because of some output that output we will use instead of k statement.
And here, instead of writing stride forward options like 123,
you can also write some patterns.
We know from our grep command how to design a pattern.
Let me write a very simple script just to understand that how to write a pattern
in your pattern for case.
Sh.
As I've not, don't worry about this.
And we will use that in our while implementing some real transcripts.
Just I am writing real-life and P enter any number.
Just I am taking num case dollar num in.
Let me close first your case statement.
At last ROA, you'll forget out too close.
You were kinda sway just while starting lowercase.
Please close that. Then.
Suppose my number may be any number between 0 to nine.
If it is single digit,
I can write in this way any number between 0 to nine.
Then I can write a goal.
You entered number.
Let's suppose if I
enter anything,
alphabet, small letters a to z,
then I can say echo.
You entered lowercase r small letters, lower-case alphabet.
That's it.
Maybe you may enter.
Just assume that here our intention is how to write a pattern to select your options.
Suppose you, if you enter some capital letters, then echo.
You entered uppercase, all 4-bits. Let say.
Suppose if you enter any two digits letter,
I'm in two digits number or two-digit letter or any other thing.
I don't know how to handle that. Then simply write.
As per my logic, echo invalid option,
unable to find, unable to identify your input, something like that.
Let me provide the execution permissions.
Now run your core.
I suppose number two.
What happens syntax near unexpected token.
Let me open that.
Oh sorry.
Are taken here parenthesis.
Now let me run your code.
I'm entering number to see that you enter a single number.
A single muttered maybe now I'm entering,
suppose you, now I'm running an entering capital B.
Now I'm running an amp routing something.
So unable to identify your input.
That's it.
Ok, so here's the,
here's the way how we can write a pattern.
So if you underwrite this pattern,
you have to know the rules to create your pattern,
which we already discussed in our Grip command.
Please go through that. Okay, thank you.