Hi friends.
Here our concept is how to write and execute the shell script.
Let me explain this concept with the help of a simple shell script.
That is simple shell script to get HTTPD version and port number.
Friends here I'm providing some steps to write your shell script.
And these steps are applicable for beginner.
So if you're already having some exposure with your shell script,
then directly go and write your shell script.
But if you are the beginner,
please do follow the steps.
The very first one is get all manual commands for your requirement.
So here our requirement is we need to find
HTTPD Washington port number using PowerShell script.
Then you have to get the commands for them.
Let me get the commands.
See if you run simply HTTPD hyphen v,
you are getting your hedge,
everybody washing information in the output.
But I need to get exactly to dot-dot-dot for one,
then modify the command.
Don't worry how I'm modifying this command.
We'll discuss that in detail in our falling sessions as of now,
just to concentrate on how to write and run a shell script.
Then in the first line,
I want to get second field.
But here we are getting some parenthesis.
Let me remove them.
Once again, just apply your obligate command or
command and print first
affiliates so that you are going to get you are required what Shen,
then we need to find HTTPD port number as well.
So there is a default configuration file for HTTPD.
Then from that, we are trying to get the port number.
So here we are getting output, I listen 80,
but I wanted to get exactly port number only.
I don't want to get lizard then apply here also edit like
a command just to print the second field.
That's it.
Now first, copy these two commands.
So I'm copying and pasting somewhere.
There's the first command and second command.
So by this, we got our commands for our requirement.
Then, now start writing web shell script.
So while writing or shell script,
first thing is you have to open a text file with extension has dot SH.
And here, dot SH is not mandatory.
We are providing that extension just to know that that is a shell script.
Now let me write some,
let me open some text file with extension as dot SH.
So I'm writing a shell script name as HTTPD Wusheng under then port dot SH,
just now opened our text file.
Then second thing, you have to write,
the very first-line has shebang or interpreter.
Nothing but what is the shell you are using to
execute your shells could see generally in interviews,
if they ask a question like, what is a shebang,
then most of the people will say that
shebang is nothing but been bash, don't say like that.
Shebang is nothing but by using which shell you want to run your shell script C,
We how different types of shells in our
It's like a systems, right?
C. Let me show you them once again.
Suppose on my operating system,
I hold these many shells.
Then what is the shell you want to use?
Suppose I want to use Bash to execute my shell script.
Then you have to provide the path
for that required shell as a very first line in your shell script.
Suppose I want to use Bash,
but I don't know what is the complete path of my Bash.
Then simply run which bash it will do the location or complete path of what Bash shell.
Then simply copy that.
Then open your shell script and start with hash tree.
Then paste your complete path for your shell.
That's it.
So that is the shebang line.
So don't say that Xi Wang Lin,
nothing but been bash in
your Bash shell scripting shebang line is nothing but been bashed line.
But generally newer inner shell scripting shebang is nothing
but a shell which is used to run newer shell script.
That's it. Fine.
Then after that, just to paste all your manual commands in sequence.
Now we have our commands.
Just copy these two commands and go to your file.
You are textFile.
Then just to place here commands in sequence, that's it.
Then save it. Then.
Now we have written our shell script.
There is the shell script. Then how to run your shell script?
That is step three.
So a running or executing shell script.
So before going to run or execute your shell script,
you have to provide execution permission for your shell script.
C, If I check permissions for my file.
So it is not having any execution permission for the user.
Then I can run simply by using, I mean,
I can provide execution permissions by using
change mode with the letters or with the numbers.
Suppose I want to provide seven, sorry 75.
Then.
Now see that our eye can remove execution permission with some letter also.
Or if I want to provide,
then I can use change more plus x.
Nausea, that isn't you.
How your execution permission for your fine.
So once you've held execution permission, then simply run,
you were sheltered by a syntax
like dot slash shell script mean.me in the current location,
we how our self-esteem,
that's a and if this is a very simple shell script.
So that is one way to run your shell script.
Suppose if you are in the different location,
just assumed that as of nano shell script isn't there in this location.
But assume that you are in a different location.
So here we don't know how our shell script,
so that shell script name is.
But if I run that, it will say that there is no such file or directory.
So if you are in the different location and
your shell script is there in another location.
If you want to run your shelf scale,
then you ought to provide complete path for your shell script.
That's it. Now see there is a right.
So friends, these are the steps to write and execute your shell script.
There is one more way just to execute your shell script.
Whenever, if your shells countries not having an execution permissions,
that is simply see that.
So as of now we don't have any execution permissions for our shell script.
But still you can run simply by SH or by providing your shell script name.
That's it. Right? Not only as such,
you can also use Bash, sorry, b,
SH, because I'm executing
with this shell or I'm executing with the shell, that's it. Right?
But please follow these steps
just by writing your shell script, provide execution permission,
then run in this way if you are in the current location where your shell script is there,
or if you are in a different location,
then just to provide a complete path to execute your shelf.
That's it. Thank you.