Friends here our concept is commanded chaining operators.
And these operators are very,
very important to implement one line,
if or if else conditional statements.
And here command chaining is nothing but clubbing or combining two or more commands.
So we have different types of operators to club two or more commands.
And those operators we can use either in shell scripting or on command line.
They are like semicolon operator,
logical and operator and logical or operator.
Be clear, we have symbols for each and every operator here.
Now let me go with one-by-one semicolon.
Just assume that you are having two commands on
if you want to club them by using semicolon operator,
you can club in this way and offer clubbing.
You're two commands with semicolon operator.
And if you run that,
then those two commands will execute independently.
Let me show you this on your terminal.
Suppose date and PWD command.
I'm running by clubbing with semicolon operator.
You're getting your output for those two commands.
Now I'm running invalid command.
And then by clubbing that command with PWD using your semicolon operator, nausea,
that isn't actually your first command is getting failed,
but that is not disturbing to get the result for your next command.
So here, those two commands or executing independently and command is
getting failure means we know that the exit status of that command is non-zero.
And not only two commands,
you can club any number of commands or logic using semicolon operator in this way.
Suppose I can define two variables in a single line.
Suppose if it is shell scripting,
then I can also display the value of that directly in
a single line by clubbing with semicolon operator c.
That or I can run some date command by clubbing with semicolon operator. That's it.
So here, each and every command is executing independently.
Then the next one is the logical and operator.
I assume that you are having two commands.
And if you want to club them by using logical and operator,
then you can club in this way,
offer clubbing if you run these two commands.
Then here, there is a dependency between commend T2 and command
one commander to will execute only if command one is successful.
Let me show you this on your terminal.
Suppose I'm running date command and PWD command by clubbing with logical end.
You are getting output for each and every command.
But I am running some invalid command.
Then I'm running some valid command by clubbing with logical n.
Now see the result. You are not getting output for your second command.
The reason is whenever,
if we club any commands with the help of a logical and operator,
if the first command is success,
then only you will get output for your next command.
Let me show you that one more with one more example.
Suppose I'm trying to read the slash EDC file.
And I am clubbing that with the logical and I'm writing here echo successful.
See even echo is also one command.
Now, if this is success,
then only it will display this message.
Because these two commands we are clubbing mythological and see that you are not getting
successful output because actually we don't
have read permissions for the file that is a root file.
That's where it is getting fail.
If it is getting fail,
then it doesn't allow to execute the next command which is there,
which is clubbed with the logical hand.
That's it.
Not only to commands, you can club any number of commands,
let say a less PWD date.
And here you have to understand that the last command will
execute if the foster two commands or successful.
Otherwise, second command will exclude if the first command is success.
Suppose you first command is getting fail,
then these two will skip.
Suppose if second command is getting faked,
the last command will skip.
That's it.
Now, let me take one more example.
C test is also one of the command without test to come and write test for iPhone EQ for.
So we are testing the condition for iPhone EQ for I mean equality purpose.
Now if it is success, anyway,
this will get Such as right,
we know that because 404 or equal.
Now if I club this with logical and echo,
I'm writing there equal.
Now see that, isn't there equal you are getting.
Now what I'm doing is I'm comparing for with 444 equal to purpose.
Now you are not getting output for your next command because this is getting filled.
Because testes not such as right, they are not equal.
Test command will get fail.
Not only test command, we have alternate symbols for
your test with the two square brackets also,
we can execute this.
Be clear.
This entire thing is one command.
That command we are combining with the second command by using logical and operator.
And whenever if you run any number of commands with the logical and operator,
the last command will execute if the previous,
all previous comments or success,
otherwise, this command will skip.
That's right.
Now let me give you one more example.
Suppose I'm trying, I want to start my hits UDP on
my host directly. I can run in this way.
Systems CTL start HTTP if a tree but is not there,
then that's why what I am doing is first I can validate whether it is there or not,
which HTTPD, HTTPD is there and my host,
then this will get success.
Then I'm clubbing that to start the work.
Httpd. Then there is a meaning.
So before starting, we are evaluating whether it is there or not.
If it is not there, it will get fail.
If it is getting fail, it won't execute.
It is that it will execute.
That's very simple.
And actually this is like a simple if condition.
We'll discuss that in our next session.
Whenever if you club two commands with the logical end,
but it's simply if condition.
Fine.
Now, we can club any number of commands by using logical and
operator r. Next one is logical or operator.
So here I can club two commands by using logical OR operator in this way.
And here, commander to will execute if command one is failed.
Be clear in your logical and operator commanded to Villegas.
Good. If the first command is success.
But here river's commander to will execute if the command one is getting fail.
Let me show you that on your terminal.
Suppose first let me take with the logical and operator,
we are getting output for both to commands.
And I am running at very first invalid command.
Then your second comment output we are not getting because first command is getting fade.
Now with your logical or if you club, See there isn't.
Both are valid, but you are getting output for
your first command because in logical or operator,
if first command is getting fail,
then only you will get output for your second command.
Otherwise it will skip. Now let me run invalid,
then valid command by clubbing with logical or operator and see the result.
You are getting output for your second command because it is getting failed.
So in case if you don't want display these error messages,
you know how to remove that error message.
Simply two greater than Donald Duck.
And these logical or operator,
it is also important in some scenarios.
Let me do one of those simple example.
Suppose you have first I will do,
I will take this system CTL status, HTTPD.
It is not running. Then what is the status of that comment,
exit status of that command non-zero.
That means if HTTPD your service is
not running not only heterogeneity, any system services.
If you run system CDL sums RVs,
and if that service is not running,
this command will get fail.
That's why it is giving returns status as non-zero.
Now let me start your HTTPD.
So after that I will find status.
It is running. Now see the exit status of that command G.
Now, my requirement is I want to start HTTPD service or any service.
But if it is not running then on I wanted to start.
If it is already running,
then I don't want to start.
Then in that case, first try to find the status of HTTPD.
I mean any sort of east and club with the logical OR operator to start that service.
Now, how it will execute if hedge UDP is already running this week,
you exit status as g means this will get success.
If it is success, then it will skip links.
Good next command because you are clubbing mythological or otherwise.
If anybody is not running,
then it will get failed.
Your first command, you will fail.
If it is failed, then only your second command helix,
good, so that you are able to start you on HTTPD.
So if it is already running,
then it doesn't allow to execute this command so that no need to start already running.
If it is not running, this will get fail.
That's why you are logical or operator will allow dx.
Good second command so that you can start your HTTP.
Now see the status previously or services already starting.
I'm in running, that's why it is not executing this command.
Now let me do one thing. I will stop that.
Now I will run our logical or operator commands.
Previously it was not running.
That's why he definitely see guys, this output.
For this command output.
So you're getting this means virtue liberty is not running head shield,
but he's not running means you will get,
this command will get fail.
If it is failing, then
logical or operator will allude to execute next command and that's it.
So that is the way how we can use logical or operator.
You can club any number of commands by using logical arm, let's say PWD,
some ls, date, systems,
UDL status, any service.
And be clear, if first command is success,
then we'll skip to Xcode remaining all commands.
Suppose if it is fail,
then you will try to look for second command.
If it is success, then it will skip the remaining.
So the last command will execute if all first commands or getting filled, that's it.
That is the logic for logical OR operator.
Now, we can club any number of commands in this way.
I mean by using logical or operator.
Now, combining multiple operators.
Yes, loginData, you are having three commands and you can club
those three commands by using your multiple operators,
especially with logical and,
and logical or in this way.
First observe this first syntax
command one with a logical end and commend to mythological arc.
Now how it will execute?
Very simple.
First of all, command three,
0s clubbing with the logical OR operator.
That means N3 will execute if any one of the command is getting fail.
I mean command, one-off command to,
in these two commands,
if any one of the command is getting fail,
then only combinatory will execute.
Suppose if these two commands are success,
then it won't execute.
And here command two legs.
Good. If the command one is access because you are clubbing with
illogical and let me show you that with an example.
Suppose I'm, I'm writing some tests to
comment because test is also another command I'm doing in this way.
Hyphen e, I'm looking for existence of this file.
Is this file is there on your host.
I mean, in the current path.
If it is there, then I want to display Echo.
Yes, file is there.
Be clear if it is success means this file is there.
If this file is there,
I want display as it is there.
After getting success of your foster command,
if you want to execute any other command,
then you have to club with logical.
And in case if this is getting fairly means this file is not there at the time, I can do.
A co file is not there.
See that isn't there.
Getting file is not there because this command is getting fail.
That's why it will skip to execute this one.
And if any one of these two commands or getting fail,
then only you are odd operator will allow takes good tardy command.
That's it.
And this is simply if fills condition.
So if an if-else condition will discuss in our next decision,
now, concentrate on second command, second syntax.
Commands and command to.
We are clubbing with the logical OR operator and command to and
command tree we are clubbing with logical and then how it will work.
Command one is getting fail.
Then we'll skip remaining two commands.
That is the meaning of logical or might.
If command one is getting fail,
then we'll try to run command to incrementally success.
Then only combinatory will turn because command to
incrementally or clubbing with the logical and operator.
That's it.
Let me show you this here.
Suppose I am writing in this way, hyphen e.
Let say we whoa,
My such file on host,
we have a file called My such, I mean the current path.
Then if that file is not there,
suppose I want to say echo file is not there,
then I will create that file.
Might be clear.
If this is getting failed,
then only it will idx good these two commands.
And here also the second command,
touch will execute if this command is getting success.
Now see there is a, You're not getting
any output for these two because already this file is there.
Now suppose you are trying to look for a file.
If that file is not there in the given path,
then at least you have to create some empty file.
Then you can unleash way.
If file is not there,
then I'm taking inverse symbol.
If every file is there, Yeah,
I will do with these indistinct.
No need to take inverse also.
Let me try for the file hyphen e. I want to create some DB confined.
If that file is not there.
If file is not there,
then they call creating empty file.
Then create it by using touch DB underscore conf.
So before running just ticket BV conf.
In the current location.
No, we don't have. Now I'm running this command.
So after running this, how it will work, how it will execute.
Let me explain that. I'm running C
that is creating empty file and this is success. That's where it will execute.
First thing, this file is not there.
That's why this entire thing is getting fail.
If it is failed, then the remaining commands we are clubbing
with logical or illogical or will alo dx good annex two commands.
If it is success, then it doesn't allow to
exclude this is failed because that file is not there.
That's why logical or operator will allude to exclude these two commands.
Anyway, the second command will execute.
The first command is axis.
Now here simply echo command definitely will get success.
That's why does allowing to exclude these touch DB file.
Now see that we have now DB confirm Yes.
So in that way you can club any number of commands by using multiple operators also.
So we'll do a lot of examples on these so that you will be good with your
combining multiple commands with multiple operators.
Thank you.