Friends here, our concepts or if
an if-else statements say before going to work with these two concepts,
let me recollect our known concepts from logical and,
and logical or operator.
Let's say how two commands,
command one and command to.
And I wanted to club them by using logical and operator.
Then you know how this result works.
Command you too will execute if command one is success,
suppose you've come in, one is fail commander to won't execute.
That means command to is depending on command one.
No, let me club with the one more command,
let's say command three.
Now command three will execute if command to his success.
I mean command threes depending one command to un-comment,
it will execute if command one is success.
Now if you observe clearly,
command three legs, good.
If Foster two comments or success.
But now my requirement is if command one is executing successfully,
then I want to exclude commander to and command three,
unwilling scooting command to run command three.
I don't want to depend command three on command to exit status.
I wonder, and these two comments independently,
if command one is success,
then this index is not a valid one for your requirements,
then you have to modify in this way,
if whatever the first command you want to validate that command,
then there is a syntax close with their Phi.
And between these then and FA,
you can write any number of commands or logic.
Let me write command two, command three,
or maybe some variable declaration,
or maybe some echo command, whatever it may be.
Now, compared to this syntax, the syntax,
you are commanded to comment three,
all these commands will execute independently.
And these commands, all these commands will execute if command one in success.
Be clear.
In this syntax, command threes depending on comment too.
But here command three and commend you are executing independently.
Only conditioning. If first command is success,
then these all commands will execute in imminently.
That's it.
Now let me explain that with a simple example.
Suppose let me define a simple cell scribbles,
simple, if not SH.
Let me read the very first line as she mainland bin bash or user bin bash.
Now I'm trying to such which HTTPD,
if Hetchy deputies there,
I want to run some commands independently,
then then UNCLOS with their fight.
Friends here, then an f phi or the syntaxes.
And whatever the lines you are going to write,
what are the commands you are going to write between then and FA?
You can start from coastal space onwards in this line,
but it's better to provide at least two spaces just for looking purpose.
Say I'm not starting with the fastest pace in that lane.
I'm giving two spaces.
Then I'm starting a co,
HTTPD is present on this host.
Then I am finding system CTL status, HTTPD.
And I'm running that command.
I mean HTTPD service, ACO.
Now, starting.
Judy PD, I'm running some number of commands.
Then sudo, system CTL, start HTTPD.
Be clear.
If HTTPD is there,
this will return exit status as 0.
That means this will get success if it is success.
Now all the commands which are there here, all the logic,
all the statements which are there between then and if phi,
those will execute independently.
Suppose while executing these four commands,
suppose this command is getting fail,
but it doesn't disturb.
It won't disturb to executing remaining two commands.
That is the advantage here whenever if you use if condition. Now let me save this.
And one more thing here,
actually reach puberty will view the output as some user bin hetero AD BD.
I don't want to display either error or success output.
Then, you know the shortcut to hide that output error or success,
or it can redirect that internal file.
That's now give me the execution permission for that.
Now I am running that.
See there is a yes.
All commands are executing.
C, whatever the command we used here.
That is HTTPD, not only that you can use any command,
let me take one more example.
I'm commenting this with the multiple line comments concept.
Now, if you can also write some test to comment that is also a command.
Let me take in this way four equals 24.
If it is success, then foster close with their fight.
Now write your logic between then and f phi.
So that is ACO,
they are equal. Those are 44.
Let say for setting this entire thing is a one command.
And if they are equal it will return
exit status are 0 means that is success, this is success.
Then these two commands will execute independently.
That's it. Now let me save this and run that.
Before that, simply see the corps and I'm running.
Yes, those are equal.
And those are 44.
Suppose if your condition is getting fail,
then it doesn't allow to execute the lines which are there between then and F phi.
Let me write it here and we have 44 are equal,
but I'm reversing that result by using elementary symbol.
So whenever, if use exclamation symbol,
whatever the status you are getting,
actually this is success, that success will become fail.
That's why it is not allowing to execute your lines which are there between your yf,
then an f phi, these two lanes now they are not going to see that.
That's a, that is the simple uses of if condition.
Now let me explain one more thing.
Suppose if we have a requirement in the if command one a success,
then I want to execute only one command called comment too.
Then in that case, you don't need to write if condition already we have
this syntax clubbing with
two commands with the logical and operator that is the best one.
But whenever, if you want to execute multiple commands independently,
if command 1is success,
then only use if condition.
So here what we're doing if command one is sexist comment
to we're executing further Dean only direct this logic simply,
you can use this one only that is the best one.
That's it. That is simple if condition.
Now, let me once again go with your core.
If this is failed, then you are not.
I mean, you are if condition is not allowing to execute these two lines.
But if this is fail,
I want I want a to some other lines.
Then in that case you can extend your code in this way.
Let me write if L dot SH script, bin bash.
See what I'm doing.
If I'm testing like four greater than four greater than phi.
Anyway, that is false.
If it is success, suppose if you,
if you are four is greater than 5x,
then I want to execute some number of lines.
Then those lines you have to write.
First let me syntax for you or if and else.
If, then, else, then close with phi.
Now here you can write some number of
lanes on here also you can add some number of lines.
But if this condition is getting, I mean,
if the command is getting success,
then if will allow takes good the lines which are there between then and else.
If it is failed,
then it will skip this part and this part that is advantage with f and l.
Now let me write.
Now here I'm writing two commands.
Let's say echo.
We are comparing 45.
In case if you are command is getting success means four is greater than phi.
At that time, the lines which are there here, they will execute.
Now I'm writing a CFO.
Four is greater than fight anyway, that is not correct.
It won't execute these two lines.
Now if it is failed,
then you will allow to execute the lines which are there within el Santo phi.
Then I am writing some lines here also.
As you can also start even lend from here onwards.
But it's better to provide at least a two spaces
are four spaces just for looking purpose.
Aco, we are comparing 45.
So else will execute if the condition is false or if your command is getting fatal,
getting failing means, in our case,
four is not greater than five.
Then I can display four is not greater than five. That's it.
Now let me save it.
Let me provide the execution permissions for that.
Now, see your core.
Now I'm running that code.
We are combining 454 is not greater than five.
This block is executing the lines which are there between Elson,
FAA, or executing because your command was failed.
Why does fail?
Because we are comparing four greater than phi,
that is not correct that way this is fail Nazi.