Friends here, our concepts or logic to handle command-line arguments.
If, if else, if, else,
if else if else, statements and statement.
And finally, how to run shell script with only root r with the root user.
And all these concepts we are discussing with
a simple shell script called automate HTTPD actions.
Before implementing our shall skip.
What are these actions?
See whenever if you install packaged as a system service,
then you can manage that service with system CDL.
And for that system CDL,
you can provide different options like start, stop, restart.
And one more thing.
Suppose if you are, are HCl is greater than or equals to seven,
on Lennox is greater than or equal to seven.
Then you can use System CDL command to manage your services,
to manage your systems are,
suppose if your voice is less than seven, is less than seven.
Instead of systems UDL,
you service command Plaza up now I'm
implementing a shell script for our children are not equal to seven.
So in our photo sessions,
we had been doing work for both.
I mean, any, any rational linux.
First let me show you that.
Hud PUT actually believes that.
But by seeing this output,
I don't wanna decide whether anybody there or not,
because logically I need this value 0,
yes, my hedge UDP is there with my host.
That's fine.
Now let me run one command, systems,
UDL, I want to know the status of that.
Status is when action, it is not running.
Now I want to start with HTTP,
then let me run this with the start action.
It is failed to start.
That isn't status action.
You can learn from any user.
Might start, stop, restart. You had to run from.
Other ways.
You have to run with sudo privileges if you're usually having Sudoku.
Now, first we will try to
implement ourselves script such that it has to walk with only root user.
And then later I will show you how to work with other user, which is having.
Now, let me move into some directory.
So here I'm implementing shell script,
automate HTTPD actions, not SH. And one more thing.
Before implementing your shell script.
How we know that from which user we're running
our cells inside of yourself simply by using Heidi are IID hyphen,
you see that they're getting one W1.
If you're the root user, you would get.
Let me show you that as well. We are getting.
Now this is our logic to decide whether you are running with the root r.
Now, let me open up a shell script or homemade HTTPD. Action's gone insane.
Now let me write our shebang lending bash on.
Now. As usual, I'm writing comments.
Then you can also write u or for personal descript.
So I'm writing something like automating HTTP actions like start,
stop, restart, and status.
Let's say. Now the very first logic,
what we hope to implement in our cells,
when and what have you done this shell script in the user is He's running yourself.
Then it's okay. If user is not the root,
then he had to say that you are not the uprise user to run the shell script.
Please run from rude or with some Sudoku ligase.
How can we decide that based on ID, right?
See, what I'm doing is I'm testing if id value,
ID of users for how we can test it.
Test operation. Is Heidi hyphen you?
If this value, let me do one more thing.
I will take one variable,
user ID equals ID, I even knew.
Now in our variable will have a value for your user who is running shell scripts.
Now that value, I will test it.
So if you did you know that meaningful, that is root,
then dollar user ID value.
If it is equals to o, then it is fine.
Then it is fine.
If it is not equal to 0.
Then so that's what I'm doing.
You see here, if it is ID equals to o,
just I am clubbing with the logical and operator, a goal.
You are the root user.
So you can run the shell script.
This shell script. That's fine.
I am clubbing with logical Alonzo.
Such the idea I'm writing.
You are not the user.
You're not the root user who
run this. Let's see.
So we know whenever if you club three commands with the logical and,
and logical or the second command will execute.
The second command will execute if
the foster command is success, you've kissed his success.
You test to fail, then the command
which we collaborate with a logical order that will execute.
No, let me save it. Provide the what happened.
Oh, let me call
this is a pathway that let me come out from that.
So somebody I've implementing,
then we go ahead and copy this into some location, automate HTTPD actions.
But again, I was in the OPD.
That was for automation.
You don't have to write some files in that location.
Now we're copying the exact script.
Now let me save it and run it before an English proverb execution by missions.
And see your core.
Now I'm running.
You're not the root user to run the shells.
But here, if you observe,
if you are writing some lengthy,
lengthy, but I don't want right in this week. Of course it is.
But I don't want run industry.
And because of that echo command is that you are getting output.
You are not the root user and run the shell script.
Yes, you're getting periorbital.
That's way, instead of this clubbing your commands with logical and,
and logical or I will use infants.
We know if command one and else.
I mean, then you can write this one and this one.
Let me write it. If whatever you
are having this place sd command, that is a foster command.
So we write that here. You've got ill success.
Then we know that the lines we thought they'd between then and else will execute.
If that is failed, the lines which are the LSA and f I
will exclude are simply tested success.
Then block will execute.
If test is fail, then we'll skip.
An LC will exclude anyone of the block.
Only will exclude. Fine. Now, yeah,
let me copy and paste discipline.
Of course you are lined this single lane logic is correct.
But for looking for,
but it is not good that way.
I'm converting that into if else.
That's fine. Let's say,
now let me comment or let me delete this line. That's it.
Now let me save it and run it.
So you are not the root user.
Two renditions, its fine.
Now let me navigate into root.
Now with root user.
From root user I'm running.
You order.
Suppose root user. So you can then,
if I am the root user,
I don't want this day this information.
My intention is to try to run your equilibri actions with root.
If I'm the root user,
I don't want to split this.
If I'm not the root user,
then only I wanted to play a pharmacy.
Then you need here if and else.
Now let me remove the else block.
See guys, if this is not correct,
then we hoped we exclude.
But as of now, if root two user is running, this value is correct.
If it is correct, this block will execute.
But if it is not correct, I want to exclude this.
That means if user ID is not equal to o,
if not equals to 0,
then you are, then block will execute.
We know that that's way what I'm doing is I'm removing then and else. Now it's fine.
If user ID is not equals to 0.
Yes.
You are, you are not the root user.
This method will display.
That's fine. Now let me save it and run it.
I'm going to use up, it is not as linking information.
Motif.
I come out and if I run our shall scape,
and I'm not a root user, you are not the rule usable.
And they said, yes,
we are getting perfect error messages if you are not.
Fine. And suppose next step is if user is having any user like automation,
if any user is having good.
Then how you can understand, let's have three year.
What is the value of id icon you?
But he played around with pseudo idea for you. What is the value?
That means?
If this user is having good privileges, delta,
you can use sudo in front of any command, our initial script.
Now see that is, let's say if user is having root privileges,
then you can then use sunscreen with too low so that inside of yourself,
it will work with the Google.
Now we cleared a boat.
Very foster concept.
That is how to run transcript with only root or root.
Now next is if it fails concept,
so only record here.
If it fails, then we have one more concept called if else, if else, if else.
Let me show you that. Anyway, I will switch into root.
So this is our shelves can find.
Next target is we need to automate actually pretty actions.
Plus let me write all the commands which are there for your HTTPD.
Islam CDL status is one command.
Then if you want to start, same command.
Only difference is here.
Stuck. Then for stop here, stop.
Then restart.
Instead of stop-start status here, restart.
Let's say.
Now you filter all these four commands.
The foster command, last word,
post-war lost, what is same?
The only difference is here.
Let's say what I believe I will take one variable that is required action or user action.
I will take one variable, user action.
Then I will read that from the user.
And meanwhile, learning your shell scripts,
I will leave please enter your action.
Then I will substitute that here.
By using your dollar syntax we have,
let's say, whatever the user is giving.
Suppose if either giving start, it will start.
Let me show you that. Now.
If you're running with the rule, that's fine.
After that, I am writing a logic hyphen p.
Enter action, your action.
For HTTPD.
Then let me store that action.
India variable core user action.
Now after reading that action, yes,
I'm reading some executing your action,
whatever the action we are giving to manipulate this ACO just I am
writing user action on HTTPD.
Then after that, just simply like system CDL.
Instead of writing start, stop, restart.
That action is there with the user, I mean,
David user action with able. Then which UDP?
Let's not let me save it and run them shelter.
So before running was to see the status first I will you they actually asked status only.
Inactive. No, let me rerun and provide the action S star.
Now see the output you are getting,
executing your action, start on it.
Now, redone and poverty status.
So whenever you feel if you,
you here we have given status as action and we are getting there inactive.
Now we rerun that subscript.
And here we provided start action.
So now you're actually,
but it was running because of this.
Let me verify that by returning yourself,
by giving status as action, nobody's running.
That means that what?
That's fine. No.
Here you need to understand one simple logic.
That is, suppose you feel are intuitively is already running.
As up no unit-free Ripley's running.
Status. It is running.
But I have given command as stark.
Nobody's saying that executing good actions taught on it.
If it, if it is already learning,
why should we run again?
Same based upon if it is already stopped state and if you act as toppling skew,
you produce already installed with state,
then why should we stop it again?
No nearly. So that's why I'm separating your actions in this middle.
C yet I'm taking if condition, if statement.
I am writing a test condition here.
That is, if user action,
if user action, if it is equals to strings rate,
you have to use comparison operators.
If it is equals to stock.
Then then I'm closing the template.
I'm concentrating only on stock.
So before starting your HTTPD, I'm ticking status.
If you remember, System CTL status,
HTTPD, will you exit status as success if it is running?
Let me show you this on command line systems, UDL status, HTTPD.
After running this, see the exit status,
such as now what I will do,
I will club this command with logical ARE who started with HUD beauty systems?
Udl dot HTTP.
So whenever you use the club to command by using logical order
of the second command will exclude if first one is.
So when it will fail, if everybody's not running, if not running,
then it will fail there so that it will try to execute
second command so that we can achieve our task to start your hedge.
But if it is already running, it will skip.
That means we have not really learned.
We are not trying to run that because all of the learning,
so that is the concept.
So that's why I'm using logical or operator inside of this if condition.
If actually start, then I am writing this term CDL, start HTTP.
And I don't want to display the output also.
Then just simply, right.
Something like, I mean,
successor output rate greater than null. Simply.
Let me implement the logic for stop also.
I'm reading one more if condition separately.
Now. If your status is running,
then only I want to stop it.
That means it has to combine with success.
So when it was a success, this was the command.
If it is running, I want to stop it left by anythings.
Could one more command then clubbed with the logical
and let's say I
wanted to write one more row index just for restart.
For status, you don't iterate anything that Italy, I mean, yeah,
you can write some condition but no need to take any external loading.
Let me if you are actually restart, then here also,
you don't need to check any condition that Italy can restart it,
see whether it is stopping running.
That is not a problem to restart your HUD.
No need to check any previous status. They started laughing.
Now let me paste it for once again.
And this is for status.
As of now, I implemented this entire script by using only if condition.
But here if implemented will test if condition that it is some problem.
I will show you that I will explain that political understand status.
Let me remove all those things.
Now, just to point you at understanding purpose,
I am writing one more echo command instead of each and every.
Cool. Starting HTTPD. Just while understanding.
But what I am writing one would understand that which if
condition is excluding equal scalping.
Stop, stopping HD DVD.
Then I am writing here restarting.
And for lost if condition.
Finding this status.
That's now let me save it and see what logic ones. Now I'm running.
We are running from boot, so no problem.
It will then enter your action.
I'm entering action as status.
So you will get the status. Proceed output.
You're getting finding these thetas.
That means last if condition is executing.
But because you have this entire script right,
let me copy it to my notepad.
I will explain, I will do is you have to understand about this concept.
This is your antilog.
Now whenever if you run your shell script,
it will execute line by line.
So very first line, it will execute shebang line.
So just you are to know by your operating system is executing by Shell.
Just for that. Then this is the next lane to are shall will execute for finding the ID.
Then it is testing this condition.
If it is success, then it will skip this block because for every success,
it will display this when it will success.
If they are not the review that if you're the root user,
then it will skip this.
Because if you're the root user, this will pay.
So that will skip this block.
That's fine. That is what our, next,
we're reading the value from the user, user action.
So that is storing into user access.
Let's say you are entering status.
You are immediately next elastic is this action.
I'm in this if condition.
So user actinic status,
but you are comparing with stock that play, it is false.
And we do that,
we'll skip the same way.
Each and every if condition will execute.
Protest.
Finally, the last if condition only, we get success.
But unnecessarily, you are executing all these tasks for excluding all this stuff, right?
Otherwise, let me take one more. Yes.
I assume that you are giving action as stop action as stock.
Then you're reading your action,
you are storing that into user action.
Then you are comparing that user action with the start node.
It is false, that way it is.
Then we'll skip links could this block so that you are, you've conditioned is over.
Now here you, that action is stop and stop is equals to stop.
It is success. If it is success,
this if will allow to exclude these lines. That's fine.
We got output, but you don't stop by that.
Still we have some logic MOOC.
It will try to combat these two values.
Also, a value is stopped and you are comparing with restart.
This is false. But actually you don't need to check remaining logic whenever,
whenever if you execute it, you stop action.
That's why whenever, if there is a dependency between immediate if conditions,
see each and every condition, there is a dependency.
If you observe this is executing,
then the remaining all if condition we'll skip the hunted, they will fail.
That means there is a dependency between immediate conditions.
So at that time, what you have to remove this if I come
here and right here else if then how it will work, I will tell you.
Again, he had also remove this F8 whenever there is
a possibility to depend if conditions on each and every one,
I mean on each other immediately if conditions then only you can plug in this way.
That's a non-iterative else block. You can skip.
Now, try to understand this.
If this action is equals to start, then this is true.
This is true. This command will execute successfully.
If it is success by default,
if we skip remaining all else ifs,
by default, it will skip remaining all else-if condition.
That is that one day. If the very success,
then it will take the remaining if conditions.
That is the advantage when nobody people up with olive conditions with
the concept of else-if No. Let me copy.
Just to commend you are and pay logic. Otherwise I will.
Yeah. We'll come here.
I'm commenting out code that logic is correct,
but unnecessarily going to take x i execution time for I am writing here, come in.
And then let me write that last comment. Now.
Let me copy and paste our logic.
I will do, I will write it one more ourselves.
And Hansel automate HTTPD actions.
Notice which I've been faced our logic. That's perfect.
Before that we have some coordinate.
Let me copy it from here. Redeposit.
Yeah, we needed this logic.
Now let me save it.
And probably distribution permissions for your new shell script.
Now I'm running under the hood action datas.
And your action will stop,
stopping HTTPD nauseated status by returning,
returning yourselves given by providing optional status.
Let's say No, that's fine.
So as we implemented our concept,
our shell to perform, to execute actions.
But initial scape, valid options valued actions are start,
stop, restart, and status.
Suppose by mistake.
I have given in this way, then there is no output for that.
So if you actually is not a valid one,
then all your if conditions will get all these.
If all failed them,
that is no block to execute.
Now, if all conditions are,
all your testing conditions are free,
then you have to write one L2 block such that it will display.
This LSA Bloch, when the cells are bug me legs.
Good means if all conditions are praying,
if all the conditions are fail,
then only this else will execute.
This one, this one,
this one involves failed them. This one, it looks good.
Then we can understand when ultimately executing means
you are not probably novalidate option val action.
So here, multiple your shell script.
Else, else.
Yes, NP, right?
Aco. Action is invalid.
And you can say to the user,
valid actions are our onStart,
onRestart hot status.
Let's now let me run it.
Now you're providing some help to the user.
Whenever if there is an invalid option,
you're actually is invalid.
Value flattens off starts kabeles or let's say, fine.
No. One more important thing.
If you observe, as of now we implemented our logic, right?
What we are writing some number of lengths.
Of course, that is correct.
Click on it. You can use this concept that is no doubt on that.
But let me do this only if else, if else,
if else conditions only this lock,
this logic, same logic you can implement in terms of his statement.
Also, there is no difference between you and if else, if,
else, if, else if and else statements.
Already we know k syntax.
What is that case?
Whatever the variable you want to handle it with your case.
Then our variable is user action.
In. Then first end of it.
That is syntax. Then what is the post option you are trying to sell the stock?
Then simply right here.
Host option adds incase if you're actually start whatever
the logic inside of your pasta if
condition that logic we would like simply inside of your cost option,
which is there in your case statement.
That's just I'm giving spaces for looking at the end.
Yes, Y2 semi-colons, non-iterative here.
You can also add in previous lane at the end, semicolon.
Let's say. Same way for stock.
So whatever logic you have,
one-stop just to get those two lines and type it in your face.
Actually, this is the best one compared to your if elseif pensive. Yes, is the best one.
Who do you want to go with a succinctly if else, if else if,
then restart, restart,
whatever the logic you How is to copy that and paste it, you restart option.
And with semi-colons.
Instead of writing in an x lambda2 semicolon iterating the same length.
This one line for each option.
And last one is status.
Let me write status
and end with semicolon, let's say.
So other than this,
if any option is given by the user,
then how you can handle in if else,
if else, if, else block, wall,
our ester conditions fade, then also links.
Good. Here also we have an option called star.
Star means exactly else options.
Then you can say whatever the logic you have.
So it is somewhat very easy,
compatible if else-if condition.
So how would we walk? First, we will read
the user action and the case will take that value here,
and this value will be mapped with any one of these.
There is a match with any one of that that block will execute.
Otherwise, if there is no match for you or input,
then star, star means anything other than this.
But don't write start before you were
valid actions regarding because tar will map for anything,
it will match for anything that way.
Always write the star at the end only.
Other than these four options,
if any option is there,
that will map this one.
Let's say.
Now let me write one more shell script and automate actions.
Notice edge
up to this.
Say we avoid the execution permissions for this C or cold ones.
Simply, you're validating user are not.
Then after that you are reading the action,
another action then that you are comparing with the case statement.
Case will take care whatever the value you are providing that value it will
try to match with anyone out there is a match that logic will execute,
that block, will x do otherwise, starlings.
Let me run.
And Hansel script with the case statement I'm providing some invalid.
You're actually is invalid.
Parallax inserted is giving yes, it's working.
Now let me rerun.
And hence remit. I am providing status.
It's giving plaza of know.
Your Apache is not a medieval HTTP.
Apache is not running.
Let me provide start starting HUD beauty then.
Either status by returning your shell script just to provide axonal status.
Yes, it isn't working. That's fine.
Now, for your shell script,
you are providing input with help of a read command.
I mean, while running your shell scripts,
Sorry, often running your shell script.
After running your shell script.
Now you are providing your input,
but I want to provide my input.
While running Michele Cook itself.
So heat itself, I want to provide my action that is called command-line argument.
We know command-line arguments concept.
Suppose I'm opening with the case,
and instead of reading with 3D command in t,
I can write user action equals $2.1.
$1.1 means the value which we are passing from command line.
Offer your shell script user action. Let me save it.
Now I'm running. Then here I will provide status.
That is the command-line argument.
Yes, you are getting an output.
Now let me stop stopping the HTTPD or you can find a status.
But here, if I don't pass anything,
you're actually is invalid.
Well actions or start,
stop, restart and status.
As of now we know where Latin thoughts start, stop,
restart so that we are providing here start or stop or restart
operand new hotels get whenever if you're using command line arguments concept.
But assume that you are implementing your Shellsort and you are
giving it to some other members which are there in some other team.
They don't know how to pass command line arguments,
then you ought to provide help as well for them.
So that's why just I am writing a logic to work with
your command line arguments after
evaluating user ID or before user ID also, you cannot do a logic.
Now I am writing after validating user ID,
I'm validating this week.
Friends, we know how to calculate
how many command-line arguments are passing to yourselves get with L profit dollar hash.
I am checking if dollar hash value,
square brackets, dollar hash value,
if it is not equals to one,
because we need at least one.
If it is not equals to one, there is a problem.
You are not passing any command line arguments
or you're passing more command line argument.
But my intention is I need exactly one in case if you are not parsing,
parsing one command line argument at the time this will become proved,
then I will say a call.
Please run this shell script.
Please run this shell script as follows.
As what other questions you want to write.
You can write C yet what I'm doing is I'm writing usage,
uses of this shell script.
Then in next line, we know dollar genome into
your shell scripts occurring which tells you how to pass,
either start, onStop and status.
Close your if conditions.
Before running your actual logic,
you are validating whether you are passing exactly one hour mark.
If you pass exactly one, this will become free.
If you are not passing exactly one command line argument,
this will become true so that your if condition will allow to exclude these lines.
Now see that I'm running ocean scooped by adding our logic.
And I am providing invalid options here.
I mean, I'm not passing any options.
First of all, that's why you are if condition is
200 and saying that please run the shell script in this way,
dot slash than anyone adoption.
Then why you are running this also,
this is actually in your case statement, lost option.
I'm not passing any option here.
That's why you are getting this information,
then money to get this output, right?
That means, that means if you are not passing any argument,
you no need to run your shell script.
You can stop yourself could without running this logic.
So if you want to stop without running remaining logic,
if you want to stop your shell script,
you how to use exit command.
Exit, exit is a command to exit from your shell scripts.
So whenever, if this is true,
means you are not passing any arguments,
are you're passing more arguments at that time.
I don't want to the meaning logic, I want to stop it.
So this block will execute.
And after the executing of this blog last you have
an exit command so that it will stop your shell script.
That is the logical handler command-line arguments in your shell scripts.
Now you are not getting these last two length it previously you are
getting the reason if you don't have exit command instead of your if command,
which is used to handling our command line arguments that say, okay,
I'd actually this shell scripts with this video you can
download and you can practice that. Okay, thank you.