Friends here we're implementing a simple shell script for backup.
And this concept is useful for Linux admins, middleware admins,
and database admins just assume that I'm running a website on webserver.
And whenever if you run any website it will create some loves like access logs,
logging logs, something like that.
Now I want to take a backup for them.
For that, I am writing a shell script.
Now before implementing your shell scripts,
let me show you where the locks of storing for my website.
So in my case,
this is the location where logs are storing for my website.
In your case, it may be different.
You had to point out that first.
Now these are the log files,
these files and could take a backup.
So instead of taking individually for each and every file back-up,
I will take a backup for this directory right now.
So this is your source.
So from this location,
you have to take a backup.
Then where do you want to store your backup profiles?
So let just assume that.
And one more thing.
Now this is a root access files.
Let me switch into root first.
Now am route, so somewhere or how?
Some backups directly.
So this is the location where I want to take him my backups.
So in your case, so this location also maybe changed based on your requirement,
you have to create the location for your backups.
Now let me implement a shell script.
C, I'm implementing a shell script.
That shell script we can implement anywhere.
Now, let me implement in this way my website backup dot SH.
Let me write the very first line has user bin bash.
So if you want write some commands.
Who is the author or what is the purpose of this cryptic and write the comments.
Just I am writing only author.
You can write the purpose of your script also.
Then, before implementing UDL shell script,
you have to know what is your source and where you want to store that its destination.
Now let me take a source.
I'm taking source as a variable in that I'm storing
the path where my logs or storing. Then destination.
Let me take destination
as you can take any variable names I'm taking simply these are the variable names.
That's it. Now if you want to take a backup,
you can use either simply copy command or you can use some tar command.
So here I'm taking tar command to unzip the file.
Let me show you a simple tar command.
So here's the syntax for your tar command.
So these are the options and destination and source.
Sources, simply our HTML directory destination.
Inside of your backups,
there is a directory inside of that.
You have to create your backup file with some name, something like that.
Right now, see, I'm
taking your options here, v for verbose.
So if you include the V tar command,
it will display while keeping your files.
It will display what other files it is.
Taking.
So simply, you can keep hyphen v option or you can keep that.
Then destination.
See our destination is there in a variable called DSD, D, D.
Let me write. You can take anything just I'm taking
that destination insight that you need to create with some name.
Now I'm creating with some name called my website back-up.
My website.com backup dot dot dot z.
Then what is the source?
That is your source, say our sources there in a variable called SRC.
Given that, let me save it.
Let me do the execution permissions for that.
See your core.
Very simple.
Now I'm running that. So backup is done.
Now you can verify just by navigating into that back-ups directory.
Yes, there is a backup.
Now, we have a small problem with your shell script.
So in case if there is no directory called backups location,
see your destination is nothing but backups, right?
If this directory is not there,
then your shells could will fail.
Now let me remove that barrier tree and we will run our shell script.
It's getting fail. That's the reason you have to take care for that inside
of your shells can see what I'm doing is I'm using test a condition.
Existence c, hyphen e.
Easy word destination is already there.
If it is there, then it will get success.
If it is success, I don't want to create that.
If it is not success,
if it will fail any to make that directory,
to make your directly have a command.
But you have to club ecological art.
Why illogical or why not logical and means.
If this is not there,
if directory is not there,
then this will get failed.
If it will fail, then only I want run some other commands to create your directory.
If it is success, I want to skip the command which is there here.
First, let me get a command.
Make directory, whatever that dire destination you how insight
that if you're first to command is fail the meaningful that there is no destination,
then all I wanted in this command,
that's why you have to club your two commands with logical r.
If I take logical end,
if it will fail, it will skip.
That's why I'm not taking logical and to club these two commands,
and that's it. Now let me save it.
First, see that there is no backup directory.
C, there is no backup there to here.
Now I'm running our shell script.
Now see the content. There is a backup,
but it has been created and your backup has been taken into inside of that.
So if this directory,
if this destination directory is not there,
so we are creating,
if it is not there,
then only we are creating it.
That's fine.
And one more problem is there.
Suppose we had taken a backup yesterday by using the shell strip.
Now today also I wanna pick a backup,
then you will run simply.
Now see the backups.
Then what about your Yesterday backups?
Today we have taken a backup and I should also we have taken a backup.
Then what I would do yesterday backup.
This is your latest tobacco
So the reason why you are old backup is deleting.
For that.
The reason is whenever you are taking a backup today or tomorrow or day after tomorrow,
you are using same name.
That's why you are wold backup is war writing.
Now whenever if you are taking a backup,
please include some timestamp so that the backup file name will be changed everyday.
So how we can create a file with some timestamp, very simple.
C, we know date command.
In your date command,
we have some special syntax.
Based on our requirement.
We can display particular value from your data output number.
Then space I am giving.
You.
See that date, then space percent a year.
Then I'm including One more thing called hours, minutes, seconds.
If you want, you can include but in case if you are taking backup every day,
known it includes hours, minutes, and seconds.
In case if you want, you can take options.
See there is a but whenever if you're creating a directory,
you should not be created editor name by including spaces.
That's why you see what I'm doing here.
Simply, I am replacing spaces with underscores.
That's a Nazi, That is an now this command output I will
store into one variable or directly you can include that in your variable name itself.
Just for your clarity,
I will take first a variable every day timestamp.
Yes. That is my variable everyday timestamp for backup.
Then I'm storing into this hour date command output by including these options.
And while creating your filename somewhere,
I will include the timestamp.
So how can we include simply here underscore backup,
dollar, every day, time stamp for backup.
So, but better clarity just I'm using curly braces so that up to that,
that is a variable, that's a.
Now let me save it.
So before running our shell script C,
what are the backups are there in your file?
Now I'm running our shells tip.
It has taken a back up, see the content with the timestamp your backup is creating.
So what are the options you need in timestamps based on that,
you just modify your date command.
Again, I'm running. Now see the content.
So if you run your shell script any number of times,
each time it will create new backup.
That's it. So these are the simple logic to create a backup
based on timestamp. That's fine.
No.
Here we are running manually our shell script to take a backup every day.
But in case if you have a requirements such
that every day if you need a backup 40 word logs file,
no need to run manually or shell script just to create a cron job such that,
that con job will run automatically based
on the time which we scheduled in that cron job.
So how to schedule a cron job to run our shell script based on particular time.
So that we'll discuss in further sessions.
We have separate concert for cron jobs scheduling with Dell, perfect contact.
Okay. Okay. Thank you.