Friends here our concept is scheduling jobs with at and crontab.
See at and crontab both or commands to schedule a job based on your required time.
But there is a small difference between attend crontab.
Just assume that I have a small shell script to take a backup for some log files.
Now, my requirement is automatically a how to run that shell script at tomorrow morning,
09:00 AM, or automatically how to run that shall scape everyday morning at 09:00 AM.
Then there is a small difference, right?
Do you want to run your shell script only tomorrow?
Every day?
So if you want to run only for tomorrow,
then go with at but means onetime task.
But for everyday go with crontab.
But thing is that just scheduled job with either at or current out.
So here we are discussing about how to schedule our jobs using at command.
So in next video we will see about contact.
So I'm giving just some simple examples.
Now, let me give a syntax for your at command.
So before going to give syntax,
let me show you on your terminal.
So however, some shell script in my route,
so I'm switching into root.
So here there is a shell script.
No, first let me show you the backups.
So how some back-ups here.
Let us do one, something,
some data is that now,
as of now suppose what is the time?
156, I want to run at 157.
Then let me schedule our job.
Simply act you how to write you what time?
One colon, I mean,
you are a hover. Then colon 57.
Then it will enter into your HAT prompt.
Then he there you how to do the shells kit,
which you want to automatically run at a given time.
Suppose I'm implementing a shell script by using Bash shell.
So that's why I'm taking simply bash.
If your, if your script is, I mean,
if you are using any other shell just mentioned,
that shall only then enter,
then press Control D so that the job will be saved.
And it is displaying, it is job number seven.
So already I introduce some jobs.
That's where it is giving job number seven and Friday number so and so date.
So what is the time now? 157.
Yeah.
Your your backup has been done. Let me verify.
C. Let us to backup 157 previously, some 1729.
Now you're having at one hundred fifty seven
twenty nine the day he had been the eighth day.
So this is a simple way to schedule you what jobs are to execute only one time.
Now, that is one syntax.
So what is the syntax for syntax you had to run at?
Then you are to provide at what time you want to exclude that time you had to mention.
Then simply suppose I want to execute out too.
That is the time you mentioned enter.
Then you are shell script, but all the shell script you want to mention execute,
then control D, but is the syntax.
One more way is also that echo, Bash,
shell script, then pipeline,
then provide you what time.
Suppose I want to exclude that.
Yeah, you now see that there are now nine jobs.
Now, you can see your list of jobs which are q, which are pending.
So these are the jobs.
Now you can also remove your scheduled job by using 80 RM.
Suppose I want to remove this job.
Let me provide a job number here.
Nine.
Now see the list of jobs.
There is no nine, just know we delegated that job.
That's it. Okay.
So here, not only these are simple way to provide your timing,
your different formats, to provide your timings,
to run your jobs using at command.
Then let me show you them, some of them.
So tomorrow at ten AM supposed Today I want to run at 10:00 AM.
Then on coming Sunday at 10:00 AM,
then at 10:00 AM, then you ought to mention sunday.
So these are the, some of the examples to schedule
your jobs by using a command to run your job only once.
I attach this document to this video,
you just don't know this and go through that.
That's it. Thank you.