Friends here our concept is introduction to loops.
See most languages how the concept of loops,
and they are very,
very useful to execute series of commands for n number of times.
Let me explain this concept with a simple example.
Suppose I have a shell script called Introduction to loops, not as such.
If we have three lines of code in our shells
taped and you get those three lines we implemented with echo command.
Now let me run this first.
You're getting some output.
Now my requirement is same output.
I want to get three times.
Same output. I want to get three times or four times or five times.
That means these three commands you have to execute for your given number of times.
Let us assume that I want to get output phi times.
Then let me modify this shell script.
So if you want to rerun your commands again and again immediately for n number of times,
then loops concept is useful.
Let me read a simple loop,
but don't worry about syntax of your loop.
I'm writing very simple loop called a for loop.
For each in, I'm writing some numbers,
let's say 12345 times I wanted to get output.
Then do an end with the Done.
See, we already know simply if conditional if-else.
So what I am writing, if some command one, if it is true,
then what are the lines which we have between then and else are then block will execute.
Else, Else block will execute.
And whenever if you are writing lines,
code statements between then and else or else and FA,
while writing, you provide some space,
then that is good for looking the same way.
Whatever the lines we hope between do and done.
We have three lines, right? For those three lanes.
If you provide some space,
if you provide some space,
then it is good for looking purpose.
Nothing is there. So that we can
understand that these three lines are there between do and done.
That's it.
Even if you keep some empty lines, no problem.
Now let me say what? I'm running. C, the output.
You are getting. How many times?
12345 items.
So simply you are repeating your logic phi times by using for loop.
Not only this case.
Let me explain with one more example.
Suppose I am moving into these laboratory.
So here we have different types of files.
First, let me take this file and I want to
check whether this file is having execution permission or not.
Let me get a very simple shell script.
Check execution permission, dot SH.
Start with your shebang line.
So you can implement with the if-else or using
logical AND logical OR operator by clubbing three commands.
First, let me write logical and,
and logical or operator with the help of those.
So two operators, suppose I am taking the given file,
whether it is having execution permission or not, you have to test it.
We how test operators.
File test operator iPhone X.
If this file is really having execution permission,
Then this test will become true.
If it is true, I want to execute one more command called let's say echo.
This file is having execution permission.
If it is not having,
I want to exclude some other command.
So if your first command is getting fail,
then I want to exclude some other calm and
not this other time you had to club with logical are a go.
File is not having execution.
Permission. Let say.
So this is simple way.
Let me provide the execution permission for
this file because we need to run the shell script.
Now I'm running seal output.
That file is having execution permission.
Anyway, same syntax, same logic.
You can also implement by using if and else.
Now I will implement with fl if an else block,
simply if you're foster command.
If that first command is true,
whatever the command we are executing that you hard to write under then block,
nothing is that, but it's simple.
Remove that and illogical and then enter,
then enter in that.
You just write the command which we want to
exclude whenever you were first attest to command the success.
And else inside that else block,
what are the command you want to exclude if your test condition is failed? That's it.
So previous and this index both are same.
I mean, both will work in the same way.
Let me save it and I'm running.
We are getting same output. Now let me take one more file.
I want to check to files whether they're having exclusion permission or not.
Let me take HTTP version Pong.asm.
I'm taking this file and eye opening our shell script.
Now that is first Logic E just to check for FASTA file.
Now I have one more file.
So first let me copy that file here.
Now, same logic.
The only thing is filename is different.
No.
Same logic you are repeating,
but filename is different, right?
Understand. Same logic you are repeating.
The only difference is filename.
Now I am replacing that file.
So wherever you have that file,
I am replacing that file. In this way.
That's it.
So if that file is having really execution permissions,
then you will get, yes,
it is having execution permissions or else you will get NOT having execution permissions.
Now let me remove this line.
Let me say we see your code
once you are checking execution permission for this file and this file.
So to check execution permission for first of all,
you are having logic here,
but same logic you are repeating with some different filename.
Now first let me run and see the output you are getting for first to file.
It is having execution permission for secondary is not having execution permissions.
That's fine.
But if you're out ten files at a time,
you had to check for ten files wherever they are having exclusion permissions or not,
then you how to implement this type of logic for ten files.
As of now you have two files,
then you have to implement this logic for eight more files.
I mean, you have to copy and pasted this eight more times.
So why should we unnecessarily increase our core length if your logic is same,
except some few values.
So here, except this filename.
And the logic is same here and here.
Even if you repeated for eight more files,
logic will be the same.
Now in that case you can modify,
you can use loops concept.
So they just basics guys.
Let me commend all those.
Foster two logics.
Comment I'm using multi-line comment.
Now I am using for loop.
First, let me let the syntax for each in.
So whatever the files you are having,
first let me copy those two files.
And those two files just to provide in your for loop syntax,
FASTA file, space file.
In case if you have some ten files, yes,
you can provide all ten files here with spaces, then do w1.
And here each is a variable.
You can take anything here, like our variable.
We know whenever if you want to define a variable, we have some rules.
The same way you can take any name here such that it is a valid variable name.
That's it.
And this allows whatever the logic you how know,
to verify for one single file that logic
just a copy and pasted inside of your do and done.
I mean inside of your loop block.
Let me paste it first.
See whenever if you are writing your code inside of a loop,
it is better to provide at least two spaces.
Then again, AN inside of you reef condition you how some block four that
I'm giving to more spaces. That's it.
Now, your file is not fixed one,
you are having different files, right?
So that filename will automatically save into this each.
That's why instead of using your file name here,
you can take this variable and we know how to substitute
variable value by using dollar, that variable name.
Now, I am substituting dollar.each.
Wherever he, how your file name.
Just substitute that with the help of a variable called each y each.
You can take any variable,
just follow the rules to define your variable name.
Your variable.
It should have only alphabets and underscore and desserts.
And it should not start with a number. That's it.
Now see here. Instead of writing two times,
your if conditions are given only one time.
And that logic written inside of a loop, then how it will work?
Very simple. Let me explain that.
So whenever if you run your code,
your firm in for loop,
you have a variable that is your concentration.
By default, the first value,
which is I mean the first to file,
which is there in your for loop syntax that will store into this each variable first.
And by taking these filename into each,
your for loop will enter into or will
execute the block which is there between blue and done.
So while executing first time,
it will take the first to file limit to each unduly
exclude so that you are if condition is executing on first to file.
Once it is done, the logic liquidities there between do and done,
between do and done.
Once it is done automatically, you are photovoltaic.
Second filename into each and same block will execute once again.
So finally, how many times it will execute means how many files you are providing
here are how many values you are providing here that many number of times.
The logic which is there between do undone that will execute.
That's it.
Very simple. Now let me save it and execute it.
Let me save it.
See your core.
Now this code is commented, it won't execute.
The remaining part is this one.
Now I'm running that code.
See there getting same output,
not only for two files.
Now you can prove it any number of files in your loop.
Let me take one more file.
Let me take our shells could be itself.
We can take any file name.
Now I am taking one more file in here. That's a.
Now this block will exclude three times because you have three files here.
Not only files, only thing is how many values you are having here as of now,
how files are zed value?
So three files you're having three times real x good, while excluding first-time,
each will take, I mean, inside of each,
the value of first to file name we'll store automatically.
And second time, these filename will go to each variable part-time.
These filename will go to each variable so that you are looping is working on all files.
See whenever if you're executing first-time automatically,
each value is this one.
That is called one iteration.
Iteration.
It is executing one time iteration.
Second iteration means whenever it is executing for
loop by taking each variable value as second file name,
that is called second iteration.
Now, instead of saying this loop is executing three times, instead of that,
we can say that for loop is repeated three times
or three iterations or done by using your for loop for given these values.
That's it.
Now let me save it. You'll see
that our cells could be is having any execution permissions.
That's why we're able to run dot slash.
And this file is having exhibition permission,
but for this file you don't have execution permission.
That's a.
So that is the simple way to understand a simple for loop concept.
And one more thing here.
As of now, if you open your shell script manually, we are providing.
Sorry, I was kept in check, right?
Yeah.
Manually you are providing your file names.
But whenever if I run myself, skip automatically,
it has to take all the files which are there in
the current location from where you are running your shell script.
From where you are running your shell script from
that location automatically it has to pick all the files.
Then how you can modify this logic?
Very simple.
C, We know if you're an ls command,
you're going to get all the files which are there in the current location.
Now, a less output I want to substitute,
I want to do to the for loop.
We know if you want to assign the output of a command to your variable,
then we are using dollar parenthesis.
Inside that we are writing LS.
I mean, we are using the syntax right?
Where originally syntax, same syntax.
Instead of writing your file names in your for loop, you can use this.
Let me write it.
Let me comment only the for loop line as of now, whatever we have,
let me rewrite new for loop for
each in dollar Ls so
that you were shell script will automatically
pick all the files which are there in the current location.
Suppose you may have a 100 files.
So now your loop will repeat a 100 times.
While repeating each time automatically you are,
each variable will be the different file name.
It will take all you are a 100 files one by one,
and it will repeat for a 100 times in case if you're a 100 files in the current location.
But how many files you're having that many number of times your loop will repeat.
Now, let me run this,
see that you're getting your information for all files.
Now my requirement is my script has to take the given path.
It should not consider.
It should not consider the current path.
See whenever if you run the shells could always it will work on current path only.
I may take any park.
Now what I will do is first I will copy this shell script.
Let me take only this logic because I need only this.
I will come out from the directory.
So here I'm creating one more shell script.
Check execution permission file of your files.
For given. I mean,
check for each and every file.
Now see what I'm doing is let me write shebang line.
First-time pasting our shell script.
Let me rearrange this spaces.
So you don't forget whenever if you start with the,
if don't forget to close with their file.
And for loops, we are starting with the do and we hope to end with a done.
So this is the logic which is repeated by your for loop.
Now instead of LS,
What I'm vagueness, given path, I'm taking a variable.
Given path equals $2.1.
I mean, I will send path from command line arguments.
Then I will substitute that path here.
Given park.
Let's say, let me save it.
I will take the complete path, then come back.
Let me probably the execution permission for our shell script.
Now I'm running our shell script while
running first command-line argument I am passing as a path.
That path will take an inside of a loop. See that?
Likewise. Now your shells QP is ready to check execution,
permission for execution, permission of all files which are there in a given path.
That's it.
So in this way you can use your loops concept.
Right? And one more thing here,
whenever if you are working with command line arguments,
we know how to handle that.
If you are not passing command-line arguments,
then let me recollect our concept.
First, I am writing a logic to verify
whether you are parsing command line argument or not.
If you remember, if dollar hash,
if it is not equals to one,
if you are passing Juno arguments are more than one,
then I don't want to run my shell script because I need exactly only one path.
That's why I'm giving simply not equals to one.
If it is not equals to one,
then I have to say CPU.
Usage of this script is simply your shelf skipped.
Then any path.
Then offer that I don't want to run my shell script, then I how to exit.
As of now if I run,
see that how it is working.
It is working on current path,
but we're not passing you in any path.
Mysql has to work if I pass any path. That's why.
See this. If this condition is satisfied,
it means you are not passing any path,
then I want to stop my shells kept.
I don't want to exclude this logic.
So then how you can do that simply. Here.
You can write exit command.
We know what is the uses of exit simply or shell script will exit.
Instead of executing remaining lanes which are there in your code.
It will exit whenever.
If this condition is true, if this is true,
it will execute first this echo command so that you will come to know how to pass.
Then we have exit command.
Because of that, your shell will terminate.
I mean, you are shells could will terminate instead of running remaining lines.
Let me save it and now run without passing any command line arguments and see the result.
You have to run your script in this way.
So it is nothing but whenever if you are working with command line arguments,
you have to take care by using this simple logic.
Okay?
Nothing. In this way.
We have different types of loops in the word shell scripting,
Bash shell scripting there like for loop,
while loop and the loop and select loop.
So we hold different scenarios to use your loops.
I mean, in some cases for loop is helpful in some cases while and in some cases until,
and in some cases select loop.
So based on situation,
you have to select our required loop.
So we will do all practices in our later sessions. Okay.
Thank you.