Friends here our concept is difference between dollar rate and tell a star.
Let me explain this with a simple example.
See basically we know dollar upgrade or
dollar star represents all the command line arguments,
but there is a small difference.
Let me explain that with a simple shell script.
So I am writing simply difference between at the rate and star dot SH.
Let me write very simple shell script. C.
If I directly print dollar at the rate values and echo dollar star values.
First see the output C while learning your shell script,
if you pass any command line arguments,
those arguments you can fetch by using dollar or dollars start.
Now I'm not passing anything here,
so you are getting empty for both dollar star and for C, the script.
Now I'm running by passing, suppose three values.
There is no difference while displaying the output to $4 or dollar staff.
So this difference I can explain with a simple for loop.
Let me take for loop.
Let me remove these two lines. Now.
I am writing for each in dollar.
Let me take first a star. Do.
Then.
So here I'm displaying echo dollar each.
And here I am writing equal
the willow output yz
is for frenzy for a $2 star.
Again, it will display the values of your dollar star.
I mean, all command-line arguments,
but I wanted to spend dollar star as it is.
Then I need to escape the purpose of dollar with the slash symbol.
Next, let me write one more for loop echo.
The below.
Output is $4 stock or directly.
You can check with TO turn with the slash,
what is the output you are getting so that you can
understand what is the use of slash humble here.
Now let me write one more for loop for each in dollar at the rate.
Let me complete for loop.
Then echo dollar each.
Let me save it out to be probably the execution permission right?
Now, see the code once.
Now I'm running just to bypassing three values,
or maybe any, any number of values to the output.
As of now, there is no difference.
Whenever if you use a dollar star or delta at the rate in your for loop.
Now, suppose, you know what is the meaning whenever if
you write any data inside of a quotation previously you are having 1234 phi arguments.
Now you're having first argument.
23 is entire thing is only one argument.
Second argument, third, fourth.
Again, there is no difference.
Actually, our intention is we have to take them as a single argument to three,
but either dot-dot-dot rate,
they are not taking them either single argument.
They are taking the splitting actually these data that are
concerning again, 12345 arguments.
That way, generally, we will take quotations for you or does
star or dollar at the rate that we take dollar star quotations.
Now you'll come to know the difference between star
and now I'm running our shell script just by passing.
Without quotations. I mean,
I'm passing phi command line arguments seed output.
Because of dollar star,
the tool we are using quotations for dollar star.
Whenever if you write quotations for your dollar star in your for loop,
it will consider the entire Phi arguments are
a single value that we are getting all values in one line.
Now for dollar star,
if you take quotations in your for loop,
then this N tied all phi command-line arguments.
We built digital as a one command line argument.
But if you observe here,
you are getting output for your double-dot data with quotations,
your data as these,
1-2-3-4-5, that it can swing phi arguments only.
Now, once again, see you are core.
I'm running in this way first.
Now I am providing our data.
I mean, 203.
I'm considering it as a one argument only.
Actually that is my intention.
But Dallas star, whether you provide quotations or without quotations,
whenever if you take quotations for your star,
it will consider you're all command line arguments and a single argument.
But dollar at the rate,
it will work perfectly whenever if you take
quotations for your dollar upgrading quotations.
First argument that we are getting one output.
This entire thing is a second argument because we heard it instead of a quotation,
yes, second value, you are getting that.
Third, fourth, that's it.
Right?
So from now onwards, whenever,
if you want to work with command line arguments,
then please use quotations dollar at the rate.
The syntax we just follow in your for loop.
Okay?
And whenever if you want to take all command line arguments as a single value,
single command line argument, US dollars.
That's it. That is the small difference between a dollar at the rate N star.
Okay, thank you.