Friends here our concept is
loop control statements or commands simply break and continue,
or called loop control statements or loop control commands.
These to break and continue are used to control the execution of loops.
Any loop c we have different types of Lucknow for loop,
while loop, until Lou, select loop.
So to control the execution of any loop here,
break and continue or useful.
Let me explain this concept with a simple shell script.
Suppose I'm defining a shell script called Display Files dot ASH.
So I want display all the files which are there in the current location.
So simply I can use ls command also.
First, let me run the shell script by taking simply ls command C.
You are quote, simply we how ls command,
instead of your shell script,
you are able to display all the files which are there in the current location.
But same output just I want to get using for loop.
Yes, I'm implementing with step-by-step.
Let me comment this unless I am using for each file.
So you know, in for-loop it immediately afterward starting with your four key,
you have to take any variable.
I'm taking each file because my concept is using for loop, I'm printing file.
That's why just I am taking suitable variable him, that's it.
You can take simply for x, for y,
for each, for each file,
or for file. In.
If a sub shoot dollar, ls, dollar pencils,
unless the command output we are giving as an input for your for loops.
So that for loop will take one by one file from this output and we'll try to do it,
will try to repeat the actions,
the commands, the logics which are there between do and done.
Now my intensity is simply,
I want to display each file.
That's it.
So what will happen? First, ls command will exclude that output will substitute here.
So we are getting, going to get some number of files that many number of times.
How many files you are having here because of ls output.
That many number of times,
this logic will repeat,
while repeating each time,
while iterating each time automatically,
the.h file will be one by one from this output.
Now let me say we see your code once and see the output.
Yes, we are getting your output.
And here you are displaying all the files,
see without extension or within some dot TXT dot ASH.
But now my requirement is I won't display only text files.
Then you can take simply,
instead of taking ls command,
if I go with ls star 2.txt,
no meaningful that is,
star means anything any file which is ending with the dot TXT,
you are getting wanted text files.
Now let me use your for loop just to get text files.
So let me comment this code.
So I'm using multi-line comments, multi-line comments.
You can take any name to come into your multi-line.
I'm taking him comment.
Now. For each file in
dollar ls dot dot TXT means any file which is ending with the dot TXT,
that files I'm capturing with ls,
that output we are providing to our for loop.
Then here simply, I am displaying
a dollar each file so that you are going to get now only takes two files.
Yes.
No, I need to extend this such that I need to display only one text file,
which is getting at very first.
If I get one text file by using for loop,
then offer that I don't want to repeat,
I want to skip all these.
Then how we can do it?
There are different ways. Let me show you.
First I will go with some complex way.
Then I will show you a very simple way.
So initially I'm taking some count,
count equals to one.
Now what I am doing is before printing you are each file value.
I'm checking if I'm taking the test condition.
If only if count equals to one means wounded very first-time.
Then, then I'm executing this eco,
sorry, echo dollar each file.
And then after that I am making,
I am increasing this counter value.
We know how to increase counter value by using arithmetic operators simply.
Then I'm closing with their Phi. Now what will happen?
You know, here you will get some list of text files.
Your for loop will try to execute this logic number of times.
But initially before starting your for loop,
we have taken some count as value one.
You can take any variable hours they can count variable.
And for loop will take first to file from
this output and it will try to exclude first-time this one.
So why legs Gooding first-time or for your first iteration count is already one.
So 101, both are equal.
That's why you are printing this.
So after printing first file,
what I am doing is I am increasing count value.
So why executing next time?
You're counties now too?
Two is equals to one.
No false, that's where it will skip.
So now four remaining all files.
While executing this code.
From second iteration onwards,
your count value is not equal to 1.So it will never execute,
so that it is executing only one time,
so that you are going to get only the first text file.
Now let me save it. See you code once.
And I'm running that are getting only one text file.
But there is a small disadvantage. What is that means?
After printing first to file, if you're intensities,
if you don't want to print the remaining files,
you can stop for Lucknow.
Why should we take next to file and why should we check the count value?
It is not equals to one.
So you are skipping this unnecessarily.
You are validating this condition for remaining files by my indents knees.
After printing first to file,
I want to stop my for loop.
I want to stop execution of your for loop.
Now, let me come in this code and I will write one more chord.
So second command.
You can, you can take any name.
See what I'm doing is for each file in dollar,
unless star dot TXT do,
then I'm printing a CO
Dollar each file.
Then I'm using exit, suppose, exit, suppose.
But there is a difference between Exit and Luke convulsed statements,
exit will terminate completely or shelter.
Suppose I am writing two more lengths.
Just for our understanding.
I'm writing yo, I'm in,
I'm writing here, starting for loop.
Then after completion of your for loop at the end,
I am writing a for loop is over.
Now because I use exit.
Because of that you can able to get only one file,
but you are stopping your shell scale so that it
is keeping the line which is the outside of your loop.
Suppose if we how after loop somewhere lens in your core,
then because of exit,
then never execute you're completely or shell script is stopping.
But my indigenous, I wanted to stop only for loop, not your shell script.
You're not getting echo for his over.
But now see the difference.
Without exit, I can stop my for loop.
Exit to stop your shelter.
If I take simply break.
Now, see, the difference between
previous output and current output you're getting for loop is over.
So here, brachii used to terminate
or exit current loop completely before the actual ending of loop.
Actual ending means you are far loop has to repeat for n number of times
that n number of times based on how many values text files you are getting here.
But now, because of break,
you are stopping only were fun when you are stopping.
While executing first iteration itself,
you are stopping based on conditional so you can stop your loop as if not directly,
I use a break statement.
Not only that, see,
let me take your count.
Count equals to one.
Now what I am doing is here,
after displaying your value,
let's say if actually in order to use this just I am giving,
you can use break instead of if condition for that just I am giving an example.
If you are dollar count is equals to one,
then you are displaying,
then you are displaying your line.
So after displaying your Lane,
What I will do is here I can use directly break.
So whenever if I display first to file immediately,
immediately stop my for loop.
See break will stop only this for loop.
Actually were for loop.
Just imagine that there are some for text files.
Your for loop has to repeat four times.
But while excluding first-time itself,
you have a break statement.
Because of that, simply,
it will skip remaining three iterations.
It won't x good remaining three iterations.
And simply it will stop your for loop and it will come out from your for loop.
And it will try to execute the lines which are there outside of your
for loop in case you have any logic inside of your shell script.
That's a simply to terminate,
to terminate only for loop, not a shell script.
So be clear, if you want to terminate shells taped you how to use exit.
If you want to terminate only loop, you have to use break.
That's it.
Now let me save it. See that you're getting your output.
Okay?
Now, one more thing called continue.
Then what is the use of this?
Now let me take one more example.
Working with continue dot SH.
Tried to understand the concept.
We will see uses of your continuum break effectively while writing real-time scripts.
Now suppose I am trying to display first,
I will do this thing.
Echo, starting for loop.
I mean, you can use these break statements in any loops,
but as of now, we covered only for loop.
That's why I am explaining with respect to a for loop,
but same concept is applicable with your wife and until unselect loop.
For each in.
I'm taking suppose sequence command, sequence,
command output, suppose one to ten I want to display by using your firm.
You then do.
Then.
So let me save it and let me run this fast.
Execution permission.
Continue. Now, I'm running our shell script.
You are getting one to ten.
And let me modify this script.
So at the end I am writing one more statement called for loop is over.
Now my intention is if you are,
each value is equal to phi,
then I want to stop to print remaining values.
Actually you are for-loop is trying to print one to ten.
But now my intent knees whenever if you are each value is equal to phi,
then I want to stop my for loop.
I don't want to print remaining values after phi.
So that's why what I'm doing here is before printing EVA value,
before printing your value,
I'm checking that value.
If it is. If Be clear,
if you are, each value is greater than phi.
If it is greater than 5x,
then I want to stop my for loop.
Then simply use break here, then close with FI.
Now what will happen if this condition is true?
It will stop your for loop to execute again and again.
It will display value called each.
Now see the result. Now I'm running our shall skip up there,
the output we are getting now only one-to-five.
That's fine.
Now.
In the same shell script.
If you are value equals to phi,
then I don't want to print it that in remaining cases only I want to print
my values actually are for loop is trying to print
values from let me come into your core.
Your for loop is print,
printing values from one to ten.
Now first let me comment this code here.
Now let me write same logic for each in dollar sequence, one to ten.
Do, done.
So here, as of now,
I am taking again each so that it is printing one to ten.
But my requirement is if your value is equals to phi,
then I don't want to print that.
In case I want to print len how you can implement that.
See, first thing I can do this.
If, if, if you are value is not equal to phi,
then I have to take here,
you have an operator called naught equals not equals to phi,
then only print your values. Then this is fine.
Then.
But as you make it small confusion while working with canoe,
but as of now, just try to understand.
It's fine.
As of now, what is our requirement?
Print values one to ten, but skip o phi.
So that's why I'm taking condition whenever it is not equals to fight that only print,
otherwise I don't want to print.
So if it is equals to phi, it will get failed.
That's why you're if it doesn't allow to execute this line so that you are
getting values from one to ten by
excluding you are number phi yes, 1234678910.
But same concept you can also implement in this way.
Working with continued on S-H.
If my value is equals to fight,
then I want to keep to execute echo dollar H. Then let me come in this code once again.
First of all, for each in Noellert sequence, one to ten.
Do, done.
Then between this, suppose actually we need to print the value of each.
So as of now if you don't,
you'll get 12x ten numbers.
But what I am doing is see,
if, if be clear,
if you are a value is equals to,
if it is equals to phi,
then I am writing here simply continue.
Then close with phi.
Then what will happen because of this continue?
But is simple. Yes, I assume that after you've conditioned,
you are having some number of lines.
As of now you have only one line.
It is executing your for loop.
This entire logic is executing again and
again for ten times because you are having values from one to ten.
If this condition is true,
then can new keyword will execute?
If continue is executing,
your for loop will stop current iteration and it will go for next iteration.
It will stop.
Current iteration means after continue.
If you have any number of lines in your code in your loop,
all those lines will skip and we'll try to pick next value from here,
and it will execute for next iteration.
Let's say C, same output you are going to get, you're not getting fine.
The reason is whenever continue keyword is executing,
continue command is executing simply.
Your for loop will stop the current iteration,
the current execution part.
And you will try to take next value for your each and Inditex.
Good next iteration.
That's why even our continues executing
the remaining Lenny is what is there you are trying to display.
Whenever each value is equal to phi,
continue is executing because it is true,
no, if it is phi, this is true.
True means current will execute.
Continue executing means there are many lines will skip in the current iteration,
in the current execution,
and we will try to take second next two value,
that is six for eight and try to execute
60 iteration for sixth iteration, which is not a true.
That's why couldn't you won't Xcode.
That's why equal annual Xcode, that's it.
So guys, this is small confusion continue,
but if you are located,
then no problem otherwise anyway,
you will get confidence when writing our scripts.
So simply can new command is used in the script to
skip current iteration of loop and continue to next iteration of the loop.
So be clear, these two commands you can use.
In any loop, we have different types of loops, right?
Okay, thank you.