Prince here, our concept is connecting to a remote server or
simply how to login into a remote server from your local or working server.
Cup, go with any Unix or Linux systems.
By default, you have a command card,
SSH, or secure protocol.
Using this command, you can connect with
your remote server or you can log in to your remote server from your local server.
So simple meaning, let me take a simple example in this way.
This is my local server.
Local server, and this is a Unix-like Unix or Linux system.
And how some remote servers,
let's say remote server 100 to see if you know remote server
one username and password with
IP so that you can login into that by using multi terminal.
But my intention is I already login into one server.
And from here, I want to log into the server,
and I want to log into the server.
So now, who login from one Lennox or to other Linux?
I work from local solver to remote server.
You have to use SSH.
And here, we can use SSH in two ways.
One is using password, password authentication.
Second one is using SSH keys are possible less authentication.
Let me go with one by one.
The very first one is using password.
I'll simply password authentication.
C, if you want to login with your remote server from your local server,
then how to use command in this way, SSH,
you're remote server username with
what user name you want to connect with your remote server.
So simply username and then remote server, IP.
And after that, if you enter it,
we prompt for password.
You have to provide the password for this username.
Anyway, remote server, so that your SSH,
using SSH, you can able to login into that server.
Let me show you that.
So before going to execute this command first,
let me take my remote server support.
This is my remote server.
So let me manually logging into that.
I am opening some separate Git Bash and null data.
I'm logging in to what?
Remote server point.
Now, if you observe on my remote server,
suppose I'm having these many users.
Now I want to log in with this test user from my local server.
So now come to your local server.
If you want to login with your remote server,
SSH, with what user name you want to login with your remote server.
At the rate IP of that.
Let me take IP on my remote server,
that is public IP for AWS or worse,
then take it and nobody showing permission denied.
Why you are getting this permission denied.
And one more thing before going into that,
let me clear my old older data.
Go to whatever this link you will get.
Okay, now other than I want to log in with my remote server using SSH command.
Ssh SCU's are, are the rate you are, the more sever IP.
And whenever if you are trying to login with your remotes,
our very first time you are current server will ask,
are you sure you want to continue connecting?
You have to provide and this is called
fingerprint adding fingerprint to your local server?
Yes. No.
Yes. But you were remote server saying that permission denied,
you are not allowed to connect to the remote server.
There is some problem with your remote server.
Some setting, some configuration details, you have to modify that.
But in your real time, most probably you wouldn't get this error.
Because already by default that configuration is enabled Inuit remote servers,
I mean in US realtime.
Now, let me open your remote server.
Let me log in and do who see you are using SSH to connect with your remote server.
That's why you have to open SSL service related configuration file called SSE 2D config.
And if you search in this file with the password authentication,
you see that password authentication.
That means, even though you know remote server,
I mean this remote server.
Now if you want to connect from your local server using SSH on a remote server,
this value should be yes.
Otherwise, why using your SSH to connect with the remote server,
your remote server service doesn't allow to connect with your remote server.
That's why you have to make it this value as yes.
You can comment this line.
And if you come about two lines,
there is already by default password authentication, yes,
is there just enable it by deleting that comment line Hashim.
But now when you are remote server,
password authentication has yes,
that means now your remote server is ready to
connect to allow the connection using password for you,
for any particular user.
Now come back to your local server and let me try with once again.
But still you are getting permission denied.
That isn't whenever if we change
any configuration detail on
your remote server Related to that service, you have to restart.
You see system CTL, restart, SSH.
In case if you are using an HL7 or less than or equal to less than seven,
then you have to use Service command,
simply Service, associate ED, and then restart.
So this command will work with your body
slotted shell less than seven and greater than or equals to seven,
but four greater than equals seven.
There is a new command called system CDL.
Use that. But for less than seven,
just use service, then service name restart.
But here while working with system CDMA,
system CTL, then your option than last service.
See they're very aware I'm writing, sorry.
But service will work with the wood all versions of Linux.
Fine.
Now, I restarted that SHE D Service on my remote server.
Now come to your local server and Cantor. Nobody's allowing.
Now you remote, somebody's allowing,
not just provide a password for your test to user on your remote servers. So that.
You can login with you or in more server.
Now am on remote servers.
Previously our IPs were not due,
these two for private IP new enemies, don't worry about this.
We are connected with the,
I mean, using test user.
Now we are on a remote server.
This is our local server from debt by using SSH,
some user and that it out host name or IP of your server.
We login with your remote server.
And in real time mission of providing IP anyway,
you fully qualified domain name for your server.
You just probably that instead of IP, you know,
some southern names are there in your real name.
You can provide introductory this IP address.
That's fine.
Now, let me come out from your remorse at our local server.
I am using SSH,
some user at the red, you are more than one IP.
Suppose if I don't provide the user name here, it will work.
But conditioning that SSH will take
the default user name as the user which we are using on your local server.
See, let me remove this test user at the rate.
And I'm running without the providing end user name C
that it is taking by default user name for your remote server as the server,
which is data on your local server.
So that's why whenever if you want to work with partner user,
just provide SSH user name or the host name.
And if you want to login with your remote server by
taking the current server locals our username,
then no need to provide the user name.
But still you can also provide local server using them. No problem.
Whether it is automation you that are new user, you can probably,
that's where I log in with my lunch.
It will simply SSH.
I can also write in this way remote IP.
But make sure that here the mod user name is same
as local terminal user.
But always the better options in this way so
that you are having clarity with what user you are connecting with you anymore server.
And these two are asking password and you are providing password.
And before that in case whenever if you're trying to connect with
your remote server and in case you forget any error like permission denied,
then foster manually login with your remote server and see the content off.
You are essentially config file.
You just opened this file and somewhere you are having.
Let me do the steps.
So in this file, just to make it password.
Yes. Otherwise you are more sorrow
doesn't allow to connect with it from your local server.
That's fine.
So the the first way to connect with you anymore?
No, let me go into the second way that is using password list.
I'll simply possible less authentication.
As of now, we are using password to Canada with your remote server,
but there is a possibility to avoid
your password while connecting with your remote server.
It ODE using password you can connect.
But for that, you need to do some settings that sirtuins cost on your local server.
First, let me log in into my local server.
So this is our local server.
And a c as of now, these are the bad actors.
There is no directory called dot. That's fine.
I'll see there.
First I am generating the keys on my local server simply by using SSH key.
Jen, just under four times you are key.
No.
Such with LSI or not,
there is a directory called dot c. Whenever if you create a keys on your local server,
it will create it that it recalled dot SSH.
And in that if you see there are two files called RSA and ID, RSA dot pump.
Now this is called private key,
and this is called public.
If you want to work with your remote server.
First, you need to exchange this key with
your remote server with respect to your required usernames.
Suppose I want to work with test user on my remote server.
I mean, I want to log in with my remote server using test user without password.
So before that, you need to exchange this key with your remote server.
First, let me take my remote server IP from here.
Then SSH, hyphen copy ID on anybody more server.
I want to connect with the test user,
then at the rate that IP.
And whenever you do that first time we will ask password,
then test user I'm giving possible.
So your key as adequate or remote server, go to worry more.
Server. Ya know, our user is let me switching to test
user and may just say this is what our verification LSA.
So whenever you've seen your video remote server,
on your remote server also not SSH and editing midi creator, move into that.
See that authorized keys are there.
Now this is the key,
probably key which we share from a remote server.
Now, once you've shared your keys with your remote server,
now if you use SSH with your particular user,
then you need to provide password directory login and you
will see that now we are under more sorrow without asking password.
It is able to login to a remote server.
So for that what we did simply,
we generally keys and we exceeded them with your remote server, right, fine.
So what can we do this server,
I'm using this user.
But if you try to login with this username,
sorry, SSH automation or the rate.
Now it, when it won't work,
it will ask a password because singular keys
with testes or not with automation user on your remote server.
Now see that it will ask password.
You have to provide password simply,
whatever the password for that user.
Let's say.
But Cmd key you can exchange with any number of
servers are on the same salary exchange with any number of users saw.
So let me do that.
Exit from your remote server.
As of now we are on a local server. Let me do this.
Ssh hyphen copy ID,
theology on the server,
we exchange our propability Batiste user,
but same public-key can also share with automation user also on your remote server.
Nazi.
Sorry,
sorry, we're on remorse a 100.
Let me come all come to mozzarella.
Now, SSH icon, Copy ID,
automation with automation user,
I'm sharing my key.
See previously, for the same server,
you exceeded your public key with a test user.
Now Amex ending with automation user, yes.
But when sharing you will get very first time.
It will ask password. Once it is done.
Now from second time onwards,
whenever you try to login with your remote server with your partner username,
it won't ask possible, let's say.
Fine.
So this is the way how we can connect with your remote server using password.
And we told password simply password authentication and password less authentication.
Okay. Thank you.