Friends here our concept ys,
y loop with IFRS,
see here i fs means
internal field separator and which is one of the shell or a neutron meant variable.
And these IFRS variable is used as a word or fields operator for the loops.
Let me explain this with a simple example.
Suppose I am taking a file called solvers info.plist.
And here I have two lines.
We know that by using while loop,
we can read these two lines line by line.
Let me show you that first.
Simply I am writing IFRS while loop dot SH.
I will do one thing. I will take the file name first.
See, I am implementing a simple shell script.
Simply VIII, read line.
Do, done.
So here I am writing a co dollar Lane
and I am providing input for your while loop as server name so that whatever
while loop will take line by line from our servers info.plist.
Let me provide the execution permission for this shell script.
I'll see your shell script one simply we are using while
loop to read the content of a file line by line. Yes, you are getting.
But after reading the line by your while loop,
now in what line you have some number of fields.
If I take space as the field separator,
then I can say that foster fetal second, third, fourth, fifth.
Now, you can separate your lines.
You can BYOD what line into fields,
into number of fields by using IFRS.
By default, IFIS is the space.
Now let me open your telescope once again.
Now what I am doing is simply I am writing,
instead of reading line, I am reading.
You can take any variables simply I'm taking for your understanding purpose,
your phony of two, something like that.
If three, year, four, year five.
C in my file,
in each line or how five fields,
if I take space as the field separator.
Now see that. Now what I am doing is I'm printing only second field, you know,
in your second freely how username from
each line and see that this is your file in each line.
The second field is the username.
Now, I'm printing that.
You are getting the username.
Now I will do one more thing, internal space.
Suppose I assume that this is some CSV file.
So I'm taking header as server name or satellite IB.
Then I'm taking username,
then I'm taking user password.
Then command one comma comma into.
Now let me provide a comma for each and every field z.
If you go with CSV file, in CSV files,
how separate rows comma that way now I'm replacing space with comma.
Just to give me a second, I will complete this.
That's it. Now if I run our shell script C first of the content
of your file, and shall escape.
My if I run yourself,
see the result, what you are getting,
you are not getting anything because by default,
while loop will split the line into fields based on space.
But if you observe now,
you are finally is not having spaces in the fields.
It is having comma.
That's why you see the result.
How to modify your while loop in this way based on your input file.
Based on your input file.
What are the fields, what is the field separator in input file?
Based on that, you have to mention that
in case if you are fields subgrade is not the space.
If anything, other than space,
then you have to mention that here.
Now, please consider comma as the separator and the way the lens into number of fields.
Anyway, if we take in our current phi,
if we take comma as the field separator,
then I can say that this is first,
second, third, fourth, fifth.
Now sea, that isn't how it is going to work.
You're getting username automation Tomcat, right?
So this is the uses of field separator in your while loop.
Suppose if you don't want to display this username header,
if you don't want display the header, see that?
Suppose you are getting all three lines.
I don't want to get first-line,
then simply use the replicate command and use number of regard naught equals to one.
Printed the lines which are not equals to one,
record number means except to fastlane,
print all the lines.
Now on this output just use while loop.
No. Let me open our shell script.
Very, very important one.
Just try to understand my comment.
I'm coming in this entire code.
Same actually my intention is I don't want to get header while working with wild loop.
That's why I'm filtering with the replicate command,
these output I'm applying for a while loop.
But anyway, fields operator how to take it as a comma.
Then read fields, you have fun,
you have to you have three, year,
four, year five, then do none.
Let me print only Foster Field and second field.
So that host name,
IP name on the user for that.
Say as of now, take two phi foster families,
server IP, secondary leaves username.
Now, let me run this and see the result.
Yes, you are getting, you are not getting second field.
What is the problem?
Okay. It's my mistake.
Dollar.
You have to, that's it you're getting.
And one more thing you have to understand.
Suppose if you open your text to file in that based on karma you how five fields.
But what I'm doing is let me open shell script.
I am dividing into only field 100 field.
I'm not taking you have three or four or five.
But if you observe anywhere fiery based on karma,
you are going to get five fields for each and every line.
But if I take the F1, F2,
then how your while loop is going to treat them.
First, let me print only a fantasy that exerted.
You're getting IP because there is the first field.
Then what about second field?
Are you going to get only user C, U, R,
a shell script ones and see your file in which you are information.
Now based on karma,
you have five fields in each and every line,
but you are reading only two fields.
And first, if we live as if now you're getting perfectly that IP,
then what about second field C?
That is, you are going to get remaining all fields as if to suppose if
you are writing here exactly the number of fields which are there in your file.
Then first, we will assign to foster field value.
Second field will ascend to second field value. Third, thoughtful.
Likewise. But if you are not passing exact number here, number of fields,
then only the first to feel we'll assign to foster v,
then u, F2 for remaining field.
I mean, for last to fail,
the remaining all fields will assigned to that variable.
And that's it. The reason you are getting all values for the work you have to consider.
So there's the uses of fields operator, new or while loops.
And very, very important point is if you are going to change that default IFRS,
then it is a good practice to store the virginal IF is inevitable.
I mean, suppose in our shells kid,
we modify or inside of your while loop internal fields submitter value that way,
just take one extra variable,
old IFF equals to store you were present IFRS variable we hear.
And after completion of your while loop,
just a replace i AFS value with the world IFRS so that
you are not changing the virginal fields operator,
internal fields operator, you are resetting
your field separator after completion of while loop.
That's it.
So initially I'm storing my IFRS into
this variable and after completion of my while loop,
because in while loop we are changing our EFS value.
So after completion of while loop,
I'll, again, I want to reset my AF.
That's why whatever the initial value is there,
that value we are assigning to IFRS.
So that is the important one.
Okay?
Okay, so finally, here's the syntax for a while loop with IFRS.
That's it.
Ok, thank you.