Friends here our concept is introduction to functions.
And here we are working with very simple words
to explain about functions and way going forward,
we will see in depth about functions.
Basically a function is a block of code.
Block of code means some set of lines or commands or statements.
So a function is a block of code that performs a specific task and which is reusable.
Because of this reusability property of a function,
we can reduce the core length or shell script length.
Let me explain this in this way.
Just assume that you How a 100 lines of shell script out of
a 100 lines AT lines or unique lines means there is no duplicate code in this.
And the remaining 20 lanes just assumed that you are
repeating filings of logic in four places.
Same logic you are repeating in four places.
Now, whenever if you are repeating same logic in your shell script in different places,
at the time, you don't need to repeat.
Actually.
Instead of repeating, what we will do is we will take
those file line somewhere in your shell scripts and we will use some name for that.
My core, suppose an wherever you are repeating this phi lines,
they're simply, I will write my code so that you
are going to reduce the length of your shell script.
Let me show you this with an example.
Suppose I have a shell script called simple menu-driven automatic calendar dot SH.
First let me run this.
Suppose I'm selecting additional option,
then 45, it is giving the result.
Now, see your code once again,
simple menu-driven arithmetic calculator.
Now if you observe in this entire shell script,
These two lines you are repeating here and here,
and here and here.
In four places you are repeating these lines means eight lanes actually you are writing.
But what I will do is I will take you first backup for this.
Now I am opening our shell script C
that instead of repeating these two lines in four places,
first, I will copy these two lines.
And in our shelf camp itself somewhere,
I will give you a name for them.
See how I am. I am giving the name for them.
Suppose my quote, I'm giving them parenthesis.
There is a syntax. Don't worry about that. Then.
Curly braces.
And inside of that, just write your logic.
All the lines you are having.
If you provide some space before starting any line in your function,
then it is good for looking.
That's it.
Now wherever you are repeating your lines,
just to remove those two lines, instead of them.
Just view the name,
whatever you are giving for these two lengths.
So how given my Kono that I'm giving here my code.
And here also just remove these two lines.
Then write simply mike cord,
known only to type your code in different places,
lengthy code, each of that is somewhat shortcut.
Now, wherever you are using those two lengths,
they have just remove those two lengths and then do the name,
type the name, or plays the name,
whatever we have given for our two lines.
Let's say my code.
Now let me save it and run the shell script.
I'm giving option a, suppose addition,
sorry, addition, some phi and some number three,
we are getting result as eight.
Now what is not, what is here?
Instead of typing these lengthy code again and again in different places.
First, we are taking the score in one place and we are giving some name for that.
Wherever actually you need
these two lines inch off writing these two lines in your court simply,
we are providing this name.
That's it.
Just assume that you are having some ten lines of
code you are repeating in four or five places.
Right?
So actually, if you don't have this type of concept,
you have to type your ten lines of code in different places.
But if held these functions concept,
then instead of typing your ten lines of code in different places,
first we are writing those ten lines somewhere in your shell script itself.
And we are giving some name for that.
And wherever you need these ten lines of code,
then simply we are writing the name which you are given for these lines,
for the code for this block.
Now, this is called simply a function,
this entire thing, and this is called a function name.
And these the syntax,
and this is the block for your function.
That's it.
So these are very simple introduction for your functions.
Now, let me show you the different ways to define a function.
There are two ways actually.
That is the first way and there's a second way.
In first away.
Function is the key.
You have to write this function as it is with the small letters.
And here you have to provide some name.
And in second way, directly how to probably
the name then parenthesis, intializer function.
You can take parenthesis and block.
You have to close with curly braces inside that you have to write
your comments or set of statements or logic.
So in both the ways, block is same,
same syntax for your book only while defining your name.
You can follow either this one or this one.
Both are valid in your Bash shell scripting.
But while defining function name,
you ought to follow some rules.
Those rules are exactly same as the rules which are there for
your variables to define the name of your variable C. While defining a variable name,
we follow some rules.
Variable name should have only alphabets,
maybe smaller capital letters and underscore and then visits.
Same rules are applicable even for your function names.
And variable names should not start with the number.
Same rule is applicable for your function.
Also, functions would not start with the number and variable should not have spaces.
Same rule is applicable to define your function name as well.
I mean, function names should not have any spaces that say.
So in these two syntaxes,
you can go with anyone of that,
but I will go with this one because I am the lazy person.
Instead of writing function,
I will simply use parenthesis.
That's it. Ok, thank you.