Friends here our concepts or define a function and calling a function,
see basically we are using functions concept if
there is a repeated logic in different places in your shell script.
But that is not mindedly.
Even though if you don't have any repeated logic in your shell scripts still you
can use functions concept just to increase the readability of your shell script.
Let me show you with an example first.
Suppose I'm implementing simple shell script dot SH.
Let me write shebang line first.
Suppose I want to read two variables.
Let me take read hyphen p, enter first number.
Then I am taking that as the number one variable and read I find P, enter second number.
Then I am taking that as num to then offer that I'm finding addition.
Suppose, suppose I'm giving some Equals two num one, num two.
And here I am displaying the addition of you or num1 and num2 is.
So here I am displaying the result that is some.
And after that, I need to find subtraction as well.
Let me take subtraction equals to one minus num two.
Then I am displaying the result,
the subtraction of number one and number two is the alert subtraction.
First, let me save it and provide the execution permissions for this.
Now let me run this.
So it is asking suppose enter num1 and num2.
Yes, it is giving three plus phi,
three minus phi result.
Now, of course he was Shell script is as of now it is fine.
You can use this just to find the subtraction of two numbers,
but just to increase the readability of my shell script,
what I'm doing is these two lines are just to read two numbers.
And these two lines are to find edition and to display the result of that.
And these two finds are to find this attraction to display the result of that.
So what I'm doing is,
let me open my shells, get first.
To read you what two variables I am defining.
One function simply, I'm taking read inputs. That's it.
So that by using this function,
what we are doing simply we are reading two variables.
Then.
Second function on using for addition, suppose.
So whenever if you use these logic,
it will find the addition of two numbers and it will do the result as well.
I mean, we will display the result as well.
And I am defining one more function called a subtraction.
Suppose.
Then inside that we are writing our two lines of logic.
That's a.
And one more thing. As of now we just define a function.
But if you define simply a function,
it won't eggs glued itself.
Let me show you are still subscript ones.
Now let me run the shell script and see that is,
we are not getting any output because simply if you define a function,
it won't execute itself.
So whenever, if you want to exclude these two lines,
then somewhere you have to call this function name.
Suppose if you want to include these two lines,
some many how to call you have to place this function name.
Now, see, now I'm opening a shell script.
And at, after define your functions.
Suppose after defining your three functions.
So here, first of which lines we need to exclude these two lines.
That's why you have to call this function first.
So calling is nothing but just to placing the name of
your function here without parenthesis.
So after this function,
after these two lines,
whether you want to get some or subtraction.
Suppose if I want to get some,
just write addition first after reading inputs.
If you want to get subtraction first,
just write subtraction first.
See that subtraction.
This is the function name.
Whenever if you place your function name in your code,
the meaning for that is you are calling that.
Now after subtraction function,
I am calling addition.
That's it. No, let me save it now you will get output for your code.
Let me enter for and what suppose some numbers you are getting 26.
Now what I will do is I will come in,
suppose edition additional line I'm commenting.
That means now you are not calling addition function.
If you're not calling addition function, then it won't execute.
See, I'm giving 690 or eating only subtraction,
but you are not getting the result for your addition because addition function
we are not calling now, be clear.
This is the way how to define a function.
And this is the way how to call.
And one more very, very important point, ys.
First, let me show you that result so that he can understand.
Now, I'm removing all these three.
Now I'm coming to top.
Here I am writing, simply reading.
Then what will happen? Let me show you that.
Now I'm running or shell script c,
you are getting an error called read inputs command not phone.
Basically function is also like a command.
So if you want to execute a command,
you are placing and list the same way you have to place
your shells function name inside of your shell script.
That's what we did actually.
But as of now,
if you observe our shell script and if you run that shell script,
you are not getting output.
You are getting an error called read inputs come AND NOT phone.
Because whenever if you want to call a function,
you how to call that after defining your function.
So here if we defined,
but before defining itself,
we are calling this function.
That's why you are shelled. Cannot understand what is it.
If it is a valid command, you will get output.
If it is a function.
Before calling your function name,
some very, very hard to define.
That's why always first-year 100 different function.
So generally the best practices define your functions first in your code after that,
somewhere here you just to call them.
So don't call your function before defining that is very,
very important rule while working with your functions.
So if you do fine in that way, then you will get an error.
Definitely just now we got an error, right?
Command, not phone ringing inputs come in not form.
Then simply read inputs.
How you are shell script will work while excluding your shell script.
C.
Whenever if you run the shell script,
we know that du legs good from top to down while excluding talk to don,
the very first line, ease bash.
That's why your operating system will understand that
the remaining code has to execute with the bash shell.
And if you observe this is something a name,
it is not a valid command,
simply doesn't name off the name immediately heard parenthesis.
So whenever if you have a parenthesis or before this name,
if you have a function key,
then you are shall understand that this is a function name.
And as of now, it should not execute.
Simply it will lead to the name.
That's it.
It will skip these two block,
this block and will keep only it will remember the name.
Then offer that again, you have function.
Then again we'll read the function name.
It will remember the name of your function.
That's it. It won't execute as off, No, you are logic.
And after that, you have subtraction,
is there again, you are shell will try to remember this name.
It won't execute this.
So after all you are functions.
Now you're calling read inputs.
Now holiday shall knows that reinforces nothing but somewhere. Function name It is.
That's why whenever a function name you are calling,
then again you are shell will go back to that place.
Note legs queue.
I'll come back to that line only offer that honey lines,
no lanes which we'll skip.
It will, I mean, it will stop the execution of your shell scripts.
So in that way,
you are shell script will execute.
So be clear.
After defining your function,
you have to call it, right?
See already we know the syntax how to define a function. There are two ways.
Function, function name or simply function name in parentheses.
So we are using this one,
but you have to remember both too,
because in online exempts,
you may get anyone of the syntax.
So at that time you should not get confused.
Ok, that's it.
So this then is the defining a function.
And this is how we are calling a function.
And still this is very basic explanation of what your function, we,
how parameters, arguments to pass your functions concept.
We'll discuss that after sometime.
Okay, thank you.