Friends here our concept is passing parameters to your function.
Let me go with that. First, let me take
a simple shell script name called passing parameters dot SH.
And in there, I want to define a simple function called addition.
Then I'm defining a function and I'm taking directly variables called X and Y.
And directly I am taking result as x plus y.
And I am displaying that result echo.
The addition of X and Y is whatever the result you have in your hand.
Now let me define x equals some number and y equals some number.
And then let me call your function C while executing your core.
Always the execution part will start from this line.
After completion of your all functions,
whatever the first line is there,
from there, your execution will start.
Now x equals six, y equals to two,
then we are calling addition that way your shell will come to here and rulings,
good these two lines.
And again, we'll come back to this line only.
Then after that, if there is any coordinate tried to execute that, that's fine.
Now let me provide the execution permission for this and see your code ones.
Now I'm running your core.
You are getting your result as eight.
That's fine. Now, after calling your function,
let us assume that you are having different variables.
Let say p equal to some number and q equals to some number.
Now I want to find the addition of P and Q.
Then if I call addition,
addition function always works with x and y variables.
X and y means always 602.
But as of now you are having variable values as 37.
See already we have a concept to find edition,
but you can't use these addition function for
these two variables because you already fixed to the variable xyz, x, and y.
But our variables are now P and Q.
Anyway, first, let me save it and see your code once,
and let me execute it and see the result you are getting in the both the cases 86062.
But first K6 and two is fine.
But after defining p and q 37 values,
you are addition should be 103 plus seven tells you how to get,
but you are functioning is working still only what x and y variables.
So in this type of situation,
you need a concept called passing parameters to your function means while calling,
please pass your variable values as well.
Now let me show you that.
Now instead of x and y,
you can take some different variables.
Let say some yum,
Andi and just assume that instead of x and y,
you can take, even if you take x and away, no problem.
But just to avoid confusion,
I am taking yum under yen.
While calling your function automatically,
you have to assign variable values for your EM and yen so
that now your function will work for x,
y, and p, q variables C. While calling in this way,
I want to pass,
I want to tell to my function,
please use em Monday n values as x and y.
And while calling in this year,
please use P and Q. Alice.
For a Monday and then how you can pass it.
So first thing, immediately after your addition function,
directly pass dollar x space with spaces dollar White and dollar p,
and then dollar q.
Suppose if you have directly values, don't write dollar.
Suppose if I want to pass,
let me take one more example.
I don't have variables but directly values in my hand. Let say 49.
So if you have a valid directly pass values, that's fine.
Now while calling in this way how this delta x2 L you
will assign to young on how this doorway value will assign pn.
But it's simple.
We know command-line arguments concept in command lines,
$1.1 means first command line argument.
The same way while calling a function with some values.
Now, this dollar x means $1.1 inside of a function.
Because these first argument for your function,
dollar way means second argument for your function.
That's why here, just assign dollar to see that.
Now I am assigning $1.1.
And here dollar luxury.
While calling from here,
X value will go to $1.1 and that $1.1 will us npm y-value will go to $1.2,
$1.2 we'll assign to yen.
Let me save it and execute it so that you can understand.
See you are core first.
Now I'm running. It's working perfectly first-time while calling from here.
X is six.
Yes, y is two.
Yes. That value we are assigning pm Monday and in this way,
then 37 Yes, perfectly they are working.
And 409 directly we are passing now four is assigned to Yum and 90 loss into yen,
you are getting diesel does cutting.
Likewise, you can pass any command line arguments,
any parameters for your function,
same as command-line arguments concert for
your shell script c. Suppose I want to run, this shall scape.
I can run and I can pass some arguments.
No, we remember that.
So now this is $1.1,
$1.2, $1.3 dollar for dollar fine.
Same concept inside of a script.
While working with the functions we can use.
I'm calling my function bypassing might parodies are called parameters.
Of course, there are arguments,
command-line arguments only parameters.
We are passing these two variables to this function.
So why parsing how we're accessing them inside of a function simply,
we are treating them this value as delta one.
This value has done a two.
Suppose if you are passing some 2.3.4 values,
that wonder to $1.3 dollars for, right?
But you may have a one more doubt in command line arguments.
Dollar genome means cells tip right?
Then here, see what is the result you are getting.
The $1 value is $1.
Let me execute it and see the result.
C dollars jury is always shell script either in
functions or we thought functions concept.
Wherever if you US $1,
that is always shell script name only.
Right?
So while passing your arguments from command lines,
whatever the concept you are using,
same concept you are using even while parsing barometers for your functions.
Also, we clear on that.
If you want to pass parameters to a function,
you have to call your function, function name.
Then what are the variables you are having in your hand?
Then take that dollar x 1 or something like that,
the inside of a function,
we can access them with the help of $1.1,
$1.2, $1.3, and so on.
And be clear, Dollar General means
either with the functions concept or with the normal concept.
Always it is shell script name only.
Right?
Okay, thank you.