Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to discuss about basics of arrays in Bash shell scripting.
So after completion of this video,
you can able to define what is an array CO2,
define how to access values of an array and how to read array values with Reid command.
So guys, before going to start this Perez concept,
just assume that I have a small requirement.
Let's say I need to define one simple shell script to there.
I had to take some five variables.
Let say, suppose some values.
So just I want to define some variables.
You can define any variables,
but here I want to take some of them.
Let's say, right?
So I defined phi variables.
So instead of defining phi variables,
right, I want to take one variable and in which I want to store all these values.
Sometimes you may get situation non-equity.
Suppose if I want to defend some a 100 variables, right?
Then you have to take like X1, X2, X3,
because anyway, let us not sufficient right? Edges it.
So that's why instead of even in this way,
what I will do take A's,
I will take X1,
X2, suppose X3, X4.
Likewise, I can take you and up to a 100 values.
It's better, right?
Interrupt making ABCD.
If you want to define some a 100 variables or some five variables,
let us take suppose X1,
X2, X3, X4, and X5.
But he also, right,
I don't want to define these many number of variables.
I want to store only one.
I mean, I want to take only one variable and which I want to store all these values.
Then yes, there is option in shell scripting that is like,
you know, foster value,
sequence six was third,
fourth, then fifth value. That's it.
Right? Now.
This is, this is one of the valid way to define your number of values into one variable.
And actually this is called array.
But once if you define in this way,
how do you access all those things we will discuss?
Right?
Now, this is called simply array.
Now you have to understand that array is nothing but storing multiple values
in one variable, right?
Or array is a sequence of values.
Right?
See, let me now start your slides.
So R is a variable containing multiple values or sequence of values.
And any variable may be used as an array.
That means, so you know,
if you want to define some variable,
right, what you are taking,
like XY Jeddah, based on some newer variable rules,
you're defining some variable name, right?
So you should not start with numbers.
Your variables should not contain spaces.
These are the rules for your variables write while taking a variable name.
The same way, even array variable names also you can take it exert rule.
This is nothing is that these also variable?
That's why you have to follow the same rules of your variables to define variable name.
So that's why any variable may be used as an array.
And there is no maximum limit to the size of an array.
Suppose we define here variable like x and here we are storing.
Suppose phi values, not only file,
if you want to define 1000 thousand, you can take it.
There is no limit for that based on your requirement,
you can store any number of values with your array.
Right? And RA's in Bash shell scripts accepts multiple data types.
That means suppose here we store all numbers, right?
Not only numbers, you can take some string also.
But while taking instance,
Don't forget to provide quotations for your strings.
That is a good practice.
Now, in a one single variable,
e can store numbers, strings, right?
So that's why, that's why we are saying that it accepts and multiple data types.
That's it.
Now defining an array.
So already we defined this is nothing but defining an array.
Right? That's fine.
So now we define RA, Right?
This is the way how you can define your array.
Of course, this is one simple way.
We have some different ways we will discuss them.
So this is one of the way how to define your array.
So array is nothing but multiple values.
You're storing India single-variable. That's it.
Now I stored all these values into one variable called x,
but I want to get it,
I wanted to get phi or four or six or two.
I mean, I want to get this value, or this value,
or this center thing is one value because we
enclosed within double quotations write this entire thing is a one value.
So how you can get all these values.
So, you know, right?
Suppose if you have a variable called phi,
how you can display the variable value.
White, simply dollar way, right?
Of course you can take a laborious also, no problem.
That is actually good practice.
Right?
Suppose, let's say, let me take my,
I'm taking suppose some number.
So I want to display the value of y.
Yes, right?
The same way, let me define our array.
Yes, I'm defining, I am trying to display the right because x is also a variable.
No.
This time trying to use normal variable to display your value.
That syntax I'm using for array also,
but see what you are getting output.
So you are getting only foster value.
But I want to get emptied array, right?
So for that, this is the syntax, nothing is there.
So if it is a very,
sorry, if the variable is an array,
then to display your all valleys which are there in your array,
you have to use either this one or with the star.
Both are valid ones, right?
So display an entire array.
So it's important when guys,
you people may forget sometimes because it's like a normal variable.
Syntax only buddy how to provide.
That's it.
Okay.
Of course you can also take it, right?
I mean, instead of
this underrated can also take star also know Barlow.
Okay?
So that is the way how you can get all your values from URL.
But I want to get only Butler value from this,
this value I wanted to get already,
this value I want to get.
So there is whenever if you define RA by default,
shall we use some positions for you on betas which are there in your x.
So you know, right, while working out though our strings,
right, we have taken some myString glucose to some shell,
something like and whenever if you define your string in this way by default,
shall we use some positions for string characters?
Right?
So for one string,
you are Shelley's giving in this way index values.
Positions are nothing but index values, right?
The same way whenever if you assign an array,
again for this also you are shall.
We'll use some positions.
They are called again index only.
So this is our nixon GO first value is always at index 0.
Seconds value is index 1.
Third value is index 3.
Fourth value, 1234.
Fifth value is at index 246.
The value is at index two, phi and seventh valleys at index 06.
Now based on index,
you can access your particular value,
which is there in your x.
Suppose if I want to get some number three,
number three is that index of fine,
then see that echo you have to write.
So get values based on get arrays values, right?
Get RA values based on index.
Simply nothing is that x just in square brackets,
just to mention your required position of from your array such that it will do the value.
Let me print this.
What is there at index four ation fine.
Index patient phi is that value is three, right?
Let me display that on your command line and see that.
Now I want to get this value.
This is at index six, right?
See, let me take six now.
That's it.
Right?
Were able to get your particular value based on index values.
That's a OK. That's fine.
No, I want to get range of values.
So what is that?
I will explain you get a range of values.
So what is this means?
Suppose I want to
get from six to 23, right?
I want to get from sixth value.
Value six means index position is at two, right?
Gyro Pfizer for is at 16 is 22 index.
So from second index two,
I want to get 2345 up to phi index I want to get, right.
See already we how you are x in this way.
Let me do step-by-step.
So if I am, if I want to display an entire array,
what I could do, right?
This is the way how I can get my entire array.
But what I am doing is I want to get,
let's say number six means index two.
Suppose let's say first index to then enter,
see that what you are getting,
index two is nothing but sixth value,
like this operations again,
same as your string operations already we discussed about string operations, right?
Same exit operations.
So second index to up to last,
what are the values you are having in your array?
You are getting all range of values from index two.
Index two is six, right?
From there you are getting, suppose I want to get from index one.
Index one is nothing but fourth while right, right,
value for not fourth value, value four.
So from this value I want to get
all the values and then just to provide index1 and see the output.
That's it. But I want to start from index one and I want to get after the two values,
C. From that value,
I want to get two values.
I want to get some three values.
That's it.
Ok?
So this is the way how you can get range of values.
So guys, you just practice once so that you can get some clarity.
So only by watching this,
you can't produce some practical knowledge, right?
Just to do your practice simultaneously.
Okay, fine.
So range of values you are going to get using Echo, euler x.
All values. This is the syntax.
But offer that I wanted to get.
Suppose second index to see if this will.
Do you have to remember that this will
display index two to last values.
Then dollar x, suppose I want to get right second index two.
From there onwards I wanted to get three values.
That's it. So this
will display index two.
And from there, three values.
That's acting right.
That's fine. Now, I want to get how many values are there in my array C,
that 1234567 values are there, right?
So I want to get the length of my array, right?
So get the length of an array.
So guys, we know, suppose if some string is there,
how can we get the length of the string already we have seen, right?
So simply dollar, curly brace, hash.
Our variable x, right?
So body here we are having some array.
So let say our arrays.
This one, but I want to get length of the entire array.
So NTIA is nothing but this is right.
So for that you are going to find length.
So already we defined on our command line, our array.
Now I am displaying the length of that array.
We're having seven values.
Right?
Now, guys here one more important point.
This will do your entire array length.
But I want to get, get the length of len,
of particular index value.
Suppose index value is nothing but see for thes at index one, right?
Let me take 0123.
Fourth index value length.
I want to find fourth index.
You're having shell word, right?
Shelley's, I mean shell,
string shall is having phi.
Let us write, just observed that I'm giving forth and see the output you are getting.
So without hash what you are getting index for whatever the value is
there in your x that we are getting so far that I want to find length. That's it.
Very simple.
Right?
So this is the way how to find length of your array and length
of particular value from your array.
Let me copy this.
And that's it.
Okay?
Okay. Now guys, we are done at different ways to define an array c. You can,
of course, it is not recommended,
but if you want, you can also define in this way.
Suppose I want to define the next steps, some array.
Yes, I can take declared hyphen a array.
So here also I can do it X equals to some 4-5-6 days one of the array.
See that echo.
Dollar, your ex, entire elements which are there,
are values which are there in your X.
So I mean this is also valid syntax.
We can use it but not recommended.
You can use one literately x equals two.
Right?
Now, let's say as of now, right?
Do we have any variable called y?
Yeah, we have let me take some Mother.
I don't know, have any variable,
calls it on my terminal C. Now what I'm doing is as I've no,
I know only one value and I want to make it as an array.
Just, you can write jet of 0 means indexes 0,
interpolation means foster value. I can say 45.
And after some time I came to know that I have one more value
now and I want to store this into my array then just write a giraffe one,
an odd title display you assert and see the output what you are getting.
You are getting an array means based on index.
Also, you can assign some values to your variable.
So I want to store so and so value in the index position of something,
let's say as of no, you're having only two values, right?
That means these indexes 0 and this is at index one.
Alright, I want to store some value which is at index of phi. Let me do something.
Index file.
Now guys, you are having index 0,
index one, and directly index five between index one and phi,
you actually you have to insert,
I'm in sequence 234,
but we are not taking them.
No problem. But if it display,
you see how you're getting your output.
So you're, by seeing this,
you may feel that,
right, there are three values and index,
this is 0, this is one and this is two.
But we are hard coding like the index of last values we have given index phi.
We are not taking default index values.
That's why I suppose if I try to display indexer to what is the value
actually help you get in case if this array is defined in a normal way,
then you have to get 45 is at index position two,
but c dot would what you are getting,
you are getting empty because this is 0.
We define this here.
This is index one.
We define here an offer that directly we are defining Jeddah phi means index file.
Now between this one and phi 342,
there are no values and that's it.
But if you try to display the fifth index value, you are getting.
Right?
So that is called a based on index.
That's it.
Okay?
Okay, fine. Now last one is reading an array values with 3D command.
So guys, you know, in your shell script write,
you can write some real hyphen p, enter your number.
Right? And I only or taking some, let's say x,
let say some p. And I am defining some 45 right now with our P,
You can see 45, same a,
I want to read an array, right?
Let's say if you want to read an array,
simply read hyphen a, right.
Take any variable name.
Let's say suppose my array I'm taking,
you can take any variable in here and it is waiting.
You have to provide a suppose numbers.
You have to provide your numbers with spaces, guys,
for 78, some string.
Again, some numbers, then offer that just enter.
Now your array has been created.
Now see that what you are having in your array.
Oh sorry.
The syntax right?
At the rate, all value.
So I want to see, see that you are getting.
So this is the way how you can read your array from command line with LPA fried command.
So what you have to do, just include this in your shell script.
Write, let me write simple shell script,
read array dot SH,
I think is the very simple bin bash.
So I'm writing suppose echo iPhone en, enter array values.
Right?
Then I'm taking the read hyphen yea, my array.
Then after that I'm going to display a code that
given array values sees or the given array is.
So here I'm going to display my array,
my array, right?
All values.
That's it.
Just run it. So you enter array values.
Let me lay arithmetic.
Some numbers like this one,
any values you can provide, right?
Even shell, Python or all are scripting.
Just enter.
Let's see what are the values you enter.
Those values you are getting as it is while displaying your array.
Okay, how good I thank you for watching this video.