Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to discuss about how
to add an element or value to an existing array,
or how to remove a value from your existing array.
So these are the concepts we are going to discuss here.
Let me open my terminal first.
So let's just assume that anyway,
lighting some shell script somewhere,
you want to define some array and after some time with
some logic unit to add one more value to your existing array.
Or you may need to remove one value from your, an existing array.
Then how you can do these things? Very simple.
Let me take, suppose some ways list as my array I'm taking,
my list is like orange shell.
Let's say open two.
And let's say some CentOS.
Okay, so this is my array.
Now, after some logic, right?
Offer some lines of code or because of some logic,
I came to know that I need to add one more waste
listed to my existing waste list of array. Very simple.
See ways list equals two.
Fostering your existing enter array elements. That is nothing but this.
Already we know how to get all the array elements
so that I want to include suppose a i X for this.
Now see you or echo dollar ways list all elements.
Now see so that you can get whether you added new value or not.
Yes, you add it.
Now I want to do one more thing.
Suppose I want to add hedge B, x.
Yes, I added. Now just check it.
Yes, it has been updated in your existing array.
That is how to add an element or value to you or an existing array.
Now the thing is I want to remove any one of the value c guys,
in your normal variables whenever,
while working with your normal variables, right?
If x is three,
how we are removing this x-value?
Simply unset x.
Now see what is X is that no value?
If I write x equals to three and if I display,
you are getting your x value three.
But now I'm removing that by simply by running unset command.
And if you see that there is no value.
Now even if you want to remove entire array,
you can do it in this way.
But I want to remove only particular value from my list, my, my array.
Suppose I want to remove.
So this is an index Juneau, right?
Index 0, index one, index two.
I want to remove this index of three value that is a x.
Nothing is there simply unset.
You are ways the list index.
So index three actually is a value of EA x.
Not try to display your array and see what is there in your array.
Now there is no hex,
just know we unset that value but based on index.
Right?
So if I do simply unset in this way,
and if you tried to display your array,
that is no more your array because we just know we remove antibiotic.
We deleted the entire array, right?
So this is the way how you can add or remove a value,
right, for your an existing array.
Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.