Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to discuss about creating an array with
command or storing the output of a command into an array.
Or why are you storing the command output into a variable?
I want to make it that variable as an array.
So this is the concept here and case before going through this video,
don't forget to follow our previous videos, right?
Just to go through that all call this reuse first.
That's fine.
Now guys already we know that if you want to store the,
any one of the command output into a normal variable.
For that already we know the syntax, right?
So suppose if I want to run command called data,
I am getting some output and I want to store this into a variable.
Yes, I can take suppose my today's date.
Something like, you know,
already we know this syntax.
And if I try to display the value of the security date,
yes, I can get it.
Today. Underscore date value.
Yes, I am able to see that.
Now my intention is I want to store
the command output into a variable and I want to make it as a very RA,
I want to make it this variable as an array.
Then how can I do that? So before doing that,
you have to understand one more thing.
Suppose if you want to display one,
sorry, if you want to define one array,
how you are defining, right?
Some array, these, right.
So here between two elements,
there is a separator as a space.
That means R a will take separated off your elements which are there in your array space.
Based on space, you'll identify the elements.
So that is anyway, by default,
the internal fields operate on your Bash shell scripting.
If you want to change it, yes,
we can change it and we will see that while going forward.
That's fine.
Now if you observe,
they'd come and outward, right?
Sunday support as of now some space may then some space, right?
So that means if in case if you stored this output into an array,
then RAB will consider this as one value,
second value, third, fourth,
you have there is no spaceflight.
Fourth, fifth, sixth, C that I am going to
create an array by storing the output of date command into my variable.
Let's say our aid date.
Any variable, nothing is there guys, actually,
this is the format to store the output of a command in t variable, right?
So just to assign one more parenthesis outside, that's it.
Now see you are RA. So I want to display all elements at a time.
So I'm taking this.
Yes. But you don't know whether it is RA or not,
right? Yes, it is.
Because you are falling one syntax because
of that you are getting output means there's definitely that is array.
Let me count how many values are there so that at least you can understand,
yes, this is RA, six.
Why you are getting six means first value space second value,
third, fourth, fifth, sixth,
6 elements are there in your array.
So we know that because we have space is there
because of space here we are creating six values.
Now those six bytes are there in your created array.
That's it.
Not only that command C,
I'm going to take ls array.
So in the current location,
suppose I'm having this many number of files.
I want to take all values into one variable.
And that means I want to take this all values into an array.
Yes, list off RA equals two.
I can write something like biosynthesis, dollar LS.
That's it.
No, echo. Dollar ls.
Sorry.
This is what we did.
We Mr. Carlin risks, right? That's it.
So suppose if you run simply first thing on your local, I mean,
on the server I less than I,
I'm going to count how many values are there here,
20 right? Now, see same thing.
It should be there even anywhere.
I also let me count it.
Yes.
That means, you know, you created an array with the help of a command, right?
That's it.
So guys, nothing is there.
If you want to store the output of a command output into one variable,
I mean one normal variable,
just to remove these parentheses.
If you want to create the command output as an array
just to provide extra parenthesis in this way.
That's it. Okay?
Okay. Yes.
Thank you for watching this video.