Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to discuss about a public key that is simply introduction to
replicate command or script c. You can use ada became like a command or like a script.
So we are going to see the intellection part for edible,
okay, in this video.
Let me start that.
See what is edible became less basically AW case
a programming language and which requires no compilation, right?
In order to compile your programming language's written by a duplicate.
And allows the user to use variables,
numeric functions, trig functions, and logical operators.
Right there.
Most of the guys know only Arabic is like a command,
but he can also use that as a programming language.
And while using that,
you can define some variables.
You can use some numeric functions and string function,
and also you can use the logical operators.
That's fine.
But coming to a Unix-like systems, right?
The air Duplicate command in Unix is just like
a scripting language and which is used what extra processing?
What is this text processing?
Let me take one simple example is suppose I'm running system CTLs status, HTTPD.
So I'm getting the status of equity, equity.
Now on this entire text,
I need to get only the status exactly where these inactive or active.
Right now I need to process this data.
I don't want to play anti data.
I want to display only in third line,
second column, or second field.
Right?
Now you need to do some processing to get that so that you
can achieve easily using your integral k command.
So as afford, Don't worry how to write in this syntax, right?
While going for, you will come to know how to use your delicate command.
So actually the meaning here is on this entire output,
get a third line,
and in this third line gets second tree.
So you are processing With Your arabic a command.
Right?
That's fine.
Now, wiki is used like, you know,
already we know that as a command and other scripting language.
So sometimes if you want to use like a command,
you can use R and if you want to use like a scripting language,
yes, you can use it based on requirement.
You can go with a command or a scripting language.
Right? Both are very similar.
I mean, the uses of income and I'm stripping is very similar.
You can easily understand that.
Ok, so as of now in this video,
I am going to do a brief introduction to like it command,
how you can use this as a command, right?
Busting. Advocate command in Unix like system is
most important command and it is used to find and replace the text.
So as of now we did the how to find a text, right?
So if you observe here,
we find that texts require thing.
And you can also replace this information with other information.
Right?
That means you can replace the text also, will feel them.
Then how we end up with git command works.
Okay, so before going to work with the biblical command,
just assume that if you have a SAM file,
let's say I'm going to store my command output.
This command output into some files.
Some demo dot TXT.
Right? Now observe that you can take a the command output or some file information.
Right?
So here, how many lines are there?
Now while we're King with the replicate command on this file or on this command output.
You can consider any one of that.
Because by you can give to you are going to provide input for your text,
for input for your enemy can command.
Now while working with your Edit Wiki command,
yet obligate command will treat each line is like one record.
Now you have filed records as per your enemy can't command.
And each record consists of some fields.
Feel some nothing but columns or words.
Right?
Now, first-line consists of dot is one field, second feed,
third field, 4567, right?
So by default you are Ada replicate command will subgrade
p lines or records as a pre is based on space at the separator.
Now here, there is a space notes that it's separator.
Now based on this space,
Your arabic AT command is treating disease first field, the second field.
This is third pill for the grip like that.
Right?
In case if you don't have space,
then how you can convert your recording to freeze of columns.
We will see that.
Okay, now, come here.
Yet public-key reads the data from your file or from standard input.
That means you can provide like standard input c.
Here.
I mean, let me thank Neil,
is command in this command for your edification command,
you are providing input from some command output.
Or let me take one more way.
So if this is some comma and bright,
and for this command, you can also provide some file as input.
In this way.
Both the ways are possible.
Some command or political directly process with your inelegant command.
Repl sound file directly can provide that file as
input for your arabic a command in this way, both thought possible.
Then edible gave US a text to file as a Records countries.
Now you know the call is nothing but each line is one record, right?
And the columns which are there in lines are called fields, right?
The columns which are there in your records because is
nothing but a line are called fields.
So by default, the fields or separated based on space,
right, in this file, right,
spaces or the separator to separate your works.
If you are of them that let say suppose with example, password file, right?
So you don't have spaces here,
but to separate your fields you have with colon, right?
So you can use that also as a separator
by mentioning hyphen yep option in your enemy can command.
We will see that.
Right?
And yet on the GET command works on each line individually.
Write c.
We have taken some command in this way, right?
So you are running this command.
So your intention is from the line number three,
you have to get the second green.
But if you don't mention this line number,
now what you are going to get the output from each line,
you are going to get second field or second column.
But don't say column. You have to say that that has a field, right?
So that's why you can say that edit bigger command works on each line individually.
Right?
And in Africa has its own predefined variables like dollar, euro,
$1.1 dollar Guanzhong Darwin,
and some number of records,
a number of whales hands-on you having
different predefined variables to work
effectively with your end of the GET command or with your arabic script,
you have to know all your predefined variables.
We will see what going forward right now.
And the way, you know that in the VLOOKUP command,
we can use like a command or like a script.
And here we are discussing about like a command.
Now, whenever if you are going to use your arabic a command as a command,
then what is the syntax of your WK?
See a WK options, single quotation, patron,
curly braces inside that action,
then close that single quotation,
then you are filename or you can also use some command output.
It can provide some command output to your enemy K command industry. But Syntax is same.
Instead of providing your file name here.
First you are running some command that output you're
providing as input for your Edit Wiki coming.
Both are valid things.
So these are the basic syntax to work in public as a command.
Alright, then what about this pattern action options?
All right, let me go with one by one pattern.
So this pattern is like the matching word or some condition.
If there is no pattern or act condition,
then by default, you are end of the cut command will work on each and every line.
For example, again, see previously we have taken line number three in this command.
So at that time it is going to work only on line number three.
But if you remove this, then you're like a pattern equation
or that is called pattern position or condition equation.
If you remember this, it is going to work on each and every line.
That's it.
Right? That's fine.
Then. What about these options?
So we have different types of options here.
Hyphen F, like you freely separator to specify your fields operator.
Then hyphen v to define some variable values C.
And you now one more thing that is called iPhone5.
It is useful in your scripting as of now, forget about this.
Only consider iPhone5, 1B.
Then what about this hyphen ever say I have taken
one of the example called cathode EDC password.
So here, suppose if I tried to display a second field with your end replicate command S0,
the output, what you are going to get.
I can feel what you are
getting in
your EDC password, right?
You don't have a second field actually.
I mean, in each and every length, only somewhere, right?
If you observe here, here you have some secondary
and here you have some second because there is a separate of space.
Right?
So in which'll anyhow a space based on that it is going to get.
But my intention is,
suppose let me display first and then you can easily understand.
Let me take first if we'll meet in each and every line,
what is the first word?
I want to display that, but you're getting entire thing.
No. The reason is by default,
a duplicate Command will work based on space.
If there is a space, then it is able to identify phase.
If there is no space,
their entire land will treat as a one field.
Now here our intention is based on colon.
I want to separate my fields.
Then you have a hyphen IAAF option than just mentioned,
hyphen f, then colon.
Now see the output.
Sorry something wrong.
I have to provide some space here.
Now see there are no you're getting only first to fill in each and every line.
All right, so that is the purpose of hyphenate option.
Okay, so again, this is just introduction to your Edit Wiki command.
We will see in detail while going forward.
Thank you for watching this video.