Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to discuss about
your air replicate command with action and basic variables.
You guys already, we know what is the syntax of your NLTK command, right?
So simply WK options,
single quotations, clothes and starting,
right pattern or close starting and closing curly braces,
then action, then you are fine, limp,
or command output also it can provide as input for your end replicate command.
And we how options, right?
Already we have seen this information in your previous video.
But here we are going to discuss about Arabic K Command with action and basic variables.
Okay, fine, but we'll go with that.
First execute LAB GET command with total options, subpattern, and action.
So you have some command or he has some file.
And that just tried to execute your edit weaker command without
providing anything like options, pattern and action.
But Columbus or minor triggers.
Your quotations and calibers on mandatory.
That is a basic syntax.
Let me go and hope m,
suppose you have some file,
it is seed password, right?
So this file, and you can do anyway, right?
A WK, No options.
Now patron, no action. C, the output.
You won't get anything.
You are not going to have any action to perform on your file.
So it will do nothing like That's fine. Then.
Actually the logic basically.
So whatever you are writing here,
I shall, That is a logic.
So simple.
Nozick is print something.
Suppose C.
As of now, I am writing a logic called simply print.
Oh kick. Tells you how to use quotations for your string.
I'm printing working.
But how many times it will work?
How many times you will print a message. Okay?
See guys, we know that whatever the action is there,
that action will perform on each and every line of your file on your input.
Now how many lines are there in these,
how many records are there in this file that many number of
times you to print, okay. Output.
Right.
Instead of printing some information from your file,
simply or printing something based on your requirement.
But how many times to display the information that is based on how many lines are there,
how many records are there in this fine.
Now I can also display multiple informations,
like suppose I want this play,
okay, or for that,
just to write a comma, then a WK scripting or replicate command as of now.
See the output.
Right? So this action will perform.
The number of times,
that number of times is based on how many lines are there, I kill it.
This actually is going to perform on each and every length.
So while performing this action on each and every line or record of your file,
you're not doing anything except a printing information.
That's why just simply are printing your information.
That's a very simple logic, right?
Okay.
Now to use your enemy can't command effectively on your files.
First of all, you have to know very basic variables.
Basic variables or dollar,
$1.1 dollar to one, so on,
up to infinity under them can or number of records,
then NF, number of fields,
and then file name.
So on which file Him you are going to work, right?
See, first thing there is not a 0 means the entire file.
Suppose if I try to print,
you know, I don't want to print any message.
Actually is printed dollars zero.
This is available for variables.
Don't write petitions.
You have to remember this point here.
Don't write quotations for variables.
So $1 means n-type file.
You're going to display whatever file
or having known that entire file it will display at a time.
Anyway, it is not much useful.
So, but from this we can say that AWPA,
we can also use like a cat command with these edible print dollar genome. Right?
That's fine.
Then he helped Danone D21 swan.
So this is based on the fields which are there in your file. Right?
And let me take one thing.
I'm going to define my fight because I can't use as of no root EDC password file,
let's say some demo dot TXT file.
You're already, we have this finite.
Otherwise I will delete all this content.
I will write something like this is first line,
second line, something.
Trace our line.
Right? That's fine. Now, if I want to US $1.1 dollar told Dorothy,
first thing you have to understand, thanks.
We're going to work as a without options, right?
That means we are going to use separate or as a space.
That means if you see your content of your file,
your three records, 1233 lines three records.
And in each record the how, how many feeds?
1234. So by default,
you are Ricard will split into fields based on space.
Right?
So as I said, we are going to work with the only using actual operation.
If you want to include any other separate app,
you have to mention hyphen IAAF option in place of options.
So while going for a rule c,
That means in later videos we will see about options.
And patterns.
Right now seeing what I'm doing is in oblique rotation, curly brace, frame.
I want to train first two column in each and every line of my file.
C that I want to print first column under
the n 30 column. That's it.
I wanted to print first third column.
Then you ought to mention comma a.
Then only you will get space in your output fees.
Right here.
If you don't take common,
Oh, just observe the output.
There is no space.
So it's important not to take comma, right?
Likewise, which if we only want to
print or which fields you want to print from your given file.
You can mention simply you are $1.1 dollar to the Altria up so and so
on in any number of values you can bring.
Suppose if I try to print the No,
let me take $1.8.
Do we haven't already new ARAF file,
you know that you won't get it.
If it is there, then only will get typically is not there, you won't get it.
Right.
So along with your fields,
you can also displays some information also,
like I'm writing using a WK command.
So on each and every line at the ending, right,
you'll get this information using a duplicate
Command M. And if you
want to club your variables with your message, yes, you can club it.
And anyway, this is not much useful.
So this is very useful in your real time by working.
All right, that's fine.
So that is using the Eurodollar 1.2x one.
Then what is an odd number of records?
This is a default variable, guys, right?
Number of free courts,
number of free course, number.
C, if I use that dollar,
sorry, is simply another variable.
Don't take governor for this variable is simply adi, use enough.
This a $1.1 is entirely one variable.
Okay?
So don't come back this with your command line arguments of
your shell scripts or with you or her variables of your shells.
Skip some Olin shells here px is available,
and if you want to print the variable value,
you have to use a quote, right?
Sorry, could capitalize site.
Kindled, X means X Valley.
But here Berkeley, the Alawite selfie variable,
enumerate applicant. Don't get confused.
Ok, so let me take it 1 second object.
Then we are going to work with the R naught and R is a variable,
then what is that m naught means.
So there is, suppose if i write somewhere here n naught, that is a variable.
So n, or we do the line number.
Suppose, you know, these action will work individually on each and every line.
So anywhere first you'll work on first-line.
Well working on first-line and not value automatically
one while you're working on second Len automatical,
that value becomes to see that 1-2-3.
So based on the line,
based on the record line is nothing but in your ED applicant analogy, it is a record.
It will give me the record number. Right?
Now.
See, suppose if we want to display only line numbers,
then simply I can use this one, 1-2-3.
Then next one is number of fields and F.
See again this also automatically,
it will count how many fields are there in each and every line.
So to get, to do more clarity,
let me modify your demo dot TXT file.
So I'm going to add some random numbers,
give me c at y,
inserts something in second line.
I'm hurting Only in this way.
In third line C.
Now, in each line you how different the number of fields, right?
So in first, first-line, suppose you have some
12345678 in second 1-2-3-4-5 fields, right?
Likewise. Now, see, now I am going to remove NR.
Now I'm writing enough.
Now this action is going to perform on each and every line, right?
While performing this action on each and every line,
automatically on each line,
how many fields are there that count dual display?
See that?
Now I want to display line number as well as the number of fields in each and every line.
By line number, I mean record
an or the number of fields in each and every link in first-line you how eight records or
eight fields in second line or second recording how fibrils
in third line or third record the how 11 fields.
So if you want to add some message, no.
Let me write in this way.
The line number is write software that a number of fields.
Or let's say it's very clear.
And first-line you how eight fields.
So you should offline, it's better to say the coordinates actually.
So in first recording how eight fields in second record
you how five rails in third recording how 11 feeds.
Right?
So that is the uses of an orange enough.
Now I am going to do one simple assignment.
I just tried to do the solution for this.
See this E limonene first to record how many fields are there.
You have some fields eight.
In secondly, how some five reels in 3011 frames.
Okay?
Now, if I want to get last to feel in each and every record,
then what is the option?
Right?
See, if I print the simply number of trees,
NFV, What do you are going to get?
Only are going to get the field,
number of fields in each and every line.
So if I want to get manually,
after seeing this information,
I have to write a $1.8 to get field, last, free love,
first-line and dollar fight to get the last field of
second record and done 11 to get the last field of third record.
But automatically if you want to get,
simply use enough heat output,
you are going to get by default lost from each and every line.
So that is the advantage with enough, right?
Fine.
Then lost one is filename C.
Let me write a variable called filename here. C dot put first.
Filename will automatically I interface of
file name which you are going to provide for you or command.
So this filename will,
this filename will print for the Aneesh and I will link that we are getting three times.
Now. I wanted to get filename along with that.
First to feel our second wondered maybe that's it.
So filename will do the currently
on which file you are working using a replicate command.
That information you will get with LPA filename.
Okay, So based likewise you how a lot of variables with
your advocate command and these other very basic variables,
we will see some other ones level wearables while
working with the war ended because cutting back.
Right?
Okay. Yes. Thank you for watching this video.