Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to discuss about Ada Lovelace gripping that to
simply very introduction part to your analagous thing, right?
Okay, anyway, from our previous videos, right?
We know what is the basic and replicate command syntax, right?
So that is like a W k,
some options than pattern or condition,
then your action, then filename.
And the syntax.
You know you are providing input from firing him.
So you can also provide input for your AWPA command.
In this way, some command output you can do
as input for your enemy k by using pipeline, right?
And in this write, this action is going to perform on this file or on
the command output based on either pattern or condition.
Suppose if you are using pattern syntax,
then if pattern is matching,
then the action is going to perform on your record of your file.
So by default, action is going to perform on each and every line of your input.
But in case if you mentioned either pattern or a condition,
then if pattern is matching or condition is satisfied,
then only the action is going to perform on the input of your file.
Write c.
Let me give you one simple example.
See, suppose if you see cat who'd EDC password file,
you are having so many records on your phi.
That means we got means number of lines right?
Now, if I use singly AW K, this is your command.
I'm not using any options simply I'm using directly print $1,
then our input file.
Then what what is your action?
Just tried to forward printing each and every record from this file.
Let means print each and every line from this file.
Yes.
Now what I'm doing is I'm going to mention some pattern.
Right now. See the output.
You're going to get only those two lines.
Because in those two lanes only you how root matching word.
Right? So this is based on pattern.
Suppose I want to display the records based on condition.
My condition is if record number is greater than or equal to
some three. Now see that?
Right?
Oh, let me print record numbers so that he can get it.
C only from three you are
displaying because conditioning is greater than or equal to three.
So from third line,
I want display all the lines.
That means, so based on other pattern or condition,
if you don't write either pattern or condition,
you are edible case going to work based on these action on each and every line.
Right?
That's fine. This is abort simply or edit wiki and you have some options for your AWPA.
And already we have seen in our previous videos hyphen here for NIH funding.
Options.
Now you have one more option that is high funny,
and this is helpful in your inner Lucas gripping part, right?
Segues a replica scripting is nothing but
including to more actions along with your, this action.
Now whatever you are having in your public key, the action part.
Along with these, you are going to add two more actions
before this one action and offer this on action.
Right. Now, see that the syntax for your Edit Wiki scripting,
AWPA begin or start action,
then you are actual action here.
This, this actually is going to perform on your input.
Then end or stop action.
Then you are filename, right?
See sometimes to write this lengthy logic,
whatever the logic you have inside of your quotation, single quotations, right?
That is Alinsky logic.
Sometimes, if it is a lengthy logic,
instead of writing this logic on your command line,
you can also write that logic in one file and you can call
while learning you're edible decay that file in this way.
Awpa hyphen AF, U was actually whatever
the logic you are having known that logic we are going
to write in this file. Then you are finally.
So you can use a stride forward this syntax.
Or if you feel your logic is lengthy for your enemies,
then you can write your logic in one file with extension has not AWPA file,
and you can call that file in this way.
Well, running your advocate command, right?
So finally, you are edible case crypting syntax is a WK,
begin or start action.
Then this is actual action,
then middle action, then end or stop action.
So you have to remember the first, this syntax.
So instead of writing this logic here,
what we are doing if that logic is lengthy than you are writing that logic into
one file and you're calling that file using these hyphenated option, right?
And here you have to know that begin block or begin
starting action is performed before reading the file.
So you know that from your edit MCAT command,
whatever the action you are having here,
note that e is going to perform on each and every line of your input.
But big inaction, no,
it is not going to do anything with your input.
Before reading the file.
You are, whatever the logic you-how inside of your begin,
inside of these curly braces that will execute in a straightforward way.
Right?
Now, end block.
And the block is perform after processing the file.
That means after completion of this logic.
At the end, that is the last step.
At the end, you're going to execute this and the logic,
the let say suppose you how some ten lines in your file.
So this logic is going to perform middle action,
Hollywood ordinal action, actual action is going to
perform an each and every line of this ten lines.
Once this action on ten lines is completed,
then ended block will execute.
Right?
So start action is before going to start your actual action on your input file.
And Andy's offer completion of your actual action on your input file.
Alright, so begin and the remaining is
your actual action or you are action to perform your file.
Write.
Rest of the actions are performed while parsing a file.
That's okay.
While working with the enemy script,
you ought to remember some points.
They are.
Awpa needs at least one action to run a script.
You can use either this action now or this action, or this action.
If you mentioned at least one action,
then there is a US with this edible can't skip,
otherwise there is no use.
Let me show you that. Suppose.
So there's, there is no much difference between your area.
Look at command nondescript,
only including begin and ending block. That's it.
Now see here WK,
I am not writing any action simply I'm providing
empty single quotations actually inside this yard, right?
You are actual logic.
I'm an actual action or begin,
orient all those things we ought right inside of
this single quotations right on your command line.
Then let me provide some file.
There is no output because there is no action, no output.
Right?
So need at least one action to run your script.
Then known enough input for big in action.
Let's assume that you are having only begun action up to this,
you have a WK, single quotation.
Then this logic, then you are completing
your single cottage near that means you are skipping this logic.
Are the time you don't need to provide any input.
Let me show you that. Suppose a WK, Right?
You have to mention begin.
Then simply I am writing print.
Ok.
That's a close.
Even if you provide input, no problem.
Even if you don't provide for your began
only if you have begun action in your edible they can command,
it will work without having any input.
But for remaining this action and inaction,
you need input. Right?
Now let me write simple edible case crypto by including all you are begin,
actual and end actions, right?
Begin, See what I am writing here.
Print working on quote,
EDC password file.
So this is my big inaction before going to work with
your file using your AW k. This is what I want to execute.
The actual logic, inaction logic what I need
is the lines which are matching with the root word,
those lines only I want to print, right?
Then end.
What is end? After completion of your actual logic,
I want to simply print completed your action,
completed work on route EDC, password file.
That's it.
Then provide your input,
whatever the input actually we are going to take password file.
Now see that before starting your actual disease,
your actual logic, right?
This is now you are getting output because of this logic.
But before this, I want to print something then that you can write in your begin.
After completion of this,
I want to print something utterly printing and add some logical.
So while going forward we will see that now you are getting that.
So this is because of the end and this is because of start block.
I will begin block. And this is your actual,
because of your actual logic.
So they sees you or begin,
then you are getting this output.
And this is your actual logic,
and you're getting this output.
And this is your block, right envelope logic.
Now because of that, you are getting this.
Okay?
So this is very simple aboard your script, right?
So while going forward,
yeah, we have one more thing, right?
Awpa, i funny, IF this option let me show you that as well.
See what I am writing is.
So whatever the logic you how here no,
inside of your single quotation.
Alright, let me copy that.
My AWPA dot AWPA script.
So I'm going to copy and paste in that logic here, right?
And I'm going to rearrange in a clear way.
So that is your begin part.
This is my actual logic, right?
Then you end and also write known enough,
I mean indentations, but it's better to provide,
but don't throw it quotations.
Not only of quotations whenever if you are going to write your logic in a script,
now eight WK, I,
F, and F, You are a WK.
Then file.
That's it.
Okay, this is one of the way to write
your edible egg case script and how to execute that, right?
So we can also write by mentioning shebang line,
we will see that y going forward.
Right?
So guys, before going to write any script,
you how to remember the standards syntax.
Okay?
Okay, yes. Thank you for watching this video.