Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to see one simple Hello World script using your AW qin.
See from our previous videos,
we know what is the syntax for your Edom located, right?
So these two are the syntaxes for our edible OK. Now you can feel this is like
an obligate command and you should have writing your logic on your command line.
If you write this logic in one file,
then you can call that as an applicant script.
Right?
And you know some of the blue points for your edible,
okay? These are the right.
Now here you have to remember that whenever,
if you want to perform some action on an input, right?
If you want to perform some action on your input,
then only you how to include your actual action.
And then this is anyway,
optional and action, right?
So if you want to perform some operation or your required operation on input,
then only you how to include this middle action
that is actually actual logic and then end block.
But here in our case,
we are not going to perform any action on your input.
So what is our requirement is simply I want to display hello world using your public key.
And then you can skip these two blocks,
actual logical and block.
Then the only thing you have to use this begin, right?
So now I'm going to show you that with the command line mode and as your script, right?
Let me open my terminal.
Phi c.
Let me move into my wondering doublet case scripts.
Like see first thing,
I'm going to display Hello World on your terminal using AW kick command.
Right?
Now K, c, I am not going to include
your actual action and end block because I don't want to work on any input.
I want to display simply hello world,
then you need only begin block and
simply print nuts it.
See you output.
What?
We missed. A parenthesis,
w, sorry, w conditions.
Say that hello world.
Right? Now the suppose like your AWPA command.
Right?
Now what I want to do is I want to run this as a AWPA script.
Then if you want to write a public case,
stepped right first to find out what is the location of your AWPA on your host.
Because you know why lighting shell scripts also you are
mentioning very first-line us shebang line.
So bin bash now been a WK You How To mention violating your AWPA scripts.
Alright, let me write it.
Hello. Dot AWPA script.
That's it.
Then you are shebang line is been
AWPA hyphen f. This is the shebang line for your AWPA skits.
Now, whatever you're writing on your command line known by
your begin block than inside this, just write, print.
Hello world. That's it.
Close it, save it.
Do the execution permission.
Then run like this.
You're getting your output, right.
Know, sometimes if you're edible because kept in your hand.
And still if you want to run as a WK command,
then you can also run in this way, WK hyphen AF.
Then you are HelloWorld.java WK.
And you can see your output.
And guys, while running in this way,
in this format in your file,
you don't need to write your shebang line off
your NW OK. Now let me remove that shebang line.
Now let me run it again because you are mentioning with
what interpretable you want to run your helloworld dot AWPA,
skip this AWPA right now checked.
But whenever if you want to run as a script,
write in this format,
and while running in this way,
if you don't have your shebang line inside of your NLTK,
Then shall is not able to identify what is
the skip command which with what interpreted or you want to run that.
That's why if you want to run other script,
very first line you have to mention about IE were shebang line off your AW, OK.
Now let me run it. That's it.
Okay.
So here's the, here's a simple script to display.
Simply print Hello world.
I mean, to display Hello World, right?
Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.