Hi friends. In this video,
we are going to see a shell script with a duplicate Command or script.
That means how we can use NLTK command
or a biblical script inside of shell script, right?
See already we know the syntax for our NW k,
right, from our previous videos.
You know, this is like a WK, some options.
And then in quotation you are logic.
So that logic consists of a begin action,
actual action, and inaction, then your file name.
Now of course we shall find limit can also provide command as
input for your ELL obligate command with the help of pipe wrench symbol.
Or instead of writing this logic here, we can write this,
begin, actual, and end the logic in one file.
And you can include that file in your AWPA command in this way, right?
Of course, you are also having a WK script in this way.
But whenever if you want to include your AWPA,
you can follow any one of these two syntaxes to write your shell scripts.
I mean shells get width here, Duplicate command.
You have to follow any one of these two syntaxes.
Right? Fine.
Now, let me open my terminal.
First guy is simply,
I'm taking your WK command without any options.
Simply I am riding begin.
Let say simply print hi.
So I use only begin, right?
Just for simplicity, right?
Easily you can understand if i go with the begin,
we're displaying some high output, right?
Or instead of that,
you can also write this into one file.
Let me write high dot AWPA, any filename, right?
Simply I'm copying and pasting that logic.
And of course you can also write in one straight line,
but that is not a good practice.
It is somewhat clear.
Right?
Now, this is just your AWPA command.
Know what our the logic you need to
display your high that is there with the high dot AWPA.
That's why I am writing in this way.
That means you can exclude your command either in this way or AWPA iPhone f,
the logic, whatever you need that we mentioned inside of high dot AWPA.
Now, our next step is right,
how we can include these things inside of your shell script. Right?
So it's very simple.
So this is like one command for your shell,
or even VC's also one command for your shell.
See inner shell script if you want to use any commands,
right? If you want to.
If you want to include any commands inside of your shell scripts,
or if you want to execute any commands with your shelf,
skip what you are going to do.
Let me take simply PWD command and some ls command or PWD for date command,
right, let me write symbol shall scape them or order SH, right?
I am going to write my shebang line.
Sorry, bin bash, right?
So simply I am writing PWD than ls.
Then how you are going to execute it.
You mean the execution permission for that?
Yes, you're getting PWD and ls command output.
And if you want to include one more command,
let me write it instead of a less simply, I want to take debt.
Of course it can take any command, that frontier problem.
Right now I'm running. Yes, you are getting your output.
And this is tight forward if you want to execute
your command with using your shells can be, you can do in this way.
Now what I am doing is the same way.
This is like a command for your shell.
Now what I'm doing is I'm going to open my shell script and I am going to
place right here you are. Edible K command.
That's it.
Now let me run it and see the output what you are going to
get sick because of your AWPA command, right?
Whatever you are having here because of this,
what you are displaying high, yes, you are getting.
So now you can able to execute
your AWPA command also as you are Linux commands inside of your shell script,
of course, edible K is also one of your Linux command.
Right?
Or instead of this,
we also followed this syntax.
So where high dot AW cases script, I mean,
inside that you, how your logic,
not that Fermat also I can use it.
Let me open you are demo dot SH.
All right, so what I will do is instead of
for your high dot already we included that, right?
Let me first observe your shell script.
A WK hyphen. If your,
these like a command,
Yes, you are getting some output.
Now even though if I include that inside of
your shells group same output you're going to get using that.
There is no difference.
So like a normal command,
you can use your advocate command inside of your shelf.
Stepped, right?
Fine.
Now we know if you want to assign the command output into your variable, right?
How we are going to do, let me take supposed to rate date
some variable equals $2 or it was singular 100 quotation.
You can also follow this syntax.
Now inside of you are you how could a date?
The same way, this AWPA,
that this syntax or this syntax,
this port you can assign into some variable using in this way,
let me open your shell script.
What I am doing is here I am taking,
let me take yj equals $2.
You can use this syntax to assign command or put into a variable.
Let me take b equals two.
You can also use single or double quotation write software that just I'm
displaying dollar gay or simply let me write.
Value is not 4a.
And let me write p value is dollar B.
So we are using dollar yen dollar b because this is shell script not
you're edible ticket in Arabic in order to write Dollree and dollar b,
if you write simply yea and B,
you will display the values of your a and B NEW right?
Now let me run the script transit output.
Yes, you're able to get E-value is high and B values,
I write why you are getting that.
Because you are assigning this command output into
this variable and this command output into be
wearable and you're displaying them using your echo command.
Yes, you are able to get the values of your a and B,
which is from your end WK, right?
Not only this command guys, so I'm in this simple,
whatever, maybe AWPA command you how that command output.
If you want to assign it to a variable,
you have to use some variable.
It goes to dollar, parenthesis symbol, right?
So here's the, here's the simple way how we
can use a duplicate Command or skip inside of a shell script.
Right?
Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.