Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to see one of the use case of your set command that is
viewing file content with set command C from our previous video, right?
We know that the different functionalities of your sed command or like, you know,
viewing file content, searching,
Find and Replace, insertion or deletion.
And you can also use some regular expressions in your set command right?
Now in this video, we are going to work with
viewing file content with your set command, right?
Let me start that.
See we know the basic syntax of your sed command is said some options,
then comment, I mean,
what are the command or actually you want to perform on
your file and then the file which you want to work with your set command.
Right?
See, first let me show you the sed command without any options and commands,
that means simply said,
single source, single quotations,
empty conditions, then file to work with said,
now this will work like a cat command.
Let me show you this on my command line.
Here. Suppose I'm having a command core,
sort of how a file called file.txt.
Let me open that cad file.txt sees that there is
the file and this file I opened with your cat command.
So for my files,
I inserted some line numbers as well for beauty,
more clarity with your sed command.
Now, whatever the file content you're seeing with your CAD,
the same thing you can also see with US.
Sed command said, write empty quotations,
then you are filed. See that?
Now this syntax will work like a cat command.
Right?
So of course anyway it is not that much useful,
but we have an option with your set command.
I mean, using, you can use sed command like a cat command.
Now, the next thing is,
so there is I want to print all the lines of my file using sed command.
I mean, whatever we are doing,
this is no, we are printing your file content.
We have one more option to print that.
Let me take it as a P print.
Now see the content.
If we observe the output you are getting each and every line two times.
The reason is by default,
sed command will print your lines.
Now externally again, you are saying that please print.
That's why we are getting two times.
Now if you want to suppress your default output of your set command,
you how to use said hyphen yen, then print.
Now see that we are getting only one time your output for each and every line.
Right?
Now let's just observe that.
Now from here onwards it just tried to concentrate.
Now if you want to print all lines with your sed command,
you can use either said.
It's empty single quotations,
then you are filename or send hyphen Yana option.
Then in place of commands simply p, then file.js.
I mean, what are the file you want to work?
Right?
Now what I'm doing is I'm taking suppose simply some 3p. Observe the output.
Third line number is printing.
So I want to print, suppose some seventh line on.
I wanted to print some,
any line number you want to print.
It will print that particular line it will print.
I want to print the last line.
I don't know what is the line number four last,
then simply US dollar and see the output.
Yes.
Now seeing 49th line is your file.
Now anyway, 49 number is also there in my file.
Right?
Now I'm using sed command to print my last line.
Then. Yes, you are getting last line as 49 and it's was 49 space L phi.
That is the last line in my file.
Now I want to print the range of lines.
Let us say suppose I want to print from third line to some tenth line.
So three comma ten p.
That's it.
Right?
So no, nothing like that.
You can also print from any number to any number.
Let me print some tend to tool no problem. 101112.
Right?
I want to print from, suppose,
let say any number you can take it.
But I want to print suppose from 13 line number two,
last line number, last means dollar, and that's it.
Right? So if you want to print one line,
then just simply use some particular number here.
Line number here, range, range of numbers.
If you want to print from Portland number two, last line number,
you can use dollar than print, right?
Otherwise I want to print a line from suppose,
let's say from line number two.
From there onwards, I want to print some seven lengths, ten plus seven.
Observed output, 12 plus 719 years you are getting.
So from Tool number 219,
line number you are getting because you are starting from 2L and frame from,
from that onwards you want to print seven more lines, right?
That's why we are getting up to 19.
Ok, so this is the simple way to print your required line numbers with your sed command.
Right?
Fine. There is just viewing your file content.
Not only that. See I want to print alternate numbers or otherwise.
Let me take simple example like I want to print,
suppose first number, I mean first-line number.
After that I want to print a suppose some fourth line number.
And then after that I want to print seven.
Then ten, then 13, right?
That means difference is three, right?
So if you want to print the line numbers in this way,
what is the difference, three, right?
C, Let me take very simple command you how?
Let line number one,
then home symbol, then 3p.
So already we have p. Let us now see the output 1471013.
So whatever the ranging between two lines,
that range you have to provide here so that you will get that required line numbers.
Suppose if I want to get alternate number,
alternate line number site,
you can provide 2pi so that what you will get,
you will get first-line, then third line,
then fifth line, then 79, right?
You are missing. I'm in second,
fourth, sixth, eighth, right?
So that's it.
So home symbol, right?
So there's, this is the way how you can see file content using your sed command.
Right?
Now are how one more concept here.
See if I print a simply hyphen in some print your file,
you're getting all your lines from your file.
Now instead of printing,
suppose I want to print like you know,
set are not print.
I want to remove but little lines.
Let's say in your entire file,
I don't want to print last line number while printing then just delimited
line number so that what will happen except to 49th line number,
you will get remaining all lines in the output.
See that you're getting up to 48, only.
Same as your previous sprint.
I mean, with the print,
whatever we did, no same thing we can delete also.
See set, right for Nellie denoted to use
iPhone Yan because you're deleting that line only for printing HUB use iPhone,
an option said, I want to delete the line numbers from four to last,
last, you know, write dollar means last.
So I want to delete from fourth line to lost number,
last line number that I can take
that Italy dollar so that you can identify that as a last line, right?
So from 42 last,
i don't want to print the remaining lines I want to print.
That's what you have to use.
You have to delete the remaining lines.
So for that option is b.
Now see that only you are getting 123 from four to 49.
You're removing way I'm saying 14,
Ms. inside my file, how fought in mine line numbers.
Suppose I want to delete from tenth align to, let's say 45.
Remaining lines. I want only during this range,
whatever the lines you how those length will delete.
See that up to nine you are getting,
because from ten to 45 you are removing,
then 46 to 49 you are getting right.
Only during this range you're deleting, right?
Not only like that, let,
let say suppose start from tenth line and from there onwards,
delete, suppose from 2A lines.
I mean, you can take any number just,
I'm taking two lines, right?
So plus 12 from tenth line just to delete tool more lengths.
C, the output. Then you are missing, right?
Then.
Between that you're missing two or more lines.
Now you are getting remaining lines.
That's it. Alright?
So as I will do one thing, I will,
I will do all these lines so that it will be helpful for you.
You can take any file content, okay?
I will paste this lines in
the description of this video just to go through that and you can,
it will helpful to practice.
And that's it.
So guys, if you're observing the output,
right, whatever that command,
deletion command we are using NMF print,
printing your printing your required line numbers.
Right?
Now my requirement is I'm removing some line numbers,
write in this way, I mean, with the d option.
But the original file content is not going to change.
After that. Your file content will be there as it is.
That means only while displaying, right?
Oil, only while displaying you are removing,
let say suppose some ten to last line number I am deleting, right?
And if you have another virtual file content,
it is not changing only while displaying.
You are deleting require line numbers,
and then you are printing the remaining lines with this sed command, right?
But my intention is what our the command I'm running now because of that,
you are getting output from one to nine.
So if I want to change the virginal file information,
that means I want to keep in my file only one to 999 line numbers.
And then I want to remove remaining all lines.
Instead of displaying in this one on your output in the original file itself,
I want to remove tend to last line.
So in that case simply you can use said hyphen IE,
inserting my Virgil file itself,
whatever the command you are performing, right?
So this is very important and very dangerous.
Right?
Said hyphen, I remove the line numbers from ten to last in my original file.
So before removing, Let me take a backup for this or copy something.
Right?
And now we have two lines.
Now see, first of all,
in your file you have this many number of lines.
Now what I am doing set hyphen IE
means instead of displaying your output on your terminal,
what I want to do is delete the files in the elite,
the lines in the file itself from ten to last.
Now if I enter, you won't get an output,
but whatever the modification you need,
that will be done on your original file itself so that you're not getting an output.
Now opening your file and see the content.
You only want to line, line,
line numbers, remaining lines or deleted.
So if you want to change the original file,
you are to include hyphen II option.
Not only here guys, wherever while going forward.
Also, if you do some command here, right.
If you don't include iPhone I option,
this command will perform on your file and it will
display the final output on your terminal itself.
We'd want to disturb original file.
But if you want to perform your command on your virginal file itself,
then you have to include iPhone I option here.
Right? Now, suppose because IE is danger, right?
See before going to perform your action on your original file,
if you want to take a backup.
Yes, you how backup optional.
So I found I dot back, not back.
Then.
Let me do one thing I want to delete,
except the first, second,
remaining all lines I want to delete in my virginal file.
Right?
Now see the output file.txt.
You have only 102 lines,
but already you created a backup because of these hyphenated dot back.
So it is very, very important guys.
See, you have your original lines 129.
Right?
Same thing. Let me do it on your own.
From 59 to last Lynn and tie lines I want to delete in my demo 2.txt.
Right now observe the output cat named 2.txt.
Yes, you have only 1.2.4 because from 59 to last line number I am deleting all the lines.
But for this, before performing your action on your file,
set has taken a backup file called demo 2.txt dot bag.
Now see the original content,
what it is there in your file.
You'll see how complete data in your back of fine, right?
So, so there's because hyphen I option is danger.
Ok.
So before performing any I mean,
any said iphone i option,
it better to take the asset,
the iPhone I dot back so that
the original file backup will be present in your required location.
Right?
So this is all about how to view the file content and outdoor delete
some file information in your original file with your sed command with Typhon eye option.
Right?
So said hyphen I is the very, very important one.
So this take the,
so this is just for your backup.
You can take any file.
So there is just to try to practice with your sed command just to view the file content.
Okay. While practicing, you can take any file.
Okay. Okay. Yes. Thank you for watching this video.