Friends.
Here our concept is working with variables.
C, variables plays an important role in any programming or scripting language.
Basically, variables are used to store data or a value.
Suppose I'm having a value or network called number two and I want to store that India
variable collects then how you can define or declared variable simply x equals to two.
So here, if I write x equals to two,
the meaning for that is we are assigning number two to a variable called X,
or we are storing that data to into a variable called x.
And while declaring in this way x equals to two,
please don't provide any space on either side of the equals symbol.
If you provide, then bashed doesn't allow that.
Let me show you that on your command line.
Suppose if i write x equals to two, then it's fine.
You are shell will accept that.
But if I write x space equal to two,
or x equals two space two,
or X space equals two,
space two, then these three or not a valid declarations
for variable simply you are right,
X equals to two without any spaces, that is the valid one.
That's fine.
So once if you define your variable,
then how you can display the value of your variable simply using a code Dalvik or echo.
Quotations with Dalvik.
Generally we will use,
I mean, in my case,
most of the cases I will use with quotations only.
Actually that is the best practice.
And in some cases,
you have to use to display
your variable value or to substitute u or a variable value somewhere in your expression.
You how to use curly braces off x.
But always you can use curly braces off x.
But in some cases you can skip that.
But in some cases your to use curly braces.
Right?
So we will see that when situation comes at
the time you can understand as of nodes simply,
we define x equals U2.
Now I want to display the value of x,
but I will use always with quotations.
That is the better practice and best practice.
And please do follow this one.
Sorry. Dollar x.
And of course you can also use curly braces, no problem.
That's it. Fine.
Now, not only number two,
you can also store some float point into a variable called y,
any variable you can take.
And you can take some string.
I mean, you can store some string India variable.
And whenever if your string is having a space at that time,
you how to use quotations for your data and to assign your data into your variable.
Basically, you can use quotations for all variables like x equals two in
quotations to why coastal quotations 5-6 m equals two in quotations shell.
But quotations are required for your data
whenever if your data is having a space. Otherwise in only two.
Use quotations for your data to
assign your data into your variable. Let me show you that.
Suppose I'm having a variable called Young and I am storing shell India variable young.
Then I can write m equals to shell.
That's fine.
And I can see that data off your m.
Yes, I'm getting.
But suppose I'm having a shell scripting as my data.
And if you observe that data is having some spaces,
at that time, you had to use quotations.
Otherwise it will do an adder.
Now see that if I use quotations, then it's fine.
Now see echo dollar p.
That's it.
Be clear.
Whenever, if your data is having some spaces,
then please follow quotations to assign your data to your variable.
And next thing, suppose if you want to assign command output India variable,
be clear, command or put into the variable.
See already we have seen how to store the command output India file, some demo 2.txt.
And if you see the content of demo 2.txt,
you're getting the list of files or directories which are there in
the current location because we'd redirected unless or put into your file.
And whenever if you redirect or whenever if you create
a file that will store in your hard disk on your file system.
But the variables are not storing on your file systems or on your hard disk.
They are storing while executing your core or while running your terminal.
The data we store in your RAM memory.
Be clear. Fine.
Now my requirement is if I run any command,
this command output I want to store in the variable,
be clear, not into your file.
If it is India file, you can use redirection symbol greater than symbol.
Now I'm digging.
Suppose D date variable equals two,
the other parenthesis date.
That's it.
Now see the data newer D data output.
So this is the command it is executing,
and that result is storing into a variable called d.
That's right, fine.
And finally, whenever if you're declaring a variable at the time,
you need to mention what type of data you are storing in t a variable,
say suppose if you go with C,
And in C language, suppose if you are assigning x equals to two,
then before assigning you,
hard to say that in dx means I'm storing number to India variable called x,
that to integer number I'm storing in PAX.
But in shell scripting, you no need to declare any datatype.
And default data or value of a variable is an empty.
Suppose I am defining,
sorry, I, I'm displaying dollar x.
Just know we defined the Ulrike.
I'm index value. That's a reason we are getting x value.
Modify, write.
Suppose dollar.
Yea, nowhere we define year variable value.
And if I try to display that,
we are getting an empty, that means.
Default variable value.
If you don't assign any value to a variable,
then the variable value is always an EMT.
And see that nowhere we define this variable, user variable.
But if I tried to display that you are getting some data.
Just now I told that default data or value of a variable is an empty.
And we proved that with the variable called yay.
But if I do this one,
you are getting output as automation.
Nowhere we defend this variable,
then how it is giving the reason he's basically Unix world,
there are two types of variables.
They are system defined variables and user-defined variables.
User-defined variables means, just now we define something like x,
y, yum, p, something like that right there.
I mean the variables which are defined by us.
But system defined variables are nothing but fasting.
Let me show you what are the system defined variable.
To know system defined variable,
you can run a command called ENV on your command line and see the result.
So these all are system defined variables.
So once if you open a terminal,
by default, your system will create some variable.
Some variables, those are nothing but system defined variables.
Suppose, if I display Dollar,
you're not getting an output because not envy is not
a system defined variable are nowhere we defined that variable.
But if I display user or suppose UID,
then you are getting some value.
Let me run home.
So because these are system defined variable,
other than that variables,
if we select any other variable name which is not defined,
then you will get an empty value.
Be clear on that.
So at anytime if you want to see the system defined variables simply you run,
you can run ENV variable.
That's fine.
Now, the last concept is rules to define your variable names.
Suppose as of now we have taken variable names as x,
y, sum p, some yum, something like that, right?
But before going to select a variable names,
you have to follow some rules.
They are, the very first one is the name of a variable can only contain alphabets,
may be clipped, capital or small,
and numbers 0 to nine.
And then underscore.
Other than these three group combinations,
don't take any other variable.
You have to take always.
You are variable name from this. Characters.
Maybe alphabets or numbers,
or maybe underscore, maybe combinational.
So, but don't start with a letter.
Don't start with a number.
Suppose. So what I'm saying is,
I can write y equals to three,
but don't write one-way equals to three.
I mean, any number are Y1 you can define.
So simply, your variable names can only start with a letter or underscore.
Please don't start with a number.
That that is the rule.
Then finally, don't include a space in a variable name.
Suppose I want to define a variable called my name.
Then generally I can write my name Eco.
Suppose Narendra.
Then it is not allowed because I have given a space.
But wherever space is there,
that space you can replace with underscore because underscore is alone, No.
And that's where you can take underscore.
That's, you know, I can display my name, right?
So guys, while taking your variable name,
your variable names should contain only alphabets
or numbers and underscore and don't start it,
start your variable name with a width in number.
But you can start with underscore or you are alphabets, maybe capitalist model.
And don't include any space in your variable name.
And one more thing, variables or case sends to.
Suppose if I write x equals some number and capital X equals to some other number,
then there are different echoed.
The RX is different.
Echo dollar capital X is different.
That's fine.
Now let me take a very simple script, variables dot SH.
So I know that on my host, the shebang line,
I'm in my shell line is,
my shell location is this one.
Now let me define some variables.
I am defining suppose x equals some 56,
Y equals to some 78 dot mine.
Then let me take my name.
I'm taking shell scripting.
So that's why I'm using quotations for your string,
because a string is having some space.
That's the reason I am assigning this output with quotations for my variable.
And if you observe here,
your variable name may have any number of letters.
But the condition is it should have only alphabets underscore.
And of course I am not taking a variable name including a number you can take.
Suppose I am taking x to x two equals to m Dickinson seven, that's it.
Now I am displaying the values echo.
Echo, dollar, x2.
Echo dollar, my name equal.
Yeah, even having one more variable called y, right?
Let me define that here.
Echo dollar wine.
But she, let me save this and let me provide the execution permissions for this.
And see the code first.
Now let me run that and see the result.
I misread the quotations here.
I started the, I mean,
echo quotations, my variable name,
then I misheard to close that quotations.
Thats the reason you are getting an error.
Let me open.
Now let me run that and see the result.
It's working perfectly.
And one more thing, you know that whenever if you run your shell script,
it will run from top to down,
one-by-one, line by line.
The first-line always.
It will tell it to your operating system.
That is, please use this shell to
execute the remaining lines which are there in your shell script.
Fine.
So the very first line,
because of this, we are assigning in data to you.
There is no output from this,
just simply assigning a data,
even here also we are assigning here also we are assigning some data
to variable here also we are assigning here empty line.
You can include any number of empty lines in your shell script. There is no problem.
Fine.
Now here I'm displaying the value of x with dollar,
same VM falling for remaining variables.
C engine of directly displaying your variable data,
data of your variable.
You can also write some message.
Suppose I want to display like x equals two,
then y equals two, Rx2 equals two.
Be clear.
Without a dollar, it wont to display the value it will display as it is.
Now let me save this and see the core first.
Now let me run that and see the out up the load.
Put x equals to 56 you are getting
because generally echo command will display the message.
Yes, x equals two message.
But dollar x is a variable value network in place of delta x,
you are getting a value like waves for remaining variables.
That's it.
Okay?
Okay, thank you.
If you have any queries, please post your query.