Hi friends. In this video,
we are going to discuss the next functionality of your set command functionality or
the next operation of your set command that is
searching content with sed command from your file.
C. We know that we can do
different operations with your set command
or the different functionalities of your set command.
Or like you know, we will file content,
searching, Find, and Replace, insertion or deletion.
And we can also use some regular expression in your set command.
So already in our previous video,
we have seen viewing file content with your set command.
Now we are going to work with searching.
So what is searching?
So you just assume that you have some number of lines in your file.
And you want to print the lines which are having your required word,
or you want to delete the lines which are having your required work.
Right?
So for that purpose,
how you can use your set command, right?
Let me open my terminal.
See you the basic syntax of your sed command,
right, said with options, then quotations.
That quotation is maybe single quotations or double quotations.
Guys. Say, suppose I want to print the lines from three to six.
So already we know that how to use that from our previous video.
You can also use double quotations,
but there is a small difference between double quotation, single condition.
We are going to see that in this video.
Right?
So here you are printing the line numbers information
or you are printing the content of your file based on your required line numbers.
But now I want to print the lines which are having you are required word
or I want to delete the lines which are having your required word. Let me do it.
Suppose I want to print the lines which are having a covert,
which are having a coin.
So to print the ADA, use p whenever if you are using P,
you have to use iPhone Yan'an option also.
Why? Because already we know that by
default said we'll display the information from your file.
Now with the pre, you are going to print one more time.
You are information, duplicate information you are getting to suppress that.
You had to use hyphen yen, right?
So echo a p, then you are fine.
Now you are going to get the lines which are having echo word. See that.
Not only that you can also search for,
suppose I have a need to print the,
the lines which are having a bin.
Or I wanted to print the lines which are having some, if.
That's it.
So guys, remember that you can also use double quotations.
No problem. Let me do that.
Right? So you are getting same information whenever,
if you use even double quotations also.
Now my requirement is I want to print the lines which are having
either a CO or which are having some, let's say bin.
So I want to print the lines which are having Either bin or Jaco or one more role also,
you can take it, right?
Whenever if you want to search with multiple words in this way,
you ought to use hierophany extra option to execute multiple commands on your file.
See that you are getting the lines which are having Either bin or echo.
Not only that, it can execute one more command, hyphen e. Then.
See that wherever you are having IV or echo,
or when you are printing those lines.
Right? Fine.
Now, let me do one thing.
Echo hyphenation.
So let me take simply again once again ECO P. Then he were file.txt.
Right?
What happened? Sorry. Not like oh, I have an n, right?
It's the sed command.
Right? Fine.
Now guys, what I'm doing is sometimes while writing your shell scripts, right?
What it will do is based on required what unit two such that what you are,
maybe you're going to read from command line.
So let say some variable in that variable,
let say you have a CFO,
or let's say such word,
it goes to simply, I'm taking echo.
Now inside of your search what you may have anything.
But based on that variable I had two such than simply said, hyphen yen.
First, let me go with single quotation.
So guys, I need to substitute the variable value.
And I notice such it. See the output.
You are not getting anything because whenever if you're single quotation, it won't work.
I made one sub shoot your variable value.
Instead of that, it will look exactly dollar SEN Moscow W word.
But you're going to have this type of war inside of this file.
But our intention is a value which is there
inside of this variable that we do that what you need to such it.
So whenever if you want to substitute a variable inside of your set command,
you how to use double quotations.
Now see that, right?
So this is the difference between
single quotation and double quotation with your set command.
Like, fine.
Now, what I'm doing is so there is,
you know, how to delete a lines.
Suppose I want the lid from one to two, right?
So you can do in this way.
So guys, you are not,
I mean, deleting material file content, right?
Let me do one more thing.
Let's say I want to delete from ten to nine to last line.
Right?
This is the remaining information.
Now guys, if I place instead of D experimentally D, then reverse action.
That means the lines which are other than this range will delete c that right,
one to nine, it is deleting.
The remaining lines are not deleting.
That is the on elementary D option, right?
We forget to discuss this in our previous video.
Right?
Now, my requirement is I want to delete the lines which are having,
suppose echo word right in your file.
Yes, they mining lines your getting right. Fine.
Now what I want to do is I want to delete the lines which are not having a code.
Be clear.
I wanted to delete the lines which are not having echo.
So basing your realtime instead of p option D option is more useful.
And most of the cases you are not going to use p option.
You should have that you are going to use a D option.
Now my requirement is I want to delete the lines which are not having a CO.
That means if I stride forward,
if I use d, what will happen?
It will delete the lines which are having echo.
I mean, whatever the searching what you are using right?
Now, instead of that,
if I make excellent mentally D, then what will happen?
It will delete the lines which are not having a coat.
And if I want to delete the lines which are not
having echo permanently newer virginal file.
What I have to do, I have to include iPhone I option.
Right?
So iPhone I I go no,
r d then your file.
So you know that iPhone I0 is dangerous, right?
Because you are going to modify source file.
So before going to modify it,
if you want to take a backup,
you can also use the iPhone I dot back.
Now see the output, right?
C.
So let us to file file.txt and observed that in that what you
how you how the lines which are having a co right.
And see the original file, I'm in backup file.
It is original file itself.
Okay, so guys here, very,
very important thing is this one.
Excellent Battery D and it is very useful in your real time.
So you are going to delete the lines which are not having your required word.
Right? And guys, here as of now,
I am using only one word if you want to use multiple words,
actually, it is a better or to use regular expressions, right?
So while going forward,
we will see that or not in this video.
In later videos we will see how to delete or how to use multiple words while
searching your words in a given file with your set command, right?
Okay. Thank you for watching this video.