Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to discuss the next operation or function of
your set command that is simply insertion and deletion with sed command.
That means just agenda.
You have one file in that file,
if you want to add or insert a new line,
or if you want to lead some existing line,
how you can perform with your set command.
Right?
So there is from our previous video site already we have seen
this concepts like viewing file content with your sed commands such fine and replace.
Now we are going to work with insertion or deletion with your set command.
And next we will see the important thing that is
sed command with some regular expressions, right?
That is actually very useful case in your real time.
But before entering into sed command with the regular expressions,
you should be good with these all operations.
So already we have seen first three.
Now we are going to work with insertion or deletion, right?
Fine.
See, from our previous videos already we know the syntax of your sed command, right?
Set some options, then commands,
then the file which you want to work with your sed command.
So here, whenever, if you want to work like insertion or deletion with your set command,
you need to remember these flags under your commands.
They are like I hear a and b.
So i and j modes are used to
insert a new line in the existing file with your set command.
And D is used to delete some line from your existing file.
But here i is nothing but inserting a new line before Butler line number.
Yea, it insert some new line right after put level line number.
Right? So further you are going to use IND,
so before line, after line,
then d. So you have to remember these three flags if you want to
work with the word insertion and deletion with your set command.
So insert your sergeant that you have your file right?
So agenda the awesome lines.
So insertion means whether you want to
insert just a generous about this is line number two.
Now you want to insert a before this line or after this line,
or maybe any line number before this line or after that line.
So before if you want to insert you how to use IE,
after if you under insert you how to use Yay.
And anyway, delete and there is only one option D, right?
Fine.
And now let me go with one by one, right?
So inserting new line.
So I want to insert some new line or
some new information in your file with your sed command,
then C, That said line number,
whatever the line number you need.
Then option I, then filename.
So guys, this IE is different from options I.
So in options if you use IE, right, hyphen IE,
that because of that you are going to modify the original file content.
Right?
Let me show you on your command line.
Suppose first let me take some symbol data called employee Info.plist file.
Okay?
Now guys, suppose this is one,
some file which consists of some embolize information.
Now in this file,
I want to add some header.
So header is nothing but unit to insert before this length,
right before first linear to insert that,
then that will become a header.
So what I can do is set, right?
So before first-line, So one is nothing but line number.
So before that line number,
I want to insert a header.
That way you have to use I,
I means before that line number.
So what do you want to insert that you have to write here?
Suppose I want to insert like serial number,
then name, then suppose salary.
Then in your file for c, the output, right,
you're able to insert the word line before a particular line number that is called one.
And because of the sed command,
you are able to write your information only while
displaying if you want to modify your original file content.
See as of now, if you see your file,
what Jill file is not affecting only while displaying the output on your terminal.
You are able to add your header.
But this information I want to add permanently
in my existing file called employee in 2.txt.
Then what I have to do simply use hyphen option.
So said hyphen, I.
Now see the file content.
Yes, you inserted a line called this one before first line number.
Now, suppose after this line,
first-line, Now this is first-line right off that, this first line.
Suppose I want to insert some something like anything.
Let me take some said hyphen I
off the lane number 11 year and just I mean, inserting these hyphens.
Right now. See that after this,
you are inserting this hyphens.
So offer first-line of their first-line.
This is line number one.
After that, you are inserting this data the same way as if nobody the last length.
So but this is the last line.
So in your set command,
you can identify by default the last line with the help of dollar.
Right?
Now, off the last line,
I want to insert again these hyphens.
Then what you can do simply see that instead of one and the existing line,
last line is this one.
Right? Now see the content.
That's it. Alright.
So using i and j inserted before inset of the particular line number.
Now not only like that,
you can also insert a new line before a particular word.
I mean, suppose I want to insert a new line before this Narendra up.
What I want to insert a new line,
suppose after this clinton, Right?
So then I can do in this way said hyphen I0.
So you know how to such a line right out
to search the lines which are having Butler word.
So we have seen that while searching with your set command.
Suppose I want to insert after this,
after Narendra, or let me take before that before Narendra,
wherever you how Narendra before that line.
I want to insert a new line. Let me do that.
So I'm taking something like That's it.
Right.
Now. See the file content.
Just know you inserted before Narendra some name called monica.
Right?
Now, same way. Suppose I want to insert offer Clinton.
I want to insert some new data.
Then said hyphen, I suppose after Clinton.
So wherever you helped Clinton line after that line.
Right?
I want to insert,
after, I want to insert,
let's say suppose some, some data.
I mislead one quotation.
Now see the content. What do help?
Yes, you insert a new data after Butler,
a lane which consist of Clinton, right?
So this is the way how you can insert based on
line number before that line number or offer that line number by using I and II,
or based on the lines which are having some particular word, right?
And that too before that word or offer that word,
before that word, and here after that word.
Right?
Now the last one is how to delete a line.
See that suppose you have this information.
Now, I want to delete a particular line number.
Let's say this is first-line, right?
Second line, third line, I want to delete.
So simply said.
So fundamentally I want to do it.
That's why I'm including iPhone.
I, I want to delete third line.
That's it.
Now see the file content. You have been deleted.
Third line, right? Not only that,
I want to delete a lane which consists of suppose some anneal.
Then first such with Annie.
That line, you just delete it.
Now, see that? Right?
So there is a simple way to insert a line before Butler thing or offer Butler thing.
And then a delete a link based on
your required line number or based on the lines which are having you are required word.
Right.
Okay, guys. Thank you for watching this video.