Prince, We have seen some of the special characters to create a pattern.
An already we use that pattern in order let expressions for your set command, right?
If you go through loss of two videos,
you will come to know some other special characters to create your patterns.
Now here we are going to see some more special characters to create your patterns.
And we're also going to see how to use
those patrons in your regular expression solves sed command, right?
So we are going to see these three special characters,
square brackets, curly braces, and then parenthesis.
Let me go with one by one.
The very first one is square brackets.
So guys, these are used to a,
matches any single character in a list.
That means just assume that first of all,
you how some list.
And in that you are going to mention some letters, some characters.
Let's say I'm going to represent a IOU, anything.
Right?
Now, if you use this pattern,
now your study is going to look to match either or either either o, right?
Or either o or r then r, u.
So it is going to take anyone of that, right?
It is trying to match for at least anyone of
the character in a given line or in a given text file.
Let me explain this with an example from my command line.
So we have a file called this one.
Now, initially, I am trying to look I am trying to print
the lines which are having put word from your file.
Yes, I'm getting now my requirement is if you are doing here guys,
you hose put port somewhere, PYT.
Right?
Now, I want to write a pattern such that,
that pattern has to match for either port or part or PYT.
First of all, after these three words,
starting and ending characters are same that way.
Just write P, then some space here we need to fill it, then T.
So what is the required letter or character to match for first 1,
second, 1, third, 1 y.
So any one of that for first 1,
second, 1, third, 1 way.
That's why you had to write a list which consists
of you will not need to follow any order. You can right away.
You also, right now the meaningful this is,
it is going to represent very first what is P from this list,
you will take one character and then t. So first one is,
BUT then again, second it will try to consider P war t,
then it is going to match for this also.
Then p y t d is also going to look for PYT.
Now this pattern is going to represent three words.
So in this way you have to use your square brackets.
Now let me try to use that.
Here in shut off PUT what I'm doing is between p and p,
I may how either you or walk our way nano to follow any order.
You can also write simply YOU also,
because between P and T characters,
I may, how wide our whoa, are you?
Now I want to print the lines which are having
PYT POD ON PUB of the output. We are getting No.
So here PUT POD, PYT, POD, PUT.
Now this is represented in multiple worlds.
This pattern is going to represent three words, right?
So based on that, you are getting the lines.
Not only this C,
i can also write a range of values engine off writing where you are.
You suppose I want to match the words which are either PAT are PBT,
RPC, t. I mean,
let's say first right, sequence.
Suppose I want to match for these words PAD PBD,
or let's say specie di PDD ET EF T.
Let me write something. Pgd, PIT,
or finally, now starting and ending characters are same.
And if you have done a middle, characters,
that range of characters in sequence right here to, I,
orient to vote, right?
So in that case, what I can do is I can write like yay, up to woo.
So not the character between P and T.
Maybe a, maybe be, maybe C.
Likewise out to war.
Now see the output o you are getting.
You are getting either p or PHP,
or yeah, both two only,
because only for them only you have a matching here.
Right?
Fine.
So that is a simple way to use your square brackets.
Not only that guys,
I can write one more thing.
Suppose instead of you are sequence.
Let me write words like this.
So how suppose P8,
I need PAT, PBT matching, PCT matching.
And then after that I
need then I need some,
sorry, it is not a sequence here right?
Under them I need suppose.
So for this set of words,
I need to write a matching word.
I need to write a pattern.
Then first thing starting and ending is same.
Now if you observe for foster three,
there is a sequence a, b, c, not.
So you can write yea 2i or hedge to i or the m2,
q or X to Z.
Now this is the pattern.
It is going to match all these words.
Let me write it this on your command line.
And let me run this and see the output.
That's it. Right?
So that is the uses of your square brackets.
No, the next one is,
let me go with your next one.
Curly braces matches for required number of repetitions.
So first thing is, curly braces are generally we are using to display or variable value.
Now whenever if you are going to use with
your normal set commander let expressions you have to write for your curly braces,
slashes before curly brace on it for these curly brace.
Then between jihad, right?
You weren't required number of repetitions.
I mean, Let's say,
I'm going to write suppose a go high.
Right?
Now I'm using sed command on this, in this way.
So if in that line,
if I have a high,
then I want to put into that line.
Yes, you are getting now let's say I have only one.
Hi. I mean, I know I want to look for there is no match right?
Now. Let me write your file once again.
Yeah, here it is better I can use this.
This, this, yeah. No, actually,
my requirement is printed the lines which are having yes.
So three times or more than that.
If there is a match for three times Orpheus.
Right?
Now, see, I am going to right side combined on this.
Let me write it.
Said printed the lines which are having this but yes.
Is three times.
Three times, yes.
If then only printed that lines,
otherwise don't print the line.
See that? The lines which are having three times yes,
those lines only you are getting.
Right?
If you want to get exactly only for three times obvious, right?
Then what you have to do after yes,
you have some space, you know how to represent the space backslash.
Now see that we are getting only the line which are having is three times this.
Ok?
No, I am writing either three times or maybe four times.
Three times, 44 times.
See that?
More than three times?
Maybe three times or four times or five times,
or maybe infinite number of times.
I see that.
So if you write only three, right?
Three times, yes, matching three comma 43 to four,
maybe three times or four times.
Right.
So I guess I'm I'm looking for a word not in a something.
Suppose if you observe somewhere here this offer that you're having one more extra.
Yes.
But I am looking for exact matching.
Only this an S3 times the 5x after yes,
you should have a space not to represent that space.
I'm using here a slash b.
Three comma means maybe three times or maybe four times, yes.
Or fight anxious like that.
So only for this yes,
you are applying this.
So that is the uses of your curly brace.
Now last one is parenthesis.
Actually this is a group matching.
This will search for Juno or more war, whole sequence.
Right?
Let me explain this here.
So is there any required thing in this? Let me check it.
Or yeah, I will write one more thing.
Okay, so this, this line and this line.
So in this line,
house somewhere ASD on in this lane,
you how he is df is the ASD right.
Now.
First of all, I'm writing something already.
We know this.
What is that means? I want to look I want to
print out the lines which are having yay yes, vf work.
So now you're going to get to do those two lines.
So yeah, yeah, I'll show you how he HDF is,
df is the, is the,
the lines which are having ASD F dot lines you are getting right
now my requirement is I should have EA S D of the entire world,
at least to two times entire world.
Suppose guys, you know, what is the meaning of my writing?
So you are looking UASB EF yay. Yes.
Def buddy f is two times.
But my requirement is I want to look for AAS BF,
and then immediately ASD,
same pattern should be repeat.
So at that time what you have to do is you want to group your required
a patron so that you can do with the help of parentheses,
but for this parenthesis also,
how to use slash symbol.
Now see the output. You are printing the lines which are having yay SDF two times.
So at least two times is satisfying.
That's why you are getting right.
Let me write one more line in this file itself.
So below this line,
I am writing the ASD F AS BF monotonous or I'm writing something.
Now, I'm trying to look.
Yes, in these two lines,
you how VA is d of two times.
That's why you are getting what I want to print to the lines which are
having the AAAS DFE entire word three times.
Now getting only one line because in second lane you don't know is DEF three times.
That's why you're not getting that line.
So to match, to repeat your entire require patron for your required number of times,
then you ought to go and use a SDF.
Right?
Now guys, I want to print the lines which are having ASD of at least one time.
So you know how good our present at least one time plus symbol.
So one time or more than one time. Now see the output.
You are getting, the lines which are having is the
if at least one time or more than that.
Now, I want to print the lines which are having ASD as a word,
as a word, right?
So before that you should have a space right?
Before sequence, you have space.
Now see the output, what you are getting.
You are not getting this word because a is df is the part of this word.
So before ASD, if you don't have any space,
that is why this is not a separate word.
You are not getting this line and you are not getting this line.
So that is the use of backslash b.
So here we combined backslash B with your grouping and also your curly braces, right?
So guys, these the way how to use your special characters like square brackets,
curly braces, and parentheses.
So here parentheses is very, very important dice.
Okay, to match your entire group for repeated number of times,
you how to group your pattern with the help of
parenthesis and while using parentheses and square brackets,
because, you know, you are going to use square brackets while,
while displaying your variables.
Right?
And to define, while defining functions,
function block you are taking as a curly braces, right?
Or while defining function name or function name,
you are taking parenthesis.
And that's why whenever if you're using a normal set command,
you how to use slash for this either curly braces or for your parenthesis,
but not for square brackets.
Remember this point in your set command.
Okay?
So guys, in the next video,
we are going to use this set command usage,
right, to grip some information.
Yet, I will update that in next video.
Okay. Yes.
Thank you for watching this video.