We'll them practice with your shell scripting and friends.
In this video, we are going to see one inventory script using your shell script.
That is automate server inventory using shell script.
So how to automate server inventory using shell script?
So what is this inventory guys first see inventories,
nothing but suppose if you want to collect some hardware information of your system,
some software information of your system,
or combination of your software and hardware information of your system, right?
So he fought this software and hardware information.
You have different types of parameters, right?
Just to finding all those parameters, that's it.
Manually, you can run command for each and every parameter and you can find out.
But you should have that.
Right, just right one shell script.
Whenever if you want to find all these parameter,
just run them shell script so that you will get all the values,
required values for your case, right?
So that is nothing but simply inventory.
Suppose I am going to take here a simple example as suppose I need server name, right?
I need IP address of that server.
And what is the waste type of that server?
And what is the uptime of that?
Not only this, just observe that suppose you install some Java on your host,
then what is the Java watching you having?
And what is the location of the Java, right?
So I can also add some parameters like Java version, right?
Suppose you've held some web server.
What is the web server type you are having?
And what is the web server version you are having?
You may have multiple web servers.
Men for all that you need to collect.
Suppose you have some middleware application,
let's say Tomcat, or some web logic.
Right?
So finding all those values are nothing but simply some inventory.
So this inventory, instead of finding
this all values one by one with the help of commands on your command line.
We would let one shelf skip.
And whenever if we required all these values,
what we will do some tubulin shall skip and we'll get the information.
And after getting your information,
I want to export that data that result into CSV file as well,
so that I can share that CSV file with some complaints team.
Right?
So generating your result into result into csv file is very,
very important in your real time.
And guys who just are not,
you are maintaining, suppose some hundreds of servers.
Now I need to find some information,
some parameters of all a 100 servers.
And I want to store all the hundreds ours information into one single CSV file, right?
That is nothing but automate
servers inventory using your shell script, multiple servers inventory.
So for time being, we are going to work with single server
while going forward will work with multiple servers.
Because before going to implement your inventory for multiple servers,
you need to know how to connect with your remote server and
executing commands on the remote server from local server, right?
So all those things we have to know,
that's why first I'm going to implement your inventory on single server.
Then we'll discuss some concepts related with your remote servers from local server.
Then again, we will implement complete.
Discovery or server inventory using your shell script.
So for time being, I am going to walk with single server.
And that to what I'm saying is,
after finding all these values,
I want to store these values into some CSV file.
Let me take suppose if this inventories for multiple servers anyway,
most of the cases you will take inventory for multiples or what's on the right.
Then I want to mention some serial number in my CSV.
Then I want to write server name.
Right?
Then I wanted to find IP address of each server.
Then what is the waste type of server?
Is it a unique Simon Linux REX,
right, then what is the uptime?
So all these values I want to store into CSV.
And once if I have a CSP than I can share that with,
suppose some complaints stream, right?
Or whoever it's, the data is require for them I can share.
Right now I am going to implement simple shell script.
Let me implement that.
Inventory of officer what?
Suppose inventory not s. Let me take simply a ENV and Kiva, right?
They can take any name that's frowned upon.
But me, right? Bin bash.
Right?
So very first thing what you have to find server name, right?
That's why I'm doing simply server name as this value, I mean variable.
So that is you have some command to find out your server name.
That is you name hyphen yen,
so that you'll get your server name.
And that is a command, that command output.
I'm going to store it to this variable.
Right?
Then I need to find out IP address.
So let me run this command if conflict.
See if you have done here, this is your IP address right?
Now what I am doing is if convict biplane grip with this keyword,
I am finding that line.
And in this I need first-line.
And in first-line I need suppose a second column.
That's why I'm taking a WK command.
It is very easy to manipulate on rows and columns with your AWPA command.
That's why I'm taking this command on the output of your ifconfig grip, some value.
Right?
Now this command output I want to store into one variable.
That variable is nothing but your IP address.
So here's here, I'm going to implement your inventory with very less parameters,
much in real-time you how lot of parameters you need to find on each and every server.
Right? Then waves type I want to find.
Let me take this as a variable.
You can take any variable, just I'm taking them.
Okay?
So one way is to simply you name. I can dig right?
So if you don't you name simply what will get you name is done.
I mean, now I want suppose up time.
So this wayfinding your uptime, you had to take cap.
What is that means?
Suppose if you run uptime as I've no,
I'm running my uptime command here.
So you are getting your obtained in terms of minutes.
I'm in one hour, five minutes, right?
So you may have in terms of Howard's,
now in terms of minutes,
human tau in terms of days, right?
So based on three criteria,
has unit implemented command for your uptime in case if you have minutes,
how to grip your data.
So here, one hour for five minutes, right?
I can do simply, in my case,
I can take simply print first column, second column third.
That's it.
Right?
So whenever six minutes I can take.
But sometimes, you know, you may have some number of days.
If tau in terms of days,
you need to take one more field here.
So fossil find out uptime in that tried to grip weather days, is there or not?
If does, is they just do one more command.
So as of now, suppose I'm
implementing this only for hover in case if you have obtained in terms of Howard.
So anyway, while implementing full discovery for multiple servers at that time,
I will write completely.
You are command in terms of days,
in terms of minutes, in terms of flowers.
So by default, whatever the code I've written here,
it will work perfectly.
Only engaged if your pen in terms of hours,
if you have in terms of only minutes or in if you are in terms of days,
then this command will not work for your server.
Iterate some if-else condition and they're going to write some logic.
So we'll implement that logic while working with
your complete discovery are complete inventory for multiple servers.
That's it.
So now we implemented all these parameters.
Now I want to store all these values into CSV file.
So before going to store the result into CSV file,
you should have some header for your CSV.
That's why I'm taking this as my header, right?
So for your understanding, just I am writing creating heading CSV.
So the energy is nothing but this is my header in my CSV file, right?
So server info, I'm writing dot CSV, that's it.
Now I need to store the result of all these values one-by-one to CSV guys,
because of this line, you are just creating header.
So if you know you, if you observe your CSV file, right?
If you open your CSV file,
how it would be, right?
Let me open my yeah.
If you open your CSV file with your excel sheet right there
having rows and columns, right?
So this is first thing,
first row is nothing but a header.
Now from here onwards you light serial number
and then for each server annexed information,
you will write that way.
First, I created this header with this line.
Now I want to stores server one information.
So I'm, that's why I'm taking anyway,
we are going to work with only single server.
That's a deadline taking one.
But whenever you are working with multiple servers in it, right?
And logic such that automatically it has to write the serial number 1234 like that.
Right?
Then, anyway, already this is our variable.
Let me store that result.
Then.
You how your IP address.
Then you, how you are ways type.
Then you how your uptime.
Then this result next year you'd into take w greater than if it takes angle greater than,
your previous information will be deleted.
So I am taking here first-time,
I'm creating this file that I am taking greater than buddy or you
need to take to get redirection, right?
That's it.
Now let me save this and just run this.
Maybe somewhere we have mistake.
Let me cross check that.
I bear does yeah, we misread that.
Symbol. Ipr does equals $2 if config, that's equitable.
Now let me run this.
It has been done.
Now if you have the LS siphon Aladdin,
the last two file server info dot csv.
Just now it has been created, right?
Just absorb the information in that SI serial number,
server name, IP address, right?
Os type.
And then your uptime. Now, if you export this into,
Suppose you are windows or anywhere.
And if you open that with your XL seat
automatically or data will be rearranged in terms of rows and columns.
So that is the advantage by creating your CSV file.
So in real-time, right?
Whenever, if you want to get some inventory data,
always we will create in this way.
I mean, the final result you are always going to store into,
into your CSV file.
And once you have a CSV, CSV file,
then you can send it to mail or you can share with some team.
Or it can also download some to somewhere.
Right?
So that's why guys, while working server inventory,
right, make sure that always the final result data you are going to store into CSV file.
That is a good practice in your real time.
Right?
And guess well, going forward,
we will go with how to work with multiple servers.
I mean, how to work with remote servers from local server,
and how to get complete inventory for all servers at a time from your local server.
We will see that inventory skipped well, going forward.
Okay. Yes. Thank you for watching this video.