Friends here, our concepts or how to execute a shell script from
another shell script and how to access variables which are defined in another file.
Let me explain them one by one.
So before that, let me do my requirement actually on my host I how HTTPD and Tomcat.
Now how to create to shell script for HTTPD and two shell script for Tomcat.
There.
Just to start and stop HTTPD on Tomcat.
Anyway, by default, you are having some commands on your host for service,
I mean hatchery buddies or recent Tomcat service.
But I want to create my own commands by using them.
I mean, I want to write my own shell script to start HTTPD and to stop HTTPD.
Same before Tomcat.
Let me take the names to start HTTPD and to stop HUD BD.
The same way, suppose I want to take shell script
as start on your data's H and then stop.
Tomcat dot SH.
Fine.
Now first let me do the commands.
Suppose here my HTTPD first,
let me take status for that.
Anybody is not running. Now I want to start that through commands first.
Simply, I can then start.
But whenever if you are running any commands with the system CTL,
then you should be the root or you should have a root privileges.
Anyway, for my user, I'm having root privileges, that's fine.
And friends here I'm using systems UDL because my Lennox is on HL7.
If you're Linux is less than seven,
then use service command.
Now simply I'm using pseudo system CTLs start HTTPD, done.
Now find the status for status, you don't need to apply.
Pseudo. Yes, it is running the same way.
I want to stop it, then simply stop.
Then find the status.
Find they're working right now let me take these two commands and let me
create a script for your start HTTPD onStop HTTPD.
Now, I will write scripts here itself.
So pause, yeah, very first an issue bank length.
So anyway on my host,
I how my bash in this location.
Then, just to start you on HTTPD,
we are using pseudo system CTL.
Start HTTPD.
That's it.
Now, same way for stop.
User bin bash, sudo system,
CTN, stop HTTP, that's it.
Now we're done our own commands to start and stop HTTPD.
Now, let me create these scripts on my host.
And we'll verify that. So here I am writing.
So let me create a directory.
So I'm creating my working directory.
Then let me move into that. Sorry.
Now here I'm creating start HTTPD dot SH.
So simply Fine.
Now let me write, stop HUD pd dot SH,
and let me paste.
And here it is stopped.
Fine.
Now let me provide the execution permissions for these two files.
Now see that we have an exclusion permission for these two files.
Now instead of system CDL,
because already I used them in my scripts.
Let me know the status of a treaty body.
Now, I'm using HTTP dot SH.
Now find the status.
Yes, it's running.
Now let me run stop script.
Now see the status.
So our shell scripts are working.
That's fine.
The same way we have to create shelters for Tomcat as well.
Now, before going to do that,
let me navigate into my Tomcat.
So here, underpinned location,
I have a command called Startup dot SH.
And if I run that, your Tomcat will starts.
Now, see that PSI funny of pipeline grip Tomcat. Now it's running.
Suppose if I want to stop it,
shadow not SH, that's it.
Now if you find your status,
see that no longer does not running.
And be clear. Our commands are there in this location.
What is the location? In this location,
we have our commands.
Now, if you want to run your start-up dot SH,
unsettled dot SH, in this location you are running dot slash.
But if you want to run from any other location,
we know that we have to provide complete path.
Now let me take complete path here.
Now.
Let me write first, Charleston taught you what Tomcat.
First thing, our shebang line,
that is, if I'm your host,
you, you'll how your bashed in bin location directly connect slash bin bash.
So I'm writing user bin bash.
Then to start your Tomcat,
you have to provide complete path for startup dot SH.
Let me copy this.
Same way. We have to write a shell script to stop Tomcat.
But here to stop commodities shouldn't not.
Sh, fine.
Now let me clear these two scripts as well on our local host,
I mean on our working directory.
So our working directory.
So here we are creating start Tomcat dot SH.
So simply based on what syntax.
Same way. Stop Tomcat dot SH.
Now let me copy this thing.
Fine.
Now anyway, they will work.
Let me try with that.
First time, you have to provide execution permissions, right?
So I'm providing for all files exclusion permissions.
Fine.
Now let me run,
start Tomcat dot SH and see the result.
Psi.
If an EF by pen grip Tomcat, it's up and running.
Now let me stop them.
Stop Tomcat.
Now if you find this status, it is not running.
That's fine.
Now, our concept, that concept
is how to execute a shell script from another shell script.
Actually, we how separate shell script to start Tomcat and hit you deeply.
Know how one more requirement,
that requirement is with single shall scape.
I need to stop or start both the services, Tomcat and HTTPD.
Then integral of writing your code, again,
simply call those two scripts. Now let me do that.
So I am writing start HTTPD and Tomcat dot SH.
Now let me write the very first one,
iss shebang line, user bin bash.
Now, friends, if you want to run this shell script from the current location itself,
then directly you can write
this shell script inside of your shell script without pruning complete path.
Now if you want to run the shell script from the different location,
then you have to provide complete fault for this.
Now let me show you that one by one.
Suppose to start, I'm taking start HTTP dot SH.
Yeah, and that it labeled right.
So your shell scripts to start and stop Tomcat and sorry,
your shell script to start your Tomcat and HTTP are there in the current location.
That's why simply connect dot slash star HTTPD dot SH,
and then dot slash start Tomcat dot SH.
So before running our shell script,
you have to provide execution permission.
Let me prove it for all files.
Fine.
Now before running our shall skip,
let me check the status system,
CDL status, HTTPD. It is not running.
Then let me find the status four.
Tomcat as well. Not running.
Now, I'm running our shell script called start HTTPD and then Tomcat dot SH.
So using single shell script,
you are running scripts which are there inside of that.
That's it.
Now, let me find the status. Yes, it's running.
And let me find this treatise for Tom get as it's running, and that's it.
But suppose if you want to create your start
Tomcat HTTP dot SH and stop Tomcat actually brew.sh in a different location,
then you have to provide complete parts for our shell scripts.
So as of now, this script and the script both are there in the current location.
That's why simply I'm reading dot slash.
Let me come back to my home directory.
And before that, let me list the files.
Now here I'm grading. Suppose stop HTTPD, Tomcat dot SH.
And in this location, suppose be clear.
If I done in this way,
suppose stop HTTPD dot ASH AND NOT slash,
stop Tomcat dot SH.
And they won't work because they are not in the current location.
Let me provide the execution permission.
Let me try that so that you can understand.
So I am running C that no such file or directory,
These two actually they are in the different location.
That's why whenever if you want to run us kids from the different location,
you have to prove it always complete path.
So it's better to provide always complete part.
Now let me copy this path and provide these two parts.
I'm in this path for two shell script which are there anymore.
Stop HTTP dot, Tomcat dot SH.
That's it.
Now I can run and it will work.
Now it has been executed.
Now let me check the status of
your Tomcat not running and the status of your HTTPD system,
CDL status, not earning.
So guys here what I did,
I exclude tie one shell script in another shell script.
Be clear, that's a fine.
Then what is our next concept?
How to access variables which are defined in another file. Let me show you that.
See, it is very different.
I mean, just small difference between how we explanations to form
another shell script on how to access
variables from another file or another shell script.
Now first of all, I'm creating one file called one dot SH RNA extinction.
Generally most of the cases we will take SH.
Suppose in this file,
if it is a text to find non-literate shebang line,
if it is, shells could be hard, right?
Shebang line.
Now, just assume that I am writing shebang line for this.
And I'm creating a variable,
let's say name equals two.
I am writing simply first shell script.
And let me save this. And let me create second shell script to dot SH.
Then here I want to access the variables which are defining.
Foster shall skip one dot SH, then how you can,
as of now you know how do we execute one shell script into another shell script?
Right?
Now?
First, let me provide the execution permissions for your first shell script.
Now, you have to provide execution permissions for second shell script as well.
Now I'm running second shell script.
You are not getting an output because you don't have any echo command in
your first shell script or in second shell script.
Now, let me try just by equating this variable name in the second shell script.
Just I am writing echo dollar 10M and see the result,
whether you are getting your output or not.
Be clear. We are displaying the variable from.
Second shells, but our variable is defined in first shell script.
Then is it giving you what data are? Not? Just check it.
It's not giving.
The reason is you may think that we are executing the shells could be here.
Whenever if you're executing any shell script within the another shell escape,
then it will create, First of all,
in new shell internally,
an insight that shall do legs good.
And inside that shell your variable is defined not in the current shell.
That's the reason you are not getting
the variable which is there in your first shell script.
So now if you want to access variables which are
defined in another file from the current shell script.
Then how to source you were first to file it,
maybe a shell script or it may be a text file.
Sourcing is nothing but there is a command called source.
Now, see the result.
You are getting.
Not only shell script, you can store
your variables in any file are without any extensional.
So let me do one thing.
My variables just I am writing without any extension.
And here simply I am writing x
equals ten and y equals to some 45. You can write anything.
And I want to access these variables from my second shell script.
Then what do you want to do?
Open your second shell script.
If you are shells cape and your variables file,
if both are in the same location simply you can write source dot slash hour where, sorry.
What is the filename that we copy this?
So also space dot slash.
Then let me display echo the x's.
So I am getting this x-value from my variables.
Fine. Echo.
The white is dollar right?
Now let me run our shell script and see the result.
Yes, you are getting. And one more thing,
we have one more syntax instead of source.
So you can also use simply dot.
Both are same. Dot space,
dot slash my variables.
When you are using dot slash,
that file is there in the current location from where you are running your shell script.
But if it isn't a different location,
you have to provide a complete path instead of dot slash.
Let me do one more thing so that you can understand.
Suppose here I'm creating one file called demo,
and here I am writing demo equals two.
This is from demo file.
I define a variable inside of my a file
called demo and which is there in the different location called this one.
Now we have our shell script to dot SH here.
Right?
Now I want to access the variable which is there in this demo file.
And don't get confused.
I use demo has a filename and inside of
that taken variable has demo. You can take anything.
Now let me take
this complete path because that demo file is there in a different location.
And if you are getting confusion,
always just use complete path.
Source r dot, you can use then complete path for Word file.
Now let me remove all these things.
One thing, I will keep them as it is.
At the end, I will display because I will share this for your practice purpose.
Demo. Now, see the result.
Yes, you are getting this is from demo file.
I used source.
You can also use dot.me.
Our source means in this file,
please get that information from this file and the current shell script,
and get the information which is there in this file, that's it.
So I come at it with the hash symbol.
So we'll discuss that in the next video.
What is the uses of hash as of no hash means,
just assume that that line is not there in the shell script.
Now this easy or shell script,
and I'm running that and see the result.
Yes, you aren't getting. So simply guys,
you can use either source or dot.
And be clear.
You can use this if you were current shell steep and you are this file.
If both are in the same location.
If they're in a different location,
please provide complete part.
That's it.
So that is the simple uses of these two concepts.
Okay?
Okay, thank you.