Hyphens will come back to real time practice with shells cooking course.
Friends.
Here we are going to work with some inventory for multiple servers.
See sometimes in your real time knowing you are,
you are going to maintain,
suppose some hundreds of servers,
some of servers, right?
Let's suppose I'm having some servers that might take
four or five serovars I'm having right now supposing this is my local server.
And for all my remote servers,
I need to find out some parameters.
It may be anything like your waist type,
ways version, CPU type, site architecture.
Or suppose if installed on Java,
what is the question of your Java?
So all those things you need to find out on all,
on each and every server.
So if you want to find all these parameters on each and every server,
what you ought to do, you have to login with each and
every server and you have to find out all the values, right?
So instead of finding in that way,
you can also automate this thing.
I mean, what are the parameters you want to find out?
Right? You can automate that.
30 shall skip.
And you can run your shells taped in a single shot on all multiple servers.
Right? Suppose, let me take, I need to find out,
suppose some parameters like let me take waste types and ways for Shen.
Right? Let me take all our capital. We can take anything.
Then.
Architecture type, CPU type.
Not only this, suppose if you have some installed java,
denoted that Java was shen, right?
Suppose you are running some web logic then what is a rational web logic?
If you are running some Tomcat,
what is a washing off your Tomcat?
And these parameters you have to find out on each and every server.
So if you want to find all these values on each and every server,
you have to login with each and every server.
And you need to find out that suppose I have a requirement
that how suppose some hundreds are worse for all a 100 servers.
I need to find out suppose these four values and I need to
export all those four values into a CSV, CSV file.
Then you had to open excel sheet and you have to find
out ways type waves washing our picture pipe on CPU type on a,
on each and every server.
And manually you have to copy those information into your CSV, right?
It will take some time.
Of course we can do it, but unnecessarily you are going to waste your time.
Right?
So finding this type of information on
multiple servers from one place is called suppose inventory.
Inventory script.
Now we are going to design one inventory script.
Right?
That is, automate sorrow our inventory using shell script.
And after finding all you are required parameters or values, whatever.
But other parameters you need.
Finally, through our shell script itself,
I want to export my data into csv file.
So this thing we are going to automate,
just assume you're going to find out some parameters for a hundreds of servers.
Right.
Just assume in case if you want to do it manually,
how much time do we take?
Instead of that, we are going to write him shell script.
Right? See that?
So just assume that first I'm going to find out only these four values, right?
And assume that you are going to use this.
Suppose for a 100 servers,
hundreds of sorrow, whatever it may be.
But here I'm going to take only two servers.
I am going to work with this shell script.
I mean, I'm going to test it by using two servers.
And guys maybe just assume that I'm going to work with.
Suppose Rachel, also open
to see some commands may be similar with your armature and open to.
And some commands maybe differs, right?
So in that case,
how you can handle your shell scripts, right?
That's fine.
And guy, suppose if you are going to login with any server,
definitely you are going to login with one user, right?
With some password.
Just assume that you don't have any possible less authentication.
You have to connect with your remote servers
using password and it will be particular user.
Now in our case, just assume that I'm having same user called DevOps across all users,
I mean across all systems.
And I'm having password called automation.
Right? Now. If you want to execute some commands on your remote server,
you know, you have SSH, right?
Using your SSH, you can run your commands on your remote server.
And one more thing, while learning
your command on the remote server with the help of SSH,
it will prompt your password.
So to our that we are using SSH pass.
Right?
See, first let me form complete command to run
your command on your remote server without to prompting your password.
That is SSH pass.
Iphone IAAF. Suppose in this I am going to have a remote pass.
This is a file. In this I have a my password.
Right? Then as such, right?
So nice. I'm including hyphen and option.
So it will avoid taking history input, right?
That's fine. Now, I need
some options for your SSH only we discussed in our SSH concepts, right?
So what are those means?
Let me so you know, man as such.
So if it come down, you're having hyphen WE Options.
And here we are using hostess heat-seeking nodes,
strict host Tukey checking.
No, we are taking right. So I needed that.
Just let me go with that.
Strict hosted key checking.
I'm going to enable it as,
Sorry, I'm going to disable it.
So it won't ask like yes or no, right?
Even if you want to disable your public authentication public-key as indication,
yes, you can add it to one more hyphen WE option.
That's it, right?
And you are having user called DevOps are the rate.
Now year. We can't fix it for
one server because it is going to work with multiple server.
Let me take some variable here.
That's it.
Now here you need to write some command.
But what the command you want to execute, right?
So guys here, based on with
what server you're going to work at the time your server name will change.
That's why first of all,
I'm going to change this entire thing.
Okay, first I will do one thing.
I will exclude manually and tested Sid DevOps,
let me take any one of the server name.
So where's my local sorrow is also I am treating as one remote server.
Then if config, I need IP address.
So in your real time, you can provide your FQ DNS server name. This thing.
Suppose I want to check
it or is released value.
Let me just run it and see the output neuron missing.
What is that? Ok, I need to probably public authentication has no,
I forgot to do that. Let me write it.
We don't have filed a remote bus.
Let me update my password in this remote pass file.
Other exotic ligand also mentioned your password.
Let me write my password here.
Now let me check it.
Yes, see that?
Now you are able to run your command on your remote server, right?
So I'm going to take one more server,
ask some open to Sarawak now let me run my command on remote server.
Let me copy my o12 IP address one seventy two thirty one.
Let me write 172 dot-dot-dot T1 dot 87.94.
Now let me run this and see the output.
So now you're getting open to information here.
You are getting here, suppose RHO l information, right?
So this now you have a command to run your commands on your remote server.
So this is our complete command, right?
First, let me take it, this perfect command.
So let's to get your waist type right.
You're, you are having this command.
So if you observe here on line,
if you are having named Red Hat Enterprise Linux server on the same command,
if you run for 012, you are getting in this way.
But I need to get only this name part, right?
Then what you have to do,
just run your command and applying a W k, suppose hyphen.
Let me first to grab that line Butler length,
grep, hyphen W, name and see the output.
Right.
Now from that, I don't want to get name equals two.
I need only open to.
Then let me do pipeline AWPA command.
So I am going to separate fields based on this name equals two,
and I am printing $1.2 means second field.
Now see the output, what you are getting.
So if you run online x, you are getting,
sorry, 012 and getting, you are getting in this way.
Suppose if you run the same command on your Linux server.
So you are Linux server IP is not this.
So even though if you have some multiple servers know bottom, same command will walk.
See now you're getting rid identifies lining server.
And I don't want to get some of these quotations,
then what I will do, transfer command you are having.
So transfer, so whatever the quotation places there that I want to replace with empty.
Now see that what you are going to get,
I'm sorry. It's syntax.
Single quotation. Now see the output.
Right? Fine.
So not only this,
we need different types of parameters based on our requirement.
Now we need to modify this command.
Now whatever the command you are having,
if you observe in this entire command, right?
Only. This is the common point is up
to this if you observe where it is, public authentication.
Devops, right?
And this year based on which server you're going to work,
that's our name will change remaining thing, right?
That's what I am doing is I will sail this entire thing.
Ssh options as one variable.
Now what I will do is now instead of running your command now, I will do in this way.
Ssh underscore options. I think he's,
I just, I'm trying to avoid some lengthy commands.
Now inside of this, what you are having already,
we are having whatever you need to execute your command on the remote server.
That's it, right?
That's fine. Okay.
Now guys, let me go with your script to implement.
Nowadays in your hand,
you are having a list of servers.
And one more thing before running this shell script,
before implementing these cells kept it,
just tried to do one thing.
You just save your password in remote past file and username, remote user.
And suppose a list of servers just in this file is stopService.doc or.txt file.
Or the similarly stuffs are words.
So these three files I need to implement our shells clip and
to execute our shell script because see it today.
You may have some password.
Tomorrow you may change your password that in that case,
you don't want to go and open your shell script
and you should not change your password inside of that.
I mean, to avoid changing password inside of shells gave to
what we will do is we will store your password in this file in case if it changes,
will open this file and we will change the password in this file.
Right?
Suppose in tomorrow I want to work with some 50 servers,
then just open this file and list out you're all servers.
So that's why I'm taking these three files first.
So before implementing our shell script,
Let me do one thing.
Vi, remote past.
So here you're already does that.
Just let me save that. Then.
Remote user.
So I'm going to take, as of now, DevOps, that's it.
And I need list off servers.
All right, so here I want to store my all the IP addresses of my all remote servers.
So I'm taking, I'm considering
my local summary is also one of the remote server because I don't want to
create one more server and I don't want to take that as
a remote server simply I'm filling that local server itself.
One remotes are all Nobel and it can work like that.
Right?
So you have one more.
That is one seventy,
two eighty one something.
Let me do this. In your real time guys.
You can provide your IP's, but instead of that,
it's better to provide if q Dn names of your servers.
That's a good practice. Right?
Sum sorrow or some cloud dot something, right?
Nazi.
Nowadays, if you have jury or having your three files,
now I want to implement inventory script invented dot SH.
Let me start this first. Bin bash.
Ok. Nice.
Before running our shell script,
I want to display some message like welcome to inventory Bash shell script.
Right?
Suppose if our Simply Eco inventory,
Welcome to Bash shell script, what it will do.
It will display your message.
But see that first.
When it come to inventory script,
simply suppose if I
run this, it is displaying here.
But I don't want to display in this way.
I want display exactly in the middle of your terminal irrespective of your tunnel size.
So automatically, our shell script has to identify the number of columns in each row.
And automatically it has to place our message in the center of your row, right?
So for that, how you can do it, right?
So let me write some simple code for that.
So it's very easy. Let me do that.
Okay, fine. See what I'm doing is I'm going to define one function first.
The purpose of that function is centering our message,
whatever you are sending to this function,
that message will be displayed incentive, right?
So for that, I am writing my meshes.
And even before printing your messages,
I want to write some header like I will show if I write can print header.
So I will write this as a one function.
So here I am writing,
suppose one more thing, bring to head up.
So between this, so print
out results of one function under defined somewhere. Let me do one thing.
I quote.
Suppose welcome, do shell are welcome to inventory.
Right?
Fine.
C As of now just I'm calling this function, right?
Okay, not only for this message, let me do one thing.
So I want to write this function as for any message,
Let me take simply misses as $1.1 means while calling this function,
I will pass my requirements is whatever the message you
want to display using that message function.
Welcome to inventory script.
That's it. Alright.
So first I'm trying to print simply print f percentile.
Yes. So this is very easy with you or print f command.
Years tried to use that $1.1.
Right? Now, what is this print of head of the function?
So I'm going to define that here.
The purpose of printf,
I'm in print header is nothing but displaying some character like a header.
So I will do this in this way.
Simply, you can do this using your printf function.
I mean print f command.
Let me do this. Hash symbol I want to display, right?
So geodata S.
Just check while running this command so that it will write C dollar.
So I want to display this hash symbol in the entire line, right?
So I don't know how many columns are there based on your see,
this columns are not fixed, right?
So you may have different width for your terminal.
I'm how different width or might add null but
automatically through Shell script if you want to identify that,
yes, you can identify with the help of t put columns.
That's it.
So after that, you know,
printf won't send your cursor to next length forcefully unit ascended next line.
Right? Now just to see this,
if I run this, what you are getting, c.
Okay, maybe printf.
Second time YOU calling my function,
this is Hetchy Ying De.
Let's say, right?
And you may get confused.
Let me do one more thing.
Print f slash n,
So that your customer will go to next line.
That's it. But I want to display this message at the center of
your line and the center of your row, right?
So for that, nothing is there.
You need to calculate.
Let me do one thing.
So terminal columns I am taking equals to simply,
it is a command, right?
T put columns. Right?
Then I'm finding my message length.
Where I'm finding, I will let you know.
Now see just up there that if you are,
this is the total length of line.
I mean number of columns.
Suppose you have some misses.
You want display somewhere in the middle of that.
Right?
Now if I am able to find out this point,
then from that I can print my message.
That means what I am doing is in this entire MSAs,
I'm subtracting my Required message,
then just remove that.
Then in this I am finding half of the length so that you will get out this point.
You'll get this point, right.
So that's what I'm doing here.
So for that, I am finding.
Please spaces for your message equals two just to do arithmetic operation for
your terminal columns minus your message length.
Right?
And then just to do divide to,
then do once again you are one more arithmetic operator.
So for that I am applying once again this automatic operators.
Right now I want to print a string. Okay?
See how I'm going to print c.
I want to print your string,
but before going to print the string, right,
I need to print some empty spaces, right?
So print f percentile geodata s. Then I want to pray.
How many number of spaces?
So sequence 123 spaces in this you're having how many spaces unit to print?
That's a.
Now let me tie this one's okay.
Sequence one.
Oh, I need to print the spaces here, right?
Yeah, that's it.
See now, dynamically, you are able to print
your message in the middle of your line, right?
It is just for design purpose, that's it. Nothing is that.
See the code completely so that you can get some idea.
Right now, we are able to print out message at the center.
Not only that messes you,
call this function with any message so that that message will
be displayed at the center of your line.
Now what I'm doing is I'm going to write one more thing, Center message.
Thank you for using this shell script.
Or even resell, skip something, whatever it may be.
Message.
Right now, see if I run this,
see now between this unit implementing our logic.
So before going to implement your logic,
you need some remote past File,
Remote username, and a list of files,
I mean list of servers.
So that is there in terms of one is remote pass first, let me check it.
See, I am going to write something first.
I want to check whether remote pascal is there or not because I need password.
So I'm going to store my password in remote past file.
That's why check.
Remote pass file are simply remote past four that I'm going to write some function,
check the remote Bus.
See here what I'm writing is if file is there no problem.
We file is not there, right?
If not hyphen e, your file,
then I want to stop myself script and I want to say something. Let me right.
Please save your password on Play,
store your password in
remote pass file and retry.
So for that I want to exit.
I don't want to run because I don't have password.
How can I execute my SSH command?
That's why simply I'm exiting,
exit with some error as one.
That's a, that's fine. That is over.
Now, same way I want to check remote user as well.
So check remote user.
So for this, again,
I'm going to write one more function,
that is this function.
So here also I am checking if not,
you are filed called remote user.
If it is not there, right,
then seaway, I'm using central message function.
I want to display my message in the center.
Please.
Store you were remote user name
in remote user filing under a time.
That's it.
So in case if you don't have remote user name than what you had to do,
simply just you have to exit.
So now I'm exiting with their record as to you can
take any record that is based on what we write.
C, I'm running these.
You're not getting any exceptions because already how all your files let me do one thing.
I am moving my remote user name file as remote user someone.
Now I'm running our shall skip C.
What did you swing?
Please store your remote user name in remote user file, unretrieved.
So that means you should how you were remote user file in the location.
Now shall ship.
It will work perfectly. That's it.
So write the same Vegas unit to check list of servers file, right in it,
a handle this in your shell script could sell because
you are trying to connect with the number of servers and you know,
you are going to store your number of servers in your file called list of servers files.
But in case if that file is not there in the current location,
then you cannot work with you're all servers.
That's why check list off servers,
file list stops or worse.
Write one more function for that.
Now let me write one more function just to check out your list of servers.
So each step I am writing as a function race,
there is a good practice in your real time.
Now here also I am doing if not hyphen e to a list of servers file is not there,
then I want to say center.
So you have a functionality to display your message in the center.
Please update the liftoff servers file with
all your IP's or F q Dn names.
Offering more servers.
That's it.
Alright.
So now you know everything,
not the next thing is you need to find out your required variable.
I mean, you required parameters on your all remote servers.
See guys, here, I need to find out ways type,
ways fortune, or a picture type on CPU type.
And I know whenever if you want to run any command,
this is the common part, SSH, right?
So off to this, these the common part.
That's why.
So I'm writing inside my shell script in this way.
As a such options equals two just I am storing this.
Let's say now I am going to work on all servers.
Let me read my server one-by-one with the while loop.
So you guys, reading line by line is a good practice by using while loop.
So that's why I'm taking while read server.
Do, done, you know,
your servers are there in the file called list of servers, right?
C I am writing simply for your understanding,
a co-working on dollar server.
We're not we're not implementing your coat,
just we are testing where it is working perfectly or not. See that.
Working on working on and guys unit,
right, this tank you for imaging the shell script at the end.
That's why what I'm doing is I'm going to call that function last.
So simply just comment this line here or just copy this line from here.
Test right at the end.
Right? So in case if you need some extra code you can include, that's a lot.
Just check it. No. That's it.
Now, working on the first server,
working on second server.
So while working with your first server,
the command should be in this way.
I mean for different parameters, year,
your IP address should be there in this V c. So what I want to do first OAS type,
I want, I need to find out for first server inside of your loop, right?
Whatever the code you are going to write that will repeat for each and every server.
So now what King on your first server,
I'm trying to find out waste pipe is nothing but I am running some command.
That command I'm going to store into some variable,
you know how to store the output of a commodity, a variable.
Right?
So this command, actually you are going to add some command,
that command output you're going to store into your waste.
Type variable. You should know,
you should not have any space new variable name.
That's why I'm taking that.
First thing.
There is the command to run SSH options user name, right?
Then at the rate, your server name,
then whatever the command you want to run,
suppose I need to find out my OS type, right?
So to find out your OS type,
suppose this is the command.
Let me copy this. Right?
So suppose if I run this,
just observe the output first.
It will run for your two servers, right?
See that? 1 second,
Maybe I didn't mistake.
Oh, what is that?
At the rate dollar Hour because inside of this dollar server variable segues,
you are able to read your server name with the help of while loop with this variable,
I need to substitute the variable value.
That's why need to place a dollar server.
Now let me run this ones and see the output.
So you are getting RedHat and you've been to,
so for this server, you are getting this one.
For the server you are getting this one.
Same way.
You need to find out different values, right?
Let me do one more thing.
So finally, I will, OK,
this is because of this command you are able to find out you are ways type.
But I want to store this into one variable.
That's why I'm taking c,
that OS underscore type equals $2 parenthesis.
That's it. Now inside of this variable you how your ways type, right?
Next thing, you need to find out.
What is the next parameter you are having.
Ways, Washington, let me take this way swaption.
I need to find out my voice version.
So guys, before going to find out your ways, Washington, right?
If it is RedHat,
you are having different file to find out the work.
If it is open to you have ways release file.
So that's why what I'm doing is see just I'm ticking, echo.
Whatever the waste type you are getting in the previous line in that,
whether do we, how open to or not.
If you have a one do,
then you will get dollar question mark of value as 0, right?
So I'm redirecting my output and error into diagonal.
So now I'm checking if dollar question mark value,
if it is equals to 0,
then it is a open to server.
Then for a woman to,
if you want to find out your waist version,
you have a file called the Hadley.
I'm assigning the my outputting two ways.
Wash invariable guys.
So for urban to URL,
let me write first command.
Yeah, cat ways release.
In this you are
having
release.
Some ID. Of course you can also use even this Fall River.
Let me write it by plane.
Grep, coercion underscore ID.
Right? So often finding my Watson underscore ID,
you can observe by taking my executing command manually.
So I need to take what's Shun underscore ID equals two,
then with the print f command.
All right, I need to take $1.2 variable value.
That's it.
If it is not o12,
then what I have to do is let me take and we up to this common part right?
Then for your Linux systems,
see you have cathode,
ETC, Red Hat release.
So in this directory you are having this.
In this, if you are able to separate it with release word,
you can able to get discerned dot six.
So that means biplane,
K, WK, hyphen F separately.
I am taking a release.
Right now. See the output, what you are, sorry.
Yeah, then I am printing too and see the output now what you are getting, right?
That's a in case you weren't going to only sound out six.
Just once again, apply your AWPA command.
Now print only $1.1.
That's it. Now, this is for my rachel servers.
So that's why I'm going to take it and see how I'm going to walk it.
That's it. So just take this in this way.
Alright, so now just close your eyes.
If condition, now I'm displaying the value,
displaying the values of our OAS type equals $2 ways underscore Thai.
Then echo, waste, Wusheng equals
$2 ways underscore version.
Now let me run this shell script so that you will get
your output for each and every server.
Sea waves type RedHat and it's Watson shown dot six,
o12 and it's worse in 14.04, right?
So likewise guys, you can also find out your architecture type.
So just I'm giving commands directly.
You can write your name Ivan p. You will get your architecture type, right.
See if you want to find out your CPU type information, right?
You are having a file called, I mean,
under root, you have a file called,
let me execute on command line.
Root proc, CPU info, right, just other,
other file information in this model type you are having here.
That means after these just pipeline grip.
Just use your and see the output.
So from this you just do your AWPA command manipulations and tried to get out this part.
That's it.
So to find out architecture,
architecture type, simply you name hyphen p.
Right?
So after getting all these values guys in this shell script,
you just tried to implement for the remaining
two information's already how given a command,
you just try to work out with that so that you will get some idea while executing them.
So what I want to find out is our picture type.
You just find out you have already commands.
Then CPU type.
So all they are given command.
You just tried to execute it.
And try to understand so that it will be useful for your realtime place.
Not only this opera finding your information,
I want to store this information into even,
I mean, I want to export this data into csv file.
So see, what I'm doing is I'm writing server name comma.
So first I need to find out OS type.
So way as type I am adding head of the first ways was shunned architecture type.
So guys, you need to find out
this article type value and you are CPU type for these two values,
just find oh, I'm giving as an assignment for you.
So this data just let me write into
servers in foods.csv that's now offer finding all your values.
Just tried to append your data into your CSV file.
I mean, simply a KOH.
Let me take whatever you are having.
First thing you need to find out server name,
right? So simply server.
Because from here you're able to get your server right comma.
Then you are able to get your way as type.
So already you know what is the waste type?
You are getting that data and then you are ways version.
And then there were architecture type.
And finally, you are CPU type case,
not only these parameters in your real-time,
you may hold different parameters requirement to find out your inventory, right?
That's it.
Alright, see, let me save this and run it.
So before going to run it,
just absorbed in the location,
you don't have any CSV file.
So after running right now,
observe that you have a CSV file.
And if you open that CSV file,
you have information in this way,
you are getting these values are empty because
you need to find out your Arctic type on CPU type.
Undoubtedly you can export this file to your main, right,
or you can download that using WinSCP and offer downloading your file to WinSCP.
Suppose if fidelity open that with the help of your excel sheet,
automatically will rearrange clearly you are a header and rows and columns.
So that is the importance using this inventory and exploiting your data into csv file.
So this concept is very,
very important while working with your real times.
All right, so now you are able to implement any type of
inventory for your realtime, right?
Just try to practice with different parameters so that you will be
good with your realtime scripts for rework these type of,
I mean, inventory typeof shell scripts.
Right?
Okay. Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.