Friends here our concept is Windows subsystem for Linux,
or how to install Linux on Windows operating system.
Let me start that.
Basically, Windows subsystem for Linux is an optional feature on Windows ten.
That means based on our requirement,
we can enable or disable this feature.
That's fine.
But why we need this window subsystem for Lenox,
There are so many advantages.
Let me go with one of the simple example so that you can
understand the uses of Windows subsystem for Linux.
Just assume that you are practicing it Python scripting on your Windows operating system.
And we know that Python scripting is platform independent,
that means same Python's cubic and execute what other operating systems as well.
Now, I have a requirement that is,
whatever the Python script ve written on Windows operating system.
Same script I want to verify on my Linux as well.
So as of now I have windows.
Now to get my lennox, We have different ways.
We can go with VMware or we can go with cloud and we can get your Linux operating system.
Yes, I assume that I am going with cloud and I'm getting a Linux operating system.
Can now i how windows as well as Linux from
my job and I how my Python script on my Windows operating system,
not to verify my Python script on my cloud Linux operating system,
how to copy my script to cloud instance.
And once if we copy, you can verify that.
So here the problem is,
each time whenever if you want to verify your Python script,
you have to copy your script into your required operating system and then you can verify.
And second problem is suppose if you go with cloud instance, suppose.
So that is a command line.
I mean, we are going to connect with your cloud Linux system through terminal.
So you don't have any GUI.
Know, suppose if you want to write your script using GUI tools,
you don't have feature, that feature with your terminal.
So anyway, you how your native operating system has windows.
Now, if you go with Windows subsystem for Linux,
on the same Windows operating system.
You can also install Linux operating system so
that whenever if you want to verify your Python script on your Linux,
you no need to copy your script from Windows to Linux,
whatever the CPU written on your Windows operating system.
Same script directly you can access from your Linux.
And the second one is any value or Windows operating system.
Because the reason native Windows operating system,
you have some GUI tools,
editors to write your scripts.
So using your GUI tools on your Windows operating system,
you can write your Python script.
Not only Python's will begin right?
Even in shell script, unsaved script directly you can access from
your Linux just for practice purposes,
it is very easy.
So that is the advantage with Windows subsystem, Right?
So using Windows or Windows subsystem for Linux,
you can install and run open to Fedora and some other Linux distributions.
And more Linux distributions are coming through that are under development.
And this feature does not work on Windows 32-bit operating system.
So you have to go with a 64-bit Windows operating system only.
So at one end you simply we can access Windows files in Bash and batch files in Windows.
I mean, Windows files directly can access from
your Linux and Linux file directly can access from Windows mana to copy.
No need to access your files.
All right, let me go with installation. So very simple.
You have to open start menu,
then just simply such four ton ton windows features on and off,
on, off, click on that just to maximize the screen.
Scroll down somewhere in the last you how Windows subsystem for Linux.
You just enable it and just click on working.
So it will take some time and ask for reboot.
You just reboot your system once. Just wait for that.
So after applying, nobody's asking,
windows needs reboot your PC to finish installation,
installing the required changes, just restart it.
Just click on it.
Yes, I'm doing restart.
Once it is come back from base dot,
then we will see how to install open to.
So this is the first step you have to perform before going to install
your Linux operating system on your windows.
Okay, we enable windows subsystem for
Linux and we restarted our Windows operating system just to verify
it ones go to simply start then such four ton windows features on or off.
Just click on that and maximize the screen.
Then go scroll down.
So here tick mark is there,
that means windows subsystem for Lenox has been enabled us to cancel it.
Then now again, opening will start.
Then such for Microsoft Store.
Then open that. And here,
just such, in such a bar just type line.
And as of node, these are the Linux distributions
are available under the windows subsystem for Linux,
you just go with any one of the required Linux distribution.
Suppose as of now I'm going to install Linux. Open distribution.
I'm installing.
So just clicky here, installed.
So we'll ask for signing, just cancel it.
So now it is going to install.
It will take some time based on your internet speed, it will take time.
So here, if you observe nulliparous tools,
basically this window such system for Linux is helpful for dollar per.
So here. Yeah. So it will download and install within three minutes.
Just I'm passing this video.
Once it is done, then I will be back. So it is almost didn't.
Just wait for remaining three more nb mb.
Nowadays installing urban to once known loaded equitable installed.
So it has been installed.
Just click on Launch here or go to again,
start, then here in the start minute will appear.
So just I'm clicking on and to now installing this may take few minutes.
Just wait for that.
So it is very first-time it is opening.
We are opening this open two terminal windows operating system.
So it will take some time, just wait for that.
So I'm pausing this video.
So once it is done, then I'll be back.
Okay, it has been done.
So now just to give some user name for this.
So here I'm giving username as suppose automation.
Then probably the password here.
And confirm it. So password I'm, we're successfully.
Now if you want to switch to rule,
you can use simply sudo SU.
Then provide the password here,
whatever the password you are given for your user.
Nazi can now am under user.
If you want to switch to a root.
That's fine.
So now you are having,
you are open to operating system on your Windows.
Now let me show you how we can access the files which
are there in your Windows operating system with your open tube.
See if you go and see the,
if you link to the file it showing total JRuby.
Right? Now, suppose I am directly moving into slash moment.
Now see here. So on my Windows operating system or how
to directly see and anybody sees for Windows installation that.
Now let me go with E. Not so now these are the files,
directories, so are there under my Windows operating system.
Now just create some directory.
You can go with existing directory are created
one directory in this location, slash mount,
slash URL required directory,
I mean your required return of your windows.
So Dr. slash moans less E.
So suppose I am creating a directory called Windows and Linux practice.
Now let me move into this.
So here as I've no, I don't know any files.
But what I will do is I will open my any editor on my Windows.
Let me open my ATM editor, Atom editor.
So what I will do is I will create a new file.
Let's say some file name is,
and I'm, I'm saving that file.
You can save it anywhere on that part you can access directly from 012 inch loved that.
We already created directed right under the directory.
Under E, we created Windows Linux practice.
So here I will save my file using my Windows operating system,
let's say demo dot i section.
So simply here I'm writing supposedly been Bash.
Simply I am writing. This file is created on my Windows,
but we can access on.
Let me save it.
Now I'm going to my urban two-terminal.
See that we have a file.
So simply provide the execution permissions for this and simply run that, that's it.
So this is very simple way for developers to test
their scripts on Windows as well as on
Linux without copying your files from Windows to Linux.
If you go with Windows subsystem for Linux, let's say.
Okay, thank you for watching this video.