Friends here our concept is grep command.
Grep command is a filter command and it is used to search is string in a given file.
Not only in a file,
you can search in multiple files or maybe in textile.
So we will see that.
Now let me explain with a simple example
so that you will get some idea of how to use grep command.
Suppose I have a file called test.txt.
Now I want to be a string called a bow in this entire file using grep command.
Then you have to use in this way,
you grab that is the command.
Then you are such a string.
What is they were requires string you want to such in a file and this filename.
Now enter.
And if I enter, it is going to display the lines.
It is going to display lines from your file called test.txt,
which are having a bowstring.
See that isn't in this entire lanes are boys,
they're only in one lane.
So that empty line it is displaying.
Now let me search with some thing called lines and see the result.
Now it is displaying two lines in which we how lines screen.
And it is highlighting also.
Now let me such weight.
Narendra, suppose you're not
getting an output because Melinda is not there in a given text file.
And whenever if you are searching a string in a given file,
please use quotations for your suffering.
If you don't use quotations,
sometimes in some situations you will get wrong output.
Let me do the situation.
Suppose, again, let me take this file only.
Now in this file, suppose I am looking for line,
this is my required string.
I want to search string in your file, then grip.
You were required to string.
Then you were filename C, that isn't there.
Getting very first plan as an error.
If no such file or directory,
actually you are Grip command is taking ease as a file.
Only this as he was string and ease test.txt.
Both are taken as a file names.
That's the reason.
Please take quotations for your searching string.
Then it will work perfectly.
Now see there is.
Now, this is the simple way to such a string in one file.
Not only in one file, you can search,
your string are dead time in multiple files also.
Suppose I'm searching for bashes stream in a file called one dot SH.
Yes, it is that I want to look in one more file.
Then immediately provide with the space is brew.sh.
Now see the result in one dot SH bashes there,
in two dot SH bashes there.
So likewise, you can search in any number of files,
just you can provide your files with the spaces.
That's a grip.
It was searching string,
then file names with spaces.
Suppose if you want to suck in
all files which are there in the current location for you are required to string.
Then simply search with the star.
Star means all files in the current location.
That's it.
Anyway, this is a directory name.
That's why you can't such,
you will string in directory name only in the content of your file.
That's the reason you are getting here error.
No problem.
Only in files you can such it is showing you a result.
That's it.
In which files you are having.
You are, but that is a display.
Fine.
Now, let me do the syntax of your Grip command.
Grep, options, string or pattern,
then file or files.
You can search in one file or in multiple files and hear how returns Klingon pattern,
don't worry about pattern,
will discuss in detail about pattern in
advance or uses of Grip command that is in next session.
As of now, just to concentrate on string,
grep, some options, then string,
then file or files.
See not only in a file,
you can also use Grip command directly on a text.
I mean, suppose I'm displaying it texture.
This is a simple Info.
This is a text no.
On this text, I can use Grip command in these wave Pipeline, grep.
What is your searching strings?
Suppose I wanted to search for simple than space.
Just enter C. That is, this is a text.
On this text you can use pipeline.
Then grep command, actually grep command needs input.
That input will take from this,
we know that uses up pipeline.
Whenever if you use pipeline,
this pipeline provides for this command input as from this command output.
So whatever the output you are getting from here,
that output will provide as a input for this second command.
Instead of file, we are providing a text c.
Suppose previously we done this, grip,
a bow, then test.txt file. Same thing.
I can also run it in this way.
First, I can content on that.
I can apply Grip command.
So based on your requirement,
you can proceed with Anyway.
That's it.
There is no difference, right?
Fine. Now.
So that is the second way to use your grep command.
Now coming two options.
We hold different types of options here.
These are the basic options and these are the advanced options.
So advanced options will discuss with the pattern,
I mean, in the next session.
So in this video we are discussing about basic options.
So these all are basic options for your grep command.
Let me go with that.
So this is the basic uses of your Grip command without any options.
Options are always optional.
If you want, you can use,
if you want to skip, you can skip them.
Fine.
Now with options, if you want to use in this place,
you have to mention you are options.
So now grep, options in quotations he was string,
forget about pattern, then file or files.
So first I will work with the single file.
Then if you want to work with multiple files, yes,
you can find very first option is hyphen.
I let me open my terminal.
And suppose I am looking for capital yea a bow in a file called test.txt c,
there is an there is no capital F0.
In a given text to file.
Now, I don't want to consider the case sensitivity,
then you can ignore your case sensitivity is simply by hyphen.
I.
Now see the result.
Yes, you are getting.
So if you want to ignore case sensitivity,
then you can use hyphen I option.
Now, second one, hyphen w v w to match your whole world.
Suppose first let me such grip line in test.txt.
C line is a string and I am looking for a string line in this file and see the result,
this line, these lines.
Actually if you observe here,
this entire thing is a word lines,
but line is the part of this word.
Thus the reason I want to skip this type of matching,
I want to look at exactly four line,
exactly four lane word matching.
Then he had to do optionals hyphen w,
so that you are Grep command will understand that this string is like an exact word.
So in this file,
wherever you how exact word,
complete word called Nine,
that lines on leading will display.
Now c that is here, line is there.
That's why the centerline is displaying.
And here line is there and the headline is there.
See the difference. So in this line, you're having lines.
And previously without a hyphen W option,
it is printing this also a match,
but now I'm looking for exact word match.
Thus the reason I use option called W,
so that you are getting the lines which are having exactly line world.
You know what it means before that word and after that,
what do you have? Some space?
That's it. Fine.
Next one, hyphen v,
to display the lines which are not having given string or text.
I mean, suppose if I search with grip,
a bow in a, in a given file,
then it is printing the lines which are having a bot a bowstring.
But I want to print it the lines other than abu,
i mean, the lines which are not having a bot.
That's it.
So that is the uses of hyphen v. Hyphen Wu,
simply to display only matter parts from Machu lines.
Suppose first see the result.
It is printing the entire lend by default.
But I don't want to print the entire line.
I want to print exactly the matching.
They use hyphen Wu option. That's it.
The next one, hyphen yen to display the match line numbers.
So in which line you are match was there anywhere given five?
Then simply use iPhone yen.
It will give you the line number as well.
Now line number and exactly match,
then you can club your previous option.
That's next hyphen C to display matching number of lines.
So in how many lines you are match was there with your text to file?
Now, let me remove these two options.
We know ABL Is there a only in one line.
That's why you're going to get count as one.
Now if I search with the line, line,
is there in not lines,
I'm taking simply line that to not a word.
I am taking simply this as a string.
Now if you observe first let me grip line,
then you were filed in these many number of lanes.
You align string, is there line string, not a word.
I'm not looking for a word simply I am looking for a string.
A string means in this also line is there
are simply if there is a line but is also matching 41 line from your file.
Now I'm writing with a hyphen.
See count, how many number of times,
sorry, in how many lines you were.
Line audio, string is there in a given file in four lines.
Now I want to look, exert word match.
Then only in three lines,
in three lanes, the word line is there.
Now this line string,
we can call it as a word because we have given options
w. So in three lines you are word line is there.
Then very, very important uses options.
These three capital letters, hyphen,
hyphen v and iPhone C. Abc options.
Hyphen yea means to display yen lines,
means you're required number of lines or after the match C,
the result, how we can use it.
First, let me show you were fine.
So I will take your same file I can take.
Suppose I've always there.
If abu is there,
then after that I want to print one line.
If above is there.
And in my given text file,
I mean any fight, then I want to print offer that one line.
See that grip hyphen yea.
After that, I wanted to print one line.
After a bow.
If a boy is there in my file,
only if that is satisfied,
then print one line offer that suppose this is not there in a file, right?
Then there is no output.
So after A-B-O matched line,
print one more line.
And before match, print one line, then use hyphen b.
Not only one line, you can take any number of lanes based on your requirement.
See that before a bold line,
actually in this Lenovo is there,
I mean matches there before that we are printing one line.
And if you see in our file before that there is an empty line.
That line is displayed.
And along with that, I want to print before and after.
I want to print one line before one lane, offer one length,
that is hyphen see, see that empty line,
an offer that one line.
So anyway, even though if it is empty in your file itself,
that is an empty line, that's a.
So these three lines are very, very, sorry,
these three options are very,
very useful in your real time.
These three, and let me do the hyphen I, iPhone W,
hyphen v, foster, three options,
then hyphen ABC, or very,
very useful in your real time.
And the remaining are maybe rare uses.
Then hyphen or two such under current directory and subdirectory as well. I suppose.
We are in this location,
and this location we have some subdirectory as well.
This is my directory.
I want to look for a string in the current two files and also in this directory.
Then recursively I want to simply grip bash.
And if I use star,
it is going to such for batch and stream in the current location.
But I wanted to look recursively in sub-directories also,
I wanted to look then use iPhone or option.
Now see that this is how sub directory in that there is a file,
in that file there is a bash.
So recursively you can, such with iPhone or option.
Then hyphens to display only filenames.
If there is a match, don't print the content.
Print only filenames.
With hyphen yelled, that's it.
So it is displaying only filenames.
See that in this file there is imagined is file that is image.
Next hyphen edge to hide filenames.
So suppose we are searching in this way, right?
I don't want to print this filenames only.
I want to print the content matching content.
Then simply use hyphen hedge.
It will hide files with recursively hedgehog.
That's it. Ok.
So there is a how given mostly used options in your real time for your grep command.
But if you want to learn some more options,
the remaining options simply go to your command line, man,
grip, and enter your having your all options here.
You can practice, at least.
Please have a look once.
So that whenever if you get any requirement in real time,
you can get at least idea, yes,
with the grep command, there is something option called in this way.
And at the time you can come back and you can look for it.
Fine.
So if you press Q, it will exit. Okay.
Now, let me show you the important concept from your Grip command that is how to
apply Grip command on the output of other Command C. If you remember,
at very first, we have done something like this.
This is a simple info on, on this.
We are applying grep command just to such simple and we are getting some output.
If you observe this entire syntax.
Actually this is a command.
Echo is also a command and it is giving some output.
What is the output? It is displaying your texts under text,
we ran Grip command to such simple.
The same way.
Suppose I am running HTTPD hyphen v and see the result.
You are getting some wash em.
Anyway, you are Washington is there in the line where Watson keys
that are watching string is that so this is the version on your this Watson is there.
If Watson string is there in that line,
that's why I don't want to print second line.
Then I can fritter with the help of grep command,
simply pipeline grid, printed the lines which are having Wusheng, that's it.
So applying the grep command on output of other command is very, very important.
We will use this situation many times in our course.
So I will run some command and that output.
I'm applying grep command just by using biplane symbol.
This is also very, very important.
Okay?
Thank you.