Hello everybody and welcome to this section.
Now in this section we're going to make a low poly chess set.
Now the great thing about the low poly Chester is it's going to enable us to focus on the modelling
skills we're learning rather than making a high detailed model.
Now if you've got the skills to make a high detailed model high poly model then please go ahead.
I'd love to see where you come up with but for the rest of us we'll follow along we'll have a low poly
chess set by the end of it.
And we will have a little look at making 3D models as well.
If you've got a 3D printer we can't dive into the details too much but I have lots of fun printing mine
out at the very end.
Now we're also going to texture our models for the first time.
So we have applied materials to our models reports give them color and make them glossy or matte and
this time we're going to start using a texture as well.
So this is a way of controlling how that surface looks whether it's color or its reflectivity.
There's loads and loads of options.
So we'll touch upon texturing your models for the very first time.
Now after we've done that of course it is time to wrap it all up and make the scene look awesome.
So going to talk about how we can set the camera up orbiting around and we're also going to give it a
background and environment to your scene as well.
So it just looks so much better than just sitting in a void like a lot of models end up doing, So without
any further ado let's crack on and hop on over in the blender.