Hey guys so welcome to the section on VFX.
Lots to cover in here.
We're going to start with a still image and actually put CGI into a real photo.
And then there's a bonus we're going to have video and put the CGI applying in this case into that in
the posh strip along with lots of fun.
But what's this section all about then.
So where bonus section again because we started all of this with a Kickstarter.
We made some promises and we plan on delivering our promises.
So you're getting this content for free.
That's why it's called a bonus section.
It's smaller than some of the others because we focus tightly on the fact you already know how to use
Blender and now you putting the icing on the cake and bringing it into video.
So lots of skills to learn.
Why why start their first lecture.