Hello everybody and welcome to this section where we're going to make a bowling ball and pins using
one of many methods you could do to do so.
Now we're going to start off by using a curve object to trace the outline of a pin and then convert
that curve object into a mesh object to finish off making our pins, We will play with a couple of material
properties as we go through to make sure that our pins are nice and shiny as they would be in real life.
We'll also stress the importance of reference material throughout this particular section, we're dealing
with real world objects.
It's important that we get them pretty accurate otherwise people spot the mistakes.
Now after we've made our bowling pin we're going to do our bowling ball and we're going to make that
using some new modelling techniques as well.
Now we're going to put those two blend files together into one.
We'll talk a little about scene management at this level and also then play with the blender physics
engine and smash that ball into those pins.
So I'm really looking forward to.
Hope you are as well.
So let's dive in and hop on over into blender.