In this video we're taking on the mouth and adding some details around the mouth full self disclosure.
I'm really bad at doing the math.
It's taken me a while to do this and I'm going to speed up a lot of this video where I play around try
a game player and try again but I'm going to let you know my technique and then we can both go through
it together and go through the process.
So let's jump in and work on our mouth.
Make sure you've got enough material so you might want to add down Clay strip if you don't have enough.
This is a good spot to say oh that's roughly where the mouth is going to go.
It's usually a third of the way down from nose to chin.
So this is the nose we say that's around about a third.
That's a third.
So I want to put my clay strip a little bit higher than that.
Okay.
That looks like I've got sticky tape over my mouth.
Perfect.
I'm going to speed up the video and tell you what I'm doing here.
I've laid down my clay strip using the crease tool to make some early lips and then the little bit of
the indent on the top lip from side on I can see that the mouth is not quite lined up in a straight
line but just continue in the process of lay down a clay strip smooth it down get more of an indent
using the crease told sort of going through that process and for me are kind of a lot of iteration put
it down trying and pull down try again and then I thought you know I'm going to Italy where the creasing
around the side of the face just getting the the crease tool just getting some of those lines of the
wrinkle type lines around the side of the face.
Just playing around the cheekbones so I can get a bit of a feel for it and then come back to the lips
in a moment.
Okay.
Now that we've got the general flow for it I'm going to give you the challenge which is to sculpt the
mouth at the lips and Matthew ahead if you haven't done so already you're probably following along with
me and also add the other lines increases around the mouth the nose the chin and the whole jaw area.
So pause the video jump in and take that on now.
Welcome back.
I've sped up the video again.
I wasn't happy with how the lips were looking so I've taken my clay strips and just stripped over the
top of my mouth and now just doing a little of shape shaping the the crease underneath the lips and
then trying again with the crease to increasing the resolution at the moment I've got it in the 30s
round the lifts your.
I found I needed to put it even higher maybe up to 50 or 60 just to get that crease nice and neatly
and to get the finer detail on the lips.
But for you play around with what resolution you think works for you whether it's 20 or 30 or 60.
Similarly with the creases underneath the chin had a few goes at that try to give myself a little bit
of a smile at some stage it looked like he'd like a little bit unnatural.
And generally when you're doing a sculptor pose you get a little bit of an unnatural Look it's often
just the resting face you do your best get the lines in there a little bit more of a crease in the lip
just continuing to finesse with it and it's around about here that I've increased the resolution up
to 70 and I'm getting a lot more of that nice crease in between the lifts and also around some of the
more delicate areas around the mouth the eyes to use that for the crease.
Just making sure that I smooth out any of the ups and downs along the lifts if I getting really closer
and have a look at it and just pulling and pushing.
Just getting the shape of it.
And you've seen my technique I tend to fiddle and diddle and move and play around with a little bit
up a little bit down.
You don't need to take quite such that amount of time if you're doing something that's more of a caricature
or a character that you're making up from scratch.
I'm trying to match a reference image something a little bit precious about it but I don't need to be
quite that precious about it.
And it's this stage I'm looking at my model and saying what else can I do to improve the positioning
of things to fine tune it just as a last pass.
So if you want.
Go ahead and add any last little features any wrinkles or creases that you might have missed throughout
the nose eyes ease mouth chin neck areas but otherwise we're ready to jump into the next lecture.
I'll see you then.