Hello everybody and welcome back to this quick tip with reflection so this won't take long and it will
really help solidify what screen space reflections really means.
And of course expose its limitations and why if you're using a scene that had reflections in it you'd
want to use cycles.
So let's turn on the rendering to begin with this is where we said stuff before.
That's actually fine.
I'm going to go to look Dave mode for the moment just oh no let's go back to solid shading.
OK so the first thing I want to do here is grab of my block.
I've still got overlays turned off to show things off.
Okay.
So let's leave that back on our block itself.
Let's go ahead and give it some material that we know will be highly reflective.
So we're gonna click on new material we're going to call this reflection.
And what are we going to do.
Well we're going to make the base color quite dark.
We know the dark something is the easier it's going to be to see a reflection.
We've we've done it in the past and the roughness.
Well I'm going to set that at zero.
This is going to be a highly reflective surface.
If we go into render mode we will probably start to see the lamp.
Almost.
Let's give the floor this as well just to really make things super shiny.
Look at that full reflections everywhere.
Let's grab our block that we've made reflective and just scale it up for the moment.
So it acts like a mirror and there we go.
So what is the difference.
Well let's hop on over into eevee and see what it looks like there.
Let's go to Evy.
Well you need to first of all of course turn on screen space reflections.
Let's do that.
Let's look a bit faint.
But oh there we go.
They're starting to reflect and it disappears again.
OK.
So it looks like all we need to do to get it to work properly is medal around with the screen space
reflections settings.
Well let's turn off half rares trace that will improve the quality of it.
Okay.
Let's turn on refraction so if there's any refraction in last scene it's also applied.
OK.
What happens if we turn up the thickness.
I'm going to help us at all in this case.
So we don't want to do that edge fading.
Let's make sure there's no fading at all.
Well that makes it look worse.
Let's include the edge fading clamping.
Does that help.
No it's nothing.
He's really bringing this back in at so we can turn up the trace decision.
It doesn't really matter.
We've still got a reflection there though.
So what is going on.
Well let's make this full screen and watch what happens as I have the reflection on my screen and slightly
pan my scenes.
The left
Oh where's my lamp gone.
Did you see that.
Disappeared.
Let's just put part of the lamp on the screen are you getting it.
Yes.
Screen space reflections require the items that are being reflected to be on the screen.
It's an optimization.
It's it's a gotcha.
In this case with our scene here if we wanted it to look like that the moment our object just disappears
out of our view whether that's from a camera or our viewport it is no longer reflected.
And that's why things appear to fade in and out from certain angles.
So how do we sort this out with eevee because Watch this.
If we turn this over to cycles it's being reflected so much better it's still being reflected still
being reflected.
It doesn't matter where we are in our scene providing the lights reaches the viewer i.e. us.
It's being reflected and you can see here it's reflecting the reflection that was on the floor.
That's how good cycles is.
Evey I almost feel like going Hello eevee.
Hello.
But there is so how do we get this to work in TV.
Well it is possible by adding what's called a reflection probe.
So let's go ahead and add one of those to see what it looks like.
I'm going to add a cursor to our wall.
I'm going to go to a light probe and add a reflection plain.
Here we go.
Let's rotate that round on the x axis fortunately these all align and look at that.
Let's make here it's minus 90 and just looking at the top right there is the angle it's required.
Lift that up only on the z axis and it's going to have to be pulled slightly forward.
I'm going to scale that up as well just such big and then g y and only a little.
And there we go.
We've now got a reflection that works off the screen of course.
Now we've got an extra bit of calculation to be done.
So you will end up finding that if you wanted this to look very much like cycles does you start to increase
the render times quite a bit by adding all of these extra things every time you add something.
It adds a cost a time costs for rendering.
Now I've not actually tried this.
If we duplicate this again so we've got another reflection plane and rotate it around again the access
x axis by 90 and place this on the floor.
Okay so we're still as we can see here we still have a limitation is not reflecting the reflection.
So in this particular example we can't even get near to the cycles reflection of a reflection.
And if we put a reflective cube behind I really want to try this one.
So we'll grab this cube and stick it behind our lamp.
So duplicate it.
Gee why pull it back now if we put ourselves in between.
And I'm going to go shift and the grave key to move forward.
There we go we've got a reflection of the back of the lamp and if we let this reflect backwards and
forwards for long enough we would eventually end up with a course just an infinite mirror scenario.
But here we've got a reflection of the reflection in the ground and a reflection of the reflection behind
me.
So this really does bring it all together and really does demonstrate that the fundamental differences
between the cycles and evey rendering engine you could just imagine a wet puddle on the ground in a
city that you're creating and you want it to reflect off of the reflect that not only the buildings
but also the reflection that's in the windows of the buildings.
And this is where the cycles rendering engine just takes off and escapes Evey.
Now of course that doesn't come free of charge cycles takes longer to render and that's one of the fundamental
reasons it does everything by default.
And you have to turn things off with cycles whereas with evil you have to remember to turn them on as
there we saw right at the very beginning that if you don't have screen space reflections turned on something
that should look really shiny fails to do so.
So I'm going to go ahead now and just need to add up my scene after I've been playing with it like that.
I'm going to get rid of my reflection planes.
I'm not going to use those.
So I'm going to get rid of this extra block and scale this one back down I might have to recreate it
later on anyway.
Doesn't matter.
Let's save that and also make the shall I keep the ground like that.
I'm going to keep the ground like that for the moment I think it's pretty cool but I'm not going to
make the ground and the block quite as shiny so I'm going to go to my material settings and perhaps
set it's a bit rough for maybe point one five.
There we go.
That's a bit better.
Okay.
That's it for this lecture I hope you've learnt quite a bit about why we're focusing on cycles so much
in this section as you can see it really is fundamentally different to Evey and I'll see you all in
the next lecture.