Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture instead of using extrusion we will use two curves in order to create our geometry that
has the advantage of being a lot smoother.
As we go up and meet at the middle.
In fact the curve will end up going all the way round.
If we want it to so curves are a little bit weird.
They don't always work very intuitively.
So what we're going to do in order to simulate this first is hide our original archway that we've created
in fact we've not called it archway so let's do that archway.
And we've also asked what anyway.
And we've also not put it in the building part of our collections.
Okay.
So that's sort of the door mirror.
She probably also put that in there as well.
Okay.
So are archway here.
I'm going to put here extrusion rather than anything else.
Okay.
And we go into take a copy of the base piece here so we can use it in our curve and you'll see it's
able to generate a much smoother transition but you'll also see that it doesn't quite follow the rules
you'd want it to.
Now there are a couple of ways in which we can do this.
I'm gonna go into edit mode and find the bottom face I'm going to duplicate it with shift and D I'm
then going to press pizza separator in separate of the selection.
Okay so let's convert this mesh object to a curve object it's an object operation so let's go back into
object mode object making sure we've got the archway curve selected and further down this list here
we go.
Convert to now these are grade outs at the moment suggests I've got more than one thing selected and
we will want this one here we want to create curve from mesh so that's D select everything and then
just select our arch recurve if you noticed there the orange that was it was highlighted with was a
dark orange meaning it was selected but it wasn't the active objects are object convert to there we
go we now have these options available to us and convert from mesh to the curve we can see that over
in the outline itself we now have the curve icon there rather than the mesh icon that's brilliant so
we can hide away our extruded archway and look at our curve now it needs to follow something that's
the important thing here but it doesn't always work as you would expect it to we can do the same trick
on the archway itself so I'm not sure if I go to edge Select and Select this front face and yes unfortunately
it's selected everything but it's going to be quite quick holding down shift and just selecting these
outer edges.
So what I had done there was I selected the loop the edge loop running around and I just remove these
last edges so I can then do the same thing here so we can duplicate that has a nice path for our curve
to follow and then we can go ahead and separate that and once again we need to give it a name and I
will call this archway curve again direction no curve direct I'm gonna have to put something here direction
and the other one is the archway profile that's important profile there we go.
Now the curve direction is still a mesh objects at the moment so let's go into object mode once again
with that selected Look it's dark orange it's not going to work the doorway is currently active selected
items so let's click on archway go that light orange color we can go to object convert to curve okay
we now have two curves which is brilliant because we can go to the first curve the direction that we
want it to follow go to the curve properties and then we can scroll down a little and go to the geometry
tab.
Now this is really awesome because it enables us to pick an object to be the beveled type.
So at the moment we can just increase the depth of the bevel and we get something like this happening
which is pretty awesome.
So you may think Okay brilliant or how about if I go ahead and select an object it's going to have to
be a curve and pick the archway profile hey would you look at that.
That's pretty awesome.
But then when you have a closer look at it you go Well hang on a minute why is that not going over what
I can see down there.
Oh interesting.
And this is one of the issues that you'll run into that the curves position in our 3D world matters.
So what doesn't matter is obviously where the archway is.
That's absolutely fine.
You need to have a path to follow.
But the other bits this archway profile here if we move that in object mode it doesn't make a difference.
However it's position from the origin of the world does make a difference.
So if I was to go ahead in edit mode looks slightly different because it's a curve select everything
and then move it around you can see it makes a difference.
You can see I've got two objects in here so the mirror is working but it's all the way over here.
Well that seems quite odd.
And of course it is the wrong way round.
So this takes a bit of playing around with to get your head around.
But because a curve is a two dimensional object we have to treat it as if it exists only on the x y
plane and we can see right here that these are just in the wrong place at the moment and they're probably
rotated round incorrectly as well.
So not only do we have to consider the curve object that's making the three dimensional shape it's pretty
awesome then it goes straight into there like clouds.
But if we have a look at the archway curve direction that we've made let's make sure we've got nothing
else selected.
So the curve direction that comes round if we go into edit mode on that and select we've got a couple
of options under the properties panel so we can bring this open with the end key and we've got these
three options down at the bottom mean Telstra's going to be the interesting one look at that we can
rotate it round and we can get it's almost to match.
So I think by moving it 90 degrees it looks like it lines up really well apart from this bit going across
the middle there's something funky happening there but there we go by moving the mean tale we've managed
to sort that's out but why is this bit going across here.
How is it being generated.
Well the plot thickens.
OK so let's go back to our archway profile and we can also rotate that's around as well.
Now I wouldn't recommend doing it around whatever I'm doing at the moment which looks like it's the
mirror point but let's change this to the medium point so I can rotate on the z axis and just move it
around so if we rotate it all the way around there that happens how about moving its Would you look
at that perhaps it needs to be over the middle here.
There's many many ways that you can go around and fiddle with this and you know it's pretty awesome
some of the shapes that you can make.
I can imagine this right now working really well as the outside entrance way.
So do feel free to play lots and lots and one of the issues that we've got happening here right now.
You notice that it also doesn't matter on the z plane if I just shift this up and down on the Z.
It really doesn't matter.
That's what I was saying but you have to just think about it as a 2D object.
I really liked by accident.
When I'm trying to show you what's going on.
But yes this will vary but the reason we have this double arch is because we don't need both of these.
If you go back to what we had before we just had it going up and down.
But with two of them we go up and down twice which is why when we shift this back we're able to get
ourselves an arch here and a very big arch as well.
Notice that the distance the same distance we've just moved it.
So in order to clean this up one of these has to be deleted and you're probably guess is this one here
deleting that's away and delete the vertices there and there we go.
That's pretty awesome.
The great thing about this of course is it means that our profile is following the curve of the archway.
Exactly.
If we bring up the other one that we've done we can see that it doesn't look like it's at all in fact
it's a bit shorter than what we might have got otherwise.
And of course you can use this as a basis.
We could go in now to the archway.
Which one is it's heavy extrusion.
Go into edit mode and adjust these faces so that they more match the curvature of the door itself.
Again that's entirely up to you and kind of just artistic license at this point in time.
But there we go there's profile modelling using curves.
Very easy to end up with doubles everywhere if you're not careful.
And again we can shorten this and then mirror it if we want and indeed you can go from the curve that
we currently have here the archway curves direction which is this object here.
And what we can do is we can solidify that if we want to which is really cool.
We can then convert this whilst we're not in edit mode it's only half the curve direction so let's say
go objects and then we can convert to mesh from a curve and we can keep the original.
I like keeping the original because it gives you the choice to change it later on if you need to or
you can just hide out of the way.
But then we end up with a mesh object in our scene.
It's the only one here at the moment so we can focus on it.
And there we go we can then do mesh operations on this if we wanted to like I think actually the subdivisions
surface modifier works on both of them but there we go by smoothing it out and maybe right clicking
and shading smooth we end up with a completely different aesthetic and this will give you an idea of
smooth shading within perhaps a game engine that's very important.
In fact let's lower the oil viewport shading is fine at one subdivision that won't increase the geometry
count too much in fact down at the bottom here we can say well actually the archway being maybe twelve
hundred faces might be a little bit much for the level of detail we're getting so let's remove it and
have a look at what it looks like with only 320 you know there's a little bit of balancing to go backwards
and forwards and again there's no reason why you can't go subdivision surface modifier and then pick
something like that decimates.
Now this sounds really weird to put the two together if I wouldn't do I don't know.
You know we've got some back down to maybe half of it even though we're subdividing then and subdivide
perhaps picking one of these other options would be better.
It's entirely up to you how you approach this type of work and ultimately it's in your game design documents
as well.
What's your polygon budget.
And sometimes it doesn't matter.
Modern game engines can probably run this absolutely fine and there's not going to be too many of them
in your scene.
Of course it will look much better as well when we get around to texturing it's of course the one thing
looking at the bottom of our model that we need to be careful with with the curve is it leaves it's
hollow and we we might want it filled in this particular case of being a game asset you can probably
leave that how it is you're never going to see that hollow however let's go back to the curve for a
moment and here we go has a low resolution version that we've got.
You can fill in these if we go to the make sure it's selected the curve properties.
Now where were we.
Let's go to our bevel.
There's an option here to fill caps and that will fill these n pieces really really useful if perhaps
you're doing a cable and it terminates in your scene.
You probably do want the ends caps.
I'm going to leave it uncapped because it adds as if I toggle this on and off it adds around 36 faces
and their triangular faces because the tri counts is also going up by 36.
Okay.
Awesome.
I'm going to get rid of my mesh version of the archway so that select that and get rid of it and turn
back on my doorway.
Excellent.
Now if you have gone ahead using the curves and it made an awesome doorway please do share it over and
the discussions are really look forward to seeing it.
And I'll see you all in the next lecture.