Welcome to transparent backgrounds in this bonus video going to learn how to set up your background
as transparence.
The options are different in both blender render and cycles so we'll cover both of those and they're
relatively straightforward.
However the options are hidden in a way and what you'll end up with as as you can see here you end up
being able to present a model on to a background because the background itself is transparent.
And let's go explore this now and hop on over into blender.
Okay so we're over in blender here and let's just go ahead and render our scene.
I'm going to hit off 12 to do that now we can see on the info head a bar and obviously by this rendering
itself being so starkly contrasted it is blender render.
And you can see the background here is still grey when it's transparent you get that kind of chequered
effect.
Now if we export this as is in going to file and save an image then we're going to end up with this
key with a grey background on it which is not what we want we want the cube isolated from the rest of
the scene.
So how do you do that.
Well it's in the render properties for both blender render and cycles.
But it's in different places.
Logical Yes.
Okay.
So we need to scroll down and t find shading it's probably collapsed as mine is here.
If we go ahead and open that up we have a series of options and we need to change the option that says
Alpha changed that from sky to transparence.
Now when we go ahead and render our image you can see that the background itself has this chequered
appearance.
And then you can go ahead and get an image and save an image.
Now I am going to I've already saved one here as a test the one you saw a moment ago.
I'm going to set one up that's for Blender render and I'm going to savour in a few moments.
But before we do let's go down to the lower left hand corner and have a look at the options.
So we've got a P N G select.
At the moment which does contain an alpha layer.
However sometimes a production of a PRNG with a now fired out layer especially there's a gradient between
it be the cue for instance is just a solid edge so that's fine if you have a graduated something like
a light effect or a particle effect.
Then you may want to select something different.
You may wish to select tiff.
Now it's going to produce a larger file but it's going to handle the Alpher layer much better than potentially
the PRNG does.
But Store is a PRNG first see how it works and if you end up with a slight halo effect around your image
when you apply it to a background then you probably want to try a different formats colour depth where
most people don't have the ability to see more than 8 bits on their monitors so you can leave it as
that.
However if your models be made for a high dynamic range environment.
HRT visa starts to come around and monitors won't be far behind.
I'm sure you'll want to make sure that's set to 16 bits.
In some ways you know it is better to have the highest quality possible but on the same fronts you don't
need extra where it's not going to make any difference whatsoever.
So with that selected I can go ahead and click save image and now I've got an image on my computer with
an outfit out background that I can now apply to whatever I want.
So we've explored that in blender render how do we do it in cycles.
Well we can switch over to the cycles render engine first so we can see what's going on.
The rendering properties change quite dramatically when this happens.
And in order to render the background transparent we need to change a couple of options.
So let's first of all render it as it is and see what happens.
Now I'm currently using my CPA to render and it's taking a little while to do harm but I'm going to
switch across to GP you now.
I'm also going to change my samples.
No not samples.
I'm going to change my proof under my performance setting this ungeared a set her 2 5 6 2 5 6 for the
moment so it renders a bit quick for you guys.
So where in this muddle of options do we change to make this background transparent.
Well it's under the film dropdown This may or may not be open for you so fine.
The film properties and put a tick in transparent and there we can see that if we hover over the world
background is transparent.
Now when we go ahead with that box checked and we hit render we get it rendered out with feet.
Alpher layer and once again you can go ahead and save that's to your hard drive.
There we go.
Nice and straightforward.
But it is a little bit complicated where they've hidden it away.
I hope you find that incredibly helpful.
And we'll see you guys in the next lecture.