Welcome to linking blend files making local in this video you'll learn why you want to make a link they
to block local understand we are starting to sever links by doing this.
Learn about the various stages of making it local and decide when would be a good time to localize that
data block.
So let's go over a couple of advantages and disadvantages that this does.
So one of the advantages is you will have more local control you will have to keep opening up a separate
blender file and modifying it before seen the changes in your scene search can be a bit quicker.
Working with it on this way.
External files if they're moved the project can stay together which is very useful especially if you're
working in a team or you want to deviate from a path and test something out.
Perhaps now potentially there's a disadvantage there's more work involved.
And we have to be careful that when we decide to make something local that we do really don't need that
link anymore.
Or which links do we need and which ones do we not need.
Remember that any edits that you make on the original affect all linked data blocks but not the ones
made local.
So when do you localize.
Well when the link is not required I know that's a bit woolly at this point in time.
How do I know whether the links are not required.
Well if that's the question you are asking then perhaps you shouldn't be actually making something local.
So when you want to make the asset unique in this particular file so say you were building up this building
and that we've generated a textual and material that go along with this but you want to take it off
on a different direction see what it looks like.
As with a different material applied to it a chrome finish to the wall says or Mary whatever you want
to do with it.
Well this may be a time to make the material date or block unique so you don't have to make everything
unique you can make individual parts of the linked file unique and local to the blend file that you're
working on.
The other thing is when you want to make changes irrelevant to other potential projects.
So we certainly don't want to change the material of a wall that we create just so effects this one
because if we're linking that in any other projects that we're working on if we've got a nice assets
store and we don't want to go ruining every other project we've got with changes that are specifically
local.
Hint there to this scene that we're working on.
So we've got four options.
Option one selected objects.
So what that does is it clone's the object data block and anything in the hierarchy beneath it to the
new blend file all the other data blocks remain linked to the other file.
And this allows changing of anything in the object data block.
So now we can scale it rotate it a movie etc. but it does sever that first link.
Option 2 is a little bit more selected objects and data so this close the object and the data.
Data block to that a new blender file in this allows editing of the mesh data.
Breaking that link and making it a local file now is important.
If that happens any meche data that you update on the original will not come through.
So that's great if you're trying to make a particular part fit an awkward place in your scene but don't
want to edit the original the materials and the other data blocks remain linked to the original objects.
If you go ahead and change or update any of those when you open up your blend file again you will find
that those come in to this blown thing.
Option three.
Well as you can probably guess the selected objects data and materials clone's the object the data and
the materials data block making all of those available for editing.
This allows the editing of all of those data blocks and breaks those links making them local to this
file option for.
And this is the final one.
All as it sounds this is exactly the same actually not pretty much the same but exactly the same a pending
the object into the scene is now entirely local with no links at all to the original file.
You can do whatever it was it's is if you had made it in this particular blend file.
So now we've had an overview of all the different ways that low calls can happen.
Let's go experience this and hop on over in a blender.
Okay so we are back over in blender and I want to demonstrate this making local.
So the first thing I'm going to do is actually bring in something else so I can work rivets in a link.
I'm going to go in two or are meshes.
I'm going to bring in my mannequins so I can work on that.
In the scene around object mannequin and link from Library.
So that's now in here.
Now I don't have to make it a proxy first.
I can make some of it local straightaway and we can do that under the object menu just like before.
And we've got this make local and you can see the shortcut key is the L key and the here are the four
selected objects.
And here are the four selections that we've gone through the selected objects the selected objects and
data which will then enable us to let's say move it rotate it scale it and then we've got enable us
to edit it enables us to change the materials and just the same as a pending and instead of clicking
one of these at the moment we're going to have another look because we know we can do these but these
don't give us full control or we can make a decision about each one of these items completely individually.
So let's make sure the mannequin or whatever you've brought in is selected.
And then we are going to first of all take a look at the major ones here.
So this mannequin I know has object data and we can see it's greyed out at the moment.
We have meshed data just here and moving forward.
We have material data now the mesh and material data are part of the object data so there's no making
that local just at the moment.
What we'd need to do first is work down that hierarchy.
So in this case and here's the material laid out here we can see they're all links the mesh data is
linked.
The material is linked and the object data is linked.
So let's go to the object data first and there's a little button on the end of the name the object data
itself and that will click to make it local.
Perfect.
That's the same as pressing L over here and doing selected objects.
The moment we've done that what clicked on this button here we can see that this is no longer greyed
out and is enabled for editing.
That's now local to this file any object data that we change in the source file will not be updated.
Now that does allow us to move it about.
So it's very similar to making that proxy.
However it has now broken the object data link so have we changed any of these other items in the object
data block.
It would not transpire it will not come across to this blend file anymore.
If we go down to the next area which is the mesh data itself that is greyed out and we can click here
and make it local of who we want and that will enable editing.
So now when we hit tab it actually goes into edit mode and we can go about editing this little mannikin.
Perfect.
Well so we have we have the material the materials are still linked as well.
So at any point we can bring in the material that says materials 001 Here's a not very well named.
We can see that is a linked material which means if we change that in the source file even though the
mash data and the object data are now local to this file if we go ahead and change that it will update
here.
I'm going to go demonstrate that right away.
So what I would do is I will make sure I save the file I'm working on hop over to this other file and
just play with it for a moment.
First of all I'm going to change the material how I'm going to rename it.
I'm going to call it manequin rough material.
So I know what it is now that I've renamed That's what I will need to do to make sure it's absolutely
clear.
Is go ahead and change the colour.
I'm going to change it to a bright yellow and hop into material mode to make sure that's happened it
has perfect save the file.
Again this is a rough file so I don't mind playing with it.
And let's say on here we want to give them a pened nokio knows sons are going to select a couple of
faces here and pull it out.
It's going to grab that and proportional editing down a little.
There we go we've got a nose coming out I'm going to lock it to the y axis completely.
So our mannequin now has a nose and a save the file.
And when I go and open up the Gothic church that I'm putting together we will see that the linked data
has been severed.
This mesh isn't updating and because we changed the name of that material that has also disappeared
and we can't even see that in the materials list anymore because we've severed the object data which
itself contained the mesh data and the material data along with it.
Now that's not a big deal we can go and link that bit back in straightaway we can go file out we can't
do it in edit mode so let's hop into object mode and go to link we've got the mannequin here.
I'm going to go up a level go to material and here we go because we've removed the other material it's
just disappeared it's as if we've deleted it and if we go ahead and open up that material we can then
assign its note as it had.
LS 0 initially has now gone because I was very quick and clicked on it and that's now applied to here
and we've got ourselves a yellow mannequin Okay.
Let's go in just experiment once more and make sure that wasn't a fluke.
Let's go and save the file.
Let's change that mannequin serial colour to something else let's change it to a green or a red.
I'm gonna change it to a green save the file and now because I've not updated the name.
We should find that it comes across Green.
Perfect.
Okay so a quick challenge for you guys.
What would you make local think about what's in your scene at the moment.
If you've already done a range of parts into your interior design and think about do you need to make
anything local.
Have you designed your design so that's not applicable that is entirely possible.
And if you do need to make anything local think about why you would want to make it local and which
data blocks if any you would make local.
Now do think carefully about whether you need to do that now or whether you're going to develop your
model a little and do that later.
I'm sure at some point you are going to have to make some of your meche or materials local to the particular
scene especially if you're experimenting with multiple scenes with the same building blocks coming in.
You might want to make a red building or a yellow building or green building.
Obviously while it might not be if it is a kid's toy building then you might be making then that bright
colour.
But you may be doing subtle shades of sandstone or granite or something along those lines where you
want to change the material but only locally in this particular file.
And that's a great way of using the same mesh but actually making it look completely different by changing
the material applied to that mesh.
Anyway enough of me rambling I'd like you to go and pause a video and give that ago.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's go hop back on over in a blender.
So the first thing that I'm going to do here is just lay out my pieces and see what I've got to work
with.
Okay.
So there we go.
There's my pieces all laid out ready to start organizing into certain sections and I've just glanced
at Wikipedia in fact wonderful place for research.
The parts of a church because I hadn't actually got a clue or clue what they called so I'm going to
have to make some empties Now just to represent those particular parts of the church so I'll be back
in a few moments.
Okay so I've gone ahead and created empties for the five main parts of the church that I'm creating.
And I need to organize is a bit better at the moment because I've got it in alphabetical order essentially
which is very difficult when I want to group them by type.
So we're going to go to the View menu here and sort alphabetically I'm going to turn that off.
And there we go we've now linked by an empty then meche object down here which is much better for me.
The next thing for me to do is start organizing these parts.
Actually in these set scenes so I'm going to start with the nave and the isles which are going to make
up the main body of the church itself sort out all the ancillary bits afterwards.
So I'm going to start building this up and I'm going to use Linked duplicates of these particular items
in order to construct my church so I'll be back with you guys once again in a few moments once I put
these bits all together.
Now before I got going to sort these out into their various empties over here the first thing I did
was make a parts empty and put everything into that.
Now in order to start using these bits what I'm going to do is I'm going to select them all straight
away so I can use them in my model and then go object to link duplicate of course the shortcut key is
Oulton.
And we've got our duplicate objects there but they're still under the weather still under the parts
empty as a parents.
So at this point in time whilst they're still selected what I can do is just hide all of the other empties
apart from the one that I want to work and I want to work on the naved to begin with.
So now because all of those are currently selected than the last one I selected that was the archway
at the top.
I've already forgotten what that's called but I can now click because the only empty left is this one
here I kind of clicked in the outline here but I can also now select it in the 3D view as well.
And then I can press control and pay a parent object and then move those copy linked copies.
That's very important across.
That also means that now I can make sure when I select the parts and everything under the parts itself
that we can move that to layer to in fact all of these other ones need to be on layer 1 that we're working
on.
We need to select everything under here and we can do that by control clicking on the nave itself and
then try moving it to lay a 1.
Now when we have a look at Layer 1 we should have all of our bits there layer 2 will also have all of
our parts.
Brilliant.
So let's go ahead now and assemble this.
I am midway through my construction at the moment and I will just say at this point in time that the
wireframe mode is incredibly useful for lining things up.
If I didn't have wire framo turned on that's the Z key.
Just remember all you can do it down here on the 3d editor head a bar switch to wireframe And then when
I'm looking it's hit from the sides.
I can actually move things exactly into the position they need to be in in the course if I'm zoomed
in enough with the increment snap turned on it allows me very fine control.
Excellent.
Let's carry on with the building.
Okay I'm finally at the end of my assembly stage so I've assembled as you can see some corner pieces
here to make a funky outside.
Know we're working our interiors but I feel I look pretty cool.
So I did it is as simple as that from the top.
Let's zoom round to the top.
We've got the rough shape that we want going on there.
I've added a bit of a side door in terms of the organization of this I have in each area so whether
it's the entrance the Charles or the tower etc..
I have sub areas so in the entrance I have the entrance way sealing the walls the floor etc. and what
that enables me to do as was holding down control is I can start to remove bits from the scene very
quickly.
By control clicking the little icon there so I can go through here and remove the tower.
And I go through and it lets say move the aisles ceiling etc. So there's lots of powerful things that
I can do by going through here and because I built up in such a way I can actually just remove bits
as and when I want.
Now a couple of things that I have made local here.
One of them was this bit at the very end so I have basically made this part to fit in here and I can
take it out the scene and work on it.
Otherwise I'm with them and actually turn smooth shading on.
On this particular part whilst I'm here to remember so that part has now been made and is ready.
So that's the last last bit at the end of the church there.
None of these are changed from their standard layout.
Probably gone to add some sort of funky window in there.
Again I'll look up reference material to work out there but that's later on it's a bit of detail.
I've added a doorway down here and let's just turn back on the tower and the entrance way.
The towers got a unique part at the top as well because that's a slightly smaller one than the main
roof sections down here but it's a similar style.
It's just been made to fit this area here so that's also a local part as well as this one.
On the end here.
Brilliant.
How did you guys get on.
I'd love to see the church design you've come up with.
Remember to share them in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.