Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to discuss bridging edge loops.
Now the pawn you see in front of you is not the same pawn we've been working on.
I just went in and very quickly used a tool called bridging edge loops to make such a porn from a single
circle.
So this is another way of creating our models and it has the benefits of where two objects before we're
joined together.
There is now no intersecting geometry.
This does not pass inside itself but we can repair other models as well so that doesn't happen.
Let us dive into a default blend file and find out more.
Okay so wit our default cube in front of us here.
If I go into edit mode because bridging edge loops is an edit mode operation and duplicate my cube and
just move it over here what we can do is we can select a series of edges that we want to join together
so we can select this edge here and let's say this top one here.
Now I've been deliberate on selecting edges of course we could have just selected these two faces as
well because when you select all of the edges that make up a face you naturally select the face as well.
So now that we've got these two faces selected I'm going to press F3 and search for bridging edge loops
or bridge edge loops.
When I press enter you can see they join straight away.
That's pretty awesome.
Now what else can we do.
Well we can open up the operator panel and we can see here we've got a couple of options.
We can merge them together.
That's kind of cool isn't it.
That makes a much different object but it also distorts the very top.
But what we can do there is we can add a series of cuts into smooth that out.
We can change the blend path as well so we can make it linear with more cuts throughout it like it was
before we can do a blend path.
We can do a blend surface it tries to smooth out the surface itself and of course we can change the
profile as it goes through as well.
And the profile shape.
That's pretty awesome for making some ducting or pipe work between two sections.
Very very useful.
The other thing that we can do here is we can add a slight twist if you want to.
Now you can see there it changes quite dramatically because we're on a low poly state so twisting it
around makes a huge difference.
So is perhaps not what we're looking for here but the other thing bridging edge loops can do is not
only join two surfaces like this but say we had inset this surface here and this surface over here.
If we select both of those sets of edges and bridge edge loops we can actually make a hole through something.
So that's again really really useful if you need to do that through an object.
If you put two circles either side you can punch through a hole in your model that is pretty awesome.
This is coming together to quite a nice little exercise here right.
The next thing that I wanted to discuss with bridging loops is how they can help you overcome intersecting
geometry.
So first of all what is intersecting geometry.
So let's go ahead.
Whilst in one object so it can be with multiple mesh objects.
But if we just take a single mesh object as an example and add in a cylinder and let's move it up here.
This geometry is intersecting with itself.
So if we go into wireframe mode and have a look through our model we can see that this geometry goes
inside another bit of geometry.
Now depending on what you're doing that will leave a matter or it will not.
And it can matter for two distinct reasons.
The firstly is this would break something.
So if we wanted to 3D printing the model that you can see in front of us here it wouldn't work it would
fail.
It's a non manifold object.
It has bits inside of itself.
And in general that's the main reason why you'd want to watch out for intersecting geometry is that
it means that you will not be able to,
Let's say in this case 3D print this model, you may also be unable to do certain physics calculations
or particle effects.
If your models are actually within each other.
So that's something to bear in mind.
Now you could use a boolean operation to make these things stick together as one whole object that is
always one option but that also creates a ton of extra geometry as well.
But these are separate at the moment we kept them as separate so I can just go ahead and delete that
extra bit of geometry and I wanted to just come in here select these two faces, inset them and bridge
loops and there you go we've got another hole in the top perhaps a vent remember you can inset multiple
faces at the same time with the top and bottom selected I'm going to inset and then I'm going to bridge
edge loops and we get a nice hole through and of course if you then selected these faces and these inner
faces and did a similar operation here we should find that it puts a box through the middle.
That's pretty awesome.
There's lots of fun to be had with bridging edge loops.
So the final example I want to show you is when you do have something that is intersecting what can
you do.
Well let's add in another cube because when you're bridging edge loops you have to have a similar set
of edges to bridge.
So let's go ahead shift this up ever so slightly.
Now there is intersecting and we can see that's the case.
I'm going to scale it down and still place it roughly inside the other model.
So what can we do here to make sure that these end up being bridged together you get real geometry from
the results.
So the first thing is going into wireframe mode to see if there's any intersecting geometry and there
is in this case we've got this face.
Can I select it.
Hopefully I'll be able to select it.
There we go.
And this face of a ones that really need bridging.
So if I come out into solid shade, hold down shift and I can select that edge.
So those are the two that really need bridging together.
Now it's not coming to a point so we don't need to delete any extra information but when it's like that,
what we can then do is think carefully about where we want to join.
So with both of those faces selected what we can then do is press F3 search for bridge edge loops.
And there we go.
They are now joined together and we can check that by placing your cursor over a bit of geometry and
pressing the L key we can now see that they are linked.
If I was to undo that and press the L key you can see they're still separated.
So having one contiguous mesh like that is a good sign that you haven't got geometry inside of itself
is not certain but it's a good test right.
So we've played with the three dimensional objects and joining those together.
There is one final way that you can use this to your advantage.
I'm just going to get rid of all the vertex data that we've got there and I'm going to add in instead
of a anything else I'm going to add in a circle.
Now circle doesn't have any faces on it.
So this is going to be a pure edge loop, I'm going to make it eight.
Much like our pieces are and you can see from this.
This is how you could potentially whilst in edit mode duplicate.
Lift up, scale in, duplicate.
Lift up, scale out, duplicate, lift up, scale in, if we select all of those edges and bridge edge loops.
We get ourselves a shape really quickly.
So this is one construction method if you chose to use it that you could make your models with, pretty
awesome how we managed to get that far.
But what you can also do with things like this is very much like the box scenario earlier I can duplicate
that.
I've got a new set of edges I'm going to lift them up I can rotate them on the X axis by 45 degrees.
I can then duplicate it move it over on the Y axis for instance and rotate it on the X axis by 45 degrees
just to make a 90 degree turn and then of course I can adjust them accordingly to make sure it flows
round as you'd expect it to.
And then I can select all of those edge loops and then bridge them, So bridge edge loops.
There we go.
Now I might want to turn up the number of cuts and this is starting to look like a bit of industrial
pipe work.
And remember you can change with the profile factor as it goes round if you want a more higgledy piggledy
look.
And of course you can play with some of the other options like the profile shape if you keep it linear,
if you make it a route, if you make it smooth throughout.
Of course if you introduce more and more cuts you can get a much smoother profile but just bear in mind
it really should match the rest of your model.
So in this case I would say about three two or three cuts matches the base level of geometry.
You run the risk of course if you had too much geometry up here it makes the whole model uneven and
it doesn't look the same.
That's a pretty awesome shape.
So now that we've covered bridging loops it's time for your challenge. Okay.
So your challenge I'd like you to first of all finish off the pawn.
Now some of you might be saying well Mike is finished off isn't there.
It looks like it but there were a couple of things that I want to make sure that this pawn has additional
specifications as it were.
And this will apply to all of the other pieces as well.
Make sure the model is a contiguous mesh.
I don't want different parts of the model to be selectable.
I want it to be one continuous mesh throughout.
And finally no intersecting geometry.
This will make sure that if later on we decide to 3D print our models we have that sorted.
If you've got geometry inside itself it will just fail.
Suppose a video now and finish off your pawn
Okay everybody, Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and finish off the pawn.
Okay so we've got on my funky it reminds me a bit of a gramophone actually if I scale this one out.
Anyway right.
So let's save that as a gramophone.
But elsewhere I'll just pop it in my documents.
OK.
So back to the pawn that we've been working on.
I'm liking the look of it so far.
Problem of course is it does have intersecting geometry but this is one of those bits of intersecting
and geometry that we're going to have to remove something from first.
So I'm going to remove this vertex at the bottom.
That will leave us a separated mesh that then we can join together.
So let's go ahead and do that make change making sure we select the right edge loops.
There we go.
F3 bridge edge loops.
Now you probably noticed that blender remembers what you searched for last.
Which is incredibly useful.
And let's just have a look at the overall shape and feel of our model turn back on my image and I'm
going to pop my model into wireframe so I can see, now you can't do it by just changing the rendering
of the viewport it's an object property. So let's scroll down viewport display and display as a wire.
Oh and switch this to lookdev so I can see my texture and then I get an appreciation of how this
object to the top is working.
Now of course I can't select individually anymore.
So actually the way that I've done things there the order in which I've done things has meant that I
cannot do the quick change that I wanted to do by just selecting all linked geometry.
So what's I'm going to do instead is select the top vertex and just hold down control and the numpad
plus you can also use select and select more and less if you wanted to.
I'm going to go control and plus plus plus plus plus and that one there and I'm just going to scale
that down ever so slightly and then go G Z and bring it down as well, Then i'm going to turn the display back off to
see textured so I can see it again.
And there we go.
Now I think I also need to bring down this edge slightly so I am going to do that and probably scale
it in at the same time, In fact if I scale into around there.
That means the edge is superfluous.
I don't need it anymore if it's in line.
Mm hmm.
Now there is an option for me what I'm gonna do instead is I'm going to scale that in even further and
then just lift it up a little bit more.
There we go.
And then alter this edge loop here just a little by shifting up okay.
Let's come out.
Hide my image at the back into object mode and have a look around my model.
Now of course when you're looking around your model do remember you've got different shading options.
If we turn back to solid we also have the option of MatCap which is really useful it really helps
bring out the shape of your objects and we can click this little sphere here to pick different objects
you will often see people in their sculpting using this one here which is a clay type.
It's a very matt color but it helps you see the form and shape of your objects.
And of course you could pick something else here if you wanted a bit more funky or glossy but that won't
affect the end result when we render.
That's just how we're looking at it now in the viewport almost like my standard one just here.
I'm pretty happy with that.
Okay.
How are you guys getting on.
Have you managed to make your object completely sealed as one mesh with no intersecting geometry.
Did you struggle to do that.
Let us know in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.