Welcome to particle editing in this video.
You'll be introduced to the part Cool Edit option.
Learn how to edit the particle's style the hairs to make them flow in a more natural manner and learn
how to reset the hairs back to their default state.
So let's hop straight on over into blender.
Okay so we have our fluffy bunny in front of us here with the new materials applied but we want to style
this hair because at the moment it's just sticking straight out of the mesh underneath.
Pretty much straight upwards like it was a series of normals coming out of our mesh so we need to style
this and make it flow in the way that it would flow naturally with an animal.
So with the objects selected in this case the rabbits that the particle system is attached to under
where it says object mode here we can change the interaction to particle edit and it's got a picture
of a comb.
And if we click that the screen changes ever so slightly and we get this in front of us.
Now I'm going to quickly on the properties window over here.
Just click on be cool over here and we will see the moment.
Well at the moment it's grey doubts but the moment that we actually do something we can in particle
edit we cannot actually change anything that's over here anymore so we can't add more hairs.
We can't change the hair length etc. The moment we start doing things at the moment if we hop back into
object mode I can add more hairs I can remove hairs I can do lots of things still.
However the moment we go to particle it changes to this and we can see we've got a couple of options
over on the tool shelf.
Here we have a series of brush types similar to how we've had them before with the sculpting that we
did earlier.
Now just like before if I there's no brush selected at the moment if I click on comb it has a radius
and a strength just like it did before.
And he used the same keys the F key to make the brush bigger and smaller.
And you can use the shift in F key to change the strength of that brush.
Right.
And there are a series of options down here.
Now when I click wait it will crash my system.
So that's important to know.
Your system may crash if you click on wait so don't click on it.
If you're in the middle of something important to I believe it's to do with the number of particles
that are currently on the scene itself.
If I reduce the number of particles it doesn't seem to happen.
But then of course I don't have a fluffy bunny I've got a very bold Bunny.
So komer does exactly what it sounds like it's going to do something to reduce the radius again.
And if I just left click and drag across our model we can see though I can start combing my model.
Now the.
Limit selection to visible talk or does work with this.
So I've actually brushed the hair on the other side as well.
But from this perspective so it's not quite Howard want it to be.
Of course you can brush that down like this like it would be on a real rabbit.
And you can spend a lot of time brushing your virtual rabbit or grooming a virtual rabbit to make it
look better.
And then of course I'm just going to add a note.
Give it a Mohawk in the middle just there.
There are loads of different options here.
So we've got smooth which will smooth out the differences as you go through.
Now that adds hairs and that's one of the reasons why now we can't add it over here.
We can change the length so we can grow and shrink it.
Very very powerful.
But we going to use a different method of determining length.
But you can certainly make some minor alterations here if you want puff will puff it out and cut will
remove.
Now a note about cuts and I'll do it now for you just to show you.
It cuts hairs but it cuts hairs completely off.
Now once you've cut them off Unfortunately there's no way of adding them back to where they were before.
You'd have to add them back with the ADD brush which you can see straight away is going to take a lot
longer to do then removing them.
So use the cart with caution.
That's why I'd say and I'm not going to click on weight.
As I've said before it crashes blender.
So I'm going to avoid clicking on that so be interesting to know and do Potin discussions if it also
crashes on your system whether it's a little bug that I have or whether it's a general one.
Okay.
And obviously.
And looking at the brush types with Cone there's no difference that's going to undo several times to
see if I can get back to a hairy Bunny.
There we go we have certain brush types like lenk for instance we can grow and shrink.
So if you were thinking about removing some hairs perhaps you'd want to shrink them back and create
more of a stubble I suppose then actually cutting them off.
But that would depend on your application.
And we're going to use slightly different methods for controlling our hair growth over our body as well.
So we've got a bit more control than this arbitrary cutting back etc..
And if we look down there's something very interesting here that deflect emitter.
So again I'm just going to undo my length changes that I had there and now that deflects amounts here
the distance changes so I'm going to send it back to comb up here it changes the skin of our rabbit
the actual underlying mash deflects.
So if I set that to zero there's a good chance there's some point I will push a hair into the model
and essentially create an ingrowing hair.
But of course when that happens if we quickly switch to rendered mode I'm going to select this area
here to render.
And if I hop into rended mode here.
Oh and that's another thing to tell you when you're in particle edit the render mode won't show anything
you have to hop back out of that.
And we see that with that will probably do various assuming it changes.
It's got a bold patches there when we've brushed it.
If we go back into particle edits and increase this amount to one point eight which is lots.
Now when we brush over our model and we hop back on over into object mode we can see that the hairs
are much better and you will have to keep going back and forth.
I'm just going to draw a bigger render border here because that's a bit small.
There we go.
And remember this isn't the final render amount that is determined down here with the display number.
So if I increase that's maybe 25 we'll get a better impression of the thickness and we can see it's
being Kome go over there and if we hop back on over into particle it and we can't see it when it's like
that so we need to hop into solid mode as well and we can comb about here we can puff the hair out.
We can even add length to it if we want but we'll be doing a different method of controlling the length
later on.
However for mine the changes at the moment this would be a great way of making those little tweaks.
Now of course when we hop back in surrendered mode and into objects he'll take a few seconds to do.
And as you can see there I've actually made the hair quite long and brisley so I don't know what that's
actually going to look like quite strange I should imagine.
Yes very quickly.
Great.
Finally if you've ever done something and it's irreversible like cut all the hair off.
Don't worry about it because in particle editing properties window over here towards the top there's
a button that says Free edit.
Now when you click on that it does say youre going to lose.
The change is done in particle mode and that will reset it back to how it was before you started playing
about and styling the hair.
Okay guys.
Its challenge time.
I'd like you to style the bunny's hair so spend a few minutes trying out the different styling tools.
Create a few styles.
Now don't spend too long in the style at this time.
For starters it's a prototype.
Were nowhere near the finished model at the moment and also were likely to in a few moments have to
reset it anyway.
Now when you've done this when you've done new styles do share in the discussions I'd love to see the
hairstyles that you've come up with.
Perhaps you've given the rabbit aside partyin.
Who knows.
Also please share that in the discussion so pause a video now and go ahead and style the bunny's hair.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's hop straight back over into blender.
Okay so let's go ahead and style our bunny.
So the first thing I'm going to do is just come out of rendered mode for the moment and hop into solid
mode and I'm going to just clear that render border so there's less on the screen.
Once I press the right key combination there we go.
So now that we've got this here what I'm going to do is go over into particle edit.
Now in general if you look and make sure the comb sighted and in general if you look at an animal most
of the fur falls downwards with gravity so it's worthwhile remembering that.
And what we can do here is with limited selection to visibility turned off and I can view it from the
side it doesn't matter which side at this point.
Well with the background it does.
Well that can help us.
But I would just turn the A pastie on the background image background image.
Here we go.
I'll just turn that down a little so I can see more of my model.
Well let's have a look at the proper thing.
So we've got a lot of hair going down here.
When it comes down here and all the hair on their head does go backwards as well towards the ears and
upwards and a little bit downwards here so we can use that.
I'm just going to turn on and off rather than looking at it so we can pull our model down now.
What's deflect deflect to me it is quite high at the moment sundermann Lower that back down to around
point five.
Otherwise I can't get the hair close to the body.
I'm just going to pull it down now because I've got the limit selection so visibility turned off will
go round the other side.
It's combed it round in a symmetrical way.
Now there is an X mirror here but it doesn't seem to work at this point in time.
So now we've got that there that's do this bottom bit as well.
Now bear in mind the bottom is not going to be seen as hot background to the side view.
The left hand side and I'm going to have a look at the head.
Now of course we want this hair all brushed back.
And if you want to do some detail around the ice you can do.
And then pull it down towards the neck just here so you can have a lot of fun playing with the Komen
brushing in fact you probably spend a couple of hours on a more detailed model just getting the hair
looking roughly right now V is for the moment.
Well I don't want hair on the air so I could actually cut it off.
But for humor's sake I'm just going to brush everything up so it's got spiky ears.
Now of course we need to remember the middle of heads.
It's got a mohawk going on at the back here.
There we go.
All combed back.
We got a few stragglers there.
Let's push those up and push those up as well.
So we we've pretty much combed all of the hair on the bunny.
Now that's part from the few little stragglers but that's absolutely fine.
So let's go and have a look how it actually looks in rendered mode.
Oh yes.
We've got a pink bunny here that's obviously the skin colour at that point was still in particle.
So that's out there and have a look at this model here that just kind of gives us a little inkling of
where the problem areas may end up being.
There's a few tufts coming out in random places.
So let's pull that back fair.
And there was a little bit around here that's brush that down and let's just have another look in object
mode.
Yeah that looks a bit better I don't mind a few tufts coming out.
And let's go and render that now.
Okay lovely.
So that's got a quite nice shine to it.
By the looks of things so we'll need to work on the materials later on for the hair because obviously
that was a well conditioned Bunny by the looks of things and there are a few things here to sort out
like round the eyes etc..
But we're going to do that in a slightly different way rather than just trimming the hair back etc.
but that's a that's a pretty good first attempt at just brushing your hair back and seeing how it looks.
Remember to share your bunny in the discussions I'd love to see the styles that you've put out and I
will see you guys in the next lecture.
Take care.