Wow what a ride that was really exciting getting that plane flying across the scenery like that.
I have lots of fun and I hope you did too.
I do remember to show your work.
I love seeing what you guys come up with.
And of course if you haven't followed along exactly with me it would be great to see what you have done
yourselves and don't stop there.
Please take what you know blend and what you've learned about VFX from Mikey and do some other cool
stuff whatever you've dreamed of whatever compositing whatever fake UFO sighting you want to create
and create the negative viral facebook.
Awesome.
Please do it.
Please share with us and a great place to share his community.
Game def TV.
You guys the blender community are the most active part of that community at least when we recorded
this video and that is fantastic.
You share your model you can share them in 2D.
You can share them with sketch fab in 3D.
Movable models but not cfx of course video put video in there do what you like but please share with
other people.
The greats show off make monkey proud.
Thanks.