Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture I want to talk briefly about sharing your work and where you can get help from if necessary.
So if you're struggling with a lecture or you don't understand something that's been said you can always
go and browse the Q and A on udemy and if you click on that link down there it will open up and you
can ask for a question you can even search for questions that have already gone.
Now what I would ask you please to do is not post your pictures in the Q and A if you do that it really
makes it difficult for us to go through and actually find genuine questions.
If you've got an image to share it's much better shared in two different places.
Let me close down the questions for the moment and go over to resources available in the top left.
If I go down to this lecture which in this case is lecture 11 there is this lectures discussions.
If I click on that it will take me to this particular place on our forum.
So this is a place where you can share your work.
And if we go into here this is the end of section challenge of this particular section that people are
taking and they've shed loads and loads of work.
It's a much better place much easier to see what is going on this is absolutely fantastic.
But it's also a great place to get feedback constructive feedback and if you're struggling with a more
challenging topic.
Now the other place that some people may have and some people might like is to go to the blender course
community sit w w w dot Facebook dot com forward slash groups forward slash blender course and they'll take
you to our blender website where you can join over 11000 other students just like yourself trying out
different things in Blender playing with 2.8.
It's amazing the community welcomes everybody so please do come along and join and share your work help
others as well if you're a bit more experienced.
The final place I just want to show you very briefly is more of a life thing that's always a discussion
going on.
No one's around just at the moment early in the morning on a Monday but on the game day of official
discord you can go to hash blender and discuss your work there as well.
There's always someone about so do ask a question in there as well.
And one of the community will be happy to help you I'm sure.
So in summary if you've got a question about the course and the content within the course itself ask
in the Q and A's if not follow the links in the lecture discussions or go directly over to the community
websites and join in over there to share your work.
Of course you're free to share over on the blender Facebook group as well.
And if you've got any quick questions you may be able to get a very quick answer over on the Discord
channel.
And finally one of the things I really love is seeing your work it really inspires me as a teacher to
see beginners become proficient in this skill whether you're starting off as a complete beginner or
you've come back to experience 2.8 from the very beginning and you've already got a bit of Blender
under your belt.
I love seeing the transformation within you so please do share your work.
I'm looking forward to seeing it and I'll see you all in the next lecture.
Take care.