In this video we're gonna be experimenting a bit more with hair we're gonna be giving hairstyles doing
a bit of combing and brushing and moving around hair particles to create different effects with our
hair.
Okay let's start a new project file new general I've already done that.
So this is what it looks like now.
It's going to turn a couple of things off.
I normally don't bother doing this with you because it gets a bit repetitive but I'm going to go up
to my overlays which is up the top near the render buttons click on overlays turn off 3d cursor and
turn off the floor just a little bit cleaner for the moment.
Select our cube I'm going to double click or F to rename that to head and we're going to find a modifier
so we'll click on modify our properties add modifier and the modifier will be adding We'll be a subdivision
surface to change the viewport to see for and we'll change the rendering to four as well just to make
sure it doesn't feel left down we'll click on Apply and we can declare this looks like a head near enough
is good enough we're just experimenting at the moment I'm gonna hit shift D and then that will duplicate
right click just to leave it back in exactly the same spot rename what I've just created to be scalp
scalp is that how I spell scalp scalp I think so and I'm going to hide the head so it's sitting there
but we don't need to see it with scalp what I want to do is basically delete all of the faces that would
be not where hair is going to grow out of this head Alice pretend head that we've got here so I'm gonna
come at this from the probably from the front from the y axis at the front and you could mirror with
this but I'm just gonna do it really fast and loose to jump into edit mode and I've selected on vertices
that's fine fine what I think is probably the midpoint actually I'll do this right from the very front
view find right the middle delete all of those I will delete the vertices okay I was in an x ray mode
so I missed the ones at the back.
Now I am in a x ray mode up in the top right select like slight delete the vertices.
Okay now let's okay from the perspective of what I'm going to see at the back that's kind of roughly
where the hairline of my crazy character is gonna be I want to get these ones at the front as well I'm
gonna change back to more of a solid view X I'm just looking at the front not out of Sorry get out of
the x ray view and hit scrolling so I can see all of my head the hairline is kind of a bit of a natural
way that the subdivision has left my cube so hit see on my keyboard and find the top left corner sorry
I'm gonna undo that I'm just going to face mode right click to get out of that and then undo face mode
now hit see again selects select like I can do shift select if I think I've made a bit of a mistake
I'll come back to that bit in a second just get my area yes down here okay and then is paint in the
middle that I'm gonna be deleting shift to that get that far corner.
Got it.
Okay.
Right click to get out of that mode.
That looks good enough for the rough area.
Hit delete on my keyboard delete the faces.
Excellent.
So then we have a bit of a scalp.
And now if you turn the head back on you can see that the scalp is sitting right on top of the head.
What do we do that.
Why do we bother with this process.
Well it makes it very easy for us to say just put hair on the whole object and that's what we're gonna
do right now.
So find yourself the particle properties click on that and then we'll add a new particle system and
rename this to be scalp I guess is a good thing to call it scalp hair click on hair and nothing's happened
because we're in edit mode sorry.
Back to object mode and we have a whole bunch of hair let's decrease the size under the emission window
scroll down doo doo doo doo doo.
Make it kind of generally the size hair that you want it to be.
Not too bad.
I'm going to give my hair some color straight away.
Let's see we'll go to materials a material on that.
Probably the same material on my head I reckon so I'll go and create a new bit of hair material click
plus new double click changes to be Hey I'm just going to call it straight up hair I think or a head
hair.
Head Hair.
Apologies if you can't see that head here.
Now we'll make it.
I think I'll make my go I have black hair just for fun black hair black hair black hair yep pretty good.
Why is it not showing.
That's because we haven't told our hair to use that color.
Let us go back to our particle system.
Scroll down to find a render on render.
We are going to change material to be had here.
And then it should become black.
Excellent.
And our head is still white.
Not a problem.
One thing that we don't actually want to see is this kind of head scalp thing.
It's a little bit weird isn't it.
So I'm going to turn off show emitter on render but it still stays there and if you're like me you can
search for a long time trying to find one Earth it's still there.
We need to scroll down to find viewport display and then also turn off showing me.
Now the emitter is gone.
You might say Oh but I can't see what's going on.
Well we turn back on the head and there we go.
The hair is looks like it's coming straight out of the head.
And no one ever need know that we've actually got this extra object down there that's acting as the
emitter.
We've got a whole ton of hair particles here.
That's go back to scroll up go to the amount of hair that we've got and turn this number down probably
to 200.
I think the idea when we're working with hair is that we want to have as few possible to get the result
that we want so that it's easier to find them and manipulate them and to move them around.
I'll show you that in a second.
So maybe 100 and then obviously as we did in the previous video we can go add children to give it the
volume that we want.
We can either click simple or interpolate it.
Now I've got to make this hair a little bit tough so you can't see it.
Let me go I'm putting a whole bunch of extra.
There we go.
Extra hairs in here.
And as we did last time we need to go to render properties and ambient occlusion.
Now you got to see it a lot easier on screen distance I'll put up to about one.
There we go.
OK.
And what tab on my own here.
That's probably yeah.
Well they will sound the materials preview OK.
So you've got a whole bunch of hair that's coming blank straight out of out of our unit just here.
I wanted to show you the difference very briefly between clicking back on the particles properties between
symbol and interpolated.
Now to demonstrate this I'm going to reduce the number of hairs that we've got on our head down to say
10.
So 10 hairs we're currently on.
Simple as our children and you can see here that they clump and the clump is based upon our radius value
of point two.
If we increase that it spreads it out it basically has a radius from the parent particle hair particle
to the children well all the way down.
Then you get the children staying very close to the parent which is good to have.
And the reason that we want to have one parent and many children is if there's any sort of physics calculation
or calculations in general going on then it can be calculated on the parent and it can just blend I
can say to the children just do exactly what the parent is doing rather than having to calculate every
single individual strand of hair separately.
So that's why we use children and don't just put in a whole bunch of the parents.
OK that's simple now interpolated.
It says I'm going to do try to do a better job of spreading the hair between the children between the
parent hairs that we've got.
So it spreads it out and you don't have that control over having a group or the radius size I guess.
So why is this important.
Well I think when we're doing little strands of facial hair you often want to have the clumps be close
together whereas if you're doing head hair you might want to be interpolated into say just do this for
the entire hairdo.
Now you increase the amount that we've got let's see 300.
Probably a little bit more than that maybe 500.
Obviously if your computer is not enjoying that you've got more on there then you can do less but we'll
start off with 500 and see how we go with that.
OK.
We've got this weird kind of hair just sprouting out now here's for the magic of particle edit and he
got to the top left where says object mode and scroll down fine particle edit and we get a whole bunch
of tools.
Now I've got just a few hairs in here.
How many hairs grow up scrawls grow up.
I've got just 10.
This is great out.
It says no more changing how many you've got.
There's 10 in there.
OK.
Cool.
Great.
And if I go and modify these then it will modify all the children.
What I mean by that well I can click on the first or the comb tool maybe increase the brush F to increase
it and you see I can brush their hairs when I first saw this in blender I was mystified so I can have
all the hairs going floating around that way wind swept to the right jump back into object mode and
look at that all the hairs now magically pushed over in that direction back into particle Edit Let's
see what else we can do here.
Well I might say I don't actually have enough parents.
I want to have more in that area so I can click on add up the top.
You can see radius that's the size of my circle count.
I'm gonna put that down to one which means that every time I click I'm going to add one new hair standing
to attention on top of the head.
This is great.
If you want to have a lot of control for example you want to have say one two three four five hairs
round the side will jump over into object mode and then from there you can see has added a whole bunch
of new stylish hairs from there I could go into my comb so back into particle Edit I know there's junk
but a bunch of jumping between particle and edit in object mode.
But that's the way we get a good look at what's going on.
I increase my brush size and maybe here I'm going to.
Sorry I've missed something I need to be on comb I am brushing that down I might have these hairs going
down side now there's three ways that I can be comb your three ways to manipulate these hair strands
up on the top left you can see that we've got selection mode path that's modifying as I comb it it's
modifying the entire path the next one along is point which allows me to zoom in on get precisely in
on a particular point and just move that point all those points any point that you mouse over you can
see the black dots to get that kind of looks like spider legs now doesn't it.
Or I can modify the tip and as I move that it's just moving the tip of the hair if I want to go and
modify in here you see it's not actually affecting anything but when I find the end of the hair it is
modifying that's a lot more difficult to drag it all the way down that's good if you wanna get that
nice curl at the end of the hair such as that we'll have a look in object mode and you can see we've
got all this hair brushed down to the side now we still want to be applying our regular old modifications
so if we look back on particle properties if we scroll down scroll down scroll down we can find for
example roughness and play around with for example random to get a little bit of a different feel so
it's not quite so pristine and perfect if you want perfect you go for perfect if you want have a little
bit of Scrabble in there you can also kind of looking a little bit weird let me go back to particle
edit I'm going to find the puff tool and just kind of puff these out that will have them separate stand
to attention I'm going to put this back to path stand to attention and just basically like giving someone
a little bit of a blow drying with the hairdryer down at the salon.
There we go.
I do want a couple of extra strands in here is going to pop a couple back in at the back.
Don't don't don't give me some control at the back here and another couple on top just so I've got some
coverage.
Coverage how's that look.
That looks spectacular.
Wonderful.
Every now and again it's nice to hop into the range of you.
We might want to do a couple of things just very quickly here.
Jump on our light and move that around to a bit of a nice spot.
That's good and something I haven't done much with you but I like to go into world properties find the
background and the colors just click on color and just drop that down a loop to make things a little
bit darker.
I find it gives a nice contrast when the background stock or hadn't been doing that with the renders
we've been doing so far but I find that gives a little bit of a nice look here so we've got our light
shining on our hair.
Isn't that beautiful.
Now a little bit more tweaking I want to do make sure I'm clicking on scalp back over into particle
edit going to hop back into one of my friendly views to look at now I might say this here around the
side is a little bit too long.
So they can do is find the scissors and it literally allows us to give our character a haircut just
snips the hairs down at the end very very handy we had to do that so I'm gonna give this guy a bit of
a short back and sides
okay let's see how that looks back over into object mode okay that's looking delightful probably a little
bit tall at the top there's a couple of ways we can address that as well back over into particle edit
I can click on length and if I hold down my left mouse button it makes things longer and move at the
same time I hold down shift and wiggle around my mouse it's going to make things smaller so this is
an alternative to just doing the cut the cut is literally cut at this point but this way I can gradually
grow or shrink the hair to give it the sort of look that I'm going for.
I think so a little bit short in some of these on the side shots on these on the side a little bit and
then back in object mode.
There we go.
And I think I've got a little bit too much roughness in there so indulge me just momentarily I'm going
to change the randomness down a little bit get things a little bit straighter a bit nicer.
Okay.
Good one.
And then we can style to our heart's content back into particle edit I can hop into the cone.
I could reduce the size I can also reduce the strength but probable or shift F as we do with our sculpting
and maybe give a little bit of a little bit of a wavy ness over to one side.
I think it affects just the tips because I want to change kind of the way the hair is pointing more
so than changing the middle of it.
Change the way it's pointing change the way it's pointing.
There we go a little bit of waving this maybe a little bit of a pot in the middle.
Been a while since I've had hair.
This is a little we've an unfamiliar familiar situation for me.
It's kind of like reminiscing I remember when I had hair and I had to brush it and put hemp rocked in
it.
Oh they were the days and I kind of accidentally gone and created a bit of a prominent world leader
I think just for completeness I'm going to click on the head and change the material of the head.
I will click on material find the material which is going to rename this to be skin and then just give
it some art and I will make it cartoonish I won't actually be trying to make something exactly correct
so I'll make it a little bit purplish.
Okay that's the foundations of putting on some hair.
I think we should do one more thing to a little pretend character here.
I'm gonna give that to you as a challenge and the challenge is to add some facial hair.
So add a new object add a particle system and style it so that it looks fabulous.
It could be a wise man's beard or a Magnum P.I. mustache whatever your heart desires.
And one last step of the challenge.
Make the facial hair a different color to the head hair just so you've got one more time to practice
the different materials and how that relates to the different things with our particle system so take
on that challenge when you done I'll see you back here and I'll quickly put together a bit of facial
hair myself
okay.
I think I'm going to do a bit of a mustache for my supreme leader here.
Not that he's got one but we'll put one on anyway.
Maybe a Tom Selleck Magnum P.I. mustache quick on head shift D to duplicate that yet right click double
click on this rename it to stash I think we'll call that and what do we do this not paint straight on
the head.
Well that gives us a lot more control over the different colors and materials and behaviors of the different
hair systems that we have we might do one for mustache one for eyebrows one for hair one for sideburns.
So it's up to you how many you want to do but this will give us a bit more control rather than just
painting everything straight onto the head.
Okay now hide the head for a second.
And on my stash I'm just going to do a very crude deleting as we did last time but you don't have to
delete it you can just leave it there but when we don't need faces and vertices then let's get rid of
those faces and vertices.
I wasn't in X-ray mode again.
Same mistake as last time.
Delete
and delete.
Okay.
There we go.
Now we've got where the mustache is going to go.
Now I can hop into particles click on plus make sure I'm back in object mode so I can see what's going
on.
Change it to hair.
That's probably not the sort of mustache that we want.
I'm going to drop the hairline.
Beep beep beep beep.
Down a generally mustache size generally down a mustache size I think.
Yep.
Cool.
I'm going to change the number down to zero.
Slightly different technique this time that I'm going to show you I will change the children to make
sure children is on simple and the display amount.
Not sure here will do.
Say 30 and 30 I think for those and I'm going to for context I'm going to turn the head back on so I
can see where the head is.
See that general area.
Eyes would be their nose would be there.
So do a big mustache just in the middle here.
So over in two particle edit I'm going to click on add and I'm going to hand place a count one that's
good radius.
That's fine.
Let's see we'll do maybe a line.
Do do do do.
Okay.
If you hold down as you do this then you do a whole bunch.
If you just go click click click.
That will let you place them a little bit like acupuncture needles.
It looks like doesn't it.
And I'm just going to do a second row below that just for completeness.
Not exactly sure what is going to look best in this mustache but we can always add and delete and change
it.
Let's just go straight up and see how that looks.
Okay.
Super nice and furry.
We're on simple that's fine I can reduce the radius of clumps a little bit more.
Yeah that looks pretty good.
Down at point zero eight.
Let's change the color wall.
I remember I'm going to add a new material click new This will be we'll call it stash which is short
for mustache.
Change the color to be more of a yellowy.
We'll see how yellow he goes and then I'm going to promote that up.
Sir it's the one at the top.
We don't need skin for our mustache.
Okay.
Now how do we start the mustache.
I must admit I'm not an expert at mustachioed but let's go and shrink the length of it for a start.
So click on length hold down shift people.
There's a little bit too long bit too long.
Now let's groom it down a little bit room it down groom it down.
There we go.
Okay.
Get a preview for how that looks.
It looks pretty good.
I think there's a weird kind of old man mustache just gonna fit in and add a little bit with some more
so back into particle properties simple display amount will make this 60 64 render amount.
Let's pump that up punch 200 and 200.
Okay.
Looks a little bit odd because you can see very clearly the two rows.
So what can we do about that.
So it's not so obviously two rows while we can add a little bit of randomness I think in there.
The rain and a surge merge it together a bit more.
Yeah.
If that's the look you're going for we can also jump back into particle edit mode maybe puff puffed
a little bit.
It's a little bit of puffing.
How does that look.
Okay.
It looks a little bit more there.
So it's near enough is good enough just for this fun playing around exercise.
I think you get the point of how we create mustache or beard if I wanted to turn this into more of a
stubbly mustache than I find the length of the hair and just put all the way in and then we can get
a little bit more kind of you know afternoon stubble.
Obviously I'd trim it down a little bit and place it around the character a little bit better that might
be a little bit too much volume so we can turn down the amount of stubble that's starting to look better
from a stubbly point of view I think if we wanted to that stubble all over the face and then as we did
before we would need to find the display.
So show emitter.
Turn that off in viewport and show emitter.
Turn that off for rendering.
So if we were to remove the head you can see that the emitter i.e. the object that we had currently
click on is no longer there.
Okay.
I think I'll declare that done for our messing around.
We had fun playing around with your character if you've got something cool you'd like to share then
please do share it with us and I'll see you in the next lecture.