Welcome to wait.
Painting in this video you will use weight painting and virtex groups to control where the particle
system actually appears and where it does not.
So let's hop straight on over into blender.
Okay so we have our rabbits that we've rended out here and just using it for a bit of reference material
for a moment the how over the entire body and is itself.
It is all uniform.
And if you have a look at a rabbit that's not the case there's a big flaw in our particular model that
I'm using here are my reference material.
I've got a big fluffy chest on my rabbits.
The hair is definitely longer on the body than it is on the head.
And the shortest place of all is the is has very little hair on there at all.
So we could go in and using the particle at it to go in and try and alter all of these.
But I can tell you first hand that would be an absolute pain to try and do.
But what we can do is set up multiple particle systems and actually apply them to certain parts of the
body and those particle systems themselves can have certain attributes.
So first of all let's hop in to 3-d you know so this is what our rabbit currently looks like now in
order to assign certain areas of our bunny hair to certain parts of the bunny body we will need to set
up virtex groups and there's a couple of ways you could do that.
We've already experienced one way where we select the mesh or of the vertices within a mesh and add
those to the group.
There's another way called weight painting.
So the first thing we're going to do is create one of these virtex groups.
I'm going to go over to the data.
The object data window over here and we've got virtex groups and I'm going to add one end called it
body.
Now it's called body.
We can literally hop in to white paints and start painting.
Now at the moment there's a load of hair in the way.
So what I'm going to do as a long ago is for particle system at the top here and just click the little
eyeball to hide it.
And we've got ourselves a Blue Bunny now like before we've got a series of brush types.
So looking here were these are all the brush types you can have add and subtract.
Generally the two that I would use in this case we're adding now it's blue at the moment and I'm going
to change the strength here.
Two point twenty five.
Because in general there are four steps there are four colours.
Obviously there's a gradient in between them.
But there are four main colours and I'm just going to draw straight on the bunny here.
The first colour is this tan or turquoise or hsiang Colour.
Sorry zero is this dark blue.
The next level about 25 percent is shown by this turquoise colour.
Then at 50 percent we have this green colour.
Then we have a yellow colour.
And then finally a red colour and a red colour donates 100 percent waiting.
Now in general with the hairs themselves in this case I do want 100 percent of the body here.
That sounds a bit funny but 100 percent of the body hair on the body itself.
So we would want to colour in the body all red.
Now I'm going to turn the strength up to one so that everything I do is straight away coloured red and
I'm going to have to sprink the brush size again using F I can do that and using shift in F I can change
fee.
I would say capacity but the strength of the brush and I'm going to leave that at one for the moment
as well and the limit selection to visibility tool is also available here.
So I'm going to toggle that was it on or off before I just put a line across there.
I think it was actually OK now it's on.
So now it's off.
We can go around to a side view and paint our model.
Literally just going over it and filling in all the way up to let's say there.
That looks a good portion I'm going to make the brush size a little larger and move it around here.
And I'm going to do that area there and the back here now because we've limited selection to visible
turned off.
We can paint right through our model and because it's a symmetrical model that works absolutely fine.
Only shrink the brush down here and now we're in it at a funny angle.
I'm actually going to turn that back on so that I don't end up drawing through our model I'm just going
to colour in the rest of the details around the neck to make sure it's as complete as I want it to be.
That's great.
Now that's assigned automatically with white paint turned on that has assigned this part to.
Here if we were to create a new group under here you can see the virtex groups under the data object
properties here.
You can see that we can toggle between those two groups.
Now finally we will want to go to our particle system and assign this particle system to this actual
vertex group.
So if we scroll down here and we'll get to where it says virtex groups and there are a lot of options.
Essentially the one that we want at this point in time is density.
When you click on that it gives us the two in this case the new one.
I've just created called group.
It gives us the body one.
So we select that and there we are.
We're all done if we turn back on our.
Particle system at the top here you will see that the hair is now wrapped around the body and the body
only.
Now of course at this point we know that there are enough hairs to cover the entire bunny So there are
probably too many hairs at this point in time just around this part of the body.
Now we're going to have to click free edit and remove all the changes that have been done so go Fluffy
again because I know for a fact that there are too many hairs in this bunny now for just the body.
So we can go in and start editing again so I'm going to get it down to a thousand and I'm seeing twenty
five.
And again I'm just going to render that really quickly and see what it looks like.
That's probably a little sparse as we can see there.
But again that's not how we're going to view it.
Finally sir let's go back to the 3-d view and let's go to particle edits and just comb them around.
So it looks roughly right.
So if we got both sides no we haven't got both sides.
Let's comb them round like this and then go back to render and render the image.
Oh I've done that thing again where I've not hopped out a particle edit.
So now it's looking like that we go and render it.
So it's a hundred children remember it's the renderer here we can see that that's just about right.
There's a little bit around the neck here where it's not quite full.
So I'm going to try increasing the number of children rather than the number of actual hairs.
I'm going to read render the image and see how that comes out.
That looks much better.
I'm going to leave it like that for the moment.
Of course I'm free to come back to these at any point.
But the moment you go to freeholder you lose the combing that we've just done.
Hello it's Michael from the future here just to give you a few more tips on mirroring.
When it comes to weight painting not included previously but is now.
So the first thing we're going to be doing here is replacing this default cube in our scene with a sphere.
Reason for that is we are virtex painting it would help if we've got a few more vertices to paint on.
Okay.
The first thing I'm going to do in this particular case is duplicate shift Andy.
So they're not linked duplicates and move a sphere back along here along the y axis.
And I'm going to duplicate again to move it this way on the y axis.
I'm going to duplicate again on the x-axis and duplicate again on the x axis this way.
Okay these two closest to us I'm going to do something with their origins I'm going to put their origins
back at the centre now because the 3-d cursor is at the centre.
I can just confirm that we're shifting and see.
Now I can go ahead and set the origin in the tall shelf to the 3-d cursor and do the same to this one
that's on the along the y axis as well.
Now this is going to be a bit of hopping in and out of different modes as far as this one along the
back I'm going to go into white paint mode and before I start painting and putting a weights on any
of these vertices I'm going to go over to the tall shelf and change it to the options tab.
Now under the options tab there's an X mirror.
And if we click on that now you can see that along the y axis anything that's on there is now being
duplicated which is incredibly useful when it comes to anything that happens to be symmetrical.
Now just a warning if you hopped into edit married and tried to move the mesh you might get something
like that happening and that is because the exit mirror function that you've just enabled is still toggled
on and then undo that for the moment and carry on with the demonstration and then go back into object
mode and so that this one in the middle go to white paint and once in weight paints what I can do there
is go ahead and all exterior make sure it's turned on me see it and it mirrors along there.
And then next to this one over here which has an origin in a different place.
So white paint make sure X mirror is turned on and that is also working perfect.
Now let's go ahead over here and paint these final two that are along the x axis.
So we've got this one here and this one here we'll start with the one with the origin in its centre.
Now this is the key to what I'm trying to demonstrate.
If the origin is in the centre when it comes to weight painting what we can do is turn on its mirror
and it will still work so it doesn't have to be along this y axis in order to work.
However the origin does have to be in the middle so that with the origin here it's that y axis that
passes through there that it will be mirrored around.
If we go ahead and select this other one and try and do that what we'll find when we try and wait paint
is there will be no mirroring because what it's trying to do is mirror with a mesh that's all the way
on the other side over here.
However to demonstrate this actually working what we can do is select all of this in object mode this
object this sphere go to our modifiers and I'm going to really quickly go to add modifying go to the
mirror modifier and just make sure it's on the x axis and then click apply.
Now we have.
A single mesh object that shares mesh around a common origin.
Now what we can do is go to white paint.
And what you'll see is all it has actually applied the mirror.
Let's just see if it's applying the mirror.
Yes it's going that way.
Let's go back and subtract So we're changing under the tools the brush type we're going to change it
to subtract so we can come in and there we go.
It is working as you would expect it to.
But that's because we're mirroring about the origin.
Whenever you use the X mirror now just a word of warning here sometimes this does work as you'd expect
it to.
And that happens with quite a few things in blender.
The simplest thing to do is just tab in and out of the mode that you're in.
And it usually then starts working again.
And now of course it's time for a challenge.
I would like you to add hair to the rest of our bunny create virtex groups for a head is whiskers.
So think about where they come from and the chest.
Create new particle systems for these areas.
White paint the appropriate areas and assign those particle systems to those areas.
So balls are video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's hop straight back over into blender.
Okay so we have the body assigned.
Let's go straight to n just create the rest of the groups that we need.
So there was head and then there was years whiskers and finally chest.
So we're going to have a big plume at the front of our bunny.
Okay.
Brilliant.
And we might have to assign some different hair types at some point.
But for the moment let's actually colour these in this century so we're going to go round to the head.
I'm going to hide our particle system so it's not in the way and doesn't slow down the viewport and
hop over into the 3-d view.
When I go round to the side and I want that side I will press the right keys one day and let's colorin
the head.
I hope we're on the head yet head is selected.
So let's go to Weight paint and literally colour in our head.
There's one thing we're going to have to bear in mind when doing this.
So that's that.
There let's go round.
Oh I didn't have a limited selection turned off.
So let's go through in just whizzo real quick.
That area there.
I should have included most of it.
Okay so let's turn it back on again and go round the top of the head.
And this area here some of to make the brush size a little smaller.
Come in and literally just go over the top of here with the strength that one.
So it's an absolute certainty that that's where I want here.
And I appear to have applied a little bit here.
Now I want to go to.
So we're subtract subtract and just go here.
There we go.
So you will have that occasionally when you go backwards and forwards and end up drawing over another
part of the model.
Don't worry if you do it because she can always undo it.
Carrie that's looking pretty good.
There's a tiny bit of tidying here to be done.
Oh subtracts.
She got a much lower strength by the looks of it.
Hey let's spin round once more and just get rid of those final bits.
Of course the eyes themselves.
We don't want any hairs going in the eyes.
So I'm going to lock it into this view again and because it's a mirror what I can do is make sure I'm
painting through the model and going oh I'm going a bit far then we can undo that.
It's make the radius just a little bit bigger initially.
So I can do that.
Excellent.
Okay.
So there's no hairs going to be growing in the base.
But there is a bit of a top here and bottom.
Now in order to do that I'm not going to be able to essentially mirror it.
I will have to do it manually so I'm going to have to have a smaller brush.
And literally.
Limited selection turned on limited selection to visible turned on.
Go around and do that there.
I mean here.
That's starting to look much better.
And I was around here.
Occasionally you will make a mistake doing this.
I suggest stopping every now and again and going at it again.
Kovats Looking good it's a bit ominous.
Being so close to the bunny.
Okay let's do this one here.
So we're almost there.
I'm pretty happy with that especially with the length of hair around.
But then there's the mouth and nose area all gone inside our model.
So fortunately that's roughly the right size for me and I'm going to try this.
It might not work but that's will keep hairs away from the mouth region as well.
Now give us a bit more fidelity with the hairs brilliant So that's the head.
Done.
We need to create a particle system for it.
And we are going to go in and create a new particle system and called it head.
Now here what we can do is pick the body hair one which looks like that and make it a unique user by
clicking on this number.
So announcer's body has 0 0 1 and we're going to call it head hair.
So that gives us the opportunity to not have to recreate all of the settings we had before.
The only thing we will have to do is go down here and go to density and set it to the head which it
will now do and we can see there that's that that's much better in fact through not got hair in the
eye socket it comes over a little.
And we don't have any hair around here.
Now bearing in mind this hair's going to be shorter so we can make it smaller now go here hair length
and bring it right back.
The density itself is actually going to have to be quite high otherwise because it's shorter we won't
see it so let's comb that back and down and around here that's just combed that round.
Spin round the other side and comb that backhand around.
And down here.
Okay I'm happy leaving a few stragglers for the moments.
That's just make sure they're going in the right general direction and the back of a head of course
comb that down it's always seems funny.
Right.
Let's hop into object mode and just see how that looks.
Looking pretty good.
Let's unhide the eyes so we can see what's going on again and just render the image and see how that
looks OK.
We can see the density of the hair is good for the head still a bit of a bald patch here.
So we're going to have to do something to cover that up or do something with that but we can come back
to that in a bit and there's a bit of roughness on the actual rabbit's face around here but otherwise
that looks pretty good in 3D view.
If we look at the front.
Ah I can see actually as we move around I can see a tusk the buff this I and a tough just there.
Some of them to go back around in two parts Collider and just brush that along there.
And it was just here and brush that as well.
Of course we can reduce the strength of this brushing as well which will help massively in fact the.
Distance from the face if we lower that a little more we can get a better brush or better style of hair
because it will be closer hugging to the face as we go round.
And of course you can style it round the eyes as well as lots of stuff you can do here to make sure
that the model is nice and clean.
Again that's that bit done.
Let's go around the eye here.
There we go there looks pretty good.
Now we might need more he is actually more.
We can't go back and do it now but the number we might need to increase it to get a better better feel
of it.
But that looks pretty good around there.
And obviously the you do end up with hairs around the eyes too much anyway.
It's a bit fluffy there.
So I think we just need to brush that back.
And again you can go back oh you can actually see that these are a bit tough.
Anyway so if we straighten those out that will flow around the eyes pretty well.
Excellent.
So let's hop into object mode again.
That's a much better appreciation of what's going on there.
And of course around the mouth area as well so we just want to keep the hairs basically away from the
mouth so depending on which way they start and go from these and these are as you can see the kinks
there those of the segments so if we just guided to around that's increase the strength from the radius
ever so slightly or not that much in fact that's decreased both ever so slightly there we go.
Pull that down pull these down and eventually we get ourselves into a lovely position when it comes
to our rabbits fur.
Okay let's go back and render that out and see how that looks.
Oh I've done it again kind of object mode and then render that out and see how that looks.
That looks much much better.
So I'm going to speed the video up now as I go through the hairs coming here for the ears themselves
not about when it comes to the whiskers.
So let's sort out a chest and ears.
Okay so finally the whiskers.
So I've got V wisk at area set up.
But this is one of these places where you're going to want to make sure that your particle system we
haven't added it yet so let's go and had whiskers in.
Now I don't need to duplicate a previous particle system here but I do need changes to hair type.
And down here said the density are two whiskers going to keep it to these hair in here.
Okay that's a bit funny.
We've got very long whiskers.
So for a start there aren't that many whiskers.
We will need to reduce the number.
So on a mission.
Oh we can't do it was in particle edit mode on a mission.
I'm going to go for 16 and they're not that long so let's go for a length of one maybe less of these
maybe eight.
And let's try different seeds which randomizers it's a little I quite liked.
No one actually.
There we go.
Maybe 10 or so.
Okay so there's lots of also things you can do here.
So they're coming out the very weird angle coming out here but that's not a problem.
So a bit of a discrepancy with the number here.
So I'm going to go back to free edits and remove it.
I've just noticed as like three over the side and whatever the number left is over the other side so
let's hop into object mode and see if we can take it down to 10.
And just change the seed until we end up with the right number on both sides.
I think that's probably the easiest way of doing this.
So you can see some signs that that distribution was quite good.
Looks to be about four on both sides there are.
And now we just need to deal with how it's looking so from the top.
Let's go into particle edit and pull them outwards.
And from the front view or the rear view that's go to the front view Yeah that's absolutely fine for
the moment we can deal with more of that later and the fluff itself for the chest.
I haven't actually done that in any detail so let's go to the chest.
It's nice and I'm actually going to go here and go to length and by the chest top of the chest I want
that to grow out a little more on both sides and is going to make sure it has applied to both sides.
Yes it has.
Perfect.
I don't know what it's going to look like but let's go to a rendered image or I've done it once again
go into object mode first and then go to render image and see how that looks.
Excellent.
That's starting to look very good.
I still haven't dealt with this tuft of hair or missing hair at the back here.
But we will worry about that for the moment.
Again we're still in a prototyping phase at the moment but we've got all the different parts of the
hair all sorted out.
So there we go.
We've got that challenge was a bit of a big challenge wasn't it.
But we've got that now.
So now go ahead and share your new hairy rabbits with us over in the discussions.
I will see you guys in the next lecture.