Hello everybody and welcome back.
By the end of this lecture we'll be able to solidify our curve object as an actual mesh object.
And what that will mean is that we can go into it grab a face loop for instance and extrude it up if
we wanted to.
Gives us lots of opportunity to edit this and of course clean this up as well.
We have a look now at the middle here.
We have less geometry there it's just not necessary.
And if we have a look at the bottom yes we've got a base to our object as well.
Let's go find out more.
Okay.
So we have our lamp base in front of us here.
It is just a curve object so we cannot just go in and edit things we've literally just got the curves.
Edit So how do we convert it.
Well it's very very straightforward.
We can right click and there we go converts a mesh so end of lecture right.
Not quite.
This has always been a bit quirky even in two point seven.
They've literally just fixed the bug where this didn't happen.
Told it wasn't even working but if we press tab we can go in and we can immediately as you've seen before.
Go install extrusion things and moving them about.
So that's a great start but we've lost our original lamp data that may not be a problem or it may be
a big problem because you may want to fall back on that and generate some new shapes.
So how do we go about preserving it.
Well I'm going to go to file and revert.
So we go back to how it was when I started.
Because when you right click with the object selected and convert to mesh you have this little area
down on the left the operator panel that gives us an option to keep the original.
However currently when we keep the original the bug that did exist still exists.
What ends up happening is the original circle gets converted into mesh data so you end up with just
an edge.
But we don't have the rest of the data there.
This is problematic.
Again file reverse will take us back to the file as it was before.
How do we get around this.
Well we have to do a little bit of a manual jump through a bit of hoops to jump through until the blender
devs get to fix that.
Now what we can do here is simply duplicate this shift indeed to duplicate press escaped to release
it and then go ahead and rename it.
So we've got lamp base path and now I'm going to call this original her.
So there we go.
And now I can go to my lamp base path I've selected it in the outline as I can right click and convert
to mash it will convert it to a mesh we can confirm it's converted it to a mesh by doing something along
those lines brilliant.
And there we go.
All done and dusted.
Now comes your challenge Okay so your challenge is to create a mesh object from the curb objects.
If you've been following along exactly already you've done it.
If not you need to go ahead and do that.
Now keep the curve objects.
Now if by the time you're doing this lecture the operator panel still does it work.
If you take keep original thing you're going to have to duplicate it.
So do duplicates.
If that toggle fails.
And then finally turn off the curve object from rendering you may even want to hide it in the viewport
as well.
But I do want you to turn it off from rendering.
Now remember there are now filter options.
So if you don't see the rendering icon the little picture of a camera it's hidden away so you'll need
to turn it on in the filtering options at the top of the outline.
I would also like you to make sure that the lamp is solid.
Give it's a base not only on the bottom but on the little bit that goes down.
And in that also needs a base to it gets rid of unnecessary geometry so inside the bit where we're going
to connect the rest of the lamp where the neck of the lamp is so to speak that is going to have far
too much geometry in them at the moment.
So go in and dissolve any unnecessary geometry in there.
And then finally think about applying the subdivision surface modifier to the mesh object instead of
it being applied to the curve object.
So I'd recommend removing it before solidifying it as a mesh object.
Pause the video now and give that a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's hop on over into blender and solidify and create our lamp base.
Okay.
So we've been through a couple of examples here.
This is far too high poly.
So what's I'm going to do once again is revert back.
Now I've got the luxury of I had saved of having my files kept in what's called a repository it's a
get repo.
I can just revert back to how it was at the end of every lecture.
But if you don't have that just bear in mind you can you save as to keep versions you can go into your
preferences to your save and load and actually give yourself some save versions.
As I said right at the very beginning of the course I do not need those they clutter up my file system.
But by all means give yourself those if you feel that you're going to be saving often and wants to go
backwards and forwards or I should developing.
Remember you can go file and save as.
Okay.
So the first thing I'm going to do here is go and remove my subdivision surface modifier from it.
So it's nice and clean.
And then going to duplicate it which is good.
And I'm going to call this one the lamp base original and I'm going to hide it.
I'm not going to hide it from my senior because I want you to see what happens if you don't do that.
And also from the rendered scene as well.
So the first thing I'm going to do is go back to my lamp profile sorry not profile the lamp path.
That's the one here and I'm going to go ahead right click and convert.
It's a mesh all being well we should now be able to go into edit mode grab parts of it and adjust accordingly.
Yes brilliant.
Let's undo those changes.
So I definitely know it's now a mesh object and look at that definitely as we've got far more options
when it comes to adding modifiers.
And in this case I want at the subdivision surface modifying cranked up to two and we should end up
with something that looks pretty close to how we had before.
But this is a great example now of some of the issues you might face.
We've got crossing over geometry it looks horrible.
And if we look at it in rendered mode for example it looks even worse.
So this is rendered mode but it's still the viewport.
So if we turn it off and the lamp base original we just hide it out of the way.
You would think that that's done and dusted.
However if we have a look through the camera itself and let's move the camera a bit closer loop to close
okay.
And what I could do here to help us is of course by a board around than it would have rendered much
quicker as I was moving around.
Okay.
So we have what looks good there.
And if we go ahead and go render render image it will take a while to go through and sort out.
But you will also see that there's lots of extra stuff there.
Even though it's hidden in the scene.
So here we can see that we've still got all lamp are mockup that we made and we've got the other stuff
also intersecting as well.
How do we make sure that that's not there.
Well we just need to toggle it off of that camera icon.
So I'm just going to close that down for the moment and I'm going to go at the top here to my filter
options and we can see that the camera icon is still turned off.
So I'm going to turn that's on and then we can come through and hide it here hide it here.
The profile Well we don't want by appearing any way in any shape or form.
And with the camera turned off it means that we can go ahead now and when we render even those to take
a few moments to do it will be a nice clean render.
So we've got that part of it's sorted out but we still need to sort out the rest of the geometry here.
Let's close that down.
Okay.
Let's go into edit mode on here.
Now we've got quite a low amounts of geometry so we won't have too much to clean up.
But the first thing I am going to do is come out of random mode so we can move around a bit quicker.
Well and let's go down here now.
It still looks a bit dodgy at the moment doesn't it.
Well what we can do is on the subdivisions surface modifier This is upside down triangle.
So we can adjust the edit cage the original geometry to match the modified results and they will look
much better by doing that.
And it also gives us a better feel of the form.
Now as you saw me playing earlier I don't have quite as much geometry to play with when we're using
the subdivision surface modifier.
But let's go ahead and just sort out the major issues here.
Let's isolate this festival.
I'm going to go shift and H to hide everything else in my scene.
So we've got these couple of areas we need to sort out.
I'm going to use edge select select this edge on the bottom here was holding down oats.
There we go.
And with that we can go g z and just lift it up and out of the way.
Excellent.
I'm also whilst I'm here going to grab this edge and go X and dissolve is unnecessary geometry I'm then
going to grab this once more and fill it in.
I could have done it at the same time.
And I'm going to do the same.
All there's a good point with the subdivision surface godfather extra bits of geometry might have been
helpful.
Okay.
And back it comes.
There we go.
Looking good.
The other thing of course we could have done here instead is inset the bottom.
Yes.
That's much better.
I'm going to inset sets are there a similar thing for the actual base itself.
We will fill it in.
It will make the base quite curved but then we can inset that base to give it a bit more control and
also define the edge much better running around here.
Okay.
That starts to look really really nice.
So what I can do here is I'm going to knock the viewport settings down ever so slightly and apply it.
We can't do that in edit Moses come out apply and have a look at my model.
Okay.
That's about the level of geometry that I want to work with.
So that's really good.
The next thing I need to do here is a font few final bits and tweaks we're going to add another subdivision
surface.
But now we only need it at one level because we've already done it once.
I'm going to turn the cage back concert follows round and then it's just a matter of picking and choosing
the bits of geometry we want to remove.
So I think I can remove those three X dissolve edges looks pretty good to me and I'm going to grab this
edge here and scale it in to make this a bit more of a vertical tube and I can double check that by
looking at it in wireframe mode.
Does that go straight down.
No it curves in ever so slightly select scale that back out just a little.
Okay.
That's looking really good.
Z solid.
Kate.
Now what else can we do here.
Well we could do some of the things that I was alluding to before giving this a bit of extra geometry
grabbing different areas perhaps scaling this bits in giving it's a bit more prominence that's looking
pretty sharp.
And then finally perhaps this edge on the bottom here we can scale that out and make it a bit more rounded.
Okay.
Nice.
That's looking really really good.
I'm pleased with how it's working out.
Did you make any further modifications to your base.
Really looking forward to seeing how they're coming along.
Almost at the point now where we can start adding some more parts to our mesh.
Yes.
And in this case it's going to be the neck coming out so we can put our first arm on and then we will
have this bit coming out this bit coming up and our lamp on top.
So we're coming together really really nicely.
And just can hide that out the way for the moment.
Save my work and I'll see you all in the next lecture.