Hello everybody and welcome back in this light.
So we're going to go over data blocks and we'll also reinforce this knowledge over the next four or
five theory and slash practical lectures on data blocks and how we can move them about different blend
files.
So we're going to learn about data blocks what they are and how we can use them.
Now we've actually come into contact with data blocks lots.
But let's now go and explore them directly.
Now there are things like mesh data textures objects lights all of these things a type of data blocks
that we can move around in our scene.
Now this is very useful if you're making parts separately or bringing in other assets you've already
made.
So it's incredibly useful.
Also when you're working in a team being able to understand which data blocks are where and how you
access them.
So data blocks characteristics what are they how do we know what they are.
So they must have unique names per type.
That's really important.
If you have something with exactly the same name it just won't like it.
So if you've seen that's if you try it will append it was 0 0 1 0 0 2 etc. They can link to each other
which is really useful they can link across the blend files which is also incredibly useful and we'll
talk later on about some dos and don'ts about linking across blend files unused data blocks are eventually
removed.
So we've come across this in the past with data blocks.
This is where we've used fake users.
So that little f simple fare to preserve that particular data block is if we don't when we go ahead
and shut down the blend file and come back again it will go.
The common thing that I've seen that happen with is materials you set up a material where you remove
it from an object you save you file you go off you come back the materials gone.
Now for our basic materials that we generally work with not a problem at all for more advanced materials
that might take hours to set up.
That's quite a big problem sharing data block.
So here's a quick example then we dive over into the gives the same texture on many materials the same
material on many measures we've already played with that one quite a bit the same particle system and
so on so on.
So you're getting the gist here that we can have the same theta block on multiple objects for instance.
That's incredibly useful sharing data means we don't have to repeat ourselves.
Now an example here is we often end up sharing and then making the data block unique.
That's a that's a given if you've got a material that's almost there but it's the wrong color but you
don't want to override the original material.
You can have another instance of that data block and then make it unique and then adjust the color to
what you want says to have a look at an example of this over in Blender Okay so now that we're over
in Blender let's go ahead and first of all just tweak a few things I've already turned on once I don't
want to keep having to turn it on.
So I'm just gonna make this area here wider so I can see everything along the header bar for the outline
helps you guys out most are going to go to the filters tab and turn back on these to be disabled and
viewport and the render icon and then I'm going to go across the file defaults and save startup file
and I don't have to do that ever again which is really useful if I might pull up the time line ever
so slightly.
It's very tempting to get rid of the timeline but every time I end up cleaning it away I often end up
needing it.
Okay so that's down there.
I'm happy with the setup here.
Let's have a look at our data blocks.
The first thing we can do actually to reveal all of the data blocks that are currently in this file
is to go to the display mode of the outlier and select blender file.
We have a look at this area helps us make it larger.
We can see all of the current data blocks that are within this file and you can see that there are quite
a few.
And of course many of these we can link into other blend files and we'll do that in the next lecture.
But let's have a closer look at how blender manages these and let's go to one of the ones we deal with
day in day out so we don't have to think too much about the details of it.
Let's have a look at objects type of objects in our scene.
Let's go to a cube a cube has a mesh data.
So this is the data data block and then we have our material data block.
Pretty awesome.
Hey you'll notice that it kind of coincides with our options that we have down here.
We have our object properties.
We have our modifier properties particle properties etc. as we go down and then we have our object data
properties of the data data properties and then our material properties as well.
So let's have a look at some of the things that we discussed in the slides just beforehand.
Let's go ahead and duplicate our cube.
Now the moment we duplicate it we can show it anywhere in the scene.
It doesn't matter.
We can now see in this hierarchy we have cube 0 0 1 and cube.
Now when we created that new cube it also had a material on it because it was a duplicate of the original.
So all of this is duplicate data.
However it is not necessarily shared data at this point in time.
We go back to the original one and go old The instead which is a linked duplicate we've not used in
a while but now if we look at cube 0 0 2 and open that up we can see that it shares cube and material.
So looking at these and following the rules that we've already learned that any particular type of data
blocks name has to be unique we can say for certain that these three cubes share the same material.
If you modify that material it will affect all three of them.
We can prove that simply by going into the viewport shading tab going to our material it doesn't matter
which cube we're on.
Let's just change it to green they all change because they all have the same material and if we go to
one of these materials and rename it let's say green.
It also renames all of the others because it's the same data block.
It's not unique.
Now let's have a look at the names here.
I'm going to get rid of one of my cubes here I want to get rid of cube 0 0 2 just to make things a little
simpler.
Okay so we have cube and cube 0 0 1.
Now if we would go ahead to cube 0 0 1 and try and call it cube your left kind of scratching your head
they're going well did they just change positions.
But now we can have a look here.
Cube 0 0 1 has been successfully renamed cube
but the original Q because two data blocks cannot have the same name has been renamed cube 0 0 1.
So if we do the same thing again you will see they switched back and the only way we can really tell
is because of the different match data names underneath.
So they those can be named independently which is awesome.
One thing to bear in mind is case sensitivity comes in.
So Cube all in capitals or all lower case is a different name they are literally different.
So that's one thing to bear in mind that case does matter.
Now what we can do with data blocks for instance let's make both of us share the same data.
So I'm going to go back to calling this one cube.
So we've got our cube 0 0 1.
Ah no look they're out of sync.
How do we go ahead and solve that.
Well I'm just going to go up to this top one and call it cube and it will flip background.
Okay to cube 001 and cube.
Now if I want these to have the same mesh data which is useful which means like if I go ahead and grab
this vertex here and just move it somewhere random just so we know it's different we can see that this
one here cube 001 has not inherited that.
However if we go to our match data properties we can change the match data for the cube the one that
we currently have selected.
Cube 0 0 1 2 the cube.
And there we go.
It now has the same mesh data and we can see that as well in the hierarchy because they both have the
same name.
And now we can see all of this data in front of us.
It starts to become clear what this number 2 is next to our mesh data name it means there are two uses
of that data block if we click on that two or any other number it makes the match data unique again
which means we can move it around and it won't affect the other one.
Pretty awesome.
Of course we can come back in at any point and set it back to the cube can't do it whilst we're still
editing of course.
But now I conflict between those two states.
However look here we've got a zero next to cube and cube 0 0 2.
These are two match data blocks that currently have no assignment.
There are no objects in our scene that are using that data.
Now what this means is that if we go ahead and save our scene and let's call this data blocks just for
short and let's correct the capital either we go ahead and save that and then revert the file.
Right.
Let's have a look.
We've got two unused data blocks we go file and reverts which is the same as opening up again those
unused data blocks have gone.
Now that's not usually an issue but where I have seen an issue several times is when you're playing
about with materials.
So we go ahead we can see here that green material is on both of these objects and let's go ahead and
open up our mesh you Oh no.
Objects again.
Remember there's a hierarchy.
Here we go.
And coincidentally you'll see that when we move an object in its mesh data in any attached materials
will also come across because they are further down the hierarchy.
Now let's have a look at our material itself on the green material here we also have a dropdown This
is similar to the mesh dropdown and we don't have any other materials in our scene at the moment.
We've got the name of it that's fine.
We've got the shield.
I like calling this protect which is probably why it's got that shield there.
It saves the data block even if it has no users which is incredibly useful.
It means that if I turn that's off let's say creating new material new material said this one as red
and then say well actually I don't want the green material on this object anymore.
Both of these will turn red.
We look at our selection of materials now instead of having the zero next to it that it would have had
if we haven't enabled the fake user option.
This will preserve it during saving.
So this is an incredibly useful tool to be aware of.
It's mainly materials that I've seen people have problems with.
OK so what you can do as well as if the red material itself has all of the properties and everything
else sets up and you want to take a copy of that material but make it unique but inherit all of the
properties the previous material had the next icon there as you can see two pages together new material
and new material is going to base it upon the original materials.
Now we've got material 001 but the original material now has no uses associated with it.
Something to bear in mind and of course you can click the X and unlinked the data block shifting click
to set the users to zero.
Well that's a good way of cleaning if you don't want a material in the scene anymore.
So I went ahead and did that.
We can see on the materials list both of these are now 0 and to really drive home the point.
If I go ahead and save and revert those materials and now gone eek.
Well happens that material took you a few minutes or maybe even an hour to set up.
When we get into materials you can see they can get very very complex.
I'm going to set that it's green for the moment just so they have a material applied to them.
And that's about wraps up I'll look at data blocks.
Be aware that there are many in the scene.
These are the things that you can link between many scenes and you have a lot of control each object
has to have each day to block type has to have a unique name.
So whereas we can't have to match objects called cube we can have shared data called cube which is useful.
However if we were to make that unique by clicking the two there.
So we now have cube 0 0 1 having unique mesh data cube 0 0 1.
We tried to cool that cube just like with the mesh object it will just rename this one down here to
cube 0 0 1 because you could not have 2 data blocks with the same name when at the same time.
Okay.
That's it for this lecture.
That was a bit of a deep dive into data blocks.
Now will start to become more and more clear as you start to use data blocks more and more and this
will be especially true the more advanced projects you work on.
And if you have any tips on how you've managed data blocks in the past.
Remember to share them with everybody as well over in discussions.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you all in the next one.