Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we are going to add the notch to our bishop or rather his hat and we're going to use
the boolean modifier to do that really quickly.
Let's find out more.
OK.
So we're going to start with the default cube in front of us and we're going to add another mesh object
because the boolean modifier requires two mesh objects to work with.
So let's go ahead and move this UV sphere just to one side.
So we have our cube and we have a UV sphere.
Let's go ahead and select the cube and apply the boolean modifier to this mesh object.
I'm going to scroll down on the properties window here to go to the wrench or spanner add in a modifier
and we are creating new geometry so we're going to generate using the boolean modifier.
Now this is really cool.
And what's I'm going to do just to help us out visually is I'm going to select my  UV sphere before
I do anything else scroll down to its object properties or up depending on where you are and change
how it's displayed to a wireframe and we can use this to infer that this object is not going to be in
the final render but is used in some other way.
Now that we've got that's in wireframe we can see what's going on when we start intersecting these two
using the boolean modifier.
So let's go back to the modifiers tab and let's select the objects that is going to do the operation
as the sphere.
So you've got the boolean modifier applied to the cube and its operation is difference and we're using
the sphere.
Let's see what happens.
It's grab our sphere and go G and just move it into the intersects the cube.
How awesome is that says literally cutting a hole.
That's the same shape as our sphere out of the cube.
Now as you can probably guess already the possibilities here are literally endless when it comes to
what you could use this for.
Okay.
What are the other two options.
Well we have two other options we have intersect which as you can see does something completely different
it only keeps what's inside the object which can have some really useful effects as if you were cutting
through an object is a great way if you've built a structure and you want to see inside.
You can use just this to cut through and show parts of your model.
Very useful doing that.
And the other one and the final one here that's make sure we still got the cube selected is a union
and the union as you can see here will create a new object if that's the combination of the two.
And the great thing about this is you end up with solid geometry afterwards so if I was to go ahead
and apply this and then just hide the sphere out the way.
If we have a look at this in wireframe we see that it's perfect.
There's no mesh inside another and that can be incredibly useful if you're trying to 3D print something
that's made up of multiple parts.
And he just can't get two parts to sits without them intersecting one another using the boolean modifier
with the union operation is exactly how you do that of course in this case I have applied the modifier
in order to get that final result to show you.
But don't have to and that is of course one of the reasons why you use modifiers it allows you to have
a stack of operations that are independent of modelling themselves and that means that you can quickly
change them if you don't like the results.
So there we go there's the boolean modifier in a nutshell and now it's time for your challenge. Okay
so your challenge create the notch in the top of your bishop and at the moment do not apply the boolean
modifier. Pause video now and give that a go. Okay everybody, Welcome back let's go ahead now and create
the notch in the top of our bishop.
Okay so with our bishop loaded up I'm going to add in a cube and use that cube, I'm going to scale
it by maybe point 1 Okay.
It's going to have to be a lot lot smaller about there Okay let's scale this on its X axis to make it
narrower and go G Z and lift it up I am going to apply the scale of the object you can have some very
weird things happening otherwise, I'm going to scale that in just a little bit more and apply the scale again
and then go G X and move its cross rotate it slightly on the Y axis and then rotate on the X as well.
And then I'm probably going to have to move it across a little.
Okay I'm.
I think I like where that intersects.
But just to make sure and turn the cube object the cutting object from textured to wireframe so I can
see through my object.
I'm gonna call this object a notch so I know what it's being used for.
And then I can go to my bishop, scroll down, modifiers, add a modifier, boolean.
Use the notch.
Okay.
This is looking good.
Oh and it's already cut straight in.
So let's have a quick look.
Now the beauty of having this wireframe here of course is we can grab it really easily and just move
it back in so I can move it closer to this central point and start cutting through the very top of the
hats.
If I wanted to I want to do that.
I want to be very close.
I think if I go G Z that will look quite nice if I have a bigger notch.
One side yes.
Excellent.
I'm happy with that.
So the final thing I'm going to do here so I can't see it is I'm going to hide that mesh object that we're
using to cut the notch out of our scene so that we have something really nice to look at.
Brilliant.
I'm going to save my work there.
How did you guys get on.
Did you start off with a cube to make your notch and scale it down.
Did you make it in a different way.
I'd love to see your construction methods how you're not just looking.
Please share them over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.