Hello everybody and welcome to this quick tip on selecting.
This is all going to be about a bit of a refresher and also just to show you some of the other selection
methods that are available to you in Blender.
First of all and this is the primary one you've got to tell blender what you're selecting vertices edges
or faces and you can use one two in three to go through those as well providing you're not emulating
numberpad.
Now if we turn all three on by holding down shift and selecting them there can be an issue selecting
faces I just managed to select a face straight off then.
But you can end up having to click several times to get the face selected.
So this is a great example of where just saying I want to select faces is great because then we can
come through and every click you know is going to select a face even if it initially isn't the one you
intended to select.
Now going to our tool shelf.
I just want to highlight the fact that there's a selection type.
We've got select, select box select circle and select lasso and you have to hold your button mouse button
down when you're selecting this area to have this dropdown appear.
And by default select box is the one that's there which means we can draw a box around and anything
any face in this case that's within that box get selected.
Now we've you notice along the top we have new add subtract difference and intersect the main ones that
I tend to use are add and subtract.
In this case if you draw a new area it is a new area it will deselect what was selected before and
then add in the new stuff if we had ADD selected that's like holding down shift all the time so this
is great.
If you can't get to that shift key to add to your selection and subtract as you probably have guessed
removes your selection difference that's a select something first so we can do a difference if I select
this area in the middle is like a subtraction it's what difference with these an intersection is what
intersects when you draw that box around it's almost like keep the ones that the box is on and that's
also available under select lasso which is more for organic models or ones that aren't nice and square
like our pyramid here and acts in exactly the same way the one that doesn't act quite in the same way
is the circle select and when you have this turned on you can use the left click to actually just draw
over your model and select things that way at the very top you can adjust the radius so if it's too
large you can come in with a smaller one and we can hold down control to start undoing these faces
which can be incredibly useful because let's say selecting this ramp here we can just draw a line straight
down and boom everything selected.
Now I have a bit of a hit and miss of what selected the moments and I saw I can double tap the A key or
go alt and A to deselect everything and A will select everything so it's up to you how you decide to
use that functionality in typically in Blender Alt and that letter will undo what the letter did to
begin with and a quick shout out here to Marc our student instructor who kindly made sure that I remembered
to tell you guys that you can also press the w key when you press the w key it will cycle through those
different selection methods and the final one I want to show is expanding and shrinking selections so
say I select this area at the very top of our pyramid I can then use control and the NUM pad plus to expand
the selection and we can see here one of the problems with having uneven geometry, so up until this point
on the top of this building it has even geometry as your going out then it becomes uneven because we've
reached the edge on just the next expansion and that can cause problems when you're trying to select
something if it was perfectly even we could select the bottom as we have done here and then expand from
that and you can see it does expand evenly and eventually as you can see here the top does also equalize
I'm gonna select everything and I'm going to hold down ALT as I select this top set of faces so as we've
experienced before with Edge selecting you can hold down alt and select an edge loop you can hold down
alt while faces are being selected and select a face loop.
So with that face loop selected what we can do is we can do something a bit more advanced we can go
to our select menu and you can see all of the other types of selection you can do keep skipping off
of it there and one of the great things you can do is selecting similar and you see the shortcut key there
is shift and G.
Now there are lots of other options here.
My favorite sometimes depending on when your model itself is co-planar so anything that exists in
the same plane as that one can be selected but one that is very useful is normal.
So basically that saying Please select all of the other faces as part of this particular model that
are facing in the same direction whose normals match.
And if I go ahead and do normal you can see here that all of the upwards facing normals are selected.
If I were to select this face here at the very front and In fact don't want everything selected as i've done there.
So I'm just gonna deselect.
I'm also going to switch my selection back to select box because that's what it's on by default.
Now I go select select similar normal.
You can see all the faces that are facing in the positive Y direction have been selected.
Even the ones that are just shadowed on the backside of this model and probably there you go, the inside walls
as well on this doorway.
So that concludes our look around selection in this lecture and it's time to put those skills to the
test with a challenge. Okay it's challenge time.
I'd like you to remove the top part of the steps on each level and create a ramp 45 degrees from the
base to the top of the steps we have created.
Now I think this is best that I show you an image as to what I'm trying to describe here as it's quite
challenging to describe.
So let's hop into blender and we see here we've removed the steps that were there originally and we've
replaced them with a ramp going up.
Now there are a couple of ways that we could go about this some of which even preserve the topology
going around the model and even fill in these triangular gaps that are left if you end up with this
result that's absolutely fine.
But in the challenge I'll show you how to do both ways.
So go ahead pause the video now and give that a go okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and create a ramp for our mayan pyramid
Okay everybody and welcome back.
So we've got a couple of options how we go ahead and create this ramp that we want now we can go ahead
and make it very simply by selecting the bottom edge just here and the top edge that it goes to making
sure we've got the right angle pressing F key.
And now that's filled in we can go in and select all of these very gently they we go gently or carefully
and there we go.
We've got a we've exposed the ramp underneath and then it's just a matter of going through and linking
all this lot up.
Is there a cleverer way that preserves some of the topology without having holes in our model.
This is a valid solution by the way of exposing a ramp underneath.
Absolutely fine.
However if there's something better that we can do.
The answer is yes there is but it does involve a bit more thinking forward as you go.
So going to undo those steps there.
Now we need to select a few more bits other than just these edges so I'm going to select the faces running
down here.
Now this does require a bit more forward thinking press the C key to enable the circle select and then
we're able to also control the width of our circle with the mouse wheel which is really awesome as
well.
So with all of those selected I'm actually going to extrude and then press escape.
Now you may think oh wow that's just created duplicate geometry hasn't it.
Not quite because what we can now do is exploit the same thing we did before.
So we go ahead and select all of these edges on this leading edge here and then when we move it we see
that we've got some solid geometry so if I move it back.
So G X one it's minus one in this case we end up with our ramp but we also end up with some faces there.
The only thing we then need to do is make sure we remove our doubles so I'm going to press A, F3 to
search and then remove doubles.
So what we've got there is the solution we're looking for but really quickly done.
There's always going to be more than one way of doing something.
You may see this hashing area here.
That's just from filling that in earlier.
So I can get rid of that face that's there.
Okay.
So we've now got a series of sections running up that are individual which is great but it's also in lock
step with the rest of our model which does mean that we've got a few more options when it comes to editing
and our model is sealed.
It's got no magical holes in it.
Okay.
So there we go there's two solutions to the same problem.
They give slightly different results but overall it doesn't change the look of the model that much especially
when these triangles themselves in a few moments will end up covered up.
So please show your work over in the discussions looking forward to seeing it.
Also if you've had any problems or different solutions I'd love to see what you come up with.
Please show your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.