Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to have a look at making our ages just a little bit sharper.
This is what we've got at the moment and we can just sharpen everything and make things much more defined
and especially at the very top.
You can see we've got much defined much more defined edge and around the model itself.
It just brings everything together and makes things much more defined especially around this area where
our STEM comes out.
It looks far far better.
Let's go over into blender and find out more
OK so let's have a look at our lamp base first for let's focus on this area where the stem enters the
rest of the base selecting the base itself.
Let's go into edit mode and let's have a look at what we want to adjust.
Well the first thing I'm going to do here is I'm just going to make sure that we're no longer following
the actual subdivisions.
So we're not allowing the cage to follow the modifier results so we can see where things really are.
And having a look here in fact being out of rendered mode would help here we can see that is very very
close this edge running around here.
We can see is going to potentially be an issue if it is inside.
And I think it's just the right size actually.
So what we can do here is let's have a look very closely.
Just make it slightly slightly bigger.
OK.
That's a good start but it hasn't really affected any of the rest of our model.
What we need to do with that hedge loop selected.
So if you use edge or vertex select to select it with the old key and once you've done that open up
the property side bar with the end key and go to where it says mean crease.
If we increase this high we get it's almost to the point and there we go.
You will find that at some points it just snaps into place.
And there we go we've got a sharp edge now running down every turn back on our cage as well we can see
it flows smoothly out and we can do the same to other edges around our model as well we can just do
things like scale in an ounce to help increase.
We can add additional geometry so we can add a loop cuts in in order to make things a bit sharper.
That's all valid.
All we can grab the edge that we've got maybe scale it in slightly and increase the mean increase and
that will add in a very sharp transition between the two.
I don't like it cutting under there so I'm just going to move it out slightly.
OK.
We could work on the rest of the model there.
But let's have a look at this stem.
Now the stem itself doesn't have a subdivision surface modifier on it.
So adjusting the main increase is not going to make any difference.
We can come in here we can select this top it may increase one still looks exactly the same.
So how do we get it.
So it looks nice and sharp along the top.
Well let's try just Beverly.
So control and be a bevel along.
Yeah looks pretty good.
What other options do we have.
So let's undo that.
Let's add a bevel modifier when it kind of does the same at the top but then ruins everything else further
down.
Okay.
Are we okay with it being a nice sharp edge at the top.
Probably.
How do we get that to conform then.
Well let's undo the bevel modifier added in this subdivision surface modifier and it looks like this
which is no good.
As a couple of ways around that we could inset the top face ever so slightly and you see that adjusts
the top here.
We still have an issue further down we'd have to do the same thing there but it all it's really Dallas
it's shifted the problem to somewhere else.
So if we could cover that up and I think we will end up covering it up we could potentially get away
with that.
But you know what.
That's not ideal in this situation because this is a cut bits of metal.
Yes ideally it would have an edge to it.
But what we can use is something called the Edge split modifier by putting that on and making sure that
we adjust the angle appropriately.
If we lower all the way down to zero you can see we can see all of the edges coming back again.
We don't mind about that so we just continually turn up anything over 20 degrees seems to be fine for
this.
And we've got a lovely sharp edge along the top.
We can then combine that with a subdivision surface modifier and without the inner edge.
So let's dissolve edges and we go up and we get a nice smooth looking object much much better.
Okay.
So nice quick challenge for you.
I'd like to finish off adding the sharp edges to your model.
Video now and give that a go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and hop on over in splendor and finish off our sharp edges.
Okay so this stem looks pretty good at the moment but the rest of this model just needs a bit of tightening
up.
I'm going to adjust this edge here and you don't have to go all the way to one you can pick somewhere
in between.
Yeah that looks good.
Now this edge here I think it's this one here I want to make it come out slightly so we've got a much
more defined rim around the model and of course we can adjust things like that if we wanted to.
It's not a chess piece so we don't have to be too silly about it.
This one here.
What's I'm going to do is I'm actually going to move that down ever so slightly as well to give it a
tighter edge.
I'm going to set it as one for the moment.
Yes that looks pretty good.
Let's bring it down.
I don't want it to be quite strong.
There we go.
That looks much better now.
We've got a bit of an oddity here.
Well I think it looks odd anyway.
It's nice and smooth on the inside of this lip and tight on the outside.
What can we do to sort that out.
Well we can go to this edge here and increase the mean crease.
I'll make it look much better around the inside loop.
Okay.
So I'm I'm liking the look of that.
Let's have a look at what it looks like in rendered mode.
And look through the camera in this particular case Yeah that's looking really good.
I might actually make the material on here.
A dark orange still more of a scarlet type red.
Yeah I prefer that red.
Okay.
Looking good.
Let's go to our object just here and I might add a manual beveled just along the top edge here.
So I'm going to go out and select the edge loop running round and just Bevel it's not by much but but
just enough and it will still end up with a nice sharp edge along the top but it looks more like a machined
edge and the other thing I want to do here is I do want to lower the roughness maybe to point to.
Yes that's better.
I wanted to be a little bit more shiny I like my shiny things.
Okay so let's just save our work and I'm gonna go ahead and press F 12 and see how that is looking X.
That's looking really nice.
I like how this is turning out.
I do press F 12 to render every now and again because it's good practice because sometimes something
in the viewport looks good.
You render it out and it doesn't look good anymore but it looks absolutely fine for the moment.
I'm happy with that.
And of course this also gives me the opportunity to get image save as and export it and I'm going to
call it the lecture code.
Okay.
Let's go ahead save that and then we go ready to share with people.
I'm really looking forward to seeing your work.
Do remember to continue sharing your progress as you go through these are these are all baby steps.
But as you go through your projects it's brilliant being able to look back and seeing everything.
So even if you're just doing this for yourself as a record that's brilliant.
If he's sharing with everybody else that's also brilliant.
I love seeing it as a teacher being able to see develop and especially if you're not following along
exactly with what I'm doing but creating something epic of your own.
I'm really looking forward to seeing it.
Please share your work in discussions and I'll see you all in that next lecture.