Hello and welcome to this quick lecture on blenders interface.
Now blender has a series of windows and a series of workspaces and it's very very customizable so you
can pick no end of different options that suit you.
Now we've already been tweaking some of the interface by making it larger or smaller in either direction
up or down as you can see here.
We just have to wait to that double headed arrow appears and then we can move things around.
However what happens if we want to change how it looks.
Where are the other bits of blender.
Well on the screen at the moment we have four main areas.
We've got the 3D edite and if we hover over this drop down in the top left we see we've got the 3D viewport.
As the editor type if we click on that it shows us all of the other options that we could have including
some of these shortcuts in order to change.
So if you're a keyboard shortcut person they're right there.
In fact most things within blender do have a keyboard shortcut annotation with them if they've got a
keyboard shortcut.
So you've got editor types and we can switch this out we can switch this to a movie clip editor.
And there we go.
And we can switch it back to the 3D viewport and we can hold down shift and the F numbers to skip through
those if we want to now.
So we can customize all of these little areas but we can also customize the entire lot at once.
So if we have a look at the very top we see this says layouts, modelling, sculpting, UV editing et cetera.
Now if you've come from an older version of blender you may find that not all of those are there if
they are not then you can scroll along to the end of this list and press the plus button and it gives
you all of these extra areas these work spaces that you can use.
And each one is set up with a different purpose in mind so if we quickly skip through these not in detail
but this is a layout if we click on the modelling tab we go to what would jump into edit mode straight
away.
We'll talk about edit mode in the next section sculpting is there.
UV editing, texture paint and you can see it changing the interface depending on what the task
is you're trying to do.
And that's one of the big things with Blender it tends to be a bit overwhelming because it can do so
much and that's why we're going to take you step by step through each of these areas as we go through
the course, including customizing your layout creating new layouts, however you want to use Blender you
will be able to.
Now one of the quick things I want to show you here is what you might do if you have a multi monitor
setup.
So if we go to the window option one of the things we can do is create a new window.
This is now a new independent window that I can move to another screen which is really really useful
when you need the extra space.
And of course you can close that down as well.
And there is a difference between a new window and a new main window.
A new main window imitates what we have before with different selections along the top a different window
doesn't have any of those.
It's like an extension of the existing one here.
And so it updates at the same time.
So there's something to bear in mind a couple of final things.
The header bars used to be at the bottom of these windows rather than at the top or most of the editor
windows.
If you find an empty space and right click it brings up the header menu and you can flip it to the bottom
if that's how you prefer it if you want to keep it like you may have been used to before.
I'm going to flip it back to the top.
I'm kind of used to headers being at the top now since they are called headers and this is a thing
that I use a lot.
Maximize area so if I'm working showing you a model I'll often go control and space whilst my cursors
in the 3D window and it will maximize that particular area and I can just go and control in space again
to toggle it back.
Now my cursor does have to be in this window.
You may have noticed that if I move my cursor out over the outline on the right hand side and start
using the numberpad keys it does nothing.
The moment I move it into the 3D editor space it then acts accordingly.
So do be careful where you put your cursor as it can change how blender behaves.
And I've seen no end of people confused.
They've just nudged their mouse over accidentally while moving things around and then they can't do
what they think they should be able to do.
Very easy to get caught out without one.
Finally at any point you can split and combine windows so at the moment if there isn't a spliter a widget
like they used to be you just move your cursor into one of the four corners of any editor window and
you get the little cursor change into a cross which means you're able to split a window.
If I click and drag to the left you see a new window appears it will automatically imitate whatever
the previous one was.
Unfortunately you can end up in a bit of a pickle with blenders interface if you're not careful.
But don't worry you can go back at any time to a previous layout very easily.
First of all you may have only opened up a couple of these and you may be struggling to make them disappear
again.
Well the windows must line up so these two can join.
Now these two can join.
Now these two can join notice that an arrow is appearing and the arrow can be flipped to the other way
if necessary.
But the areas that you'll merge in have to be the same size.
Alternatively if you'd made a real mess of the interface and you didn't want to do it you can right
click on layouts and delete it.
You can then go along to the plus button at the very end go to general and load up layouts again and
there you go it's back.
You may want to then right click on it and reorder it to the front so ends up where it was before.
So there we go.
Blenders interface is incredibly customizable and I encourage you to explore it and not be scared of
it either even though it covers a multitude of different disciplines but you will learn these throughout
the course and you'll become increasingly more comfortable with not only the different workspaces but
altering blenders layout so it suits you and your workflow.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.