Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we can specifically look at lowering your cycles render time.
We're getting to the point now where I'm asking you to share your work and it would be great if you
weren't waiting for ages in order to render things out.
So the first thing we need to do is make sure that we are using cycles.
The second thing is is your CPSU or your GP quicker.
I cannot tell you straight away because there's not necessarily a right answer.
Couple of things that we can do in order to work for our is make sure that we're doing tests that are
appropriate.
So for instance when I go ahead and press have 12 at the moment you may notice that I don't have lots
of little squares going round.
I have one big square going round and that's because I'm using one GP you in order to do my rendering
and you can see as it goes round it gives us a time in the top left.
The last one I did was 20 seconds this was probably going to be around the same time.
Okay brilliant 20 seconds but with cycles there are a couple of things that affect the actual outcome.
The first one is samples and I have seen people do samples at 3000.
And of course they are wondering why it took so long to do.
Very rarely will you ever need to go that high.
I very rarely go over 500 even in complex scenes.
There is a case in point that you need really high sample rates if you're doing volume metrics and things
like smoke if you want that to look realistic then you're probably going to have to render it out for
a very long time.
However for the general models that we're doing it's just not necessary and 128 is absolutely fine if
we scroll down a little bit further.
This is area code performance this is really important with a GP you your tile size is typically set
higher than it would be for a CPO I can demonstrate this really quickly at 5 12 and 5 12 for my particular
graphics card.
It takes about 20 seconds to render if I lower this down to 16 so I've highlighted them both types in
16 and then I go ahead and press F 12 to render.
Yes it looks like it's going very very quickly because it's got that small space but I can tell you
straightaway that this is going to take longer by the time it starts up and stops each little segment
that time it's taking is much longer so that switching time is too much of an overhead and this is how
you basically work out what it is for your seeing that you're currently doing is going to be quicker.
So having it set at 16 is obviously too slow and this is a relatively simple scene as well so it's not
going to have a big impact.
Okay.
So this took 31 seconds to do that.
Okay I'm going to move into Slot 2 here and close down that render window and I'm going to change the
next big thing that changes things so let's set this back to 512.
Let's change the resolution.
So on the output tab let's set it to 50 percent of 10 ATP.
So this is just standard high definition 50 percent.
If I go ahead and press render we can see that it's done much more quickly than all four times more
quickly.
How about that.
Will this four times less information.
So that's not that surprising.
Evey does not suffer the same thing though.
If we change the resolution of EUV it doesn't scale quite as well.
And I'm guessing here that if we set this to 200 percent of 10 ATP which would be a four K resolution
and press render is going to take a bit longer I expect it to take four times longer.
So instead of it taking around 20 seconds I'm expecting this one here to take four times that so around
80 seconds or a minute in 20.
Now it will not scale exactly but it is likely that that will be the case.
Okay so there we go.
It actually took a minute 30 in the end as I say this is not an exact science.
It would depend on what your computer's also doing at the same time and because before it was 10 ATP
and this is at 4 k they will be different size images.
Okay so say we did want to render something out of 4 k what else can we do to speed this up.
So our resolution sets we have to use that.
This is a false constraint if you were showing off or testing your work please just render it a lower
resolution and save yourself the time waiting.
Only worry about rendering things out a higher sample rates and higher resolutions when it comes to
near final work or just one render remember we're animating this.
So if it takes a minute for one frame in this case a minute and a half but let's say one minute for
easy calculation if it takes one minute for one frame and you're at 30 frames per second you're talking
about 30 minutes per second of render eek.
That's a long time to wait for your render to come out and obviously if we lower the resolution that
works.
So what else can we do.
What if we go back to our rendering options and set the samples back down lower.
But before we do that I'm going to go to the rendering tab.
There it is and change this to slot 3 so we can have a direct comparison because every time we change
one of these parameters it will affect the quality.
So I'm going to try and be a bit brave here I suppose we're going to lower the render down to 32 samples.
Let's see how that looks Okay brilliant.
We're down to 25 26 seconds.
That's a huge difference.
Let's see the quality difference between the two.
So it was slot so compared to slot 3 not compress the keys on my keyboard as well to change this slot
so Slot Three.
Now at first glance you may not see too much difference but if you look in the highlights it's a bit
more sparkly and around the back.
Here in the shadows this is where it definitely starts to impact anywhere where the shadows your lower
samples often end up grainy.
So we zoom in there and have a look.
We can see this is not as clean.
It's a much much cleaner image when we've got 120 samples but it's taken significantly longer three
times longer.
Let's see if the dinos feature sorts that's out.
Well they the noise feature does is it adds a kind of a blur to the image which can get rid of detail
if you're not careful but it can also make things look much better at a lower cost.
So let's close that.
Well let's switch the slot for first close that down and this particular setting is hidden under the
view layer.
So we go to that we have to scroll down and we've got the noisy at the bottom.
We open the drop down we could see there's a load of options.
I'm just going to put a tick in the box for now and let's render that out.
Now what you will find is that as your rendering it then goes back over once it's got a group of four
and Dean noises and we can see here is the noise.
Two of our tiles three of our tiles so far and if we have a look we can already see this problematic
area doesn't look so bad anymore but it does look a bit more blurred so if we go back to slot three
we can see that it looked like this before.
And if we go to slot four it's much much smoother.
How ever saying that it is blurrier so perhaps we don't need to be so forceful with it.
That's the other thing that we can do here.
We don't have to have the setting quite as high.
So when it comes to rendering out anti noises it doesn't blur it quite as much.
But this is one way that you can speed up your renders and of course as you can see has added additional
time.
But the question is at a normal full screen distance can you tell the difference between this and slot
to well actually looking backwards and forwards slot 2 now looks not quite as good because it's been
blurred out with slot four.
So I would say that instead of waiting one minute 30 we can probably get away with this one only one
minute that saves us a huge chunk of our time over a third of our time.
And if you're talking about hours say this is a 10 hour render you've just saved yourself over three
hours.
Big big difference there now this is with the GPO.
Your CPSU favors smaller titles.
So we've played around for a bit there.
And what I'd advise that you go and do when it comes to a particular scene especially if you're animating
it is when your rendering you try different settings.
So if we come here to our cycles rendering engine with GP you compute we want these tiles to be quite
large.
However when it comes to the CPO and the video might get a bit jerky here if I start taxing my CPA but
generally you'll want this a lot lower and you'll see because I've got those four calls and eight threads
that we talked about earlier on when we were talking about setting up cycles.
If I set this around 16 I believe that's right for my processor and render out.
You'll see that you end up with eight blocks whizzing around and they're also de noisy.
Now the interesting thing in here is you can compare directly between one type of system and another
and we can see here as these are whizzing round at their optimal size it estimates that this renders
going to take over three minutes and doing some sort of rough calculation here as it comes to the areas
where there is no model it's going to go much much quicker.
But because it's taking over three minutes you can see why I was mentioning in the previous lecture
that combining the GPO and CPA on my particular system isn't ideal because the GPA requires much larger
sizes.
The CPA requires much smaller putting them together.
It really doesn't make much sense.
However if your system was a bit more balanced in that regard where perhaps you didn't have quite as
powerful graphics card or you had a more powerful CPO then you could put the two together.
And of course as we'll discover later on when it comes to rendering on multiple machines or with multiple
instances a blender because it looks like my CPSU is roughly one third of the speed my GP can be when
it comes to rounding out all these different frames we can give my GP to two thirds of the frames to
render and the CPSU to render the other.
Now this type of rendering does puts a lot of pressure on your system.
So it's really really important that you make sure that your system has adequate cooling so if you're
working on a bed or a soft furnished area the moment on a laptop potentially blocking some of the vents
do be careful because it may overheat.
Of course different computers act differently when you put them under stress but this is one of the
most stressful things you can in fact puts a computer through.
And if you think about Disney Pixar when they're rendering out some of their individual frames for their
movies take several hours to render not just the whole animation but one single frame and that's not
using our lowly equipment that's using very very high end equipment so whilst it's quite mesmerizing
watching these little squares go round and complete a four K render that's it for me in this section
please do render out your models as you progress.
I hope these tips have helped you out remember your tyre size for you ideally smaller try 8 16 and 32
with a graphics card it's typically larger starts around 128 if you've got an older graphics card and
if you've got a relatively modern one you can pretty much go up to 512 but again if you go to large
it will slow back down again you can find your own graphics cards niche by just practising and trying
different settings out and then we go that took four minutes to do vs. one minute to do so we can allocate
the CPO one quarter of the workload if we were using it for rendering out multiple renders and that's
it for this lecture I'll see you in the next one.