Hello everybody and welcome to knowing your topic and specification.
Now understanding your subject is key to being able to model it.
Draw it or do whatever you want with it especially later on when we come to animating things if you
don't quite understand how something works or how it's really assembled you can end up with something
looking just a little bit odd. Planning your model.
This is key knowing your scales.
Knowing how things are going to interact, that is key to making sure that your model acts in a way that's
believable.
And also knowing the importance of research I will repeat this throughout the course reminding you to
go and get some reference material reminding you to check that what you're doing is real is something
that's tangible and makes some sense.
Now I'm going to hop on over into blender and show you just what I mean.
So here we are over in Blender and I'm going to go to the drawing section of blender so I'm going to
go up to file new and go to the 2D animation part.
So here we go to the animation we get this white area here that we can draw on which is pretty awesome.
I'm going to undo that for the moment and I'm going to go control and space which will make this area
here whilst my cursor in it, full screen.
So what I'm trying to get across here is if I asked you to draw a bowling ball and some pins it might
look something like this and you might kind of get the pin like that and you might know go No it doesn't
quite look like that they're more like this.
And before long you just end up not really knowing where you are.
And the same is true with anything.
If I ask the majority of you out there to go and draw a house you might draw something that looks something
like this especially if you're from England because we all draw houses like this over here.
So you go and draw a house like this and to be quite honest there are very few houses that actually
look like that.
If we really look at a house you suddenly see that actually this comes out slightly and there's this
bit here called eaves and windows don't look like that.
They've got window sills first and they've got lintils on top and yada yada yada.
I could go on and on but the important thing is if you went and got some reference material of lots
and lots of houses you'd know exactly what it should be looking like now it's your artistic license
to take those realistic features and maybe exaggerate them.
So this chimney on top here might be realistic in how it looks because you've put the correct number
of bits at the top but making it exaggerated like that.
That's fine that's with an artistic license actually getting most of the way there is a good way of
starting.
And with that in mind we're going to jump straight into our challenge now because while I'd like you
to do is get the dimensions of a bowling ball and pin once you've done that get images you can use as
reference material.
Now reference material can come in all shapes and sizes and all sorts of angles and views.
But what's important here is that you get profile images.
So this is what we're going to look at here especially for the pin a ball is a ball.
We can pretty much line that up and that's fine.
But when it comes to the pin itself may be useful if you've got a view directly from the side or the
front so that we can use the profile of the pin itself and trace around it.
So we don't even have to think about things so go off, Pause the video now and give that's a go. Okay everybody.
Welcome back.
Now when it came to the dimensions of the bowling pin and ball you may notice that I didn't give you
any specification as to whether I wanted it.
Milimeters, meters, feet, inches whatever.
Truth be told it doesn't matter because in a future lecture coming soon we'll switch out those dimensions
within blender itself so it doesn't really matter.
So what have I done.
Well I've gone ahead and got myself a profile image of a pin.
And here we go.
This is the pin I've got for my reference.
Now of course this is more of a clip art style pnn.
I like its overall form and shape and I think it's going to look pretty good when we use it as a profile
image and trace around it to make our 3D model.
Now the one thing missing from this is actual dimensional information.
I don't know the radius that this is going to be or its height at the moment.
So let's go find out what the height of the pins are, and in this case I've happened to go over to Wikipedia
to get these you may have got them from other places.
And what's important is that we're just consistent.
So if you get the information for the bowling pin and the bowling ball from the same place it doesn't
really matter if it's slightly different for someone else.
So we can see here we've got the weight of them.
They weigh about one point five kilos and we can go down here we can see there's different types of
them look about.
I didn't know they exist like that candle pins.
That's pretty awesome.
So here we go.
The top here we've got our specifications that we need to focus on.
We can see that pins a four point seven five or twelve centimeters wide at the widest point and 15 inches
or 38 centimetres tall.
So I'm going to be working probably in meters still or and might even switch it to centimeters or even
millimeters so I can match these up.
Exactly.
It doesn't really matter if we're roughly in the ballpark of you've made your pin in this case four
point eight inches wide or 125 millimeters wide is not going to make that much difference to our overall
scene.
So those sorts of details are useful to know because we can set up our scene accordingly and make sure
that the units we're using for our models over in Blender are correct and we'll learn about that more
over in the next lecture.