And there's video we're going to play around with metal balls just experimenting I'm going to make this
slug by the end of the video and I'm going to challenge you to come up with your own sort of biogas
slug or Caterpillar that you're going to create.
So let's jump in and talk minerals.
So I started a new project here.
I've just turned off the camera and the lights so they're not getting in the way of what we're doing.
I want to start by talking a little bit about organic modelling versus hard surface modelling.
So we have our cube here we're pretty familiar with the cube hit tab to enter edit mode hit three.
So I can click on faces.
You don't need to do this I'm just showing you a little example.
This is us doing some hard surface modelling we're extracting.
We've got sharp pointy bits on the end we've got flat lines we've got right angles.
It's the sort of thing that is relevant for a chair or a building or a car or an aeroplane.
Those sort thing things that have a hard surface what is not as good for is making organic objects like
you can see here it's a little bit more difficult for me to create a human with all that kind of squishy
ness that us humans have or an animal or a caterpillar or a plant or a mushroom.
It's more difficult with this structure of modelling so I'm going to delete my cube.
Thank you.
Cube and add a metal ball into the scene.
I'm going to shift a and then find my meatball menu and we've got five different types.
Doesn't matter hugely when you choose you can change it later on I'm going to start with a bowl drop
that into the scene.
You see we have this bowl.
Not much is going on just yet but if I add a second bowl I'm going to shift to duplicate.
Move it over to the side.
You can see that there's a connectivity there there's an influence where it allows us to have this smooth
transition from bowl to bowl.
I'm going add by hitting shift a I'm going to add a capsule as well to show you that it's pretty much
the same with these different objects.
The capsule I can add down here I can scale loops not that big.
Come down I can scale it up.
I can move it around I can rotate all the good things that we can normally do but it has an organic
feel to it.
Now if I look into wireframe let's see what's going on here with our metal balls I've got three minerals
in the same mineral mineral won a medal too they're named automatically like that if you click on the
outside ring you can see currently we have this orange selection if I click on that it'll allow me to
move the first medal I put into the scene and as I move it you can see that my whole mesh is changing
super cores being updated I move it to there and it snaps away now those two aren't connected to this
not connected to the main body there if I click on one of the other rings of influence that was the
capsule I can move the capsule around again you can see how it's changing and morphing based upon the
positioning of where that capsule is there's no harm in adding lots and lots of minerals because you
can see the information on the inside is not retained so I'm gonna add another capsule just to plop
it over there I'll go back to my solid mode so we can see it drop another capsule in over there duplicate
pop another one over in there just to kind of get a feel for what's going on and in this video I want
you just to experiment that's what we're doing we're not keeping any of the stuff we do in this video
we're just experimenting.
So click on any of the metal balls and we have a look in the properties you can see the the green here
with the two balls click on that that's the metal ball properties we can change the resolution there's
two resolutions he wants a resolution in our viewport.
One is when we go to render it the viewport is the one that I'm most interested in at the moment I'll
go back into wireframe mode as I reduce the number there we get a lot more detail on our mesh.
Now be careful you could accidentally make your computer lock up if you go a little bit crazy with this
in dropping it too low but you want to have the right amount of detail for what you're doing at the
time generally you start off with less detail and you add more detail as you go and as I said that's
changing all of the the mesh for all of the metal balls that I've dropped into this object it can also
change the influence threshold and that will make the metal ball mesh itself smaller or bigger within
the area of influence here.
Similarly we can click on one particular metal bowls say Mirabelle oh one here or I can click on the
outer ring as I pointed out before click on this outer ring if I go into edit mode just hitting tab
on my keyboard now in edit mode I'm looking at just this one metal ball we get a few extra options down
here so I can at this point change the type from bold to capsule to cube and so on I can also change
the size of it nice and easily change the radius now something I point out with the cube is as you change
the radius to be smaller on the cube it gets a little bit sharper around the edges if that's what you're
looking for if you make it bigger it kind of gets a little bit more rounded and gruyere on the outside
of the the cube we can also change the size of it on the x y and z axes if I was on the capsule then
I would just have on the x axis if I was in a ball and we don't have any of that we just have the radius
that I can make larger or smaller it's kind of good if you want to finesse something and you don't wanna
go playing around with the scale or you could just see s and do a pretty similar thing with the scale.
However when we are in a capsule there's a little bit more control we can say just scale on the this
x axis and the other main the owner to jump within this menu is really cool we have the ability to make
a negative metal ball I love the common his set metal ball as a negative one.
So if you click on that that will eat into the other metal balls now it's disappeared which is called
is negative but I can still hit G and move it around you can see as I move it it's absorbing into the
other metabolize that creates a pretty cool effect here it's also a good way of chiseling out a hole
within something.
So let me just show you that super quickly which one of my meatballs were on a grab here that one duplicate
moved over to the side Oh okay I've made my first error here I did this deliberately while I didn't
actually but let me show you if you duplicate while in edit mode all manner of nonsense happens so I'm
going to undo that I'm going to jump back into object mode now I'll duplicate it will create my object
properly I'm going to now jump back by hitting tab into edit mode just reduce the radius so it's a little
bit thinner and I will rotate this guy around rotate rotate.
Okay so I need to g z bring it up in the world now when I click on negative it should be eating a hole
within the rest of my object so as I move it around you can see it's creating kind of a cool organic
bullet hole or a cave or some sort of weird wound on my blob object here you can see the amount of detail
around the outside don't stress about that too much we're using meatballs as a strategy for blocking
things out as opposed to giving us the final detail at some point you might get there and say that's
not quite enough detail I don't like that messiness around the outside I'll click on my first of all
back in object mode I'll click on my top level met a ball and I will decrease the value here to give
us more fidelity so it makes it a little bit smoother.
Okay that's enough watching it's time for some doing I have a challenge for you to make a bug so using
medals make some sort of or Slough or Caterpillar or something similar to that I'd like you to use at
least two types of metal so a sphere and a capsule not just spheres entirely use a couple of different
things and also use at least one negative metal bowl so to subtract the shape from your overall shape
if you come up with something that you're proud of then please do share in the forum.
This is not something we're going to put a lot of time and love into is just to practice the process
and to make our mistakes now so that when we're working on our proper animal later in this section we've
already had a chance to play around with it so pause a video take on that challenge and when you come
back I'll take you through my process of making my own little caterpillar okay I've deleted my other
things because I'm going to start from scratch.
I'm going to shift a ad metal bowl.
I will add an ellipse soit I think because that kind of feels a little bit like a caterpillar body.
My idea is to make my caterpillar look a little bit like it's walking if I can figure out how to do
that so shift D.
Moving that long I'm just going to hop into my side view and shift D dropped along again.
Could I get a little bit variation in the height.
Don't have it all exactly the same.
You know I'm going to make this go up in the air.
This is where it's going to look like our thingy is walking a little bit of an arch because that's what
caterpillars do when they walk.
I think they do an arch definitely that exaggerated.
Okay.
And then the tail I think this is the tail yes it is the town in the end here.
And then up the front end we will do a head click on this metal bowl duplicate up in the air a little
bit.
I think I'd like to have the head as a sphere rather than our lips oid just before I jump out of this
view.
I'm going to just change some sizes of things that doesn't look quite so everything's exotic exactly
the same.
Just go a little bit variation in there which is good to do I think when you've got organic things you
don't want it to look too precise.
Now do we.
So this first medal shift move it up to the top.
Going into edit mode in edit mode I'll change this to a bowl.
Increase the radius.
Nice and big.
Excellent.
Back into object mode so don't forget which I sometimes do and we'll have the head just there.
The zing around looks good.
I like it now.
What's a caterpillar need.
Couple of antennae back into my side view I'm going to duplicate this metal ball move it up not too
far scale it down to about that big we move it back a little bit of forward.
How would the antenna maybe forward.
Looks like it's in racing mode or racing mode it might be behind anyway.
Don't overthink it Rick.
I'll just put the metal bowl there in the front you are holding down old and middle mouse wheel just
zinging around.
G move her over to the left a little bit.
Shift D.
Move this guy over to the right a little bit now and use a capsule to join the two.
Here is scrolling a little bit.
Shift D move that down into the place if I use a sphere it doesn't looks quite so good but I think a
capsule will work nicely there and change into edit mode changes to a capsule to a bit of rotating that
should be the right spot.
Make a little bit smaller radius and play around with detail just to get it to the point where we don't
have too many of those weird artifacts going on that's pretty good don't want too much detail.
Decrease the radius a little bit.
I got to speed the video up here while I make the second one.
Okay.
Not too bad and just a reminder I know that you know this already because you've been through a lot
of this content but make sure that when you duplicate you in object mode not edit mode because that
will create all manner of nonsense with our middle balls if you are accidentally in edit mode when you
duplicate.
Now I said that I would subtract something let's subtract a mouth.
I'm going to shift a metal bowl ellipse soiled hit G on the keyboard move it down to the front jump
into edit mode hitting tab and I will flatten this out a little bit so it looks a little bit more mouth
ish.
That's not too bad.
What view do we want here side view.
That's good.
Up up up up up up over to front view.
Back view front view.
Okay.
Get into the right spot.
Now you can see that we have a thing in its mouth doesn't look so good but while I'm in edit mode I
can click negative blink.
There we go we've got a mouth.
I can even make came out to be.
Yum yum yum.
Eating.
There we go.
Awesome.
So we have a very quick Caterpillar.
I'm not quite done with the metabolic yet so I'm not going to convert it into a mess just yet but that
will be a step that we need to do before we start sculpting and playing around with it and getting it
looking exactly how we want to look.
So make sure that you've finished twiddling with metal balls before you go onto that next stage which
we will do in one of our upcoming videos.
So as I talked about before I'd love to see what you've come up with please do share in the forums and
I'll see you on the next video.