Hello everybody and welcome to this quick lecture where we're going to overview what were you about
to do in this particular section fluffy bunny.
That's a good clue as to what we're going to do.
But let's have a look and a bit more detail of what's coming up.
Okay so the first thing here is a drawing we want a rough sketch of what we're going to do.
But then we jump into some modern and we're going to use metal balls and then jump straight into sculpt
in some basic sculpting techniques.
Then we're going to start applying our first particle systems and you will end up with a fluffy bunny
we sort out the fluffiness by starting to comb it in stylizing their hair and then we add some more
particle systems to generate some variety in our model.
And then we go through with children as well and making sure that we get a more realistic output.
We work on the eye because there's a focus point an ad in a sky box.
The next thing we do is start to focus on the environment so we start with a blade of grass and then
we put hundreds in there you can see that's a bit fuzzy and I'll explain a bit more about that later.
Then we start sculpting the land a bit more and making an environment for this baby to sit in.
We learn how to use saplings to create some wonderful trees and even using particle systems with a bit
more control to make a bush like this.
Finally we bring it all together and make a simple scene like this.
And if you're up to it we can even make a little animation here with depth of field to really bring
things alive.
Now do want to show you some student work here.
Absolutely phenomenal.
I'm really impressed with what these guys have come up with.
And I can't wait to see yours as well.
Yes you can see here.
And this was for normal reference material all the way through to a 3-d scene.
Absolutely spot on.
Really really impressed.
And wow what an amazing set of artwork there.
And I'm really impressed by what you guys of what I've been seeing you create already so I just wanted
to show those off.
Now before we jump straight in one thing I do want to say is that this section is going to be quite
taxing on your hardware whether you've got a fully blown system or just a basic laptop or something
along those lines.
But don't go rushing headlong in and tried to make super high quality things with thousands or hundreds
of thousands of particles.
We need to keep things sensible to do work within the capabilities of system and don't get beat bit
and if things are taking a while to render.
They do take a while to render one of those animations that you saw in the in a few seconds ago that
she took about 10 hours to render out.
That's just the nature of rendering.
And so do be patient don't worry about your quality settings don't whack them up high again as you saw
in some of those pictures.
It was quite fuzzy and fuzzy for a reason because I didn't want to wait hours and hours and hours for
a rendering.
I just wanted to see the basics of how is going to look.
And I must impress upon you as well to do that and not spend hours waiting for a rendering anyway without
any further ado.
Let's hop straight in and begin this section.