Hello everybody and welcome to this section.
So in this lecture I would like to go through a bit more detail what's coming up.
What are we going to be covering.
So we're going to be creating assets to be exported straight into an external program in this specific
case where we're going to be focused on exporting four game engines now creating your own textures and
other maps from high detail models and applying them down to a low poly version.
We're not just going to make high poly detailed models we can start off with those low poly models.
They are important and we'll dive into more details about them.
Now some of you may be thinking oh hang on a minute I don't want to make game assets.
However you can use all of the techniques.
I say this technique but any of the techniques that we discuss in the section most of them can be used
within blender as well to speed up things like rendering and just basic optimization of a scene.
And we're going to be focused on modelling a Gothic church.
Well that's gonna be my focus and once I'd encourage everybody to do is take the lessons as they come
and actually apply it to your own project as well.
I think that's really important.
So what else is coming up.
Well I'm gonna be testing my model as I go.
I won't be always bringing it on screen and just showing you opening up in Unity or unreal or Godot
but I will be testing my model as I go.
And I expect you guys to do that as well.
There's no point in making a model and then finding at the very end of the creation Oh it doesn't work
as expected.
And if you test your model as you go just as I'm going to do initially and then I'll do that in the
background rather than boring you every time with it.
But if you test as you go you spot the errors spot the mistakes or spot something quirky something that
you may need to adjust as you progress through and create your models.
We'll be looking at level of detail which is how detailed a model is based upon its distance in more
detail and I'll be keeping my scene simple primarily for teaching purposes more than anything else.
It's so tempting to start layering a ton of detail especially when we're talking about environmental
scenes within games and things like that.
Now that's not to say that you need to do that.
Now I do recommend if this is your first time running through with such a setup then I do recommend
that you also keep your scene simple so as not to overwhelm yourself on the first run.
However if you're not I expect you to push yourself at this point and really go for it.
And I encourage you to add more detail experiment and have fun.
That's the most important thing when it comes to playing around in Blender.
If you get frustrated with one model this is a great section where you can actually just make something
else and use that in my scene.
Obviously your scene will have a specific theme that you want to want to stick to.
And as I've written here wouldn't it wouldn't the scene look much more interesting with a chess set
in it now I might not get round to actually importing the chess set that we've made it may not make
sense with what I'm going for.
But if you have the opportunity to bring in some of your other models that you've already made into
the scene all the better that type of thing brings a scene to life.
OK.
So that Bout wraps up what this section is all about and I'm really excited for all of you because this
is a chance to stretch your legs and make the projects your own.
And we will start planning that in the next lecture.
See you over there.