Hello everybody and welcome in this lecture we're going to have a look at creating another scene that
we can work on but can always go back to our original layout as well.
This is incredibly useful as as you progress through making various objects you will want to make variations
perhaps to experiment with something or indeed just to create a different scene and what you don't want
to have to do is save multiple blend files and you also don't want to have to keep resetting positions
and moving things around when it's complete.
It's just not necessary at all.
Okay.
So here we have our standard layout our starting layout
The one we've got currently and we're going to create a new scene called Smash in this case and we're
going to be able to set it up and we've moved the camera and everything so that when we have a look
at the final image it looks completely different to the original one.
Let's find out more.
Hello everybody and welcome back.
So in this scene what we have currently is a cube.
Let's go and add a bit more vibrancy to the scene by adding in maybe a cylinder and let's add in an
Ico sphere over here.
And then finally a cone over there.
So we've got a scene that has objects in it we may have already set up some various collections we can
do that now, I'm going to press M and I'm going to name this collection shapes of course.
So we've got the shapes collection that's inside this scene and the scene is called scene and we can
see that at the very top here.
If I click on that I can rename it to let's say defaults or perhaps shapes.
You know it's up to you how you decide to name your scenes and what naming conventions you've gone for.
Now say we wanted a different scene but with all of these assets that we'd already made as a couple
of ways of doing that we can create a new scene at the top here to the right of shapes.
We have an option to create new, copy settings, link objects, link objects data and a full copy.
The keyword there is a full copy.
So if we wanted absolutely everything in the scene we could just go full copy it would create a scene
called shapes 0 0 1 and we can call this bam or something else depending on what you're doing with the
scene.
And then we can move things around to our heart's content and we can switch backwards and forwards between
the scenes at the top here.
We can also in the outliner change the outliner's view type and at the top here, we can click on the display
mode we can select scenes and then we can also switch between the various scenes and we can also drill
in and down into the scene detail as well.
So that's an incredibly useful thing to be able to do when you have got multiple scenes around.
The other thing that we can do to change that that's a view layer is that we can copy individual ones
so if we've got another scene a new blank scene I'm going to call this one test copy.
We can go back to one of our previous scenes that say Bam here and select the ones that we want to move
go control and C to copy them and then go to our test copy, control and V to paste.
Now one thing I want to draw your attention to is that these are all distinct and unique objects.
If we move this cube, scale it or rotate it.
What you will find is that none of the other scenes inherits those changes if we started off with our
shapes and used link objects.
We get shapes 0 0 1 and I'm going to call this linked.
So we're really clear now if I go back to my shapes and I move them scale them or rotate them.
What we find is when we go back to our linked it's exactly the same.
So if you've got a blend file that you've put together let's say a building with multiple components
to it and you change it in the source file you can have it update across everything that is linked.
That's probably not going to be a useful case in our scenario where we've got the bowling ball and pins
but it's useful to know that that exists that if you change the original would update across all of
the rest of the scenes as it stands linked is the only one that will do that.
Obviously there are some things that you won't want to update.
So this in this case that's not going to be too useful when we start moving our pins around.
Otherwise we'll be changing our default scene as well.
And that leads us on to our challenge okay.
So your challenge is to go ahead and create a new scene once you've done that set up the scene where
the ball has struck the pins so they might be flying about a little, and name the scenes appropriately
so that you know what they are at descriptive name is worth its weight in gold.
And then I'd like you to go ahead and share your scene as well.
So go ahead pause a video and give that a go. Okay everybody, Welcome back.
Let's go create a new scene where we're smashing the ball into our pins.
Okay so now we've got our bowling scene all sorted.
This is like our standard layout.
So I'm going to go up to the top here and just call it standard layouts or something along those lines
you can name it.
Of course what you want to name it so mines just going to be standard layout so I know what it is.
Let's go ahead and create a new scene and what we can do is we can link options, create a full copy.
I mean there's loads of different ways that we could work from this.
I'm going to create a full copy because then I know I've got absolutely everything there and I'm going
to call this one smash or something along those lines.
And then it's just a matter of moving things around to create a convincing look and I've still got snapping
turned on.
So let's let's move the bowling ball into here.
So if it's in that position we would have certainly struck this one so let's move over here rotate it
round slightly as if it had been knocked this one here.
Let's put it all the way back here and rotate it around like that.
This one here would have obviously been knocked this one over here.
I say obviously it might not have been.
Let's just move it around to a happy with it.
You can double press R anytime.
By the way when you double press the R key it goes into this track ball rotation.
I think we've had a look at that in the past but obviously it does depend on what you're up to.
So there we go.
This is busted through here.
This front one here looks like it's been missed.
So let's have a look at how that looks from here.
That looks like a pretty dynamic shot.
Let's move the camera in ever so slightly smash, Lets render that out and have a look and that is
pretty awesome.
Whether or not it's realistic and oh this is why it's good to render and double check.
I would have not seen that this pin was in fact clipping through the bottom.
So let's just have another look at this pin here with a look from the side and that way I can make sure
that this isn't clipping through the bottom by just moving it up and out of the way.
Okay.
So I think this one here could be moved a little bit out there a bit more dynamics and the bowling ball.
I don't want it to go through the floor so I'm going to go shift in Z to say don't move on the Z axis
and let's place it smack bang there in the middle.
Let's press render.
Okay.
I think that looks pretty good.
I'm just going to save my image, So save as and I'm going to call it smash and that's something that
I can now show off as a final render.
Now there are a couple of other things just looking at this.
These are highly glossy surfaces but they're currently not reflecting anything around them.
And also the lighting itself can be done a little bit better certainly perhaps a couple of different
lights.
So we don't have these harsh shadows around our objects.
We've already discussed three point lighting of course we could perhaps create a lighting rig around
the scene and we've got these shadows.
I'm not very happy with these shadows.
They kind of don't really connect with the objects themselves.
And we'll find out why that is in the next lecture.