Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to talk about library overrides and as you can see at the top there I've
made it very clear this is an experimental feature.
It's still in the process of being built.
Now is the new version essentially of proxies.
But it comes with a few bugs some secret ones where you go and scratch your head but essentially think
of them as the modern version of proxies.
They come with some extra features which is really useful.
And of course because it's experimental I'm really just going to go over it briefly at the moment until
it really becomes the way of doing things independent overrides to the same linked data that's useful
because you may want to say change the material on your linked data on one of the particular instances
of your object.
And on the other one you don't.
Well this will enable you to do such a thing adding independent modifiers.
That's really useful being able to subdivide something or not and not having to worry about whether
it was done in the source file making a library override of a library override.
So this is like nesting so if you have a scene in which you have a proxy you cannot create a I won't
say new thing you cannot create a new blend file linking to that scene blend file that has a proxy in
it.
That won't work.
However if it has a library override you can chain together multiple blend files.
Obviously the more you have in this chain the more potentially unstable your project is.
One change could break the law a corrupt blend file could could end up destroying something.
So we need to be careful when you go ahead and make library over and overrides of library overrides.
But enough of talking about it let's hop on over its blender and look at the library overrides
OK.
So now we're over in Blender way in our proxy church scene at the moment.
And I want to demonstrate that essentially it's exactly the same as we were working on before we've
already linked things in so we could just destroy the building that we've created so far.
Get rid of all these pieces and there we go.
We've got an empty building collection but we still have our linked files so let's bring those back.
So linking is the first step and we've made a proxy.
However what we can do instead is go to the object itself and then in the Object data properties what
we can do if we go over the chain link icon that we have here we can make that local by just clicking.
And there we go we've got no linked icon at all.
But we've broken that link and we don't want to do that we want to make sure it's able to be updated.
So I'm just going to undo that.
But you can see the other option here is to shift click to create a library override.
Now every time I've tried to do this it doesn't actually work unfortunately doesn't do anything at all.
This is likely to change in the future.
And again the warning at the beginning this is experimental some things that work as you would expect
them to.
But just the same as proxy you can go to objects relations and make a library override when we do that.
We see that we've got the chain link icon again but this time with an arrow through it and like the
proxies we can now move things around which is really really useful and that means that we can start
doing the same to the other objects here.
Let's go in and make a library override.
I'm just going to do it to the other couple here and there we go we've overridden the library links
there.
Now much the same as before we can then come in and if you go Alton de to make a duplicate of that window
to use it elsewhere you may think initially oh it looks like if we go ahead and pop it there.
Oh if I just remove the duplicate Yes I did.
OK so we duplicate it and let's just move out here.
Look we've broken the link.
Oh but it's not made it local because we cannot edit it so even though it's a unique object in our scene
with the new Object data if we go to our mesh we can see that it's still linked data and the same would
be true of the material as well.
So we can build things up.
Now I'm not going to challenge you the same as the last lecture because you're just going to end up
building the same thing again which is just a bit silly.
However this is your library overrides in a nutshell.
But one of the final things I want to show to you is that if we go ahead and save this file and go into
a new file but then try and link let's go into our links come out of here completely.
If we go into arch proxy or proxy church and go to our objects we can see our objects are here.
We can bring them into our scene.
We can't move them just as normal.
And if we look at the outline there we can see it's the linked file will 0 0 1.
However if we now go to objects and go to relations we can make a library override again.
How useful is that.
And then we're back to the stage where we can start moving things around that's really cool that we're
able to nest things like that where possible.
But remember a chain of these things may break.
Blender.
Now I've just discovered something as well.
Oh blender crash there.
So let's go ahead bring back where I was before and that's not unexpected of course because I'm dealing
with experimental stuff is bound to happen.
So where where we proxy church we went to an object doesn't matter which one let's go to our archway
bricks we can see it's linked we cannot move it around.
So what I was going to show you is that if we go into the object data properties and you know are saying
shift in click of that doesn't seem to do anything.
It doesn't.
However what you can do to realize this this is.
I read the instructions they don't work.
If you click it once it makes it a library override if you click it again then it will make it local.
So it's going to undo one of those.
And there we go.
Blender has crashed again.
Okay.
So I think I will leave it there for the moment.
As you can see it's still just a little bit unstable.
Hopefully that will all be sorted out over the coming months and we'll become much more stable.
Okay.
So that leaves us with a choice as to whether to use proxies which is the old way of doing things or
to do the library overrides I think personally I'll probably use proxies until I know that library overrides
won't crash when I undo that's that that's something I rely on the Undo key.
So yeah I don't want to risk a project like that.
However if you just going and testing try out library overrides and when you think you've got a stable
copy give us a share in the discussion so everybody knows that it's now stabilized and then perhaps
I can come back and refresh this video with working versions of library overrides and I'll see you all
in the next lecture.