Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture we are going to get on making our lower arm.
And as you can see here it's repeated on one side and another.
So we're going to revisit the mirror modifier and learn how to use it when we start moving objects around.
Okay everybody Welcome to over to the default blend file.
The reason why we're starting here is because we need to make ourselves some arms coming off of this
cube and then we'll see what effect it has when we move the cube around and then we'll go apply that
over on our lamp as well.
Now I want to go to the 3d cursor and plonk it on the edge of the cube.
Once I've done that I'm just going to add in you probably guessed it another cube scale it's on the
x axis by a little and just move it manually out and I'm going to leave a little gap there and rotate
this around 45 degrees on the x axis and then I can go into edit mode and because this is rotated if
we go and extrude or move this edge along its local y axis There we go because it's been move around
we can make it have an arm going up and then we can just scale that down accordingly probably to maybe
there.
And then of course we can stretch it out again.
Okay.
So there we go everything's almost sorted there let's go g x and move in a little closer.
I'm happy with how that's looking.
So if we wanted another arm like this over the other side because the whole scene is built around the
origin we could quite easily go to the mirror modifier and just add it in.
So where is Mira modifier.
There it is.
Now at the moment we're going to need to reflect about an object because otherwise we're just reflecting
about the objects own origin.
So we can put the origin in the center of the scene if we wanted to.
Let's say we had done that let's go g x and move that roughly to the center of the scene and then we
move the geometry out you can see how that would work.
But then if we go ahead parent these things together and we move it around you can see here that it
follows along if we move rotates or even scale it which is kind of the desired effect.
But what would be better at this point rather than just having its origin all the way over here meaning
that this object cannot be independent is if enough undo levels Yep.
There we go back to this stage is having it mirror around another object.
Now at the moment in time this object is in the center of the scene.
So we could go ahead and select the cube as that mirror object.
And once again when we move things around although it's not parenting together we do need to bear in
mind some sort of parenting or linking two together is required to move things around.
We get a similar result which is perfect that's exactly what we want.
The other thing that can be much better and not relying on other objects in the scene that make up the
match just in case you add it or move things around and you don't want these to follow is use some sort
of intermediate objects and an empty is great for this.
We've explored empties before.
There they are these null objects that you can put into your scene use them as control you can use them
as organization.
I've managed to put this one in a very odd location so let's put it back at the center of the scene
where we go and then when we're talking about the mirror modifier we can link back to the empty and
if I go ahead and grab the empty it's another way of controlling where the mirror point actually is
and if we rotate this you see that it's separate from everything else which can also be really really
useful both linking to the object that these are parts of or linking to an empty if perhaps the object
isn't centered over a particular place or linking it to an object which is really useful if the origin
might change position or you're working on it and you're moving things around and you want it to be
static and linked in a different way we can then parent the empty to the cube.
Now it seems like it's jumping through a couple of hoops but what it does mean is that now if I move
the cube everything else will follow suit.
However the arms themselves are one step decoupled from the cube.
So with this knowledge it's time for your challenge okay.
So I'd like you to create the rest of your stem at the base and then create your lower arm or arms using
the mirror modifier now and use another object to control the mirror points.
I would recommend an empty it's entirely up to you whether you use it and I'd recommend pairing thing
them together.
So at the moment if you move things around as we experienced in the last lecture they actually stay
together.
Pause video now and give us a go.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and hop on over into blender and start creating our lower arm okay.
So this is where we left off before.
Just let me spend a few moments tweaking the layout here to give me a bit more working space.
Okay so we're focusing on the stem at the moment.
So let's select the stem.
Have a look at it.
Now I could start manipulating this geometry but I think what I'm going to do is I'm gonna create a
nother bits of mesh data in here that's separate from that STEM.
Just to keep it all together and progress quickly.
Now remember when you're doing this especially for the first time don't focus too much on the modeling
aspects.
We're really focused on this adding armchairs and doing some animation.
By all means if this is your second run through or you're a bit more competent then by all means make
a more polished model.
But in this case what I'm gonna do is I'm going to move my curse it's a selective sits at the top and
in a cube.
Oh that's not a cube that's a plane.
Add in a cube.
Scale that down and you'll notice that we've got a few weird things going on here.
And that's because the subdivisions surface modifier is turned on.
I'm going to ignore that for the moment because I can see what I'm working with my zoom levels here
are a bit crazy.
I can't really focus properly on the modelling.
So with that selected I'm going to press the period or full stop on the number pad which is going to
allow me to focus and zoom without those very very large steps.
If you don't have a numb pad you can get that under view and frame selected.
There we go.
That's the shortcut for that.
Okay.
We're gonna need a couple of loop cuts in here.
I'm only going to do them one way so I'm going to need two in there.
Looks good to me.
And then I can wrap these edges here.
I could do a couple of things I could go GZ and lift them up but that's not really going to do what
I want it to.
I think that sort of tuning fork look is pretty good.
Now I am just going to turn off the subdivision surface modifier for the moment.
It's not going to do me any good.
And we can come back in and remodel things later on.
Now I've got an option here of starting to need to add up maybe put some devils around the edges here
to make it look a bit neater.
But again we can come back to that later on now in order to place the first.
Amen.
I'm just gonna go round to one of the sides and I'm going to select one of those faces and I want it
to appear right bang in the middle of that.
So with that face selected oh I'm going to go control is to save my work and I'm gonna go shift s and
cursor to selected because now when I add in another it's a mesh data we'll be able to work from that
but I don't want to add it as part of this object.
Otherwise when we use the mirror modifier we're going to have an issue actually doing our work so we're
going to come out and make this as a separate objects.
Now I can add in a cube.
So very standard basic object scale it down to point 1 and then we can start tweaking and messing around
with things.
Now I'm struggling to see some of my scene when I was round from one side to the other.
So I'm just going to hide everything else that I don't need in my scene looks good.
And then we're whizzing round to here.
Okay.
Now this object itself I'm going to go into edit mode and start manipulating it.
I want it roughly there and I'm going to grab this face and just push it in.
Now at this point in time I could turn on snapping that would work really well in terms of where to
place it's going to turn on snapping and just pull it across.
I'm going to leave a little bit of a gap there is going to add to the look of the lamp and later on
I can even puts some sort of joining material between the two pivot points as well only come and grab
this and rotate it around by 45.
Again I'm doing a lot of this in edit mode at the moment and let's extend this out.
So let's go look about I rotated it by forty five.
I didn't specify any particular angle access to do that round.
So that's where it sits on the x axis by forty five.
That's better okay.
Brilliant.
Now it's rotated at 45 degrees with this top face selected.
I'm going to switch my transform orientation to normal.
Which means that when I look at this from the side and extrude my new piece it goes where I want it
to.
That's probably too far.
That's fresh DG so I can just move along the existing edge is probably about there.
Okay so that's the first part sorted I'm going to come out and I am going to use shall I use the stem
or an empty.
I'm going to use an empty.
I'm going to move the 3d cursor to the middle here.
So with the property side bar open I'm going to go to view.
And here we go.
So X to zero and then I can add in my empty there.
Am I still in edit mode.
No I'm not.
Okay.
Empty plane access and I'm going to call this lower.
Mira I'm talking about naming how I actually got things named that's lamp stem.
That one's not so let's call this lower arm looking good.
Now we've got a bit of parenting to do here.
I'm just gonna parent those things together and then in a bit we'll be parenting to bones for control
as well.
So that looks good there.
Let's go ahead select this arm go to our modifiers mirror modifier.
I'm going to use and I'm going to type in here Mira and the great thing is with the search box there
because I've named something we can just hop in and do it like that.
That's looking pretty good.
Yes I'm liking that lots.
Now one thing I can start to say straight away is perhaps this mechanism here is far too big perhaps
I can have one single stem here coming up in the middle and needs to be closer in who.
Now there's an idea I'm going to modify my design immediately to do that.
So let's grab this go in and I'm just gonna select these two tops.
Press X and delete the vertices.
Use this one here and extrude upwards looks good.
And then we've just got these faces around at the bottom which I can do a loop select for and press
F to fill.
Of course you can't really do that unless there is not a face there.
And that looks good.
And then finally we just need to grab this object here and move it in closer once again we can look
at their square g x and move it in and I'm just going to eyeball it at this point rather than faffing
around with anything else.
Now I can see an immediate problem here when it rotates it's going to bump in here but we can sort all
of those details out later okay.
That looks much much better.
Well this is one of the great things about reviewing your model as you're going making decisions.
Even though this is rough and ready we've come across a couple of problems having it how I thought I
was going to have it made it look really odd and super wide on the stem looks much better now.
And we've come into the problem that as this rotates and because the origin is there this is the other
reason why put the origin there.
We can fake it rotating it's actually impacting slightly here.
Now there are ways of getting rid of the easiest way once we're in edit mode to select that edge that
edge that edge and that edge I could use selected the two faces at this point and just go GZ and pull
that down ever so slightly and that's given us the clearance we need.
Awesome.
Let's save our work.
We don't want to lose anything that's very important.
I haven't had a look at this in rendered mode looks pretty good so far.
Excellent.
I want to switch it to look death mode and look far prettier and turn off my overlays.
Yes that's coming along really well.
Brilliant.
How are you guys getting on.
I'm super excited that this is now coming together really really well.
Please share your working designs over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.