Welcome to profile modelling using curb's in this video.
You'll create some alternative detail convert mesh objects into curve objects.
Then use two curves to create geometry along and then use those two curves to create geometry one controlling
the profile.
The other path will see that this is great for a more accurate path following.
So let's hop straight on over into a blender.
Okay so we're back over in blender and the first thing before we move onto the curves I notice wind
spinning around my model.
It looks a bit odd at the top here and when I say went all the way round I saw that I've got crossed
over geometry.
I think when I was scaling I've inadvertently managed to push the model through itself.
Now whether or not that's going to have a massive impact on the end of production it probably will.
So now I spotted that mistake I will have to go back and correct that.
Make sure you check your models over and make sure that you haven't pushed any geometry through itself.
I didn't spin round so I didn't see it.
I was just looking from the area that looked good unfortunately.
But there we go.
So let's move on to Curves themselves so first of all I'm going to select this object the window frame
that we've made and I'm going to duplicate it because I'm going to use the same profile that I've already
created to generate the next curve and then going to hide the original window frame hop into here and
I'm going to call this window frame profile curve for the moment so I know exactly what it is.
Once I've done that I'm going to hop into edit mode and remove all the unnecessary geometry.
Now you can limit vertices to a visible if you want to with the toggle on the 3d edita header.
I do prefer using the wireframe mode because then its really is explicit that you're going to be able
to select items through your model.
I'm going to go here and grab and we can see the mess at the top there and then go and grab these top
vertices here and deletes those and then I'm going to grab the ones down here as well and get rid of
those.
And that leaves me with the profile itself.
But this is a mesh profile at the moment so what we can do is hop into object mode and go to object
and convert.
And that's right at the top here.
Convert to curve and obviously have so convert curve so curve from mesh.
And here we have old C..
Just to remind you what that is.
So now it is a curve object.
I do not want to keep the original.
In this case I'm a believer untaped and that will remember the last setting you had so if I had kept
one before then it would still be there.
The next thing that I want to do is generate a curve.
Now I could go through creating a curve and lifting it up and through.
Now one of the things that you can do is obviously duplicate this edge that runs around here and use
that as a curve.
So lets go and try that.
Now lets go ahead and go to the appropriate model and hide the other one is well from the scene or is
done automatically.
On a different.
Okay so lets go ahead and copied to edit mode.
Select the edges we want to be used for a path which are these outer ones here.
Once those are selected we go going to duplicate them.
We are going to separate them.
And there we go we've got here and I'm going to call this curve.
I suppose I should call it window frame path because that's what it's going to become.
Now in object mode I can use Oulton see.
And once again convert from a mesh to occur.
Well again I don't want to create.
Keep the original.
So let's go and see how this works out so we need to give the path a bevel to go around.
So whilst the path is selected we can hit the curve data and down here we can bevel it around that particular
object and in this case we can use the profile curve.
There we go we end up with a very similar curve as we did before of a help out of wireframe.
Ah ha.
You will see here that the normals are in fact the wrong way around.
No we're not going to deal with that right at this moment.
How would just have a quick look around the rest of the model first before sorting those out.
Let's just check that that's right does that fit the curve.
It doesn't look quite right in the middle is something missing.
Ah okay.
So when I selected the outline originally from the window frame it looks like I've missed the bit.
It hasn't come back out here at all and it should have done or is it inside the model.
Okay so there is a rotation going on here now.
It's a rotation of the path itself even though it's a line in 3-d space.
It has rotation.
So what we can do is hop in to the path's rotation so go and go into edit mode for the path itself and
we can see is there a select all of them and change the mean tilt which you can see here over in the
propertys panel of the 3D editor and that will twist it along that path looks kind of funky obviously.
If you keep going round and round and round if I hop out of wireframe married we can see that as we
tilt that round it then appears the right way.
So at this point I think it's going to be minus 90 to put it in the right place.
No more than that.
Oh that's mine as tight the right number in is it minus 90.
No that looks wrong let's try 90 that looks right.
And of course at this point if we wanted something the other side which we haven't done yet.
If I wanted something the other side could apply a mirror modifier.
Now I have in this the do I have the mirror plain.
Was that the doorway.
I don't seem to have a mirror plain here so I'm going to try mirroring our round.
Nope none of these options are going to be good enough Sard have to create an empty and mirror around
that.
I'm going to do that at the moment but there we go that's a nice and simple path.
The normals are the wrong way round and that will be generated from this profile curve itself that means
the normals of this curve are in fact the wrong way round so we can sort that out now.
Now we can convert this to a mesh objects and flip the normals.
We know how to do that.
However we can also change the direction that this curve is being generated.
It is the profile one that's causing this.
Normal inflection and we might not want to remove the curve object from the actual blend file for various
reasons.
So in this case we can flip those by selecting all of the points along the curve.
The profile curve and then go into curve going to curve segments and switch direction and there we go.
That has been reflected of course at this point.
We can play with the resolution of the curve so we've got a couple of resolution points here.
We've got the one that follows.
It's round and we can't really make that any sharper than it already is without manually editing it.
And we got the profile itself so we can go in here and change the preview for both of those.
It doesn't get any better by changing the profile curve because it's already got as many segments as
it needs and the window path.
Well let's just try changing that.
And surprisingly or unsurprisingly it doesn't make a difference either.
And that's because the path is fixed at certain points.
There is no bend.
So changing the resolution doesn't matter.
However turning smooth shading on can help it look much better.
Brilliant.
And of course it's time for a challenge.
I would like you to create some curve driven geometry try using a bevel curve on your other models and
remember to share your work.
In the discussions pause the video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's go straight back over into blender.
Sunday is going to make sure I've saved my work here so I'm going to go file save and then I'm going
to go to my door and demonstrate a similar thing on the door.
So get a copy the archway and see a group get of that perfect.
And name its arch.
Way.
This is going to be profile or convert that to a curve in a moment.
Now I'm going to do V.
Elodie door as well and select.
Excellent.
I could just select the edgeley there it's got all of the information I need yet.
So let's duplicate that.
Separate that.
And there we go we have it down here and I'm going to call that arch way all path.
Okay so now that we've got the archway path and the archway profile we need to sort out the profile
itself.
So it is an actual single profile of entire work so let's pop in.
And of course it's myriad.
So this is going to be even quicker we can just select those there.
In fact if I hop into a wire frame and make it even easier to select everything x for the LEA and legal
vs. no case so let's hide away the front door archway that we've created.
There we go.
And we should now be able to convert.
That's all.
There's one the other side as well.
That is the mirror modifier going to hide that to prevent myself getting confused or in fact in this
case I can will just remove it altogether.
Okay so now I've got a hunger to leave the subsurface modifier hidden for the moment.
I'm just going to see how much of a difference that can make as well.
So I've got my profile ready.
Let's go ahead and convert that into a curve and the same with the archway path as well.
So now those two items are done.
We can go straight into the PAFF curve data scrolled down to the bevell object as like the archway profile.
Now is it the right way around.
And are the normals the right way.
Normals are the wrong way.
But this time the archway itself has actually been generated the right way round which saves me a lot
of time faffing.
The only thing I need to do here is go to the profile itself and go to oh don't edit mode curve segments
switch direction.
And that is sorted.
It's gone all the way over.
Let's just see if the subsidies surface division makes any difference whatsoever.
I don't think it will.
So let's go to the PAFF itself add a subset.
The always made quite a bit of difference that helps smooth out the archway really nicely.
A pleasant surprise there of course.
This one's actually got the mirror objects inside can go one step further on this particular model and
mirror it around my mirror point.
And now my all he says needs to be on the y axis that we do not be x.
Okay.
And there we go we've got vads in roughly the right place now it looks like ah okay the mirror object
is not really in the right place doing this is to be in the middle of the door itself so I'm going to
go ahead and grab the mirror.
And in its location transform on the properties I think it's going to have to be minus point one.
Location.
So minus point one.
There we go.
Now the archway is on both sides of the door.
Interestingly here is that's.
Yeah.
There's a little bit of a dent here where it's being constructed but that's okay that adds to the detail
in the door itself that is coming along really well.
How are your models coming along.
I'd love to see them please share them in the discussions so everybody can see what you're up to in
your designs.
If you're going for an alternative style I love seeing those as well.
If you're not following along with the Gothic church what are you doing.
I can't wait to see it.
So remember to share them in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.