We're starting the process of creating an animal, I have chosen a cat as my animal.
And in this lecture, we'll go about the process of grabbing a couple of reference images so that we
know what it is we're creating.
Let's get ourselves set up with a new project.
I'm going to start mine and then just a little bit of twiddling with the overlays.
I'm going to turn off the 3D cursor and turn off the floor.
And also, I'm going to hide the camera and light.
It's just so those things don't get in the way of seeing what's going on.
I'm going to right click start a new collection and this collection I will double click and coal lights
and camera and action, of course, as the saying goes and click and control click.
Drag those into the scene.
The Cube.
I'm going to click on and delete.
So the wall already with a nice clean scene, ready to go save that into your place of choice.
Save excellently.
Now for those of you feeling advanced, I've got a mega challenge for you.
You don't have to take this on, but this is a good way for you to test out all the things that you've
learned so far.
His take on this challenge without following along with me and the challenge is to choose an animal
could be any animal you want.
It could be a rabbit.
It could be a cat.
A dog could be a mouse.
Guinea pig.
A lion, a tiger, whatever your heart desires.
Obviously, if it's more complicated, it's going to be a bigger, deeper challenge for you.
Once you've picture animal, find some reference images for it and then to block it out, sculpt it
and add hair to the animal, adding some color in there as well.
And for bonus points, place the animal in some sort of environment or scene.
So this is the process that I'm going to be going through in the next bunch of videos.
But if you wanted to test yourself, you could go and build your animal, create your animal, I should
say, before I do.
And then maybe compare notes as we go along.
Or if you'd like to follow along with me.
Fantastic.
That's a process that I'm going to go through now.
And the first step is to find ourselves some reference images.
Now, I've got a couple of things to recommend to you here.
One is pixels, dot com.
There's plenty, plenty, plenty, lots and lots of free image stock photography sites.
But this one just at the moment is free and free use and no license issues.
So you can do whatever you want with the images.
That's why I like it at the moment.
But by the time you're watching this video, hopefully it's still free and still cool.
If I jump in here and type in CAT, then I get literally a million cats.
It seems people love photographing cats.
That's part of the reason I've chosen these.
You can also type in rabbit and make yourself a fluffy bunny if you wanted.
There's so many cats.
What I'm looking for when I'm looking for animal images is something that's a nice, clean front on
shot and also a nice clean side on shot so that I can get those those angles and I can have two images
that I put into my scene.
What I'm also going to do is grab a neat little app called Pure RF to a pure Radford's at pure RF dot
com.
This allows us just to lay out our imagery.
This is a tip that I got from Grant Abbott, one of my fellow instructors get pure refs.
I've already downloaded it.
But if you want to do this, download pure ref and then open it up.
Go through all the usual instillations steps with pure ref.
Find where that's been installed or just search for it on your machine and pure ref will open it up.
So it's a little bit different to use.
You have to right click to move it around to get it where you want to.
Right click.
Let me just organize my windows here so I can see these side by side.
This is pure ref on the left and images as I'm searching through.
Okay.
This is a good front on shot.
I can just left click and drag straight into pure RFM.
Look Verity's and I can scroll in and out using my mouse will and left click to move the image.
Let's see what else do I want.
Looking, looking, looking.
That's another good front on this artist.
Grab that and drag it on in.
What else have I got?
So this is a process.
You can go and grab a whole bunch of reference images very quickly.
I like the colour of this one and have it as a nice little mood board.
What you will need to do for ease if you find the two that you want to have in your scene.
I'm going to have to in my scene, a front on one and a side on one.
Make sure you save those to your hard drive so you can then add them easily into your scene.
Of course, if you have downloaded something already saved, it's your hard drive.
Then you can just go ahead and drag them in to your heart's desire to set up the images that I've got.
I'm actually just gonna go and grab all of them, drag them all in and see what happens.
Bom, bom, bom, bom.
Okay.
And it nicely arranges them in a mood board like that.
That's really handy to be out to do that, just to dump them all in one go, just to have to give you
more depth when you're doing maybe little add details like, oh, that's what I need to look for in
the POI.
You can zoom right in and use use H RF as a tool or you can just do it old school by clicking on a particular
image and just scrolling through and having a look.
So one thing I wanted to point out, this is a kind of scene that I like.
There's lots of foliage and stuff around grass getting in the way of the cat.
So it's not just all that he's a cat sitting on a pedestal.
I'm putting it into the scene, which means I'll probably take some short cuts down the bottom of the
animal and not do the feat in superhigh detail just because I don't really need it in my final scene.
Okay.
Back over into Blender.
Just a couple of notes.
Make sure in.
Preferences, if we go to add ons that you still have images as planes that is clicked on that superimportant
cool, because now what we're going to do is I'm just going to drag two images straight.
I'm going to find the two that I like the most.
OK.
I think I like this stalking image fir from the side.
That's the sort of pose that I want to have in my final image.
And front on I think this gives me all the detail I need, particularly with these front legs.
I think that's what I need for details.
So I got to put those too into my scene.
And I'm just going to find those where I've saved them on my hard drive.
Just drop stalking cat straight in.
And that should go in as a plane.
Let me click on that and just hit and delivery of tidying up on item the rotation, whatever you want
on the X, I'll do 90.
On the X Y.
I'll put zero.
And on Z I'll do to 90 as.
Click on X.
Move that into position.
There we go.
Roundabout there.
Excellent.
The size and scale.
I'm not worried about so much at the moment because I'm not putting this into an external scene or a
game engine.
I'm just going to work with what it is at the moment.
So that should be fine.
Probably about one meter for the whole image making the cat.
What would that be?
Maybe about 70, 70 per cent of that.
So, yeah, that's fine.
That's in the right ballpark.
It's not like I'm working it on a scale where it's 100 million or something.
Push that back on the X.
Okay.
My other image.
What did I say I was going to work with.
This image here.
Drag it on in.
Once again, just get the rotation.
Correct.
This I believe is going to be.
90 on X, zero on Y and zero on Z.
Is that correct?
I think that is G.
Y.
Move it back.
Blink actually, logically, I think because the head is facing that direction.
I'm going to put my image g y.
I mean the other side.
Okay.
Yes, that's good.
I think that's how I'd be looking at it.
So the challenge I have for you is to pick your animal, choose the animal you'd like to model, gather
reference images for your animal of choice.
Make sure you have a front view and a side view.
Drop them into your scene.
And when you've done that, I will see you in the next lecture.