Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we are going to use the array modifier in order to make these steps.
There is in fact only one step here and it's repeated several times.
You can also see there's some other things that we need to watch out for as these steps are pushing
through our railings and we don't want that to happen as all but over into a blender and find out more.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
The first thing that I wanted to do before we do anything else here is I'm going to rename my cube.
This is this hasn't been a cube for a very long time.
I hope some of you have been screaming at the screen saying Mike you haven't even named your pyramid
yet please name it.
And I probably think you have already mentioned that.
But here we go.
I've renamed my pyramid.
I'm just going to go ahead and make sure I save that appropriately.
And now that that's saved we can go ahead and play with the array modify now instead of playing with
it in here.
I'm gonna go ahead and create myself a new blend file that we can hop back to in a bit.
Okay.
So with our cube here I am going to just duplicate the cube and move along the X axis.
So it's just over to the side. Lets start off with this cube and go to the wrench or spanner icon I'm
going to make this column just a little wider.
Now once we're in this area we can add a modifier.
Now the great thing about modifiers is they modify what you have in front of you in a non-destructive
way.
As we see that it's a procedural operation or effect to the active objects.
In this case we're going to go to generating additional geometry using the array modifier.
And what this has done is it's added in another cube as we can see here the count says 2 so there's
two of them.
The original one and the one that's being generated and we can increase that number let's say to six
and then we have underneath a constant offsets or relative offsets.
Now relative offset takes into account the size of the cube.
So if we put one in the X direction and one in the Z direction it will step up like a series of stairs.
If we have a constant offset and have a 1 and 1 you'll see it looks significantly different.
And the reason for that is the cubes are two meters by two meters.
So relative is great when you need to repeat an object over and over again and constant is great when
you've got to fit them into a certain space.
Speaking of fitting them in and we'll get to these settings later on in the course we also have a couple
of types so we can fit an array around curve we can fit them around a certain length as well which is
also incredibly useful.
I'm going to leave it is relative offset for the moment and turn off constant.
As you can see you can have more than one turned on.
Finally you can have something actually offset with another object.
And that's really useful for having curves and spirals and once again we'll get to that later on.
So now that I have the array here it's not real.
That's the important thing to bear in mind if we go ahead and delete the array.
Everything goes and let's undo that for a moment if we decide to apply the array then it becomes real
geometry and it's editable but we've lost the flexibility of it being part of a modifier.
So we can't quickly modify it anymore.
There are pros and cons to doing this.
In you'll experience those pros and cons as we start using the modifiers more and more for the moment
what's all the device that you do is only apply modify if it is necessary if it is not necessary leave
it as a modifier because it gives you the options later on to go back and edit the modifier and create
new geometry and easily edit your models.
The final thing that I wanted to show you is if we want to use the modifier again on another cube in
this case the one that we duplicated earlier we can go ahead and select the cube or the object we
want to inherit.
Let's try something else.
Let's add in Suzanne the monkey and move her along the X axis.
There we go.
And now I want to shift select the objects I want to inherit modifiers from I can't just pick a single
modifier if there were more than one
applied to our cube.
Suzanne would inherit that as well.
But if you've spent some time tweaking and setting up some settings in an array modifier and you want
to reuse that it would be silly to have to type all of that information again.
So what we can do is select them like we have done here so the one we want or ones we want to inherit
the modifiers are selected first and then we active selected as the one we want to inherit the modifiers
from we can then go control
and L, we will see this a couple of times throughout the course where we need to grab something really
quickly from another model and then we can go ahead and grab the modifier.
So we're going to make links and copy those modifiers over.
Now once we've done that if we go back to our original and change it it does not cascade down it doesn't
inherit them anymore.
It just inherits the modifier as it was at the time one final thing to touch on here is that modifiers
in general can be affected by UN applied transforms.
So if you have scaled rotated anything do bear that in mind when you go ahead and use a modifier that
it may change depending on what that modifier is and how you're using it.
It will vary as I say from modifier to modifier.
In this case the array modified can actually be affected by any unapplied transform so make sure that
you apply them to avoid any undesirable effects.
And with that it's time for your challenge okay.
Challenge time, its time to create those steps.
So using an array modify creates smaller steps leading all the way to the top of the pyramid.
Now I recommend half metre, quarter metre or even eighth meter height steps.
Just makes it a lot easier to do the numbers all the way to the top.
Fix any holes left in your model you may find after you put the steps all in the either of the top all
the bottoms align aligned quite right.
So just fix that up at the end.
Puase the video now and give that a go. Okay everybody welcome back.
Let's hop over into blender and create some steps.
Hello everybody and welcome back.
So in front of us we've got our pyramid.
It could do with some steps.
Now I know these big steps are approx.
Well they are one meter high.
I'm going to try half meter steps going up and I can just add in a new cube and scale it not on the
Y axis which is useful because it would be correct by point two five.
Now it's half a metre tall and I'm going to move on the Z axis by 10.
Excellent.
And then I probably need to lift it up by let's have a look let's just move it by
eye initially is going to be point two five isn't it nought point two five.
So there we go.
We've got our step in an appropriate place and we're almost ready to use the array modifier on it.
One of the things that I noticed when showing you guys earlier is that these two ends are pushing through
so I'm gonna make sure with those ends selected they are moved in.
So snapping is a brilliant option here I'm going to snap to face the press G to move that and snap it
to this face.
Of course locking it to in this case is local Z axis.
I was not expecting that.
There we go.
Of course here upon reflection I've just left it with the transform orientation set to normal as we
can see at the top here.
so G Z,
There we go.
Perfect.
And we can check in wireframe mode that is in fact where we would want it to be and we can even turn
on transparency to see it's perfectly lined up.
Okay so that's a great start.
The next thing we now need to do is go to our array modifier.
So let's add array modifier in, it looks like we're going to be moving negative 1 and up 1.
Here we go.
And now we just need to ooop all the way up.
Okay.
It looks like I'm gonna have that many.
So 16 in total.
And let's have a look around our model.
Now I think we could actually probably do more steps up there so I can tweak that in a moment.
That's the great thing about it being relative and we will need to move around our model as well to
compensate.
But anyway that's the basics.
Done.
Here we go.
This is what I was warning you about in the challenge.
We may need to alter our model to match up with the steps now before we decide where we're going with
that.
I want to make sure I've got the right number of steps present first.
Otherwise adjusting the rest of the geometry isn't going to work.
So I'm going to backpedal a little.
I want this to be half the size again.
So I'm gonna scale everything selects everything and scale it on the Y.
Sorry not on the Y axis.
By point 5.
It's going to get smaller.
And I'm gonna have to move it down at this point.
And I've also not applied my transform so let's apply my scale.
It hasn't made any difference to our model which is useful and I'm going to move this down to point
1 2 5.
I'm having to think there.
There we go.
And now this is gonna be 32 up.
I'm pretty sure and once we get to the very top we've got ourselves some alignment to do so I'm going
to go ahead grab this edge the other edge.
There we go.
Edge snapping.
I'm gonna go G to start moving it around I want to snap it to this edge.
I want to lock it to the X axis.
Now that doesn't appear to.
Oh it's locked it to the wrong X axis.
There we go.
That's now the appropriate X axis.
So we no longer got a hole in the top of our model and that is looking pretty good.
I think those double steps there made all the difference rather than having them as they were before.
Brilliant.
Let's turn.
LookDev and have a look around our model with a bit of shading turned on.
We're gonna start adding some lights to our scene soon.
You may have already done that in anticipation at the moment of course.
The lamp is not really in an appropriate place but anyway that is starting to look really nice.
I like the number of steps that I've got there and I'm liking the overall feel of my model.
How are you guys getting on.
How many steps did you choose did you go for the big ones that I had.
Have you gone for even smaller.
Of course all of these decisions are just aesthetic at the moment and I think this looks a lot better
as smaller steps than I did as larger.
So I'm happy I made that change.
Please share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.