Welcome to the mix.
RG been showed in this video will use it to mix two colours together.
Will see that it can also be used to mix more than just colours except six channels in through the two
colour inputs and three channels out mixing together those two colour inputs based upon two things.
The blend type and the factor says Go play with this mix r.g. be note now and hop on over into blender.
Okay so I'm going to be working on a sphere because I'd like spheres.
Simple as that.
So let's go ahead and add a basic sphere to my scene.
I'm going to lift that up and I'm also going to add a plane to the scene and scale it outwards.
Now just to make sure my materials from last time are working I'm going to make a chequered floor and
this is going to be that.
Ready.
Plastic.
Let's switch into rent mode.
Perfect Couple of things left to do here is this particular sphere needs to be so nice and smooth so
we can see what's going on.
Excellent so that's all set up and ready to go see the power of having all of these materials set up
ready to go just makes things setting up so much quicker.
So let's grab a node editor.
I'm going to just get rid of some of the toolbars around here and the node editor open here.
Now one thing we can do here is change the colour so oh notice this is polished wood here I've obviously
used this basic for an L node that we had set up before the scroop node used on something else and forgot
to click the little number over the property to make it unique some chemical that P.
B r and I made a note to go ahead and make sure I save that to my the fault file again so I don't have
to do that multiple times.
So we've got a colour input here.
Now what we can do in this colour input is have a mix of two separate colours coming in for instance.
So you could go ahead and add in a colour under the add colour menu mix.
RG So you've got a colour output that we can put straight into here.
Now we've got two colours now I'm going to choose almost 100 percent green.
I know we shouldn't choose 100 percent colours but again we're just testing the mixing that's going
on here and 100 percent red and non-support or not surprising at all we get a yellow out with a 50 50
mix.
Now we've got a couple of options here we can change how all these are mixed together.
If we want to and you can go through and try the different varieties of mixing that we can go through
I tend to leave it's just on mix in general and we have a factor here that obviously we can change it
from one to the other.
But of course that's boring.
We'd want something to control this factor itself.
And that leads me nicely onto a challenge.
I'd like to go ahead and get mixing so use the mix.
RG been known to mix together to colours control the factor with the generated texture.
And then for a bit more interest why don't you try adding a bump node into the system using the texture
to add more interest in the material and affect the normal so it's not just a smooth surface anymore.
Pause the video now and give that ago.
Okay guys welcome back.
Let's go mixing over in blender.
Okay so we're back over in blender and we've got this mix note here and it's a bit boring at the moment
with just these two colours.
Now I've got an idea I'd like to try.
I'd like to try adjusting this factor using a texture.
So let's go ahead and go to textures.
And of course if you got an image texture you could apply.
You could go ahead and do that.
But in this case I'm going to use one of these generated textures wave.
I to add that to our model.
I've added it to the wrong part.
There we go.
So in fact and let's just have a look at what the wave is outputting on the colour and on the factor
whereas putting the same thing on both in this case.
So here we have a black and white texture so it's alternating between green and red.
So let's go back to our Mc snoad and see what the outside of there is.
Okay.
And everything together.
Okay that's starting to come together.
Now I'm going to play with the scale settings here.
And I want to increase the distortions a bit wavy Yeah.
Okay.
That's a lot of distortion there that's lower the scale even more if I can.
And this detail I'm going up the detail so we get a kind of a mottled affect.
So so go take a little bit of playing to get the kind of effect that I want some not quite there at
the moment 50.
Let's try a hundred and fifty.
How that's starting to look better.
Excellent.
So we changed these colours here servair a bit more representative of what this sort of colours that
I want to.
Again I'm going to try and avoid using extreme to extreme colours.
I want them to be semi realistic.
Okay so we've got almost like a cloud covered marble or something on those lines.
Now to add a little more interest into this I could actually use this wave texture that we've got here
because it's black and white.
We can use it to control something else now flat things like this are boring so we can add some real
texture some real bumps to it.
By utilizing this wave texture as well to control a bump node so if I go ahead and add in a bump node
to remember where it is and a vector bump and we can use it to control the height some would become
to use the factor in this case to control the heights and then are going to have a look and isolate
the bump mode and see what's happening.
Now we will see the normal output but we can see there's quite a cool texture being applied there and
we can adjust the strength of that accordingly and leave it set to one and distance here is obviously
going to make kids more or less extreme.
And I'm going to leave that's quite low down so we don't o'farrelly exaggerates what's going on.
Okay so these together let's have a look at what it looks like.
I need to plug the normal in to the normal input we've got set up a How about that they're starting
to look much more interesting with all the textures.
Now we've got something we can look at and I can see the we can still see some facets around here because
we've not applied a subsurface division modifier to it to smooth it out for shading.
Now we can go in and tweak these settings to see little of all those almost like rivers running through
a valley.
We could use a colour ramp know to make things even more interesting here.
Now I'm going to go diving into details there.
I really like that looks like some sort of rocky marble Let's turn the scale down tweak it a little
more.
Okay.
There's lots and lots of fun you can have just tweaking settings left right centre.
Just see what you can come up with.
And of course I have not got time to play with it all.
All.
I like that.
Another time to play with it all day long.
But I'll leave you guys to do that.
Please share your work in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.