Hello everybody and welcome to this lecture where we are going to hide all of the other pieces that
are on the board so we can focus just on the board itself.
OK so let's just have a look at our scene here.
Now we can go ahead and hide things by just pressing the H key.
Now you'll notice when you hide something its effects on the scene disappear.
So if I've hidden our porn there I can no longer see its reflection.
If I zoom out slightly select my lamp and press H.
It will hide the effect of that lamp on the scene.
I'm going to undo that but not just by going control and Z to undo.
I'm going to go alternate H.
That's brought back everything that we've hidden in the past.
Now to go through all these places and press H would be annoying.
We're not gonna do that.
What we are going to do is hide things with a bit more intelligence.
First of all I'm not happy that my lights are called light and I'm not happy with how they are not linked
to the camera in any way.
So I want to change my view back to view layers over on the outline.
And let's have a look.
Where are my lights at the moment my lights are actually parts of the black pieces.
That's very bad.
So let's go ahead and select them so we've got this lamp here and the other one is while the other ones
right in the way of that camera piece but there we go.
Selected them both and the press the M key and move them in with the board camera and lights.
And I'm also going to name them appropriately as well.
So this one over here is the blue light.
We can see the outline.
It's highlighted orange so I can come in and I'm going to go lamp blue.
And the reason why I've named it lamp blue and this one over here will be lamp yellow or lamp orange
whatever you want to call it is because then lamp gets put together.
Same word at the beginning.
Okay.
So now what we can do is we can intelligently hide things using the outline.
So we have all of these eyes.
We can literally click and drag to hide and UN hide objects.
Hi guys.
UPDATE This lecture as some of the methods have been changed.
Coming up if you cast your eyes to the outline and hover over the chessboard you can see that the options
the old and control are no longer available.
You hold up a whole variety of the collection.
You can see sorry control and shift are available.
So if you hold control and click it isolate everything else apart from that board camera and light collection
old however will do the opposite and isolate that from everything else.
This no longer works for anything underneath.
So if you want to hide anything in the viewport what you have to do is click the whole shift page to
isolate that and remove everything else and you bring that all back by old and hake as well control
and Haiti will allow you to isolate entire collections so if you press control and age you can isolate
which collections you would like.
You can isolate the port and the camera
being careful with that because old and hate will not bring that back.
You have to go back over here on the outline and turn those collections back on additionally.
You can also hold the shift key and over and the outline collect the eye of any parent and it will turn
off any of the children as well and shift collect to bring them all back again.
With that in mind I hope this helps you through the lecture and back to my case we can use control to
isolate things.
If I just wanted the board being shown I could hold down control and then click the eye and it will
isolate that one object.
It was so low it's now if I hover over we can see we've got a couple of different options here.
So control isolate visibility old to disable for all view ports that can be useful if you're working
across multiple viewpoints.
If you want to undo that control clicking the chessboard again doesn't bring things back.
So let's go alternate an unhealed everything again.
Now we're going to be focusing on our board itself.
So what we need to do is hide the black pieces and hide the white pieces.
And because we're on The View layer all we need to do is hide the black pieces and then select the white
pieces and hide those as well because we're hiding the collections.
Everything else just disappears as part of that collection.
That's one of the beautiful things of organizing things in these collections.
And then finally I don't want the camera interrupting our seeing so I'm just gonna hide the camera itself.
The camera still works by the way and we can still render something out.
Now you will notice that even though we've hidden things they appear when we render them.
If you didn't want that to happen there's another option that we have to look at.
So let's go ahead and get a press escapes come out of that.
And if we have a look here there are these camera icons as well.
If I hide the camera icons they go from this White camera to a camera of a cross in it.
Then when we go ahead and render There we go the objects no longer appear at render time either.
Okay.
That's everything hidden and out of the way.
I hope you've enjoyed this quick tip on hiding objects out of your way.
It's gonna be incredibly useful whenever you've got a complex scene that perhaps a part is blocking
another or indeed if you've got something complicated in your scene.
If you've got a high poly object in your scene and you're not working on it at the moment it's not crucial
to what you're doing then you might as well hide out of the way and get the performance benefits as
well.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you all in the next one.