Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture we're going to have a look at textures and explain
pretty much what a texture is.
Now in this particular case we've got some tiles in front of us and you may recognize some of the types
of texture I'm about to show you.
So this is just a series of tiles and it's a tiling pattern.
So it means that if we repeat it lots it should be seamless.
We shouldn't necessarily see where things join together.
However you'll see later on in this section if you abuse that you still see repeating patterns our brains
are very good at noticing that.
And this one here.
Well this is a normal map and you're probably familiar with this.
They've been around for absolutely ages.
We'll go into more detail of all of these maps as we progressed through this section.
This one here I believe this is a roughness map.
So it shows where things are rough and where they are smooth.
We'll have a look at a little bit more detail in this picture.
And a lot more detail later on.
So our textures just images.
Well no they're not just images.
They are a map of bits.
In fact you may recall the name bitmap which is essentially it's a map of bits.
Now the most simplest one would be a single pixel.
So just one individual pixel would be a tiny image but it could represent a 1 or a 0.
That's the lowest bit depth you could possibly have.
But you can have more bit depth and the more bit depth you have the more of a graduation you can have
between black and white.
So then you end up with gray scale.
Now typically a lot of the images would deal with the images your basic camera will take are typically
8 bit images.
Now while lots of modern smart phones and some modern cameras can take a higher bit rate than that and
that means they've got more data in them.
The more data means the more you control using the images.
Now a word on this eight bit thing here.
Most people's monitors are typically these days eight bits.
So that's absolutely brilliant news if you've got a relatively modern monitor it's going to be 8 bits.
Now if you've got a really fancy monitor it may even be HDR or Dolby Vision compatible.
And that means you're going to be able to see a lot more colors.
If you've ever seen some graduation where it looks like it should be a very smooth gradient but it's
not and you end up with lines going across as it slowly transitions between light and dark.
That's the bit depth essentially if it's not got enough bit depth.
It will look like it's in stages rather than a smooth transition.
You will not be able to see a 10 bit image properly on an eight bit screen.
That's unfortunate.
If you have one a very modern TV that's got HDR or Dolby Vision that will be able to show you 10 or
12 bit depth images absolutely phenomenal being able to see them.
I don't have access to that unfortunately I'd love to but it is absolutely amazing the type of dynamic
range and if you ever download an image that's for your world so you can place your models in a realistic
lighting setting.
Those are often high bit depth images.
Now they can have multiple channels.
So if we take a one channel image then that's often that is just grayscale.
It will be from zero to one.
So black being nothing white being one and therefore everything.
And in this case it would be gray scale depending on the bit that would depend on how smooth that gray
scale is.
Now three channels now that's often going to be color.
So your normal maps will fall into that your diffuse maps or your albedo maps whatever you want to call
them red green and blue channels.
Now occasionally and we'll come across this in the fluffy bunny section when we use textures with transparency.
Well the fourth channel can be used to add transparency to color so it can be quite confusing because
you may see that an image is 24 bits but what it actually means is it's three channels of eight bits
and a 32 bit image might be you're catching on here.
It may be red green blue and Alpha.
It doesn't mean that the bit depth is 32 bit.
It means that in this case it's got four channels of eight bits.
So you can get some very very large images extra bit depth equals extra storage space required.
Now I've mentioned these standard ways of using it but technically you could use the channels how you
likes you could store different information on each one and being able to control different things blenders
got an incredibly detailed notes system will allow you to strip the channels into individual grayscale
images essentially and be able to control different things with them which is incredibly useful to do
now the final thing here is resolution.
Now you.
You okay.
So resolution here is the final thing.
You've probably all heard of resolution your screen in front of you will have a resolution it be so
many pixels across by so many pixels down on the X and Y.
A typical 10 ATP screen is 1920 so 1920 pixels across by 1080 down.
Now that's the quantity of those bits.
Obviously they can have various bit depths as well and they're arranged in that grid which is absolutely
fine.
Sides are typically a power of two.
I'm not going to dwell in detail in this lecture about the power of two.
It doesn't have to be a square image it can be a rectangular image but simply you will see things like
256 by 256 or 512 by 512 or 1024 by 2024 etc..
Now you will notice that's also in line if you know anything about computers with things like memory
and everything else.
And there's a good reason for that.
Basically graphics cards work far better if they have a power of 2.
It also allows in your games etc. for something called MIP mapping which is not something we're going
to cover in this course but it's probably something you've seen when playing around in a game engine
so they can be just images.
I'd like to circle back around so well is it just images.
But it can also be procedural.
So blender has a great wealth of procedural ability.
So basically you can create anything you like providing you link certain nodes together and it does
get increasingly complex.
Now we're not going to dive into a lot of detail with procedural textures will touch upon them in this
course.
And I think we've used some actually over on the chess set when we were making the board.
But if you do want to know more of course we've got our environments course which does do a huge deep
dive into procedural texturing and how it can be used on your model.
So if you're really into that do check out the other course now map types where's map types come from
a heap say well mapping is what we do when we apply a texture to the surface of the model.
So these are often also referred to when when an image is used as a texture is often called a map.
Now there are different names for that base colour diffuse or albedo.
That is the colour of the objects.
Now depending on the game engine you're using it may call it different things height.
Well that's simply a grayscale image with black being the lowest points and white being the highest
points.
We'll dive into these map types in a lot more detail as we start using them as well.
So this is just an overview of what's going on.
We've got our normal map which shows us the direction that's a red green blue.
It's purposely in colour but it will have three channels to it being vector values.
Now metal on and spectacular these aren't names that can just be interchanged they are often not 100
percent but they are often inverse of one another metal.
This is how metallic surfaces.
It's a physical property and therefore is often used in the PBR workflow and then we've got spectacular
how shiny surfaces and the colour at which the lights will be reflected off.
That's not physically accurate however is another way of working with your textures roughness now roughness
is basically is something smooth or is it rough the smoother it is the shinier it's going to be the
more reflective it will be.
And again this is part of the PBR workflow because as you get to a tight angle on something that's shiny
it reflects more and more.
And if you crank the roughness all the way down to zero you essentially get yourself a mirror up and
then we have our ambient occlusion so basically areas that are in shadow not having a shadow cast upon
them but if Light was being shown on the surface from every direction.
What areas would be naturally occluded crevices cracks in pavements etc. as you'll see in a moment will
often be exaggerated or have ambient occlusion so make them look more realistic.
Displacement is quite an advance the map type you can have individual displacement which is essentially
the heights map or you can have what's called vector displacement vector displacement we are not going
to be covering in this course it can get quite complex it's very exciting but we're not going to delve
into the details of it however we will use height based displacement as we move through final one here
I wanted to touch on it's not really a texture that you'd see but it's a texture that controls where
things are and where they aren't.
It's called a mask and on the on the basics you could have a white and black mask showing you a brick
texture on one and a paint texture on another and you can make it look like the paint is starting to
wear off and showing the brick underneath but just having a black and white one wouldn't do you probably
want a gray scale so you could fade the paint in announced try and make it look a little bit more realistic.
Now each one of these by themselves doesn't add to a very convincing image.
However when you combine them magic really does happen it's amazing when you get your diffuse texture
and you start putting it in with the normal and height and the roughness automatically your texture
looks so much more raw life it's amazing the difference these textures make and they say if you work
modelling that detail that's half the point behind them.
Now let's have a look at a couple examples before we move on.
So in front of us here this is the base colour map.
These are all of the same objects and then we have a figure this is the tiled or bricked surface.
Then we've got our normal map.
Now I thought this was the height map originally it's not this is the height map down here with the
dark hair is being low down and that obviously be in the crevices there and the gray areas being higher
up.
Notice there's not a big difference between the darker areas and lighter areas when it comes to the
height map.
That's kind of important.
If you make it too big you can end up with quite an exaggerated height map and it just looks wrong if
that's the case.
This one here is our roughness map and then we have this.
Oh this is ambient occlusion in the crevices are black basically and the everything else is white and
you can see that's quite a large area of contrast in comparison to some of the other ones here.
Let's have a look at a final one it's kind of a leather armor.
In this particular case this is our base.
This one here is our normal map it's got a lot more detail in it.
This is the height map so it's in a slightly different order this time around but we've got three at
the bottom here.
Well one of them is the ambient occlusion that's our first one here.
Then we have our roughness pretty uniform but you can see how the edges here have ended up being quite
all white quite light indicating that the edges of something are rough but the rest of it's quite smooth
pretty awesome.
And this one here is technically a mask.
In many ways because it is black and white like we were talking about we can see that these areas as
a white are probably these metal studs works in the leather armor itself.
Now what is happening here.
Well these are the metal.
It's saying that these ones here are metal and anywhere that's black is not metal.
So effectively it's not only a mask but it's also a metal map or a metal honest map.
Now these textures that I've shown you here are ones that I have gone to textures dot.com and downloaded.
I've got no affiliation with textures.
Dot com is just a great place you get 15 free credits every day that you can download and you can just
use and download textures experiment with.
I'll make sure there's a link in this lecture.
So you could go off and check that out if you've not seen it before.
But there are plenty other places you can get textures from and you can even make your own if you want.
Right.
So that's a overview there of textures themselves.
And we'll start playing with them and seeing how they affect in the next lecture.