Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we are going to focus on Poe's mode where we can grab our bones that we've created and
move them in turn.
The model will move as well which is really cool.
And obviously we've got a few issues with it passing through itself but we'll cover those later on.
Let's go find out more about postmarked Okay so we left off here earlier and we've got everything parents
ID all do we.
So let's just have a quick look at everything.
I'm going to make the outline a little bit smaller for the moment so we can see our properties window
a little bit better once we're in there.
I'm going to select my armature.
That's important.
And then up the top here we can switch from object mode not to edit mode like we were doing before when
we were at adding more bones and changing it around I'm gonna go to post mode and we can grab this top
one here or the bottom one noticed there highlighted below.
If you've got more than one selected take note of the different colors just like with objects around
with selecting them the lightest color is the active selected.
So if we select this one here and rotate it we see our model moves around as Reid expects it to brilliant.
We grab this one at the top here.
Something went wrong with the parenting.
So I'm gonna make sure this is the bone select it we can come back out into object mode select our objects
select our bones again go control them P parents it to the bone go to pose mode and now does it move
it does indeed causes the mirror modifier to play a bit funky which perhaps means the are empty is not
parents it's the right place and making sure that selected again and then to go out into object mode
I'm going to select the empty select the armature and parent sets that will clear the previous parents
if there was one there and then when we go to post mode when we move things around because the mirror
is following the bone we don't have any funky distortion happening with it there we go.
So now we've got an appropriate hierarchy of parenting and we've set up the pose mode isn't this exciting
we're starting to actually get our model moving and becoming alive.
Now the great thing about post mode is it does allow you to move your model around position position
it in funny angles and of course this doesn't really work at the moment because we've got geometry going
inside one another and we need to sort out some sorts of constraints to stop that from happening but
the other thing that this is allowing us to do is put things into funky places.
Now the downside of that is how do you return everything to normal.
Well I've mentioned this in the past but it's a great time at the moment to start playing around with
posing.
But if you want to reset things there's one very easy way of doing it.
Now at the moment all we've done is rotated things so what we can do is highlight our entire armature
whilst impose mode and go alternate.
Ah that will undo any rotations that we've done if we've done some scaling which you can also do in
pose mode.
We can use Alton s and if you've moved your model around and want to reset it you've guessed it.
Alton.
And it will go back to where it was before so that's a great way of resetting what you've been working
on to its standard form.
Now you can of course change what's known as your rest position so let's have a look at that.
Let's go over to our armature and we'll see at the very top here we've got Poe's position and rest position.
So if we move our armature here just rotate it down.
If we click rest position it will go back to how it was before we did anything else.
And that's really really useful.
However if you've not realized that you've got a rest position turned on and you try and do anything
you just get errors popping up which is useful cannot change pose whilst rest position is enabled stress
position.
It does vary from model to model.
I'm going to have my rest position look roughly like this but with the rest of the lamp how we've drawn
it so far however in a character you might have them in a T or in a pose a t pose is simply where they
stood upright with their arms stretched out so they looked like a giant T and then a is very similar
just that arms are down about 45 degrees so your wrist position is really important and we can go back
to our post position and we go just by selecting and moving.
Now you may be wondering well perhaps my model isn't in its rest position at the moment.
How do I get it there.
Well what we can do much like applying transforms is we can apply positions.
So if we go ahead and let's say rotate this by a no no I'm gonna do 45 so I can put it back again.
If that was going to be my rest position of the lower arm what I could then do is either go up to pose
and go to apply control and I apply the pose as the rest pose we go control a bring up the same menu
or if you like searching we can search for pose.
And here we go.
Apply poses rest pose.
Now when we do that whenever we go back to our rest pose.
There we go it's there.
And we can move our model any which way we want like so and we can always go back to the rest pose whenever
we need to.
However that's not what we wanted.
So in order to get ourselves back again we can apply it to the other way as well.
So what we can do and just to check posed positions or awkward rest positions over here we can go ahead
go control a apply visual transform to the pose and then we go back to the pose position.
What's happened there.
Well we didn't have anything highlighted so let's try that again control and a apply visual transform
to pose.
Then when we go back to pose position we're back where we were before finally because I want to alter
this all around again I'm gonna get rotates by 45.
Wrong way some will go minus on that and press enter and then finally go control an A and apply the
pose as the rest position.
Okay so that's it for this lecture we've covered pose mode switching into it's making sure that we have
got things that we think repair and set correctly parents it there we go that's all sorted now.
And we've also gone through Po's position and rest position you're going to find that very useful as
we move forward as it's going to become very useful when we start adding in our animation.
So that's it for this lecture and I'll see you all in the next one.