Welcome to making objects separately.
In this video we're going to get back into modelling and the main reason for that is we cannot fully
texture our model until the modelling stage itself is complete.
And of course at the moment my model doesn't have an ear and it needs a bit of detailing on it as well.
And of course with texturing we need to use young wrap our model and every time we move the mesh the
UAE map will get less and less accurate and start to cause artefacts so we want to get that modelling
done or as done as there were as close as it can be so we can then get on to texturing and adding those
materials to our model.
Now we're going to take a look at the ear in the section with all the folds in it it can be quite a
challenge.
Essentially there are two main loops for the year the inner and outer loop.
And we'll show you those in a few seconds.
We're going to make it separately.
In this case in order to focus on the actual model of the ear itself.
So isolation can be both a good and a bad thing.
There is some natural isolation if you were making a model where let's say a car you'd have several
components that would be separate from one another with them.
With the model of the head of course ideally you don't want separate nose separate mouth separate eyes
ears.
Eyes Yes because we have made them separately.
So that's about the only thing if you were making teeth I suppose you'd go for that as well.
But the ear itself is actually attached to a head.
So in some ways you would think oh well can I just make it from the head mesh.
Well in this case what I would like to do is actually focus on the ear without worrying about the head
itself.
Now obviously that has good and bad implications but we can move backwards and forwards all the time
or just turn the head on and off and see what's going on.
But it does mean that you're not going to spoil your head mesh accidentally in the process of making
the year especially if you start using something like sculped.
So you don't accidentally grab part of a head and have to keep undoing some making it separately at
this point is a good thing.
And then we can reattach it to the head after it.
So let's now go explore those two main loops and hop on over into a blender.
Okay so in front of us here we have one I made earlier.
And you can see that the ear itself looks pretty good once we've got.
Let's turn our lights.
Let me guess.
The lights are on a different light.
There we go.
So we've got a nice ear going on here now.
It will depend on what your ear looks like that you're modelling on in may look different to this.
Some is have more folds or more creases or more defined shape.
Some people have bigger ear lobes etcetera.
Of course I've modelled mine on the head.
I've got in front of me.
And it follows nicely the curvature of the ear I've got in fact the low down here is perhaps a bit bigger
than is in the reference material but I am absolutely fine with that and of course we've spread the
ear out itself.
So let's go back to the mesh.
There you go.
Looks nice.
We've actually got a sort of plane to mount it on.
Now one of the things that will have to contend with in a bit.
And this comes with all modelling when you do something separately is joining it back together.
So we will have a series of seas around the edge.
So taking this one for example when I selected it there are 20 vertices.
That means there needs to be 20.
On the one we're linking it to and I can almost guarantee there won't be that on the head model so we'll
have to when we get to this stage actually move the detail down as it comes towards this edge here.
So we don't have such a problem merging it together.
Okay.
So without further adieu let's go ahead and start modelling this and I'm going to go ahead and open
up my head file.
Okay.
That looks a bit odd.
There looks like blenders being a tiny bit funny.
Well the eye is in fact there.
It just happens to be a work of blender.
Never mind so let's was round to the side and go to layer.
So okay now I'm going to be modelling now Polly to Polly this year itself and this is just one way of
making it.
There are loads of different ways of making it.
We could literally go in and sculpt it's fresh.
We could go in and and make it from the head itself.
But this way itself is the easiest way I found of making something that's a bit more complicated like
an ear but actually getting it's sort of to the shape I wanted straight away.
Now I'm going to add this in a very straightforward manner I'm going to add a single vertex and then
extrude that Vertex and that gives us an edge to work with and when we extrude an edge we get a face
to work with.
Now this is one of these times where if you want to copy me exactly Ira that's absolutely fine.
So I want AITs of these pieces going out.
So one two three four five.
Six.
Seven.
It's okay.
So that's the outer loop made.
In fact I'm just going to move some of these bits about.
Eric go.
And this is obviously going to be quite low poly.
Now let's get the inner loop itself.
I'm going to start from this place here and come down.
Now what we'll want to do on a scale that in Eleusis like what we'll want to do as we come around here
is make sure that edges start lining up properly so that when we.
Get to this point here we can merge vertices here and this one here so this one does need to come down
a little more.
Okay.
So this itself will become a quad shortly one two three four.
This one will become a quad and they'll be a quad in the middle here as well.
So I'm going to go down to this point here and move it around.
Now this is quite manual issue probably as you're watching me there.
Now I don't want to actually merge any verses just yet just in case I want to move things about so I'm
going to turn my snapping tool off and I've got automatically merged vertices turned on at the moment.
I'm going to turn off the safety.
I know that sounds an odd thing to say but I don't want a problem where when it comes to sorting this
out.
OK.
So we're almost there because this final one it's selfless just move this here and scale it up a little
is all the way to the top here it's going to require a big rotator.
Now be careful about going around inside yourself.
You don't want the model looking like that.
You want it like that.
Okay.
So I'm happy with this rough outline here I'm going to go to virtex and snap mode turned on and merge
virtex Automatically.
So I'm going to move this one and plonk it on there and this one to here and this one to here.
This one to here.
This one to here and this one here.
Okay.
There's one final one here and here.
So we should end up with a quad that we have to fill in here one two three four fill 1 two one two three
four fill 1 2 3 0.
Three for Phil.
Okay.
So we should end up with a shape looking roughly like this.
Now at the moment I'm not too concerned about it not matching exactly the reference material.
This is of course an opportunity that you can go in and start tweaking it slightly so it resembles it
just a little bit close or more closely but I'm happy with the overall layout of that win.
We need more detail anyway in there and we can sort that out in a bit.
This particular one here I am going to scale in ever so slightly.
Okay.
So this face in the middle here is going to be the hole in the ear so I might as well sort that out
now.
And I'm just going to literally push that all extrude it actually move it here scale in ever so slightly
and move it to the front.
So there's that.
That is a bit deep actually as it goes.
I mean orthographic projection that that's happened.
So I've got no idea a perspective of course.
So that would do for the input there.
So around the outside here if we imagine the ear itself at this edge here is going to have some thickness
to it so we can go round the edge itself all the way to the bottom and extrude.
Now under that change the transformer orientation back to global.
So I can actually extrude in the x axis in this case I've also noticed that my model seems to have its
Normal's all skew whiff probably just the way I started the modelling.
I'm literally just going to flip those Normal's.
Normal's flip Normal's.
And there we go.
We've now got things on the outside and the inside.
Perfect.
Okay.
So now we've got this here.
We can go around the edge itself.
The complete edge not just there okay.
There we go.
And then we can extrude again.
Now this is going to require a bit more manipulation.
So I'm just going to pull it out now.
Yeah that far because we can faff about with it in a moment.
And I'm going to move all of these just the part ever so slightly and also move snap is snapping off
again.
And we want these to line up some glasslike the entire edge loop running around there.
And scale x x 0 with this set and normal so let's just try that scale.
I think it's going to be x x 0.
Yeah there we go.
So now everything is co plainer.
Excellent.
So I'm going to move this back now.
About there.
Oh no.
That is far too far.
We get and scale that in.
So that's kind of the back side of the ear itself.
And then we need to do another extrude because we need somewhere to mount it to the head itself.
And then we can scale that outwards.
And move our model around.
So I don't want that selects I want this select Let's grab this and move it back and get a term proportional
editing on or not insert editing on so I can move the entire thing just back.
There we go.
It's just not in the way and then it's a matter of manipulating these here and getting them.
Getting that flat surface for the it.
Now at the moment you can see we've got some intersecting faces here that is a matter of moving vertices
around until you get them in the right place.
Now this can be a bit challenging to get it right and a bit infuriating but if you go around your model
lots and make small changes rather than big ones you'll soon see what's going on.
Now this at this point here these this is obviously too wide that it is standing out massively.
So we've also got to move the edge that's somewhere along here and just push out ever so slightly.
And again bring bring your mateer your reference material back again so you can move things in a more
realistic manner.
And this has a lot of tweaking to do.
And of course that leads us on to a challenge.
Okay.
I'd like you to finish modelling the ear itself.
So go ahead.
Finish off the ear.
Remember to add detail now.
Ears are not flat.
You can go a bit crazy with it as well.
So obviously some features when they're exaggerated only a little.
Don't go over the top but if they're exaggerated they can help convey a better sense of depth.
They're now at the moment the ear we've got is far too wide so there are have to be manipulated flip
forward and back between the head model itself and the ear and remember that you will have to add a
subdivision surface modifier at some point.
So the ear would actually shrink from where it is now.
I wouldn't recommend in my experience just adding a subdivision surface modifier and applying it to
get yourself Self more and more vertices to work with.
I would actually just subdivide the mesh if you need more vertices to work with.
The reason for that is if it shrinks immediately you've got a problem from way he was starting from
source just subdivide with out actually using subdivisions SERPs monifah or just use simple as the option
on the subdivision surface modifier.
That would also work as well.
And just a reminder you have the sculped tool as well.
This can help if a struggling moving vertiz about just dragging them.
You can use the sculped tool to help provide a bit more adjustment in air in a more artistic manner
rather than precise moving that Vertex about.
Okay so finally before we crack on with that just a reminder that this modelling itself when I've done
the modelling of an era in the past it's typically taken around half an hour or so to get roughly right
and maybe another half an hour of tweaking as well.
So don't expect this to suddenly miraculously look like a wonderful ear.
You're going to have to tweak and modify it.
And of course when I show you that challenge results as far as I'm concerned it's not going to be real
time.
I'll skip through the various points that I find important when I'm modelling the support of video now
and give that a go.
Okay guys welcome back.
Let's go finish modelling our ear.
Okay so before I get cracking with any further detail I am going to see what it looks like on our head.
Now I'm not expecting it to be smack bang on the head just at the moment.
It faxes e in in the head itself.
So it's going to be roughly here and I might as well get it orientated correctly as well surman irritate
it's about there and push it back into the model.
So there we go we've got a bigger front profile there we have so we can see here.
One it sticks out further than the other that you may or may not want to do that with your particular
model.
But it is important to have a look at reference material because some people's ears stick out more than
others.
So even though it's not it's too high at this point in the model on the backend it really needs to be
pulled out.
But first of all let's add some more geometry to here.
That's go to delay it too by itself.
It is important to hop backwards and forwards and check this often.
Now before I do anything else here I need to sort out this mess down at the bottom here.
It shouldn't take too long to do but I will see you guys back in a few moments.
Okay so that is looking pretty good now.
They were just a bit on top of one another.
Or rather one was pulled one way too far and not the other so you ended up with a lot of non plane geometry.
But that doesn't matter too much.
But it was intersecting which does matter.
So I'm happy with that overall shape for my ear.
The next thing to do is to go ahead and select everything because we're subdividing everything.
I'm going to use the specials menu to get with the w.k. and all where subdivide right the top there
and only one level some just going to open up the tall shelf I'm sure as only one level Xome sense.
Now we should find we've got a couple of loops.
Let's make sure our loops are still intact as well.
So we've got a loop running around here.
Of course it'll go all the way around our model.
In this case and there should be another one right next to it and then we've got an inner ear loop as
well.
Okay perfect.
So we've got a very flat ear at the moment.
This is no good.
It's self.
So at this point now I've got the extra geometry I'm going to go in and subdivide or add a subdivision
surface modifier.
Now this extra geometry helps cage our model and stops it collapsing too much in on itself so that should
still be roughly the right size which is.
And of course now's the time to go in and grab the edges like this.
Edge here let's do all the way round here.
Of course an ear is not flat so that's where you just move that in.
I'm going to move it Imber selects normal here and just push it in essence so we start to have a shape
of our ear.
Now in this case I'm going to also push a couple of these upwards.
We sure help pinch the ear itself.
Now I've got proportional editing turned on I don't actually want too much of it turned on here so I'm
going to grab this law here and pull it over the top to make a lip.
And of course this is going to be more and more tweaking to try and get the right shapes involve the
mosque and turn smooth shading on as well as our is a lovely so we can already see this is starting
to take shape wonderfully.
So going to go around here and manipulate some more vertices and get it sorted.
Okay so I'm just putting together the final bits of my model here and just going back to the reference
material and looking at the contours So we've got a contour that flows round here and back again.
So it's a good idea to try and make your mesh reflect that's by just tweaking it ever so slightly and
pulling some bits closer and some bits further away so sometimes I can move a face as a whole.
Sometimes I push virtex up just to add that little bit of a crease in to our model.
So I'm quite happy with how my ears turned out.
How is yours turned out.
Did it take you a couple of times to get your ear right.
It certainly does.
When you first start and that's what it's currently looking like on the model.
So of course I'm not too happy with how it looks in terms of here's I'm going to modify it a bit more
I think but I'm happy with that as a starting point now because we've got a fairly detailed year on
our model.
Please share your ears in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.