Congratulations everybody and well done for completing Section 2.
You're now able to make some really basic models and I suggest you put those skills to the test and
do a couple of other models as well whether it's from your favourite film, a book from your imagination
or just something you've got in front of your desk.
It's entirely up to you but I do suggest you just practice the skills a little more before you move
on with the course.
And once you've done that we'll be learning some additional modelling techniques in the next section
and before long we start texturing and animating too.
So there's lots of exciting things coming up.
So please share your work that you've done so far over on the discussions and really looking forward
to seeing what you've made.
And if you're revisiting this after being a bit more skilled up and you're going through the course
with 2.8 then please do share what you've created as well to really inspire the students that are just
beginning their journey.
I'd love to see what you've created with a bit more skill and a bit more time put into your craft.
Looking forward to the next section where I'll see you there where we all hop on over into blender.
Take care.
See you there.