Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture we are going to map our texture repeatedly.
So ends up being not so blurry and a bit more concise on the surface of our model looking much much
better.
Let's go find out more.
OK.
So we'll start off with are default cube here and we'll go ahead and add a texture to it but this
time I'm going to open up the shading tab as I do so now we've got our cube in front of us here were automatically
placed in Look Dev mode.
And I'd also like to draw your attention to the area at the bottom because that's what we're going to
be focused on as we start adding things to our material.
So first of all let's go to our materials tab and start setting up the material as we would do normally.
Now I've inadvertently hidden my sidebar along here and we can reopen that at the top here and I will
also unfortunately not have a blank area for my screen cast key so I'm going to add that back in now.
Okay so now that that's done notice here we have material and material that we named this wood notice
that the material name updates over here as well.
And as we scroll down notice that it says use nodes these things in front of us.
These two boxes are both nodes the material outputs is what our material looks like the principal
BSDF is the shader.
So this is where we can change the color of things so we can go to here and change it to a yellow and
notice it changes over here as well.
So there are plenty of places that you can actually change things.
And as you get more comfortable in Blender you'll probably be playing around in the node editor more
so than over here.
Now we've already gone into the base color click that little circle gone to an image texture.
And here we go is added another node in for us.
That's pretty awesome.
And then we went down here and under the vector added in if we scroll down here generated for instance
and there we go we've got four nodes altogether generating our material.
If I go ahead and click open on image texture on this node and then go to the wood folder and then
just select any one of these we end up with the image on our model looking pretty good.
That's exactly what I'd expect to see.
Now when it comes to mapping a image to a model or a texture to a model this is the basic set up that
you would have you may decide to use a different type of texture coordinates UV's we'll cover later
on.
And of course different textures themselves and there's lots of things that you can do with image textures
in order to control your model.
You can move these nodes about and you can also add new ones in and in order to change the scaling of
our image on here as you can see here is quite a large image on our cube.
What we can do is we can add in another type of node called a mapping node.
Now we could do that over here as well in the materials editor but to be quite honest it's a real pain and
faff to try and do that we'd have to remove our texture coordinate first and add things in a very specific
order.
And when it comes to creating a material for our models it's really not a great idea to have such a
rigid structure when creating a material is often better to just flow with it and change things as you
go.
So let's go to the ad menu.
Go down to vector.
And here we have mapping that's the node that we want to add.
We can also find it under the search menu if we type in mapping.
I often use the search menu because I know what things called I'm going to press enter to select that.
And before you click anywhere what you can do is you can start moving it's around and what you will
notice is that as you move that your mouse cursor over these connecting lines that join the nodes together
you can go ahead and add a new node in and it will map it in place and it will even move nodes across, How
Cool
is that!
So now we have five nodes making up our material.
Now if we want to if we want to change the type of mapping from generated to object we can simply just
click and drag.
And it will replace the previous line.
Now you may find occasionally blender crashes when you do that's and if that does happen reopened blender
try and recover last session.
Well it's called a cube there.
Has it got the material applied.
No it does not have material applied.
It doesn't remember it at all.
So that didn't work.
What we can do instead is go to file recover autosave and then find what we were on before.
So we're looking for something around the right time.
That's right.
Auto save here.
There we go.
That's where we were before or at least almost where we were before.
So let's go ahead spread these out again and add in a mapping node.
Now the great thing about the mapping node is it enables us to change the scale of our texture.
Now we've got vertical lines going down here because it's being projected from above.
And of course there's nothing to project from above is infinitely pixilated.
This is just the color of the pixels on the edge of that image.
Okay.
So first of all let's have a look at scale.
Now scale works counterintuitively if you want the texture itself to be smaller on your model.
So using more of the image or repeating it more often you have to increase the scale.
Now what I can do here is individually go through and say type in five five and five.
Now you'll notice that last one doesn't do anything.
And that's because an image is just two dimensional X and Y are often the only ones you need to modify.
However because we've got these vertical lines coming down here we're going to have to switch from flats
to box projection.
Now we get something different going on first of all.
It doesn't look that great we've tiled it too many times.
So I'm going to now highlight and drag down slightly and you can see that we can adjust things that
way as well.
Now if you don't quite manage to highlight them all.
It can be a bit awkward and it can be awkward try and get them all highlighted.
But what you can do is high hold down shift and change these very slowly between one another.
The other thing you can do of course is rotate things around this can end up making your model look
a little less uniform but you do have to watch out because you can end up with some horrible distortion
if you're not careful.
And if you like your keyboard shortcuts you can click the top one here type let's say zero.
Then just press tab to go to the next field.
So that can be another way of going for 4 4 4.
And there we go those are all set.
Now you will find that the higher you set the scale it does start to become silly at certain points
with any texture even if it was a repeating or tiled texture you'll still be able to see the repeating
pattern at some point.
Right.
That's gone a bit too far let's set it back down to around three.
That seems to be about right for this particular model with this particular texture.
Now the location can be very useful if something isn't lining up quite how you want it to.
You can move up and down the Y will move it from the left to the right in this case.
So we need to align it perfectly with one bit of the image that's how you do that.
And then finally the Z because we now box mapping the Z does come in.
So for some reason that match just a bit better on one way than the other.
Then of course do that.
Now I'm going to save my work in this case just mapping because I'm going to change something.
I'm going to go to object instead of generates it and just see if I get a better mapping of my texture.
So it's gonna be smaller in this case I can probably increase the scale here two maybe so that I'll do
for the moment you can see it's repeated around four times across the top here.
And what you can see is at some points it goes from the dark side the light side around here.
So is a bit of discontinuity in our texture.
And the same I think around the bottom as well yes.
So we've got it all dark side dark side come round light.
And this is where taking more control over the mapping of your textures using something like u v coordinates
can help massively but we don't want to get too far ahead of ourselves and we won't be covering that
in this section so we play with the location and scale the rotation and you can tweak it to your heart's
content.
I generally only rotate it ever so slightly and I find that that if we go too far basically as you approach
90 degrees or a hundred and eighty will be fine and then to seventy will start stretching its out as
well.
So it's pretty cool being able to angle it slightly that may give you a better look especially on your
board itself making sure it's not completely uniform.
Great idea.
And now it's time to make your board look a little bit better in your challenge OK so your challenge
is to experiment with the mapping node.
Remember there is no right or wrong here.
So just go wild and see what you come up with.
Adjust the scaling of the texture.
See if you can get it to fit our board a little bit better.
Try different rotations having everything lined up perfectly.
Often makes for a dull model.
And then try using the object and generated texture coordinates and see which one you like the best.
Or even just which one suits the board the best, Pause the video now and give that a go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now hop into blender play with the mapping node and change how our texture is being mapped
to our board.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and just going to save what we've been working on here and open recent my chess scene.
So we've got our board here.
You'll notice that it's always defaults back to this solid view.
There's a good reason for that.
If you opened it up in rendered view and it was really really heavy to render I required a lot of system
resources.
Well you wanted to open up in rendered view and be nonresponsive for a bit whilst it works out what
it needed to do.
Right.
So I've got the reflection working really well here but this texture is blatantly too big at the scale.
So we need to reduce that down.
I'm going to hop straight into my shading tab and I can't really see my board it is selected i'm going to press
the delete key on the number pad and zoom in and I'm gonna have to create myself a little permanent
shading setup here so let's go ahead do that now.
Okay.
With that's all sorted.
Let's go ahead and add in our mapping nodes.
I'm going to add search mapping its loose there, going to hover over the top of the appropriate link between
our nodes and there we go we've plopped that in now I might play with the rotation and move it around
ever so slightly to be fair I think I'm only going to adjust the scale.
So let's start with maybe three.
Mm hmm.
Yeah I think that's about right.
Boom done.
Now let's play a little bit more.
Let's rotate this round.
I think we're going to have to do all three , I don't think i'm going to get away with just rotating X although
the Z looking down and making a slightly diagonal that's looking promising actually.
I don't think we can just rotate everything by 35 I believe that will just look silly.
But you never know it might keep everything in line.
Something really weird happens here on this transition.
Those are the sorts of things you'd need to really watch out for.
Is these sharp changes in the actual image itself as it goes around that's really going to break the
illusion.
When these are all set to zero.
That's not an issue.
They're going to rotate it on the z axis probably to about 45 degrees actually.
Let's make it exactly diagonal across as if it was cut the other way.
I like that a lot.
Let's just check for distortion there's gonna be distortion at some point but does it matter.
It looks very very lovely from the bottom a view we're not going to see that much.
I really like how it's looking let's save our work before we go into rendered mode switch to rendered
mode.
And yes that looks gorgeous.
The blue light on this side obviously doesn't make it look quite as warm as the yellow lights on this
side.
So I think this is going to be a good angle to take our render from.
So I'm gonna go to the camera view and a press shift and the grave key and whizz round all that really
is whizzing round very very sensitive cases about here go back slightly to get more of the board in
shots and go up as well but not too far because the lower you down the more reflection you're going
to get on your model K that's looking pretty good from there.
We'll go back into layout mode for a moment so we can see more of our screen Yeah that's looking pretty
good I'm not quite liking these black pieces at the moment and this is when you're scene starts to
come together do you like how things are looking they're not dark enough as far as I'm concerned I'm
gonna make them nearly black and I'm going to make them a little less shiny oh they're reflection it's
all the way down I don't want the matte either do you want a slight sheen on them so I'm going to set
that that's about 40 percent okay yeah that's looking much better something to go ahead.
Press F12.
There we go.
Forgot to turn them on in rendered view as well.
Easy mistake to make and we've got some bits in our scene that we don't want either.
So let's find the bishop itself and turn off any of the notches when it comes to rendering and what's
very useful is at the top here instead of just searching for them manually I can just turn off the notches
let's go and render it again.
Excellent.
Well I might do.
Not yet but perhaps when it comes to finalizing the board itself the bishops themselves are uniform
at the moment they're both facing exactly the same way.
Now I really want a bit of rotation in them.
Maybe a bit of randomness as well just to make the board look less computerized less rigid and more
realistic because let's face it even if we set up the board perfectly now everything is going to be
aligned in dead center.
Okay but there we go.
That's my render.
I can now save that image and boom.
There we go.
Please share your results in the discussions.
I look forward to seeing how your boards are coming along and I'll see you all in the next lecture.