Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture we're going to look at texture projection and how and
all the different ways that you could map a texture to a model in blender.
So there are lots of ways many many options of how to map a texture to a model.
And they're incredible and super useful especially when prototyping because we can slap a texture on
a model without having to worry about UVA unwrapping it and everything else.
And that can be a real great thing to do if you're rapidly prototyping and trying out different textures
on different models to see how they affect one another.
However ultimately if you're exporting to a game you will need to use UVA mapping.
So even though we can do everything that we need within blender and if you're staying in Blender that's
great.
However if we're exporting to any other program the other program needs to know exactly how we're going
to map or how it is going to map a texture to its model and any way of doing that is with the UVA mapping.
Now you can use the others.
That's one of the things that we'll have a look at later on because once you've got a texture on your
model you can then bake that texture from what you can see on the screen over to an image so you can
have the option of using any of the other texturing methods and then bake the result down to a u v map.
And that's incredibly powerful and quite liberating to be quite honest.
Now you're using map and what that means.
We'll discuss that in the upcoming lecture.
But I'd like to show you now using the cube example where we were playing about with the node wrangler.
I'd like to show you how the different projection methods can actually affect your your overall texture
and the appearance of your model.
And for that of course you'll need to hop on over into blender.
Okay.
So over in Blender.
We've got quite a complex node set up here.
I'm gonna delete that material and just start a new material with a basic texture on it.
So we're not worried about anything else.
Now you could see there how quick that was to actually get that up and running.
And again if I go to the dropdown next to new because I haven't shot blender down it hasn't lost any
of these bits of information so I can come in and I can go and grab the albino.
That's what I want.
And there we go.
It gets applied to the model so there are a couple of areas that we want to look at here that all this
side so that to do with these three here we briefly touched the fact that you can move your texture
around we can change the scale etc. But we can play with the texture coordinate that gives us some interesting
results but also over on the texture itself.
This node here with the orange top we've got a couple works as flats here.
We've got a couple of projection types and I'll show you more about that in a moment if we might need
a another object in our scene.
So if the mouse up in the 3D viewport look a shift they add something a little bit more interesting
it will come you ve unwrapped for us they all do.
So I'm just going to move that over to one side with it selected.
I'm gonna go to the materials drop down in the shade of view and I should be able to attach material
0 0 1.
And there we go.
So that looks a mess on here looks awesome on the cube which is you know pretty understandable.
Even though that's you v unwrapped I think we might be able to do better and with another objects in
our scene I am going to add another object let's just add a cylinder cylinder would be quite good.
Let's go g and shift that out and assign it the same material then we can see how different materials
get affected in different ways.
And all of these have you v maps on them.
That's why it's able to map to it really well.
And look we're using a u v coordinate a texture corner in order to place the texture onto our model.
Now we have this mapping node here.
I'm gonna go down to the scale and bump that up to 5.
I think that's a nice level of detail that we can play with and see what is actually happening now generated
an object will often give near identical results.
This is a great start.
If you've not yet you've unwrapped your model.
So if we go to generate it and pop it into vector we get a different result coming out and we can see
that we've got lines coming down when anything's vertical looks like hits.
And so the textures all stretch to infinity down the edge and works on the tops and bottoms.
I'll explain that in more detail in a moment.
If we select normal I've almost never used this one.
It's not going to give us a great results u v if it's EUV unwraps.
This will work it is not it won't.
In fact we can force one of these to not be you v maps anymore with the cylinder selected.
Let's do it to the cylinder.
We need to come down not to the object properties but down here to the mesh data properties and then
under U V maps I can delete the U V map it's currently got.
So with u v map highlighted I'm just going to press the delete key and it can't map the texture anymore
on this model it doesn't know how to.
If you select t u v and that's the sort of result you will get if you've not unwrapped your model.
But now we can use generated pop that's on and we get the results we can use objects and we'll get a
different result but very very similar.
We can use the camera camera and window will be nearly identical they have different scales to them
but they will be literally a projection from our viewpoint or rather the camera's viewpoint in this
case directly on our model which results in when we move round the texture not moving you can see the
scaling is just a bit off here so we set this back down maybe 2.5 we can really see that the texture
really just stays in one position is almost as if these are cutouts and windows through to the texture
behind all of this slot and we'll find if we select window and do the same we end up with exactly the
same but this time the texture is scaled a little differently we go.
And in fact is a little bit squashed as well by the looks of it.
Finally reflection is very interesting.
It's as if things are being reflected off the outside world and these have all got they use this in
general though I've not found this one to be particularly useful as as you can see here can result in
quite a mess.
So if you didn't have a u v map object or generated are two to try.
I'm going to plug in generated into our vector component of mapping it where we could remove that altogether
let's remove it altogether to keep everything nice and simple and plug the generated node output sockets
into the vector input socket.
OK so let's look at this projection.
Len go through these options here.
Linear closest.
That's just the interpolation.
So if you've got a particular texture that you're having to zoom in on is going to use a certain type
of filtering in order to kind of make it not as blur as it might otherwise be flat.
Now this is where it starts to get interesting.
What's really happening here is the image or texture is it being projected onto our model from above.
That's what flat means in this particular case.
So if I press seven on the number pad to make the view off the graphic we can see that this is absolutely
right.
If I grab my cylinder and move it we can see we can align it up and it's pretty much perfect in terms
of how its test relates with one one another.
And that's because it's being projected from above.
But the problem is when you're projecting onto something from above as the edges curve away what you
get is the texture stretching.
And eventually when it reaches a certain point the texture.
In fact when it's exactly vertical the texture can only repeat whatever the edge pixel is.
So whatever the individual pixel is right here on the edge.
Notice that it's blurry.
So we won't know the true color but that's being stretched down the entire side.
In fact if we play with these options there we go closest even though it's not as blur is it's a bit
more pixilated.
We know exactly what color the stripes are going down.
So playing with a sometimes will get you a different result and maybe a smoother one.
And to be quite honest I like closest something and leave it on.
It's more true to nature what you see is what you get with that so how can we solve this.
Well instead of flat if we imagine that we had a box and on each side of the box including the top and
the bottom was a projector projecting the image onto our model and that's what box will do.
Now that is incredibly useful.
Look at that straight away we've got ourselves some models.
Now bear in mind that the cylinder is not usually unwrapped at all.
That's a very nice texture being applied.
I would happily just put that in the scene as perhaps one of my pillars for the church in fact what
we could go ahead and just you know cheekily do is scale that up.
But I would do that in edit mode.
I'd grab the top bit here and go GZ maybe five and then we go we've got ourselves some extra geometry
did I extrude that.
No there we go.
I need to tap backwards and forwards and this is a potential problem here we've got the texture but
it's stretched.
So if we brought back our mapping node we'd be able to sort that's out.
So let's go ahead and search for mapping and drag it over the connection and it will join it in for
us and then we can come in with the scale on the z axis.
I don't know point five.
Now bear in mind this is a shared material so it's going to change all of the others as well.
Okay.
So it looks like that's going to be the one.
But look here this is where repeat comes in.
We do want it repeated up and down our model.
And interestingly it's not actually repeating.
I felt that was a bit weird Hello everybody and welcome back.
This is Mike from just the near future just stepping in here.
You know we had this issue here with the texture not mapping properly.
That's actually a result of this touch the top one here.
There's no interpolation.
So for some reason it won't repeat as we've got it here.
It were as you repeat the texture.
So we have to change that from closest linear will bring everything back cubic.
Does that bring everything back or does that play silly.
No cubic works.
And I said probably smart will work as well.
Excellent.
So that's how we go ahead and sort that out and of course that's going to be necessary in order to make
sure that things fit as they do serve.
Now scale.
That's all we've got here.
We've got it on object.
Let's put it on.
Generated these big easy this ones now all stretched out whereas objects isn't stretched out as much.
She's really useful.
If I turn up the scale so type in a smaller number.
Yeah that looks a lot better.
And I'm going to turn off the blender.
Thanks.
I don't think it's needed too much on our on our pillow just here and there we go.
So that's the solution to the model's going black is if you're using closest then it will do this.
Unfortunately there's no way around it.
Okay.
It.
I'll pass you back now to past me.
Okay so that does cause a tiny bit of stretching on the side.
So that's just something to bear in mind and we'll look at how to sort that type of thing out later
on.
If we put objects in instead we get a similar effect.
No we get this projected in a very weird manner.
Oh that's bizarre.
Others have not seen it work like that before.
Let's just change shading modes for a moment.
No it is being projected in a very weird way.
OK.
Wow that's that's an interesting results.
So that wouldn't be the correct way of mapping it in this particular case I'd go back to generated and
I'll deal with the stretching with a mapping node if we need to.
Now the final thing I wanted to look at was the color space.
Now this is something depending on the type of texture you use.
You need to remember to set up otherwise your textures won't work as you'd expect them to.
So currently we're in s RG B which is color basically but we've got loads of other options here.
Now I will remind you when it comes to using them.
But if you're not using something that's color in general you should set it to non color.
Now it will obviously look weird in this case because it's supposed to be color but if you don't show
your normal maps and your height maps won't necessarily work as you'd expect them to because blender
will be interpreting it as a color image if it's set to be color.
Okay.
So before we wrap up I have totally glossed over blend blend is pretty awesome.
It's not going to work too well with this texture.
It works really well with things like moss and rock that don't have rigid edges.
However this will also show how blurry things can get.
So fortunately our texture lines up perfectly with everything on our cube.
However if we increase the blend what it tries to do is blend between two joins.
Now it's going to work best on our Suzanne head.
So if I change the blend there you can see that it's changing how the texture is applied and blending
it with another texture because of the uniform nature of this particular texture.
It's not going to make any real improvements.
However if you have something without direction or lines on it can help blur edges of textures so you
don't get any sharp seams between the two.
I mean I'm not sure of that looks any better with the blend turned up and down.
I think it does just a little there's a harsh edge.
Here's a here's an example of it anyway we've got this harsh edge running around here.
If I increase the blend amounts it does make it a lot more palatable not so contrasting.
So it's harder to see.
So if you're at a distance like this you'd be absolutely fine.
Okay so that goes ahead and covers our texture mapping and projection.
The combination of these two and if you need it the mapping node as well will enable you to make the
most out of your textures remember you just experiment with these and have fun.
It's very easy to get yourself in a pickle if you're not careful so don't be scared of using the Undo
key.
But now is the time to practice whilst we've got some basic models in front of us just slapping the
texture on seeing what all of these levers do.
Just playing with it and having fun occasionally you're not going to get a desirable result sometimes
you'll get something that you didn't even expect or is exactly what you wanted.
So if you're playing around with this now I suggest you go away.
Spend the next 10 or 15 minutes just playing with different ways of linking up the texture coordinates
make sure you link all of these via vector by the way otherwise it won't pass the information through
properly.
But playing with your texture settings playing with your mapping you know what does rotating do does
it add anything useful to your particular model.
I doubt in this case rotation will do anything useful.
However scale is bound to be useful.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you all in the next one.