Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to talk about managing our chess scene assets at the moment.
I feel like things are getting a bit skewed and things are getting a bit messy as well.
I think we're fine within the blend file itself however outside I think it's not looking as good as
it could be.
And let me explain why.
First of all we've got our texture.
Let's have a look at this half figured Rosewood pixel 128 Tiff.
Okay.
You may have a pinky if you've loaded from the resources themselves.
Let's have a look at the file system.
So we're within my file system at the moment into the chess set models.
OK.
Let's go into models and we've got these extra things here.
The arm parts of the models and also where is that texture.
So this is an issue that you'll run into lots especially with a bigger projects.
You download a texture from the Web you apply it to your model and two years later or three days later
you come back to your model and it can no longer be found and you end up with a pink model and you don't
know why.
Or it could just be one really important texture in a scene and that can be incredibly frustrating especially
if you're working between multiple computers as well.
It can just fall apart at that point.
So with our models I'm going to also have textures.
So let's go ahead create a new folder called textures and we need to think about our pieces and scenes.
That's what I'm going to go for here.
Let's zoom back out.
We've got our reference images models and I'm going to also add a folder at this level called render
or perhaps even renders would be better.
So we've got some well that we can put this chest scene that we've rendered out so I'm going to cut
that and put it into renders he probably get what I'm going at here.
Things aren't really organized particularly well at the moment.
In fact at this point we could probably put everything else in a pieces and even get rid of the mapping
and test piece potentially as well because they are just archive bits and bobs up as a name for our
folder isn't it archive.
So these are the folders that I would recommend at the moment.
Of course it would depend on what type of projects you're working on.
I'm going to move my mapping and test PS into the archive.
I'm going to have another folder called pieces and textures is always going to be at this top level
at the moment.
So what I'd like you to do is your small micro challenge for this particular lecture is to go ahead
and organize your folder.
I'd also like you to put your texture that you're using for your board into that textures folder.
Make sure it's named something appropriately and then go back into a blender and reeling kits at that
particular folder that you're working on Paul's video now and give that a go Okay everybody Welcome
back.
So this is pretty straightforward for me to start doing.
I'm going to not open them all up.
Okay so the pawns can end up in the piece is the bishop.
The board is now an archive piece because we're working on the board directly in the chess scene.
And then the chess piece base can go in the pieces as well.
Okay so that's starting to look pretty good.
I'm going to go in to my blender folder now and pull out the appropriate texture.
I'm going to just split the screen here.
I think that's the easiest way of doing that.
Here we go.
So within that folder itself and the piece of wood I've got is this one here.
Figured Rosewood now I could drag the other two across at the same time but we're simply not using them
at the moment.
So that would be a waste to do that.
So let's put it into textures.
I don't want to take it out because this is my other repository so textures that's absolutely fine.
And I'm going to load back up blender going to my chest scene go to figured rosewood and this time.
Go ahead and open and go to the other place that we're working on.
So I know I'm going to get there quickly going through this way model's textures figured Rosewood.
Okay.
And then finally we do need to check it's working don't just assume it is.
And there we go.
Everything's all back up and running.
Got to make sure I save my work and we're done.
Brilliant.
How did you guys get some have you gone for a different folder structure.
Remember at this point there's no right or wrong.
This is one I've come up with at this point in the course.
You may find that later on if you start let's say exporting these models into unity or unreal or Godot
you may want a different hierarchy.
The most important thing is being able to be flexible and being able to adapt to changing requirements.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you all over in the next one.