Hello everybody and welcome.
So in this lecture what we need to do is have something that is infinitesimally thin like our lampshade
currently is something to get rid of my default Cuban add in a plane.
So the plane has no thickness.
It doesn't really exist.
It is literally just a mathematical surface that is infinitesimally small.
Now how do we give this thickness.
And by the way this is another benefits.
If I turn on black face culling and exported this plane into a game engine it would be invisible the
other way round.
That's really annoying.
In fact we can just demonstrate that even further by adding something else just on top of it and going
GZ lift up scale in so we can definitely see through our objects.
But if we select our plane go to the modifiers tab and we're going to generate some geometry.
We're going to solidify now the solidify modifiers going to give us lots of different options.
Let's start with the thickness.
We can make this thicker and thicker.
But not only down but up as well now.
Sometimes you have to watch your normals when this happens but we can see at this point we've given
ourselves and thickness it's a real solid object.
And this is one way of really speeding up your work flow because you don't have to worry about extruded
things if this is the case it can be a very rapid way of working.
We can clamp it in places to make sure that it doesn't extrude too far.
We have vertex groups.
Now we've not covered them properly yet when we get to vertex groups it means that you can thick in
some parts of your model and not others by controlling what vertex groups this modifier affects.
We've got options here to do with the creases and then we've got an offset here offset the thickness
from the center.
So if we have a look at regretfully from the side we can see it's currently minus one minus one what
well it just means that it's at one side of the origin.
If this were 0 it would be in the middle.
So separating out from the origin itself and you can see it's equidistant from the origin every time
it's expands.
And of course offsetting it to one shifts it's the other way.
So it's not really a value of negative 1 to 1.
It's saying Are you one side to the origin or the other or are you straddling it in some sort of fashion.
And that can be incredibly useful depending on what you're trying to make.
Sometimes you will want it to just extrude away from a surface and not either side of a surface.
It's entirely up to you how you use that's flipping the normals where we're not going to need to do
that in this case but if we did want this effect where it looks like we can see through the box we can
certainly do that.
And of course that does recall about face coming to actually be turned on even thickness can be really
useful when we have more complex surfaces than just the plane.
It make sure that it doesn't get very thin around places where the sharp turns.
And as you can see there's a warning here.
Don't just turn it on if it's not needed because it will slow blender down because it has to do some
calculations.
High quality is a similar option very much like the even thickness it will slow down your computer if
you're not careful.
In this particular case with a plane it's highly unlikely you're going to need it and you're probably
not going to need it with the lampshade either either with these unless you're doing something really
really fancy.
Phil room is an interesting one.
It basically means that the rim If it's unchecked you can just see we've created two planes that isn't
really the desired effect that we're looking for today so I'm going to turn Phil room back on.
But it also gives you an option through only the rim which can be useful for boxes because then once
you've got this you can add another solidify modifier on top of it and make this new box thicker look
at that.
So you've generated a whole new mesh just by using a plane.
And that's one of the advantages of this type of modelling where you're progressively developing a simple
shape.
It's not really hands on you're generating your geometry by tweaking sliders rather than physically
putting vertices in specific locations and the both options are incredibly valuable to know about because
this has an amazing workflow we can go ahead and all we need to adjust at the moment is this one vertex
in the corner.
And let's just say we wanted to move it in and make this shape.
Well we've done it.
We didn't have to mess around with inserting extrude thing or doing anything like that.
Now whether your model's made out of mesh data like our plane is here or it's made from curves the solidify
modifier will still work.
And with that knowledge it's time for your challenge and your challenge is to add thickness to your
lampshade.
Now when it comes to this.
Yes you could just apply the solidify modify and be done with it.
But do play with the thickness play with some of the other options do you want it adding thickness to
the outside to the inside.
He's up to you how you set this up.
I wouldn't just leave it is default.
I would explore the various options that you've got because it can change the look of your lampshade
itself quite dramatically.
I found when doing this challenge that if I add my solidify modifier and have it on the outside rather
than the solidifying happening on the inside it tends to make it look not as I would expect it to are
in my head.
I have modeled the outside of it so far so I want it's basically solidifying inwards rather than outwards.
Otherwise it doesn't really look like I intended it to.
And if that ends up looking bigger overall but whatever you end up doing go and add thickness to your
lampshade possibly an hour and give that's a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go and use the solidify modifier to add thickness to our lampshade
Hello everybody and welcome.
So we need to make this lamp at the top or the lamp shade at least a bit more solid.
So let's go to our modifiers.
I'm going to hide away my screw and then add in solidify.
Now already changes the look and feel of the shading coming round and the overall model so before I
do anything else here I am going to add in the subdivision surface and I'm not going to have it at this
point.
Notice lower down.
It's subdivided what we've already done.
If I lift it up we get a much different result.
So where you place this does make a difference.
So I'm going to screw first that I'm going to subdivide I'm going to leave at relatively high.
Now this is going to be a focal point so I want that and then I'm going to solidify and let's have a
look at the options here.
Now I do want to make sure that it looks like it's got some depth to it before.
If we just turn it off you can see quite clearly push the right button.
It's just a thin nonexistent piece of lamp.
How can we turn it on.
It does suddenly start to look more tangible.
Now what we do need to do here is just make sure it looks the part so we can increase the thickness.
And notice it's growing outwards now at a certain point.
That's just going to look too big.
We could also grow its inward so we could do minus all not minus five.
But that looks pretty cool minus nought point five.
So let's just bring that back so we can see here when I'm holding down the shift key.
We can have it grow outside or inside of the already made geometry.
Now the one thing to watch out for if you're putting thicknesses at negative is you may if we go to
solid view and go to the options here blackface culling going to make sure here that we're not pushing
geometries through itself because you can end up with it looking invisible if we're not careful.
And that's no good.
So in this case it's behaving itself even though we've got a negative thickness showing a slight scaling
itself through itself.
In fact this particular view in solid shading is giving me a much better appreciation of how thick we
need to have it that is too thin.
This is too thick.
This is going to be somewhere in between.
I'm starting to settle around the point nought one that it already had maybe a little bit more as a
minus point one we got minus point one or minus nought point one.
There we go.
So that's looking pretty good and if we go into wireframe we can see that we've got lots more information
there now because it's it's added geometry SATs it's thickness to it and solidifies a great way of making
sure that objects that are just thin films actually have some geometry to them really useful with physics
as well.
By the way because then there's more for something to interact with.
Now I don't think there's any other particular settings that I need to adjust here.
So are filling the room.
Obviously we don't want it looking hollow around the edge but it does change the shading.
This is always a good way of quickly checking if you sharpened up this edge here.
What would it look like in fact it doesn't look much more defined like that.
So with the amount of geometry on has it comes around this edge.
It kind of blends around it looks like it's lovely and smooth as it goes round.
However if that wasn't there or we put an edge split modifier it would look much much sharper and I'm
not sure which which version I like.
Probably something in between to be quite honest which our next modifier that we're about to learn about
will certainly help with.
So that's how my lamp is coming along.
Please share your work over in the discussions.
Looking forward to seeing it in fact you can always render it out at this point in time if you wanted
to.
I don't know if I've got enough lights in my scene to do it on mine or if it even the camera's in the
right position.
Doesn't look like it is in fact let's let's render out what we've got so far my camera is not in the
right position so let's make sure it is awesome and let's just render that sounds.
It doesn't really matter what stage your modelling is at at the moment is always good to render things
out and have a quick look now I would argue at this point in time that perhaps my render settings need
a little bit of a tweak my resolution I think is set just a little bit too high.
You can see here that the bulb the original bulb that we had has dropped all the way down here.
But you know what for this particular render that's not too bad and that's all I need that really is
all I need that I don't need any extra information that covers what we need to see so I'm just going
to cancel the render and then it will pause where it is and then we can just have a look.
Yes that's coming along really nice.
They are like for a lot remember to share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in
the next lecture.