Welcome to adding more detail in this video you will go and do some organization to the outline before
things get out of hand if it's like minors at the moment it's not too bad but it's starting to get a
tiny bit unwieldy and we need to make sure we name things appropriately.
We'll get an elodie B level besch object ready to be linked into our main scene.
So let's go hop straight on over in a blender.
So I am going to go ahead now and open up my.
Oh where is it here.
Front door.
That's work on the front door itself.
I'm going to make the U.S. image editor a bit smaller but I'm going to be using that in a few moments.
So let's go ahead here and just have a look at this.
Outliner itself it's a bit of a mess.
So the first thing we can do here is create a couple of empties to organize things.
I know immediately.
I need to be in object mode.
I know immediately I'm going to need an empty and I'm going to use a plain access as I do normally and
I'm going to call 1 elodie a lady a barm also going to here put in there that is the holder because
that's what it's doing is your elda.
Now the reason why I've done that is when we import them into another scene none of these have.
When we link them they all come across as objects.
Little square blocks because their object data it doesn't tell us what type of object they actually
are which can be a little bit confusing.
On first glance.
And if you haven't named them correctly.
Well that's going to be a very sore point as you start moving things about.
So I've duplicated those two air load D and I'm going to make it an elodie B Holder and the other one
is going to be called archive.
Oh I can't spell archive but there we go.
And I am looking around my model itself.
If I enable these things I really do like this smooth arch way.
I'm going to go with my block working set so I'm going to move those two archway profiles.
Bear in mind there curve objects anyway to the archway profile.
Now this archway array is going to hold down control there and make sure I turn off everything under
the archive empty there.
So I want this one that's the one I want to move across so I will move those two.
I'm not going to rename them at the moment but I'm going to move those two into the elodie be holder.
I've got an l o d b front door and that is the actual door itself something to put that there.
The elodie that needs to go into there and the archway itself is that the.
I'm not sure what that one is that's hide everything else would be useful to have the actual doorway
on itself.
The elodie be archway.
Ah yes that's the one we extruded manually.
Im not going to use that one at all but Im not going to delete it at the moment.
Im going to call this L O D.
B Well it's not elodie I don't want to confuse it with the actual l'eau mesh mesh when we solidify it
in a bit.
I'm going to call this extruded arch way.
Might as well say what it is.
Hey.
Okay and I'm going to pop that in the archive.
This was out of way.
Of course if you really don't want those you can just get rid of them just delete them out of your scene
especially if you're using version control.
If you are using birth control then you don't have to worry about doing any of this because you can
always go back to how it was at this point anyway.
Now I am using version the job I just want to show you this particular option later on when I start
trimming out all of the nonsense are probably want to get rid of anything.
I really am not using just to keep things simple so the archway array that we've got here that needs
to be moved to l.a..
DP Okay so now we've got that I'm going to turn off elodie and go to the B.
Service is what we want we want.
This is one solid object so we can just import it as a whole.
The issue is of course at the moment.
This isn't one mesh object.
It is a combination of two mesh objects and a control curve and a series modifiers.
So we're going to have to be careful about how we go ahead and apply these things because some of them
once we've applied them we can't undo them again.
So with that in mind I want to join all of these bits together.
But first of all let's get all the texturing and everything else sorted so the wall itself.
I'm going to switch over to ren mode.
The wall itself is going to have the same material wall door material now is not quite there yet because
we have not unwrapped it to tell it how to put the texture on the wall so the material is already set
up with the texture in it.
We just not defined how the texture is mapped so I'm going to go into it.
I'm going to come out of rended mode go into edit mode select everything hit you and smart use projects
that worked before it should work.
Now I'm going to pivot this around the 3-d cursor it's already selected to select everything and just
scale it up so it's roughly right again at this point in time.
It doesn't really matter if it's not accurate because were bound to make some changes once we start
building up detail the changes themselves are the detail essentially.
So with this in mind let's hop into surrendered mode.
That's absolutely fine if I go ahead in object mode and select the bits going around the outside.
The brick work and going to call it brick work.
I am going to give that a new material.
I call it brick work or no no arch block work or something along those lines.
If I call it brick work that kind of got a different meaning I want to avoid.
I want to avoid confusing myself because it's so easily done.
I can give it whatever colour you want.
I'm going to go a bit outlandish at this point in time I can always change at any point but just to
make sure it's really apparent that the materials have come across individually after we've joined all
this lot together.
So looking at the modifiers tab.
What's going on here is you've got a layer or a layer here of four modifiers in total.
And some of them when we turn on and off dont make any difference whatsoever in terms of the general
layout and in this case I would do want to keep it as low poly as possible so I am going to actually
just turn off the subsurface modify it's not difficult to reapply any points that aren't any special
settings I've just gone for too.
So with that in mind I'm literally going to delete it from here.
The array defines the length of the repeat.
And the curve defines its shape.
That's sorted now if I had if I was doing this with a bit more detail I would probably remake the curve
so it stops halfway and then that mirror that's around and around the other way as well so it comes
on both sides of the door and that way we get a much better lump at the very top.
So it's not well so it's not asymmetric so symmetrical at the top.
So with that in mind we are going to go ahead now and solidify these and make firm into one object.
Now that we've clicked apply we've got to mesh objects left in the scene so that the arch way first
and then the thing rejoining too which is the block work behind.
And I'm really going to hop out of here so I can see what I am selecting Also we've got a dark orange
around everything that's selected and then finally the active object has the light orange and go control
and J that's now join them together into one mesh but it's retained all of those material properties.
And that now if I make sure the naming is appropriate so elodie be front door I dont need one there.
Ldv front door that is what I will need to import when I go to my main scene and with that in mind I've
got a challenge for you guys.
Now this challenge can be as big or as small as you like but I would like you to up your models to l'eau
dbe status so increase the level of detail of your building blocks you are using in your scene.
You don't really have to up the level of detail of a wall segment at this point in time and you certainly
need to be careful around the perimeter.
Otherwise you cause it to look horrible when they're joined together.
We'll go into more detail of how to ensure that works properly later on.
And I'd like you to link them back into your main scene.
Remember.
Replace your elodie a parts with elodie be.
Where appropriate.
So if you don't need the extra level of detail don't worry about adding it's at that point.
As I said off the wall parts I'm not going to do anything to that at the moment.
And of course the floor the walls and the floor at the moment can stay as solid blocks.
We don't need any extra detail at this point in time.
So both video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's go get my doorway into my scene.
Right so let's go ahead and make sure that it is saved before we do anything else and open my Gothic
church scene.
So let's go ahead and as you can see here set it so it renders a bit vertically from the outside from
this camera.
And just to show you guys real quick and then we'll link this other part in I have literally just reverse
the resolutions here.
So instead of being ten feet wide.
Sorry.
920 wide it's 920 high by 10 feet wide and that gives us a wide screen on its side anyway anyway so
let's go in and first of all go and grab that so we need to link the file.
Go to our meshes our front door object.
And here we go.
This is why I was saying naming is really important because if we have lots of things that were similar
in names then you wouldn't be able to pick which one it was and you can see here they've all were the
object data block.
Now of course you can filter in the menu of options at the very top.
Here we can turn turn on.
Is this seen as a curve is it an object.
Is it a mesh.
Well not in this part of it.
Etc..
So we can filter up the top here and we can hold down Shift to term more than one of those on an arm
can move them all turned otherwise you can get very confusing and I'm going to go ahead and link in
the front door.
There it is.
And I'm not sure what layer it's on at the moment has it gone to the right now.
Yes it has.
And of course I need to select that and make it a proxy then I can start doing things with it.
So we've got a couple of options here as to what I want to replace so I've used the archway itself at
the very top of my church but I dont know at the moment whether I want the fancy bit around it.
But I know I certainly want this one down here.
So this obviously has own object data block here.
Now we just go and try and change that.
My initial thought was that would be the one of the best ways around doing it.
I can't type that in there.
I need to first of all select here.
If I now go and type in d e.
And a school B.
There it is the front or proxy.
It doesn't actually do anything.
It literally just changes backwards and forwards all the time.
What we need to do is change the mesh data.
So lets go to the mesh data part of it and select elodie.
Front Door 1.
There we go.
That's in there.
Now the one thing that we've got so be careful with here is when we've got multiple objects in our scene.
So we've got another one of these doors over here and I can't select everything else.
Now I've selected this one and changed it over.
So what I could do before actually applying them.
Let's do it with the walls for instance so those silly with the walls we selected the walls and then
we can use our linking options as we've done in the past when we've been creating these and moving them
about.
So I can go shift in how to select all of the ones that share the same object data and then it's highlighted
all of the wall 40 force.
Now I can go in and go and change that by clicking making the act the selected active one misword down
at the bottom.
Because that's already in the scene can also change one of these to the door and then go control and
L. And then we can make a link and if we do object data we end up with big doors all over the place
or Windows of course if they're high up.
I can then set it back again if I wanted to but since I'm just toying around here I'm just going to
undo.
Of course now I can go in and move the other parts in as well.
And I will see you guys back in a few moments.
Well are those Zen.
So I'm midway through constructing my window piece at the moment and few things as you can see the outliner
is nice and neat at the moment.
One of the things I've realised is that I want to use the material that I created in the last project
of the actual door the blockwork I think I called it BLOCK What door block wrote archway blockwork.
I think what it is anyway I can go in and go file link.
And as we are more ready I've already gone to it.
But I need to go to my front door blend file into the material this time not the object but we want
to go and grab the material and there is Arch and blockwork.
Once I've linked that I can make sure I've got the appropriate mesh selected and under the materials
tab here we can see it's linked and apply it to there.
I've also decided to make the texture slightly smaller because I don't think it was making it look a
bit Noddy's actually the blocks are looked far too big.
I think this is a better scale for them.
One thing we have to watch out for with scale is repetition starts to become more and more apparent
the more and more you scale or tile a particular mesh even if it is already a tiling texture it can
become apparent that you've tiled it.
If we're not careful.
But that's absolutely fine and it also the other ones as well.
I'll continue working on this particular model and I'll see you guys again in a few moments.
So now I've brought the window itself into the scene as well everything's coming together nicely and
this is going to give me a basically go ahead or not on whether the textures themselves I need to do
the wall.
So here we go being lean about only to do the wall as well.
But whether the textures themselves if that's the right size.
Now that does look much better.
I'm going to change the wall and see how that looks as well because that takes up a vast majority of
the entire rest of the model.
Okay so we're back in the church hop into random mode and that blog post you can see a bit of repetition
but otherwise that is looking pretty good.
Does it match up with the model underneath.
Yes it does it pretty seamlessly as well.
I'm liking how this is coming on.
I might go ahead and obviously change the colour of this.
It's almost terracotta at the moment and we can see one of those rendering artefacts that I've mentioned
coming through just on this area here.
So I still need to sort out the actual alignment of the building and lots of other things to do with
that.
But I did want to make sure I got all the brickwork and everything right.
First before I start messing around the underlying structure.
How did you guys get on how are your elodie Level be piece coming along.
Please share them in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.