Hello everybody and welcome to this lecture on topology.
We're going to focus mainly on triangles quads and other angles so anything with five six seven eight
sided faces.
And we're also going to have a look at the layouts of particular mesh data we can see here that we
have two spheres and they're both spherical but they've got a different topology they're laid out completely
differently.
So let's go all the way back to our first one here.
Let's have a look.
But the main difference between a triangle has three sides a square or a quad has four sides and then
n gon has more than four sides.
Now that's pretty self-explanatory just by looking at things.
And if you've been playing around with Blender for a while or a lot of 3D software you often hear that
and ngons are bad and triangles are bad and you should try and stick to quads as best you can.
And predominantly That's true but I wouldn't go out of your way to create your model just using chords
if there's a quick way of doing it that doesn't involve that.
In fact there are several subtracting modelling techniques that you can use.
We take parts away from your model and then trying to make everything back to quads again would be a
real pain in the backside and would just not be worth your time unless you wanted to progress your model
further.
So let's have a look and see what happens in the background with these particular objects.
So I'm going to select everything and go control and T.
This will triangulate all of the faces.
This is what's really going on in the background regardless of what you think you're doing all of this
has to be converted to triangles in order to render it.
So this is just exposing roughly what might happen if you render your model or if you export it to a
game engine.
This will be happening so let's have a look at what's happened.
I'm going to switch across to edge select so that the edges are just that little bit bolder than they
were before.
So here we can see that the triangle has been made into a triangle it hasn't changed at all and we have
a look at the rest of the model itself it looks like it's just split the quad straight across and the
same is true of the cube.
You can see here it's been split pretty evenly.
This one here.
Well it's kind of been split a bit random along the top.
We've had no control how that has been splits up.
You may have preferred it to be split up into five triangles along the top and have the pole in the
middle.
Very similar to how you have a pole at the top of this u v sphere.
If we have a look at the U V sphere Well the top parts of it is triangles any way.
And the rest is a series of quads.
But now that everything is being triangulated you can no longer access the rings running around the
U V sphere that used to be able to access and you cannot do any loop cuts.
This is the power of remaining with a quad.
So if we go back to everything being quads should just take a couple of undo steps to get there.
There we go.
We should now find that I'm able across these quads here but not over the top all the way around on
my cube and essentially because this is a three sided cylinder and this is a five sided cylinder it
will act the same both way so if I go control and are we can add in loop cuts on this side.
We cannot go any other way though it would look like you can cut up but that's just because we've added
these new loops and by doing that we can only do on this one face the cube however is a completely different
matter.
I can add in many many loop cuts all the time and continuously.
And the reason for that is because every time I add one it keeps the quads consistent and that means
you can continue cutting up your cube again and again and again.
And that's true of subdivision as well.
You get a smaller version of what was once there and that's the important and critical thing when it
comes to using the subdivision surface modifier.
And if you're animating something you can have it deform in a predictable manner stopping things pinching
together and looking horrible.
I'm expecting this one to behave exactly the same as the one over on the side here.
We should be able to put a vertical cuts just here but nothing will run around the model.
See you quickly end up with being unable to select various parts of your model quickly because you can
no longer loop around them.
I'm not going to cut up our UV sphere or just follow the same pattern as everything else.
And finally the icon square.
Well there's not a hope at all.
Your course you can manually go round and select things.
I mean it does look like there's a nice cut across the middle a nice straight division that you could
do roughly there to cut this sphere in half but these two spheres are a great example of topology.
They're both the same shape they're both spheres.
However if I turned on shaded mode into smooth shaded you'd be hard pressed to tell the difference between
these two.
If they weren't so low poly This is obviously a lower poly sphere than this but you cannot see the underlying
topology at this point.
You certainly can.
When we reveal it.
And that can make a big difference.
So in summary overall it is generally better to make your models have quads in them rather than triangles
and ngons
However that's not a hard and fast rule.
And often there will be times when you just cannot avoid having a triangle in your model or if you could
avoid it it wouldn't be worth the time trying and that's going to be very useful in the upcoming challenge
and your challenge for this lecture is to create your queen.
I'm going to give you a bit more guidance.
I suggest starting from a similar base maybe the bishop is about the right size.
You have to do some changes but it is a relatively good starting point for the Queen.
Of course you could build it up from the ground using the base piece.
Now try and get good topology when it comes to the Crown itself.
I will be using a triangle at the very top but I'm going to make sure it blends nicely to the quad underneath
it.
So it looks like one giant face rather than its changing angle all of a sudden.
So go ahead pause video now and go and create your queen Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and hop on over into blender and create our queen okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead and make our queen so in order to do this I'm going to go and open up something that's
very similar to the Queen the bishop and it's obviously been moved.
That's one thing to bear in mind when you move all your pieces around.
Well guess what you'll have to make sure you reopen them.
You can't shortcut your way through.
Now the first thing I'm going to do is save as and obviously save it as the queen once I've done that.
We can go in and do a couple of other namings.
So I'm going to name the bishop or the mesh object queen and I'm going to delete the notch itself.
It's going to need to be visible in order to delete it.
And then it can go the next thing I need to do.
I'm going to whiz round to the side turn on my staunton  Bishop now that i have got the image turned
on I'm going to go down to the material properties and as we can see here we're using the storm from
Bishop in the background so we can actually go to our shading tab as we've been doing before we've
got a Staunton Bishop PNG.
You can see a group of nodes has been set up here in order to show that image.
So what we can do is go ahead and open up the correct image.
I want to go to my reference material and open up the queen.
And there we go.
And we can see that they're roughly the same size as one another.
Which is why I've picked this.
However they are a slightly different shape.
So I'm going to select my bishop at this point and go to its object properties and in the viewport display
set it's a wire so I can see through it for a moment so I can adjust things once I've done that.
I can have a look from the front how long I need to make sure I can select through my model in order
to do that.
I'm going to click this button at the top here show whole scene transparent and that should enable me
now to hop into edit mode and select the appropriate vertices in order to move them around and we can
just come out quickly to make sure that everything is selected which is and hop back in again.
Now I think in this particular case I'm going to select everything but the very top bit no.
No I'm going to select it a bit further down go G and just lift it up and then select this next bit
here.
G and lift it up again.
So it's in the rough right place here and then it's just a matter of selecting things and moving them
to the appropriate place.
Now this is the great thing about using predefined geometry.
You get to an end point much much quicker than you would have done just making it from scratch.
However you still do have to be careful because you can run into this situation.
We end up taking too long modifying what's already there.
And I think that may be the case with this crown I'm not quite sure at the moment whether it's just
going to be a pain to do or whether I'm just going to have to redo any of it.
So I think it's going to be fine.
But the Crown is a different shape it's going to flare out as it comes to the top of the Crown.
And obviously we've got these triangles running around here as well.
And we do need to think that this is a three dimensional object.
So once we've got the rough proportions we're going to have to put some extra loop cuts in to make sure
that the Crown comes out at the right angle.
Now I'm going to suppose that this bit is actually much lower down than it looks.
And then I can make it much wider as well.
So about there and I don't know if I need all the extra detail I've currently got here.
This bit needs to come out a little and I think this one hand just needs to be further down and then
bring it down a little bit more.
Okay.
Yes I'm liking the look of that.
I'm going to turn back on textured mode and I'm going to have a look at this top bit here and hide the
Staunton Queen I'm also going to name it whilst I'm there.
OK.
Save that and turn off showing everything as transparent.
And look we've got a viewport clipping issue that's a sore that's outs as well so I'm gonna open up
the properties panel here the sidebar and change the clip starts.
So one centimetre I should be able to zoom in much better.
Okay so the final thing I think I need to work on in lots of detail is this crown parts at the top.
And I think I can get away with adding a loop cuts in roughly there and then adding another one in a
bit further back and then manipulating that bit there.
So let's go ahead.
Go G, Z and move that down so that can actually be part of the Crown itself.
Now I don't know.
That looks a bit steep to me.
Let's go round and make a few alterations to it
G,Z and lift that up.
There we go.
That's looking pretty good.
Now comes the point where we need to start thinking about whether or not we're using triangles and whether
or not some of this is a bit redundant.
I'm going to dissolve this edge running round here, Yeah that's much better.
Okay.
So we need to have those spikes coming out of the Crown and I could make them out to quads that would
that wouldn't be an issue at all.
I could literally grab all of these edges.
All of these faces sorry and just extrude them up and out and then scale them in at the end or it could
make them into triangles now and just extrude that middle edge going up has lots and lots of options.
I could subdivide them all and grab the middle vertex and pull it up.
Let's see what that looks like.
There are so many options here.
It's possible that all of them are viable and there's not going to be a wrong one that's so important.
It's so easy to forget there's always going to be multiple ways of doing something.
I'm going to change my pivot point to individual origins.
I'm going to switch our transform orientation to normal and I hope that's going to enable me to go and
H.
No not extrude to move these bits out on their normal was brilliant that's worked perfectly okay.
There we go.
Now looking at this.
This may look a bit odd having these triangular faces here when everything else literally every other
surface of this model is not triangulated.
So let's just make sure that it's not going to look odd.
Let's switch over into lookDev mode and come out and yes it does look at this.
We've got things that are triangular at the top which is fine it's fine it being that shape but it really
does need to be flat rather than the shape it currently is.
So back to the drawing board there.
So I'm going to remove the subdivision that I had made and now we need to look at it in a slightly different
manner.
I think I'm gonna have to put a loop cuts not down the entire model necessarily.
I could do I'll be an awful lot of extra geometry just fill this one little bit at the top.
See there's so many different ways that you could approach this I'm not going to do that.
I'm not going to add all of the extra geometry when it's just not necessary what I am going to do instead
though is I'm going to select all of these faces running round which I can use a face loop select for
and with that face loop selected.
You think you'll be able to do exactly what we did with the vertices a moment ago and just extrude out
based upon the normal by.
It's not going to work it's just going to lift it up.
So the way around that is to select alternate ones.
We could a checker deselect in order to do that and then extrude those up by certain amounts one looks
like it's too far.
So maybe point two point three point four I'm gonna go point five here and then do the same but not
before scaling down to zero and then we can do the same to these other ones to extrude point 5 and scale
down to zero select everything and remove doubles okay.
So what we should find now is when we look at this even though they are triangles we don't have that
split down the middle that we did before.
We can just confirm that by having a look in Look Dev mode with that turned off and excellent.
It looks like one giant piece in this particular case.
Okay that looks really good.
I'm going to just finish up by having a look back at our model and looking at this base bits because
I've just assumed that that is going to work.
And I have missed a couple of bits here so I'm going to go G.G. lift that up slightly and pull it out
because it's a much bigger piece and I'm going to do the same for this area here.
So I'm going to select these and lift them up and scale them out slightly and the same goes true with
this bit here's a scale that out and lift it up as well perhaps even scale it in a little at that point.
Perfect.
That looks like an awesome piece to join our board.
I'm going to hide the reference image.
One final time come out and have a look around.
Excellent.
How did you guys get on.
I'd love to see how you made your Queens especially that bit at the top.
There's numerous ways of creating those spikes around the queen's crown.
Looking at it now I think there might be a bit high but I'm going to leave it for the moment knowing
of course I can adjust it later if I'm no longer happy with it.
Please share your Queens over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.