Okay everybody so let's go ahead and start here.
Go to your browser that you use day in day out and go to w w w dot blender dot org.
Now you'll be able to download 2.8 straight away from 2.8 beta is out.
Very exciting.
I can't wait to get into it.
However there are a few things to work through because when you go ahead and download blender 2.8 you're
presented with this screen.
If you're downloading for another operating system you can switch between them but the installation process
is slightly different.
Now I'm going to require 2.8 windows 64.
Occasionally the blender website might indeed change if that does happen.
Then go to the download tab at the very top and there's an option to try blender 2.8 beta.
If you click on that we get to this screen as well up here.
Now that's going to take a few minutes to download.
And what I tend to do is once it's downloaded I open it up and I extract it to a certain place on my
hard drive.
Now that is different to how you usually install a program.
And since I download these on a daily basis they are released daily.
It is worthwhile checking back here if you're having issues with your particular version and obviously
don't leave it too long otherwise you might miss out on some features.
So now that that's downloaded I'm going to open up the zip file itself and then I'm going to drag the
folder across into My Documents folder where I have a blender 2.8 folder already set up.
Okay.
So that's opened up and I'm literally going to find that blender 2.8 folder. There it is I've already added
it to my quick access bar.
You can do favorites over or onto the side bar on Mac and I'm sure you can do a very similar thing over
on windows.
Now that that's copying across what I tend to do is I go to that blender 2.8 folder find the download
that I've actually got I'm going to go Date Modified to get the latest one here and then I go and find
the blender on in this case executable on a Mac it would just be the program file and I drag that to
my taskbar you can drag it to your dock if you wanted to but just be aware that it probably hasn't finished
extracting yet so you do need to wait for that to finish then once the extraction has finished you can
go ahead and launch blender 2.8 you may get a security warning.
I'm going to run the program and off we go.
I'm going to maximize blender and all being well you'll be presented with something similar to this
if you do not have this screen present you may have already tried blend a 2.8 and it already already
had remembered the options that you had you'd actually selected.
So currently this quick setup is what you see if it's brand new.
And you can even load in your two point seventy nine settings.
Now as this course goes forward am going to be using what the default settings are here and I will change
them later on if I want to.
So one of the big changes is if your experience with Blender you will remember that we selected things
with the right mouse button.
Now that was very confusing for a lot of newcomers.
And so it's been switched over to left and then we have what the space bar does.
Now I'm going to leave as play at the moment.
And later on I might switch it across to search or perhaps something else.
And that's the great thing about blender.
You can swap things about as and when you need them depending on your workflows if you're doing a lot of
animation you probably do want the space bar to be playing.
However when I'm modelling I tend to prefer to be searching.
So we may switch that quite early on in the course.
This next one's interesting.
And it depends on how you work.
I like blender dark.
That's the scene you see at the moment.
If we switch it the blender light is a lot lighter.
And what I tend to find is I end up using blender light more on my laptop when I'm out and about because
the lighter interface is easier to see especially if I'm and light environments.
Perhaps the sun's out at the moment I'm in my office so I don't want to blast my eyes with bright interface.
So I've selected blender dark and I'm going to save new settings.
Now though this is the splash screen you might have experienced if you hadn't gone through what we'd
just done and you'd already install blender.
So this is your splash screen we could start a new file here we can open we can recover last session.
I've got no doubt we'll be using that a couple of times as well.
I'm going to click away from the splash screen we can bring that up again at any point in the top left.
We can go ahead and click that little blender logo there not the top top one but the black and white
one there the monochrome icon and bring up the splash screen.
OK.
So before we go any further I just want to do one final thing whilst we're here and go to edit and preferences.
Now Blender is very very customizable so you can change pretty much everything and anything about it
but the first thing I want to do in here and we're going to have a another look at the blender preferences
towards the end of the section as well.
But the first thing I want to do is go to interface and under the scale we can change how zoomed in
the interface is.
Now personally I find it useful to have about one point two five.
Well when I say personally I don't mean for me.
I mean so you guys can see what I'm doing.
So I've blown up the interface ever so slightly see you if yours is more zoomed out all your perhaps you
can't see as clearly on the screen then do remember you can turn up the scale.
I'm going to remember to save my user preferences so I'm going to save preferences in the lower right.
And that will save preferences for all future blend files that you open.
I'm going to close down the Preferences window. In front of us,
We have our interface our main interface.
And this is the 3D editor window that we're presented with with our lovely default cube.
Unfortunately we're not very kind to this cube.
We're going to end up deleting it several times.
However I do like it being there.
Because sometimes I do use it sometimes I don't.
And towards the end of this section we'll talk about customizing your interface as well.
So the first thing I'm going to do is introduce you to these icons in the top right.
So this is to control the 3D view which you can do a lot of with your keyboard and with the mouse as
well.
These here have been paramount in me be able to use Blender on my laptop beforehand.
Without these here in the older versions of blender I just couldn't use my laptop as efficiently as
I might have been able to do I always had to remember three button
mouse.
I fully recommend having a three buttoned mouse if you've got one.
So using the scroll wheel we can zoom in and out
holding down that middle mouse button we can orbit and notice at the top here that little gizmo in the
top right was spinning around as well and we can hold down shift and we can do some panning around our
scene.
Now it will take you a while if you're new to get the hang of all of these different controls.
We can also change our view by using these buttons at the top.
So this whole orbiting that we were just doing we can click in this circle and move around if you happen
to click one of the letters or other dots that are there you will find that it was around and switch
to what's known as an orthographic perspective.
And if we have a look in the top left of the 3D editor window we see it says top orthographic, So we can
view our object from multiple angles just by clicking on here.
Now you can also use the numpad on your keyboard to do that.
If you have a number pad now the other ones here the plus as you probably guess allows us to zoom in
and out.
The hand allows us to pan around our scene and sometimes you may find that when you do that you lose
your model like we've just done here.
How do we sort that out.
Well we can go to the view menu and frame selected.
If we had anything selected we did we had the cube.
I'm going to use the scroll wheel to just zoom back out again.
And the middle mouse button to orbit around. The next two we're not going to use that much initially.
We're going to use the camera view towards the end.
This is what you will be rendering.
So this is what the camera sees in our scene and we can click that again to come out of camera view.
And this final one is toggle and if we hover over there it's the first time I've hovered long enough.
We see that it says numpad 5.
This is the switch between orthographic and perspective mode.
Now orthographic is very very useful when you're trying to align pieces that are the same size but
where perspective can make it very difficult to do so.
It basically removes all perspective from the scene, So ig a cube
this size is five miles away.
It looks the same size in the viewport regardless of how far away is in reality.
I'm going to switch about perspective mode and I think that about covers it.
And what I'd like you to do just to warm up is make sure you get comfortable with moving around the
scene using your mouse or using these controls up at the top right here to move around this cube.
This is a fundamental skill that you will have to develop and will practice over and over again as we
start modelling in blender.
So we've got blender installed you up and running.
Ready to go.
You've been introduced to the preferences panel and we're take another look at that later on.
I think we're ready to go.
So that's it for this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.