In this lecture we're talking about metal bowl families I'm going to use some eyeballs to illustrate
my point and we're going to play around with a little bit of the naming of the medal so becomes very
clear how mutable families work.
Why do we have medieval families.
Well it allows us to say that these particular medals are within in essence within the same object and
they can influence each other.
So it's a medal O three.
If I move that around you can see that is influencing the other medals around it.
So we're saying yes there is a relationship there.
The structure is that the first medal we've put in is just called bowl and then the other medals in
the family have the same first part of the name.
This is the family name if you will amble and then dot 0 0 1 0 2 that is the identifier for each of
the individual children within there.
Now if we make any changes to one of these metal bowls if we click on medal or medal 0 0 3 for example
we go down into our properties when we change for example the resolution that would change the resolution
for the entirety of our object.
So some of the documentation says you need to click on the parent amble to do that but in reality you
can see that when you click on the individuals it is modifying the resolution or the influence threshold
for all of the objects in the family.
Some of the properties you can't get away from that once you're in the family you're in the family it
sounds like a good gangster movie doesn't it.
If I was to click on materials create myself a new material we'll call it let's say I just call it green
maybe green OK and then we'll change green to be actually be green jump up into my material preview
and you can see everything here is green.
If I say hang on a minute.
But I want this one here to be a different sort of green.
I'm currently selected on that let's make it a different sort of green.
I can not because it's all part of the family like saying once you're in the family you're in the family.
So if you wanted to create your metal ball object and to have some different properties between them
or if you wanted to say you know I want to add something for example and I that doesn't influence the
rest of my object then I need to create a new metal bowl family to do that.
I'm going to just shift a metal bowl click on the bowl.
You can see by default it is going to call it made a bowl or two.
Now if I want it to not be part of the family I just need a change.
The first part of this so I will call this for example I metal bowl.
There we go.
I'm in a bowl and let's see if we can find it's right at the very top.
Now as I move this around it's a different color it hasn't got the same material hasn't got the green
material and you can see it's not influencing it it's not causing things to change around so I'm going
to just very quickly make myself and I plop plop plop plop scale it down move it across drop it into
place and you can see that's just sitting on top of my object some other things I wanna show you just
briefly if I was to go and change the name of any bowl that is the parent of my might be green caterpillar
here too for example cat pillar if I do that everything disappears it goes crazy it's yelling at me.
The one original metal bowl that was the very first one we dropped into our scene is staying there it's
happy it knows what's going on but everything else says I no longer have a parent I've become orphaned
if I go to m bowl 0 one and change that to cat to pillow.
I'm spelling that correctly dot Oh wow I'm sure someone will let me know if I'm not one then it says
Oh okay that's my parent right there I know who I am I know what's going on now I'm not gonna go through
and do all that rename me I'm just going to undo that and of course if I go and create a second I met
a ball by duplicating that okay you can see that I've got I met a ball Oh one.
Okay now these two medals obviously will cause an influence upon one another if I click on say I am
miserable oh one moved over there you can see there's a relationship so those two will obviously affect
each other but they're not affecting the caterpillar the original metabolic and if you want some more
specifics on this then jump to the blender document that I've linked to you against this lecture that
gives you just a little bit more information about how medical families work and at this point I have
a challenge for you add or modify your creation by using a second metal bowl family as I have done just
now here's different materials and it's one of those different colors for you different metabolic families
just so you can see what belongs to what so it doesn't need to be complex it can just be eyeballs as
I've done but it be cool if you add something else just to play around with that second object the medical
family so take on that challenge and I'll see you back here when you're done.
So to conclude my process I'm just going to click on.
I met a ball.
I will give me new material this material I'm going to call eyeball and I'll make it yellow.
There we go.
Little bit of a cute yellowy metabolic Caterpillar guide going on there.
And like I said before I could put a lot more love into these eyeballs I could dig out a hole in there
by using a meadow bowl in the original M bowl family.
But for now and I'll leave it as is I think I've made my point about how all this works.
The final point I'll make is just be careful with your naming and your renaming sometimes things go
a little bit crazy.
So for example if I was to take one of my original metal balls from the caterpillar and say you know
what let's find let's use this kind of antenna.
Oh actually I want that to be part of a different family.
I could go into this and change from any bowl I could change it to and 10 eyes eyes but I'm just gonna
go and because I'm not sure I'm spelling it right and remove the 0 0 1 8 because this is now going to
be the parent of the family.
Click on that.
It now loses its properties but scroll all the way up there.
Not a problem.
It's separate.
There's no relationship between this kind of circular bit and the stem that is coming from it which
is good.
That might be exactly what I want to do but sometimes you might have some issues doing this particularly
if you accidentally name this and dot whatever it was before 0 2 2.
It's going to disappear because it's saying okay you literally just changed me from M ball dot 0 2 2
I think was our T2 into and or 0 to 2 but I don't have an ant as the parent for me so make sure there's
always a parent.
If you've got any of the dots you could solve that a couple of ways you just put this back to Ed or
we could click on one of the other ones and I could say this one here.
Where are we.
Is M. bowl 0 17.
I'm going to make this tree and drink.
And now those two know that there is a relationship between the two of them because this one is now
called and the other one's called Aunt dot.
Oh two.
And they're happy because they're now part of a family again they were kicked out of one family but
they found each other they maybe they're husband and wife.
The blobs on top of the antenna are gonna undo that.
So I leave them as green in the original family they will go.
Just wanted to illustrate that last point.
Make sure you're careful with your naming.
So as always I'd love to see what you've come up with.
From this lecture and I will see you in the next lecture.