Welcome to planning your project.
In this video you will plan your project defining its scope and your goals.
It is important to make sure we prevent scopes lepp.
We're going to gather your reference material now if possible.
Explore real world locations to get a feeling of the environment.
Scour the web for your reference images as well.
Now will be focussing on building blocks and modular thinking now going to be thinking about the ways
that you make parts reusable and modular so they connect together easily.
So you don't have to make bespoke parts every single time.
If you think about Lego that great kids and adults toy there's a lot of modularity with it you can make
pretty much anything.
Your imagination has parts it does have some restrictions too obviously is quite blocky.
Fortunately with Blender we're not we don't have quite that restriction.
Now realize that this gives you very quickly serrations cause you can put things together and take them
apart because they're made of modules and it's great for prototyping from only a few parts so you can
build up a building very quickly with a couple of squished cubes.
Now if you're a supplier of assets to a level maker or even if you've got multiple hats on yourself
you're going to love the way that they can redesign a level with your assets.
If you give them one building completely constructed they're going to struggle modifying it.
However if you give them all the pieces to construct any room then they'll be able to make any other
room from those assembly.
The same when you're modelling inside blender itself it means that once you've made let's say a wall
section you can use that repeatedly rather than making different shapes and sized walls.
So I've got a challenge for you to kick off this section Unlike to you to plan your building or room
that you're going to be working with.
So go ahead and gather lots of reference material.
Go ahead take photos look around you if you're in a in a building with lots of different things I'm
looking around me right now and I can see an interior environment that's got a sink water jugs a couple
of plants cupboards there's lots of things that you can include and remember of course things like walls
and windows and doors.
They're very important of course I don't want to go over the top at this point in time because we're
not focussed on micro detail so focus on the main items at the moment the big things that support everything
else the walls the ceiling the floor doorways even to chair and table level as well so we can start
fleshing out a room as well.
Then I'd like you to go ahead and list at least 10 models.
You want to include in your interior design.
Now remember that I'm going to be focussed on this gothic church style building.
However you can just model the one you're sat in right now now be a good challenge and remember you
need at least 10 individual models that you're going to be making lists them not done.
Don't go ahead make them just yet.
We've got some other things to cover first that you want to include inside this building sketch your
design and share your goal in the discussions Bozzo video now and give that a go.
Okay guys welcome back.
How did you get on.
What did you decide to go ahead and model what type of Interior are you going for.
This is my rough sketch of where I'm going.
I've got the stained glass windows perhaps at the end.
I've got a rough shape of a building with some pillars chandelier's perhaps candles hanging down there
lots of different options that I can go for here.
But this is a rough sketch to get into my head.
The rough plan of course this is subject to change as we go through as it is a beginning point.
It gives me an idea and a direction to travel in.
Okay so finally the list of components and items that I'm going to be why I think so far putting into
my goffey Church so I've got a blank wall or the window wall of doorway a bench an altar an altar twice
apparently but a large windows.
Floor tiles archways candle sans carpet etc..
Just to bring this place to life.
Now what have you guys got.
I'd love to hear your suggestions as to what you're going to including your scene.
In fact Are you going to go along with me and make a gothic church.
Or are you going to make another indoor environments.
Please share that in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.