Welcome to you v. manipulation in this video.
You realized sometimes the Smarts a unique project is 99 percent of the way there but something is not
quite right.
It could be that a face is being projected the wrong way around.
It could be that it's just unwrapped in slightly the wrong order.
Now we move on to more manual control with scenes later on.
But if it's almost there you might be able to work with what you've already got in front of you without
having to worry about anything else.
So we'll be using the U V image editor to change individual parts on your mapping.
So let's hop straight on over into blender.
So I'm going to be working on my corner piece at the moment.
My Gothic church it's selfless just have a quick look at it.
My new Gothic church after accidently destroying the old one is coming along nicely.
And when we hop into rended mode we can see here that's the corner pieces.
Sometimes they look okay because they're a different colour.
That's absolutely fine.
They look okay.
But around these this window down here for instance of us zooming down there it just looks horrible.
In that instance so what we need to do is give these a texture.
But there are slightly more complicated shape than we've dealt with in the past.
So let's go ahead and go back and open up that corner.
I'm going to open up the U.S. image editor so I can see what we're working with.
And I'm just going to hop into edit mode and do a smart u v project.
And there we go.
We've got r u v map there.
Now what we don't have is immaterial yet.
And instead of repeatedly creating the material over and over and over again what we can do is go ahead
and link.
We can't do that whilst we're in the edit mode.
So let's go and link and then go up to my meshes and then to the wall was the ball the first piece we
put it on it was yes and then material and grab the wall material and then the materials properties
we just need to assign it we can see it's linked bill currently has no users.
So let's go and click on that.
And there we go we've got the texture on our model and it's looking pretty big at the moment.
Now I've already counted my brick work and I know that there are going to need to be 12 bricks but it
can be very difficult with the u v map to work out where the bricks are extra so I load the image in
here.
Hop into edit mode.
Now I've got what looks like some of these pieces look like they may be upside down.
So looking at I'm just speculating here but we've got this edge loop around the bottom that shows us
the business under the ground and parts of it are up and parts of it down.
So let's hop into face select and just.
Yeah.
So that one's up that one's down.
And what will happen is if we start moving the U V.
So if we go over to the V Ed and selects all of the points there we start moving things up and down.
You will see that one side gets up and one side goes down.
And if we whiz round the other side does it do the same.
I'm guessing not because of the layout here.
So once again move up and down.
So that seems to be working in a reasonable manner.
I'm guessing this edge does the opposite.
Yes it does because I can see it's opposite.
It's upside down over here.
So there's a very quick way we can fix those problems and that's by selecting the face that you want
and just rotating it by a hundred and eighty degrees.
But not in the 3D editor.
And he did move over to the other window first so let's go over it over here and rotate it by 180.
I'm going to do the same here.
There is select that face go over the u v image editor and then rotate by one a.
And I don't know the other face that was moving the wrong way so I think it was this one here.
So let's go in grab a note.
It's was this one here so I grab that and again rotate it.
Now I have just noticed a little red and Mark has appeared.
That is a pin.
You do have to be very careful with pinning it can ruin your day if you do not realize it has happened.
So I'm just going to highlight all of my geometry again and we see here that one of the points there
has gone red.
That means it's pinned.
Now under uv's we can pin and unpin with P and Oulton P And those themselves are very powerful We're
not going to use them at the moment.
So I say we actually want to unpin So make sure that that is selected and then oltz MP and we can unpin
that I'll look at wire that's not actually unpinning I presume that's a pin that we put there that's
another pin in the E.
That's what a pin looks like.
I I'm guessing I've not actually highlighted the right one.
P other riego is cleared at that time.
Don't know what was causing that before.
But sometimes you have to try it out.
So this face here is also upside down so I have selected it over here.
Rotate.
And rotate by 1 80.
In the U V image editor.
And I think I'd probably have to do this bottom one as well although this bottom one doesn't really
matter because we're probably Oh no it does matter because we will see at the top of any of these pieces.
Let's go in select those in the image editor and rotate that one again by one.
Now we should see when we select everything and start to move things up and down we should see that
it all moves at the same point this time.
Now you can see there's a mis alignment and that's to do with the placement of these.
Now we can move any of these about's very easily.
So I'm going to make the 3D view a lot smaller there.
And now I'm going to see if I can align these bits here so I'm going to go in to face select and select
this whole face here and see if I can move it.
I can move in as you can see I can map it to any area.
Well be nice though as if it snapped exactly to the other bits that make up this section of wall.
So I'm going to turn on snapping.
And it's already on virtex Snap and that's almost head off my screen there.
So you've got the magic magnet and the snapping type virtex.
Now when I try to move it it will snap to the appropriate one and it's right next to it's have texture
is going to flow across.
We could have it share exactly the same texture.
It's on the other one but that be a waste of our texture at this point.
And that is pretty good.
I'm happy with that.
But the one thing I'm not happy with is its position.
There's not enough bricks and what we can do here is move the entire object down to this cursor.
So I'm going to highlight everything and move the u v map down.
I peered out snapping on that's causing problems but to move it down so it's in the corner not can.
Not exactly.
Doesn't matter so much.
But just roughly in the corner and then under my set the pivot point to that 2D cursor and scale up
from there.
Now if we watch the euv image editor and the 3D view as was scathing we can see that we're adding more
bricks and the top isn't really changing but we're adding bricks in from the bottom so that is one brick
two bricks three four five six seven eight nine 10.
11.
Twelve.
Okay so that should now match up with the rest of our model.
So let's go and save that and check it.
We've applied this let's look around first.
Yeah that's looking okay.
Let's go to the Gothic church.
Or your interior if you're working on something different and one may switch over to textured mode rather
than material mode sorry.
Aha.
And that is looking much better.
One of the issues that we can see is there's a tiny bit of misalignment here whether or not that's an
issue at this point in time.
I'm not going to call it an issue.
However it is something that we need to pay attention to.
It looks pretty well aligned here.
It actually looks like the wall texture may have a different number of bricks in it which is why it's
getting misaligned in places because the it is perfectly aligned with the archway itself.
And it I think we need old to some of the other ones to a standard this one look doesn't look right
as well.
So we've got a few other ones to modify.
So they all line up and I'm going for 12 blocks in my case and if you're using completely different
texture obviously they will be different numbers as well.
But that's coming together really nicely now.
Ann is not making it look so horrible.
There are a couple of other pieces that I will need to make sure are unwrapped suitably and a texture
applied to them an appropriate texture applied to them and of course with that in mind I have a challenge
for you guys.
I would like you to manipulate your uv's So get your brick work texture aligned across your basic building
blocks the ones that require the brickwork texture on.
Of course now it doesn't have to be perfect to this point but get it close enough.
Remember we're still working at a relatively low level of detail starting to look pretty good even at
this low level of detail.
But we don't want to go over the top with trying to align things absolutely perfectly.
When things are still subject to some change balls a video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's go through manipulating some more uv's.
So I am has she quite happy with not faffing around with these particular textures at the moment in
time.
They're good enough as place holders and I'm only going to be of minor tweaks and as a say I may even
change just texture so I don't wanna faff around with that.
But this at sure large object here and these here might actually be worth texturing now.
These are not separate objects I have built them in.
This scene itself.
So that means I need to do all the unwrapping etcetera.
In this main scene and the reason of course why they are not linked objects is because they're bespoke
to this particular scene.
I'm very unlikely to use these parts anywhere else so let's go ahead and unwrap and use a smart yuryi
projects and then you're into edit mode on that and unwrap the model.
Duly disliked everything.
First try again.
There we go.
So now we've done that.
I'm going to have to have a look at the 3D.
Have a look at the image editor and we were on renderer result.
This is always confusing when that happens.
So I have a couple of roof parts here and these two triangles.
In fact in this case I'm going to open up my cinderblock which is a linked.
Object there and in fact and apply but not to everything I've got.
Be careful here.
I only want the cinderblock texture on these faces that I can see so it's worthwhile actually resetting
the euv Completely and then going ahead here and doing a face select and selecting the faces that I
want so those ones are fine.
The rest is a roof piece.
There are some internal faces that I need so I'm going to grab those as well.
So that's those done and we've got some on the other side.
Or have we.
No we haven't got any on the other side so that's fine.
That's all we need to unwrap for the brickwork texture we need to unwrap the rest of it for anything
else and the other side is very similar.
We don't need to worry about the other side asshole.
And we've also got a right angle triangle at the top there and that we will need to unwrap.
I probably won't do that in this video are do that outside.
It's a very similar process to this one.
So now that we've done that what we can do is apply the material which is the wall material which is
fine now is applied it to everything on our model.
That's okay we can go and change that later but we see here it's applied.
This all skewed.
So what we can do there is go over to our u v map.
What we have an unmatch So let's go and unwrap.
So there we go we've got a much better use we unwrap we just need to move these around so there are
a more appropriate angle.
So ominous us first of all selects in face select.
Oh that's great.
I've whizzed round to the other side of my model.
I'm not editing this.
This is a link to one.
I need to go over here severiano That's my confusion.
Some to select this lot first and in the movie images that literally rotate it round until it's facing
the right way we in which case it's going to be like that.
I can now move that to the lower corner as we usually do and then scale it up around and set the pivot
point for the 3 the sorry the two Dhikr I keep forgetting that.
Now I'm just going to move the corner without snapping turned on so that's roughly over the 3D cursor.
Then I'm just going to scale up.
Now I could literally scale this up until they match.
And in this case I think they do there.
So let's quickly zoom in and have a look.
I've missed it slightly there.
Is that it.
No we need one more layer of bricks.
There we go.
So you can do.
Oh I know I don't think I've got the right number of bricks here at all.
And you know what I think I'm going to get it close.
But not perfect because again we can manipulate that around later as well.
Now I'm just trying to work out why it's gone a bit skew way off.
Nice thing.
I think it's the extra corner a bit down at the bottom the extra.
20 centimetres or so.
Part of the wall there but I'm happy with that.
I just think the make sure that is then adjusted on the inside as well.
So here I said that's it.
And it looks absolutely atrocious and needs to be more like that so that's turned snapping back on.
Turn it off again for moving you up in a place in the top corner because it's easier to work that way.
And then I need to move the 3-d cursor but because it's position on the image isn't critical to working
anything else out.
I can pop it down here instead.
And scale it from there.
And we need the scale it from 3-d cursor of course so let's select the pivot point as the 2d cursor
I will get that right one day and I'm going to scale up from there until they run once again roughly
match.
Which is going to be about that.
Oh no not there at all about there.
You rotate they'll look about the right size there.
So yeah I think the issue there is the extra 20 centimetres or so that's in there.
But looking at it from afar I don't think we can spot the difference at this range.
I certainly can't tell the blockwork isn't consistent there at all.
It's made the roof look quite interesting actually because it's scaled them up.
Now I'm going to go ahead and do my other parts as well and will have a look in a moment at the finished
model.
Okay so I've gone around my model and I have altered a few bits and bobs and is going to go take a saw
immaterial mode so we can just have a quick look after this area here and this is the one the U.S. map
that we're looking at at the moment and I've matched up to the bricks.
I'm just going to leave this pseudo tiling on the air on the roof.
There obviously is different directions there but it gives it a little bit of interest.
I wonder if anybody will spot the difference between the tile house anyway and I've changed the colour
of the door archways that terracotta colour was a bit bright.
Now the rest of the.
Image itself.
The rest of the church is improving slightly.
I've got those bits lined up and I also went through and just sorted out the alignment here best I could
as well because that was quite a bit off and if we were close she would see it and it works reasonably
well from the inside at the moment as well.
How did you guys get on.
Please share your newly textured churches or interior environments in the discussions and I will see
you guys in the next lecture.