Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to learn a few know techniques to add a bit of where to the edges of our
lamp.
As you can see here where it's a sharp edge it looks like it's been rubbed up against and is a bit worn.
Now as a bit uniform but this is the start of experimenting with nodes and adding a bit more finesse
to your model.
Let's go find out more Hello everybody and welcome in this lecture we're going to have this very simple
Warne effect working and in order to test it out we're going to do something slightly more complex than
a cube.
We're going to go and grab Suzanne once she's in the scene.
We can start working now.
I'm just going to split my view here so I can work with my shaders very quickly.
There we go.
The shader editor I'm going to hide that's away.
I'm going to create a new material that will apply to Suzanne and then I'm going to change the material
name to warn.
Now that's I've done that I'm going to move these nodes just over to the right.
So I've got this area on the left that I can play with.
Now before we continue doing anything else there are a couple of things that we need to make sure that
we've got working.
The first thing is the render mode needs to be set cycles.
What I'm about to show doesn't currently work in TV.
It might do soon but it doesn't.
At the moment and then I'm going to change mine to GP you compute.
So doesn't slow down the recording and then finally we're going to add in the nodes that we want to
use.
So we're going to add in the geometry node and place that there.
This is what's going to drive where we're detecting things being sharp vs. them being smooth.
And with that we can color it in.
So we do need to put our view over here of Suzanne into rendered most of the press the Z key because
I can't see the tools at the top and pick rendered now annoyingly the lights of our scene is not in
a great position so I'm going to look at this from above find our lamp and pull it in front of her for
the moment.
And now let's go back round.
Zoom in and because she's the only thing in the scene she's rendering quite quickly so I don't need
any render borders.
Now we've got that sets out.
Let's plug in points in and see what we get.
OK.
It does change the color but not in a meaningful way.
And the reason why we're plugging this straight into the base color is just to see what's going on.
There are a few other ways more advanced ways later on that will look at previewing how things are working
but at the moment this is a great starting point.
The next thing that I want to do is add something between the geometry node and our shader node in order
to manipulate the data that we're getting out of the point in a sockets.
So let's go ahead and add in we've got a couple of choices.
I'm going to search for brightness and contrast.
Here we go.
Let's go ahead and add that in and see what we get as increase the brightness.
We should expect it to go white.
But then you notice the insides of her ears and mouth and parts of her eyes are actually whiter than
others.
So this increase the contrast significantly.
Look at that.
So this some of these areas are getting darker than others.
So let's continue playing our look at that.
So now only the outside edges here the ones that are sharp enough have actually got any highlights to
them.
And that means what we can do is take the output from this brightness in color and use it to control
something else we can say where it's white.
We want this color and where it's black we want another color.
And of course there's some blending it will be a mix in between.
That's a make this just a little bit more realistic especially since we're going to be working with
our lamp which has a higher poly count only to quickly subdivide our Suzanne's head here and you can
do that with her selected.
You can go control on one for one level of subdivision control two for two levels of subdivision etc..
And in this case I think that's enough.
And I'm going to shade smooth now the first thing you'll notice here is that where we were before unfortunately
what we've currently got sets up no longer works.
And this is something that's really really important.
What I've just shown you is not the settings for it to work on every model.
You pretty much have to set this up either per object of a model or on the model as a whole.
If it's roughly proportional in terms of how sharp it is in various places.
So now we need to come back and we just need to tweak these settings a little until we have what we
want.
And I'm going to leave it quite broad like this and this is quite typical where the edges would naturally
be a bit more worn than somewhere that would come in contact with the outside world.
What can we do with that.
Well we can use its control a mixed node but before we do that I'm going to unplug from the base color
and just leave this over here.
We know that setup is roughly working.
I'm going to add in an input node of argy bargy.
We've already done that and I'm going to duplicate that for two colors among the set them as really
bright colors.
So maybe green and pink and now pink is going to represent one color and green is going to represent
another color and then we're going to mix them together.
So in order to do that we're going to have to mix and then we get two types of mixing.
We've got a mix shader and the mix are G.B. and in this case we do want to mix colors together not mixing
shaders together so we can put these in a logical order.
I'm going to bring them down here.
So we've got green on color one pink on color too.
And let's plug that in and we'll get a horrible murky gray and that's simply because of how when we
mix these together using the blend type just mix.
That's a it's the middle point basically of where these two are.
If I was to move this one round slightly would see or turn yellow.
If we move it towards the blue it'll turn cyan.
So there we go.
I'm going to leave it as pink vote because this will really stand out.
Let's set the factor which is what we will be controlling in a moment to zero.
So when it's zero.
So where it was black before we will have green and where it was white.
We should have pink.
Well let's plug in the output from our control into the factor and boom we've got exactly what we predicted.
Now obviously these are quite garish colors.
What you would probably want to do is change.
So say this was a painted bits of wood.
The pink wouldn't be great.
That's changed to a more wooden color.
And then let's not have green have a red or an orange or a yellow.
You know something else that really helps highlight sets.
And now of course this is when you can start tweaking as your is going to be looking different from
how it was previously you've now got the colors applied.
We can come in.
I'm going to hold down shift here.
I think that's important to make sure that you can change these settings very slowly and perhaps have
it just a little less worn.
And that adds to the rest of the model reasonably well it's hot.
Yes he is a don.
Yeah.
I'm liking how that's turned out.
So armed with this knowledge we've got to all G.B. notes the setting the different colors.
And we've got this controlling how the colors are applied to our model.
And this is the start of something that's incredibly powerful and can end up very very complex as you
can see the possibilities here are literally endless but without getting too carried away it's now time
for your challenge okay.
And I straightforward challenge for you add one edges to your lamp.
I'm only going to focus on the lamp shade and lamp base material.
However if you want to look at the other parts of your model as well.
Feel free to do that.
Paul's video now and give that's a go Hello everybody and welcome back.
Let's go ahead now hop on over into blender and create all worn edges Hello everybody and welcome back.
So let's go ahead and add a bit more interest especially to this bass part here looks a bit too clean
and a bit too new.
Let's make it a bit more.
Beats up says come out of here and go into the shading tab.
I'm going to go into this one here and rename it again shading small because I forgot to do that last
time.
Here we go.
Shaving small.
And let's focus on our lamp.
I think it's already selected.
It is.
Bring this area up close down the properties panel and let's have a look at our model.
Go and select one of the areas that we want.
So at the moment we've got an R G.B. node controlling the color and we want a worn Archie B as well
so let's go ahead and duplicate that and say well where it's worn it's going to go through to the base
coat.
So those are two different colors that we want to use.
I'm going to minimize those and get them out of the way make them a bit smaller.
Now what we want to do is mix these two together.
So we're going to need another type of node a mix.
RG B that we've explored R G B.
And here we mix Archie B.
Now I'm going to hold over the top of this one so automatically plugs in the top and then we've got
this bottom one as well.
Now at the moment it's only going to show us the color.
I'm going to go into rendered mode here which is really important and zoom in on our base.
And I'm also gonna go control and B and just focus purely on the base itself.
There we go.
So it's gonna be nice and quick to render we need to control with this factor.
How much of the lower one which is a factor of 100 and how much of the upper one we want coming through
in order to do that.
Yes.
We've already explored it.
We're gonna go to another type of input now called the geometry nodes.
It's going to have a look at the geometry of our model.
When we've done that we want this one at the bottom.
The point in us now because our model isn't normal.
Rather doesn't have a lot of sharp edges to it.
We're going to have to adjust the points in a simple we just plug it in straight to the base color.
At the moment you'll see that we don't really get much variation over the surface so we need to add
a another node in between to make sure that we can control how these edges are displayed and we're going
to use that as a mask.
We're going to say whether it's white or whether it's whiter.
We're gonna have one color where it's black or darker we'll have the other one.
So let's go ahead and add in under the color menu a brightness and contrast.
That's probably the easiest one to play with.
There are several other ones that you could also use the color ramp springs to mind but we'll explore
the color ramp later on.
So now we've got that in place.
We can play with the brightness.
So we see we've made it all white.
And then we can up the contrast and see what happens.
Okay.
So here we've got something coming through we've got areas of black and areas of white.
This is looking good so far but there's too much whites in this.
In this particular scene.
So let's see what happens if we take the contrast the other way.
That's kind of looking better.
Now we've got black around the edges.
By the looks of it.
Yes that looks pretty good.
So this is the important thing.
We're just playing now it doesn't look quite right at the very top pair.
We've got an entire surface that's gonna be what was going to end up essentially being worn.
So let's see if we can just tweak these figures here.
Now I'm using the shift key to control that so we can add a little more on the top here.
So that's looking a bit better.
Well let's see what this looks like when we plug it in to our mix.
No.
That's the important thing so let's plug the color output here into the gray factor.
So this is one of these moments here where we're actually plugging different colors together.
It's going to take the average of all of these.
When we plug it into a single value and then we can come out again.
Well first question is yes.
Here we go.
We've got our nodes the wrong way round.
So what simply we need to do here is click this top one put it into color 2 instead.
Well he says put that in color too.
And they will automatically swap around.
And here we go who starts to get somewhere on the edges.
Let's have a look at the top.
Ashley you know why I don't think tweaking this too much is going to make that much of a difference
if we lower the brightness there which just gets a bit too much Yeah I'm liking that.
There are some other things we can do to control it.
I do want to make sure we get some of the red coming through at the top here.
In fact one of the things we can do is open up this RG being node and actually add slightly redder form
of our gray.
So it looks like it's still got a bit of paint on it rather than just being this white a color that
we had before.
We have that looks much better now that we've got that in place.
I think we can actually increase the amount that we've got on the rest of our model.
Yeah that looks really nice.
Now one of the trickiest things about getting this right I'm almost there as far as I'm concerned with
a model is one of these this edge along here.
If we go into edit mode on that this particular edge loop here is just a bit too shallow to make it's
a tight weathered edge.
So if I scale that out ever so slightly.
Yes it's a bit more exaggerated there.
And now go in.
So we get an edge because it's sharper.
That is more worn.
And if we just scale that back in again you can see that the effect gets lost.
Now I can manipulate that so that we start to get a worn edge which is great.
And then perhaps on this part here make that less of an angle and then have the inside edge here worn
rather than both of them.
That is looking much much better.
Let's come out and have a look.
Yes.
I think that looks a ton better instead of having that really dark area at the top.
So a bit of a geometric change there to make our model look better but I'm happy with that overall now
because we've affected this material you know what it's also affected the lamp itself.
Brilliant.
It really does help highlight that edge that we've got inside our model.
Awesome.
How did you guys get on really looking forward to seeing your worn edged lamps please share your work
over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.