In this lecture, we're adding a different sort of grass to our scene by using images as planes and
transparency to scattering some other sort of grass OSAT by making sure we've got the right.
Add on in edit preferences.
We need to make sure we've got images as planes turned on, which, yes, we do.
Now, what I'm going to do is shift A and then find image, look for images as planes that will add
a new images plane once we find what it is that we're looking for.
Kind of just like life, isn't it?
Find what you're looking for.
I am looking for fluffy grass to see, you know what that looks like.
It's this image down here on the left.
Once again, you can go to texture's dot com and find yourself your own good looking image that you
think could be used as a piece of grass.
I'm going to hit G.
Y to move this down to the side so that we can see it.
I've got to lighten it up in Photoshop just now so it's more yellowy.
Hopefully that turns out okay and is in a little bit of a mistake.
But let's see how it goes.
Now they've got that image sitting there.
I don't need all this real estate.
I'm in the silo.
Move that over a little bit.
I'm going to click on my plane and add a new particle system.
Click plus double click.
This will be our fluffy grass.
Not sure if it's fluffy, but Fluffy is a fine name for it.
Click on hair blink.
We get a whole bunch of particles, change the length down to a more modest point.
Eight.
See how that is as a starting point.
I'm also going to change my emission much lower down to, say, 200.
I don't want as many of these and scroll all the way down to children just to get our numbers figured
out.
First of all, interpolated, I'll change this to five.
And also in the render amount, five might come back to that.
But that's okay for the moment.
We'll do our trick that we did before in terms of getting some randomness in the heights, all at the
randomness.
This is under render timing, random, random, random, two point five.
And I've kind of saved the best till last, actually.
Let's go and make our particle look like our image.
So under render instead of Renderos path will renders object.
And then down a little bit lower, you can see instance object.
Click on the selector eyedropper.
Find your image that you've just brought in fluffy grass.
Click on that and then hey presto, not much happens.
Gosnold pretty tiny.
So under rindo we see scale just increase scale until it gets the point where they're starting to look
like this sort of size.
We want them to be that starting to look like it, I think.
But you can see they're all underneath the ground, which is not what we want.
And that is because of the origin point.
So up top right options, click on options.
You'll see origins, select origins.
We need to select back on our original object.
This is where we can see our origin.
If I click on G and then Z, I can change the origin point to be down at the bottom of my object.
That will have everything sitting on the ground as it should.
Back on options, turn off origins.
So we're not seeing that all the time.
Now, this is great.
We've brought in a whole bunch of these bits of grass.
You can see a lot of depth already, but when we're on the side, it looks pretty.
Not so good because they're just flat.
There's a flat images.
This is a more efficient and I think quicker way of doing it, then modelling geometry.
But we end up with these planes, these billboards.
Now, you can absolutely model geometry, particularly if you're having issues with this approach,
with the transparency or with it working.
You can model a leaf or or a stem or a stalker, a bit of grass, and you can put a texture onto that.
And then you can duplicated a bunch of times to make your own little arrangement within a job geometry
that can be an object.
And then rather than clicking on this flat image here to populate your particles, you can click on
an object so you can use the particle system to spawn a whole bunch of whatever you want.
It'd be crazy even thinking about it, but I could spawn a whole bunch of cats as particles around here
if I wanted to do that.
You know, I'm going to try that to see how badly it breaks things.
OK.
Hasn't broken it so far.
It's Kalakala, it's silly.
Scale it up.
There you go.
We've got a whole bunch of cats being spawned, so I wouldn't recommend this is the best look of making
grass look good and goodness only knows what sort of geometry we've got going on in there.
But just to show you that you can use any object so you could make little flowers and arrange them using
this same technique.
I'm going to remove that particle system before my computer implodes.
There we go.
Now we're back to the problem we've got here, which is everything's facing in the one direction.
So make sure advanced is clicked on and we're clicked on a fluffy grass.
Scroll down and you'll see rotation, click on rotation, open up the opening puppy thing.
And instead of orientation axis being velocity hair, I'm going to change this to global Z.
So we're gonna rotate around our upby Downy Axis.
Now, when I increase the randomize phase, you'll see that things turn.
If I play around with it, you'll see that they turn in a random direction.
So we have a lot more of that depth of depth of the look to what we're doing with our grass here.
Let's do a quick render to see how things are progressing and we'll see if I made a huge mistake by
going and doing my last minute coloring of that grass to make it more yellow.
So far, it's not terrible.
And you can see straight away there's more of a realistic, high, detailed look that we get with this
image is plain than we do when we've just got our our hair particles from our previous lecture just
bombed in there.
So it's a step up in terms of complexity.
One issue we're getting here is look at we've got all these black spots in here.
This is where the light is not getting through.
The transparency information is not working.
So you see down the front here.
Transparency is working.
But over here, it's not working.
One solution I've found is that if we jump over to our render properties and we look at light paths,
what I found is VI increase the total number of light paths to 20.
And the transparency to 20.
Then I can fix most of those black hole issues.
So I haven't played around with it to the full extent.
I just put those numbers up.
Both those numbers up and it seem to fix it.
If you're getting the issue in more an extreme way, you might want to put your numbers higher.
Depends on the transparency that you're using.
This is going to get pretty intensive on your computer if you've got too much of this going on.
So bear in mind that it's a little bit dependent upon the rig that you're running.
And if you've got a bit of a potato, which is what I had up until recently, then it's pretty tricky
to do.
But this has ended up pretty good, I think, in terms of getting that extra flavor in here.
So I could play around with this a little bit.
I might just increase the density of this.
There's a few more of those, and I'm definitely gonna change the randomness of the height a little
bit more and add a little bit more randomness in general, I think.
So if I do a live randomise at the top, he can see that it's randomising in a number of directions
on different axes.
So going to a little bit of that to push it off.
And then I'm going to add some scale randomness so we get different heights.
And you can see here, if my scale is one point three, that's the maximum height and the scale randomness
is going to scale things up to that height.
So let's see around about there, I think is going to give us some of that height, randomness.
And then just for fun, I'm going to come down a roughness and play with the randomness there, see
if anything at all happens.
I don't think it will because we're using an image.
We're not using up strands of particles.
When you're looking for randomness, you just twiddle anything that says random, don't you?
Just to see what happens.
Okay, then there's one more thing that you can do.
If you're feeling brave and adventurous, you can hand place some of these flowers if you want them
to get to get them in a specific spot.
So click on.
Plus, I'll hide the other two particles systems.
I'll rename this to be, let's see, larger graphs.
Now I'll turn the number down to something more manageable.
Ten click on hair length to one.
Scroll down, scroll down.
Instead of paff with sprinter's object, click on these selecta.
Find our object.
Now obviously you could do with this with a totally different object.
Totally new flower or something.
Increase, increase, increase.
While it's still in this mode.
Before I go and do anything else, I've got to get them all set up exactly how I want them, because
I'm going to go on hand, place them in one year.
Once you hand place them, you lose some options.
So click on advanced scroll down to rotation like rotation once again, Global Z, etc..
Being randomise, I'm going to use phase and that will rotate all of them in the direction of where
the camera should be.
Okay, mostly to where the camera is.
So this is specific rotation as opposed to random rotation, which we could do.
If you've just got one fixed camera, you can have everything in exactly the right alignment if you
wanted to do that.
But that won't look so good if you're doing a rotate around.
But for me, I'm seeing a fixed camera.
So this is is or should work.
Okay.
Speaking of camera, where is my camera?
Where is all the way back here.
So let's go and get generally where it's going to be.
Okay, so a couple of these are going to be in front of the cat.
That might be a good look.
I don't know.
We've already got a couple in front of the cat, so it's just a little test.
Renda, while we've got those couple of new ones placed in there, I might not need a hand place them.
Maybe the randomness will do the job for me.
Okay, I'm liking this one over on the side here.
That looks nice.
The one in the front, not too bad, hides a little bit of the cat to make Libya more mysterious just
to show that that's an approach that we can take.
So what I will do, I think they're looking pretty good.
Might just scale them up a tiny bit more.
Sorry.
Back on to my ground.
And find scale and render scale just a little bit bigger.
Yep, that's fine.
Now going to try something crazy, which between just you and I.
I've not actually yet done so.
I'm going to change the number down to zero for my particles.
Jump over into particle.
Edit bearing in mind that as soon as I do this, we're going to lose some of the controls that we have
over in our control panel.
And I will place one just there and just there, a couple over in the background.
I think if I place them here, they probably won't be in camera.
But we'll see what happens.
Now, when I jump back into object mode, they're facing the camera.
Good.
They're in exactly the spot that I place them.
Now, I have a little bit of control in terms of saying where would I like some of those longer bunches?
Now, obviously, you could just take your image.
The texture is plain that we imported and you could just duplicate that and place it exactly where you
want to.
But the point of this exercise is to show you how we could do it with the particle system so that we
know the full power of the particle system.
So let's scale this down.
I'll have this in view.
So I see exactly what I'm talking about.
Okay, so we want to get some couple more at the back and maybe one down in here and one over in there.
I got a couple of tests renders I figured that I need a little bit more volume at the front.
So there's not quite the contrast between my two particle systems and I'll probably do some more of
this in the next lecture.
But just a reminder that you can increase or decrease the length of your particles when you're editing
the particles so that you get taller or smaller flowers.
But this is what I've come up with.
I think it's pretty good.
My point here is that you can add any type of object that you want.
You can add a whole bunch of different flowers.
You can create geometry.
It doesn't need to just be the image as planes.
And if you're having any issue with the transparency with it, not working with it, not rendering correctly,
then there's other ways, other solutions to go about implementing something that's looking grass like.
So I think I probably put a little bit too much in here now.
It's a little bit of a wall of grass.
I'll take a couple out just so it doesn't look like my cat's completely hidden.
And if you haven't done so already, your challenge is to add some flavor.
Find a transparent grass or flower image to add to your grass scene, to add to your plane.
If you want add more than one, add a whole bunch hand.
Place them if you want or just have them randomly spawn if you would like that as well.
There's your challenge.
And please do share what you come up with after you go through this process so we can see what you've
created for your wonderful grass scene.
Okay, I'll see you in the next lecture.