Congratulations guys.
We've got an awesome human head some of the work you've done so far.
Absolutely brilliant.
Thank you very much for sharing.
Very important So we've learned a lot in the section.
Just to recap we've done materials really really in depth.
Absolutely.
So hopefully this gives you the ability to make things that are close to photo realistic you're going
to have to put a lot of time in and doing a lot of work to get it there.
And these things aren't easy but you've got all the tools that you need now.
And it's not quite the end of the Course yet.
No.
There's plenty more to come up.
And also we've covered good mesh topology incredibly important when you're dealing with this specially
facial structures to keep things realistic and to stop horrible pinching going on.
So great work putting some extra time finish a few model polishing up show in the discussions show us
what you can make and make you proud of what he's taught you.
Brilliant.
And we'll see you guys in the next section.