In this lecture, we are going to be adding an HDR background and doing final polishing.
Lights, camera and action to get our image looking the way we want to have it look.
So let's get cracking on finishing our scene.
Okay.
Let's make our background look good and make the light in our scene.
Reflect the background, adding ourselves in HDR eye.
If you wanna jump over to HDR, I haven dot com.
That's a great place to find HDR eyes, which are images that can wrap around our entire scene.
I'm looking for something that has trees and grass in the background and would suit what I've come up
with.
So probably something like this with the autumn forest or something else with trees in the background.
So I'm gonna play around the couple and find one that I think will work for my scene.
I've decided to go for one called Noon Grass.
So what we'll do here is, first of all, open up our shader editor and jump over into world within
here.
If we scroll our libit, find what's going on, you can see that we have not much going on in our world.
So I need to shift a and then add in a texture.
It'll be an environment.
Texture had this in.
Drop it next to our background.
Connect color to color.
Open up where we have our HDR.
Mine is called noon grass.
Click on our render tab.
Now we should see a little bit of noon grass going on to do.
I think I want that shady area.
So at the moment, a little bit of an issue that if my camera is facing here, I can see all that sort
of stuff in background might not be exactly what I want.
So we need to be at a rotate once again.
Make sure that you've got the node wrangler on.
I'm gonna work on noon grass control tee that will add in our mapping, texture, coordinate and mapping
as we've done before.
Now, if I rotate around these, say these z., that should rotate my entire background, which has
gone super slow.
What can I turn off to make this quick?
And maybe the cat and maybe the.
Ground plane.
See if this makes it go quicker, little bit quicker.
Get to the point where I think it's the right sort of.
I think it's the trees, the dark, iconic trees behind.
Turn those things back on again.
Do a little test render and see how this looks.
Okay.
That's more where I want to.
You can see a little bit of a snack between the background and the foreground.
Might be hard to solve that with little bit of depth of field on our camera.
Let's find our camera camera settings and then depth the field.
Turn that on focus object.
We want probably on the face of the cat or it's going to be on the entire cat.
It's also a click on that as our object aperture.
Now, the best aperture thing is that we drop this all the way down to very low settings, a point five
and see how that looks.
Give that another render.
It might be a little bit extreme, but at least it's showed some softness at the front, which also
helps explain the softness at the back.
So it's okay for the moment.
We can finesse that a little bit more.
You can look for a better edge between the grassy you've put in in the background.
You could look to have probably if I put some more objects over on the side there, maybe on the side
here as well, and had them a little bit blurry outside the depth of field that would have a better
look to it.
But this is heading in the right direction.
And what I'm going to do now is play around with my lights, my camera and do a little with tootling.
So you might want to do the same thing to around with your scene and I'll come back and let you know
what I've been up to when I had finished.
Okay.
I have to do with my lights.
I've made them a little bit less bright just so you can quickly see what they are set at the Phillies
point five.
The key is one point five in the room is point five.
Just wanted to drop them down a little bit.
You can do what you like with yours.
Move the camera a tiny bit.
One of the big things I did was I wasn't enjoying the fact that my cat didn't have a nose because we
haven't painted on the nose.
We haven't put a lot of detail when put painting detail on the.
The object.
I was trying to solve everything with particle systems in this particular section of the course.
And I thought, well, why not try to solve the nose with particle systems as well?
So I've gone and put a very simple little let me see if I can find my cat.
Very simple little particle system on the nose here as an extra.
Let's see, so a nose particle system, I created a nose material that I've just been tweaking and you
can see that I've gone and groomed a little bit of nose on my cat.
Just holds a bit silly, but it was really bugging me that there was no nose there.
There's a lot more we could do in the face to improve it.
But when we're just dealing with sculpting and with particle systems, I think this is kind of a fun
challenge to give ourselves to work within those constraints.
Oh, and I also changed the camera for the depth of field.
I put it up to to to get a little bit more of the detail at the front and at the back.
Suddenly I realized I hadn't been showing you a lot of because we've been doing on a lot throughout
the process, but I've been putting down new particles, reducing them in height or increasing them
in height.
So I'm getting the exact look that I want, having some long ones at the back, having some of the front
that are just the right height.
So they're a little bit in the way of the cap.
Not too in the way.
So make sure your raising and lowering your particles to get the look that you want to turn my samples
back up to 128, do a final render check to make sure that I haven't missed anything or forgotten anything.
And then declare that I'm done so well, it's rendering.
I'll give you the final request in this whole process.
Please share your work.
Tidy up your scene at any last details.
Play around with the lights, the camera, create a final render.
Then please do share that with us so we can see what you've come up with, whether you think it's great
and amazing or whether you think it's ah needs a lot of work or whether like mine, you can see there's
some good bits and some bits that could be better.
Please do share and let us all enjoy the process.
So there's your challenge.
Let me see what I've come up with for mine.
It's rendering away nicely.
This is gonna be my final result.
Go ahead and create your final result.
And I look forward to seeing what you are sharing.
And I'll see you in an upcoming lecture.