Welcome to making texture's look more three day in this video you play with the texture planes to alter
their appearance.
I understand that the more complexity you add here the less you may need later on.
So we're going to take a simple blade of grass.
Just our texture that we've played with before and we're going to make it into something much more vibrant
a 3D object as we spin round here.
We can see that it is truly 3-d.
So let's go create something like this and hop on over into a blender.
Okay so hidden in our hills at the moment we've got some blades of grass.
The first thing I'm going to do is just well I'm going to rename these so this grass seed here well
there are one fifth layer so let's hop over to there now getting rid of everything else or actor press
than number five on the keypad itself.
On the keyboard itself an ominous zoom around here and I'm going to change the viewport shading down
here to the material modes I can see what's going on.
Okay so it looks like this one here is the tool blade of grass.
So I'm going to call this grass.
Tall.
And then see.
Just so I know what's going on.
This is grass medium.
And I'm going to call it grass medium one because we've got another one here which Scott on a raid modifier
applied to it.
I'm going to remove that array we're not going to use that.
That was just to demonstrate the light path's themselves.
And I'm going to call this grass medium too.
And then the final one is this little one down here which must be this one the grasp of background.
I'm going to rename that one grass short.
Excellent.
So we've got these four here.
I'm actually going to hide them now.
I'm going to take a duplicate of my grass short by using shift Andy.
Of being there.
That's absolutely fine.
And I'm going to name this grass short example because that's what we're going to use in a few moments.
Now I'm going to do a bit tidying here and I'm going to select these grass grasses and put them.
On the ground plain themselves.
Just move them there manually.
Probably be quicker.
Okay so underneath the ground plane I have four types of grass.
We've currently got if you've got more or less that's absolutely fine.
Okay.
Let's go ahead and move this should short example that we're going to be working on to a new layer a
press m.
And I'm going to move it to layer 6 I suppose.
There we go.
Now we've got it on there six.
We can just view it by itself.
So we have our blade of grass and we want to make it look a little bit more 3D.
So I'll just pan across to it now.
Right now we have this in front of us.
What we can do is start manipulating it and some very simple ways you can do this is to duplicate again.
Now you got to watch out on the outline of us and get too crazy.
But we can group it together all at the end.
So we're going to duplicate that which we've done.
I'm going to rotate it immediately on the z axis by let's say one at 80.
Disappeared somewhere.
Where's it gone.
So it's just zoom out and see if we can see what's going on okay the pivot point is the 3-d cursor down
here.
So I'll be spinning around the 3D cursor so we dont want that we will change the 3-d as the pivot point
from the 3D cursor to the medium points which will put it right on the origin of our object which is
great.
Thats what we want.
So Im going to wrote Oh sorry jubilate first and then rotate on the z axis by 180.
Yeah.
We get Okay.
And now I'm going to move that out ever sisler.
It looks like I'm going to have to do a bit of rotating otherwise that's going to look like a funny
grass plants.
I'm just going to rotate that round.
I am viewing it first from the front.
You may have to do a side depending on where you place them or even the top if you still got them laying
flat on the ground.
Although they should have completed one of the last videos challenges to make sure that they're all
the right way up.
All looks we've got another blade of grass here that's okay we'll scale that one down by pressing the
right key and do excuse me I can't always see the keyboard and rotate that one around a little further.
Okay so now we've got a grass plant that's still to day but it's getting there so let's select all three
of those and duplicate them in a scale them up ever so slightly and rotate them around on the z axis
by Nancy.
Okay that sunscreens and looked pretty good.
And I'm going to scale them.
Oh my.
Will want to take a duplicate first and then scale that in ever so slightly and rotate it on the z axis
by maybe 60 this time so it's not always 90 and there we go we can slowly build up a grass plant that
looks pretty awesome.
So the final thing that we're going to need to do here will be to group all this slots together some
coming use border select by the b key select everything and I'm going to join them all together with
control and J.
And um I feel like just duplicating it once more was shifting day and rotating it on the z axis again
by another one the pick a random number one hundred thirty five.
Just to make it a little bit more dense and I'm going to.
Scale that in ever so slightly to select them both and join them.
And then I'm going to do one final thing.
I'm going to duplicate it once more.
Rotate it on the z axis.
But this time it's going to move around and randomly pick a point.
That feels right to me.
Okay so it's much more dense now.
And when we go to I'm not going to render the image there I'm literally just going to be rendered just
here that looks like a much fuller grass.
So let's go ahead and hop back into material mode selects the two grasses that we have joined together
into one and I'm going to call this grass paw grass short.
Plants.
Excellent.
I'm going to group that under the ground playing.
And there's one final thing that I'd like to show you here.
Perhaps I should have shown you before making a whole plant up.
So what I will do is I will work on a another layer quickly and I'm going to add a nother images plane
and I'm going to grab my grass blade PRNG again or let's just undo that let's put the 3-d cursor in
the middle and try adding that again but this time remembering to select the fuse and transparent and
to use the alph for Channel.
So with the grass blade selected here it should come in.
I'm going to look at it from the top so you guys can see what's going on.
Not to bother reposition the origin but what we can do here is for instance add loop cuts in.
So in edit mode we could add a couple of loop cuts in or we can even subdivide.
So I'm going to subdivide it a couple of times and you see that's probably over the top but you will
see that this allows us to alter the shape of our model.
And I can't see why that.
Oh yeah the proportional addicting size is up.
So this enables us to twist and shape and remodel.
Ah ah.
Blade of grass to our heart's content obviously you can do some very weird things.
And the reason why we add this extra geometry is if we've just got these four vertices on the end it
becomes quite difficult if we go and grab a vertex and move it.
You can see it has a harsh change just around here.
And that's not so great when trying to make something look a bit better so you can move this around
in the more geometry your ADD so we go and subdivide select everything.
Subdivide it gives us more control.
Over this particular model so as well as rotating that well like we did to make it flat we could actually
pull this virtex out a little and make it a little bit taller although sometimes it can squish parts
of the model you didn't want to squish.
There's lots of to play with for her.
And in fact what you can do is make this a bit more three dimensional in itself so you can have the
grass actually curving round in 3-d space even though it's just the flat texture and unlike normal geometry
when you're filling it in.
It's obviously got a couple of sharp angles here as it moves.
Now those angles are determined by the geometry itself not so of just for example or not anything to
do with the shading.
You've got set so if you wanted to be a smooth transition if you're making a texture more 3D you're
going to have to add more subdivision's or something along those lines.
And once you have more subdivisions you can start moving things with a little more fun ness.
So it's not so wonky.
There we go.
So that should now curve round a little bit better than how it was before school got a few sharp angles.
But in general that is much much better.
Okay guys it's Challenge time.
I'd like you to make more grass plants.
So make one or two more grass plants.
This will help with making our grass look better.
Now remember to preserve the original blades when making those plants pulls a video now and give that
a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's hop back over into blender.
So I'm going to use the blade of grass.
I've been working on here to demonstrate how you can work around your model itself.
I'm going to set the origin point first of all so let's come out of here and hopefully that sat on the
mesh.
Yes it has.
And I'm going to go up here and set the origin to this 3-d cursor that gives me lots of options including
planting it firmly on the ground.
And I'm just going to rotate this round on the x axis by 90 I think minus 90.
There we go.
So we've now got that coming out of the ground.
I'm going to hop into object mode and I think I'm going to duplicate it all.
Let's set the zero first.
Before I do any of that I think I've got a duplicate there as well.
Yeah.
It just helps when things are all sprouting from the same place especially with grass because if you
have a look at a grass plant it does tend to all sprout from a similar location and can adjudicate those
pretty and round locks them to the z axis.
Come round here perhaps.
Okay so that's starting to look pretty good.
I'm going to do some scaling here.
So it looks a wee bit different.
I'm actually going to bring in another texture on here.
So we've got our grass tool I'm going to Jew placates Our can't do it whilst the layers not active.
So let's go and find our grass was our grass tool Oh my upsidedown.
I think I just might have built the last thing upside down.
Did anybody spot that.
I certainly didn't.
I was too engrossed in making some grass.
Me Wait.
Let's duplicate.
That's embarrassment out of the way and move it to the appropriate level.
I think I'm working on they are 6.
Or am I on there 7.
I think I am on layer 7 at the moment so let's move it again to layer 7.
Okay it does look like I produced some stuff upside down so I can select all of these grass blades here.
And just dropped this one out for the moments of these one.
This one this one and this one.
And explain why the rotation was a bit funky.
And there we go.
It's amazing what happens when you're not paying full attention.
So I'm going to bring that up and sighted at zero zero and zero sort of one here is to produce a plant
that's basically a seeded plant.
Let's see how that's looking at the moments.
Looking pretty good.
Now it says she got some grass down the bottom.
I'm pretty happy with that.
So I'm going to group them all together song and select them all.
And let's just come out in back into material mode.
This orange border by the way can get quite irritating.
You can turn it off in the propertys if we scroll down and go to display there's an outline selective
that you can toggle on and off and when you start having a geometry as you can see here turning that
on and off can help massively and we'll probably use that again later on when we've got lots and lots
of blades of grass going on.
So I quite like what's gone on there.
I'm just wondering if you look at it from this way it's not so great.
So let's produce two of these tools seeds before grouping it all together.
Or.
Yeah.
That's that's worked from there so that's duplicate that and rotate it on the z axis by 90 degrees.
Not the z axis I'm British.
There we go.
So we've got that coming out there.
Might as well have a third one I think so.
Jupe Cates rotate Z.
Let's have it fair solent.
So that looks like a pretty good grasp.
I'm going to make these one of these look ever so slightly different so again I'm going to turn on the
outline selected.
This is when you do want it on of course when you're trying to see things.
And let make this one a little taller.
This one a little shorter.
There we go.
Now they don't look so much like copies of one another and then go into edit mode here and try at she
to straighten that up a little more.
So just look straight and tall.
And I don't mind of the other.
Are a little bit curvy.
Let's grab this one here is where I am of course this is one of these things again.
Does it matter if you do so much with it.
Well with most things in blender and in life I suppose the more you put into it the more you're going
to get out.
Obviously we've got diminishing returns at some point.
I'm going to stop there.
I'm going to group all of these together.
And that I think is all of them are selected them in the outline and thereby holding down a shift.
And I'm going to join them all together with control and J.
And what's it called at the moment grass blade 0 1 dot.
That's no good.
So it's a grass tone caps off.
It's a grass it's a seeded grass.
And it's a plants so grass seed plant planet not quite plant.
Excellent.
How did you guys get on.
Id love to see what grass plants you managed to create.
Please share them in discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.