Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we can set up some new constraints that will work with inverse Kana Mattox the original
constraints that we've set up are no longer working there.
I don't think they're going to be much use for the rest of this project so we'll actually remove them
from here and then use some i k limits so that we can prevent the lamp looking like it's been squashed
into itself.
It's horrible when things like this happen.
Let's find out how to prevent it.
Hello and welcome.
Let's first of all turn back on my overlays so I can see what's going on.
Now the constraints themselves that we've currently got on our bones.
Let's go ahead and remove those.
So beforehand we were limiting their rotation because we were manually moving them.
We don't want to do that that's going to be too costly in time to manage.
So we've removed all of the bone constraints.
The next thing we need to do is give it a different type of constraints and we can do that under the
bone settings because we've already started playing with this under the inverse can Mattox menu.
If we go in here we've got we've locked it to stop it twisting through itself or twisting the wrong
way.
But what we haven't done is prevented it from actually collapsing through itself.
We've not given it some range of movement.
The first thing I'm gonna do is set it back into rest position.
So we're looking at it once again from the side.
Most of this model is just two dimensional in terms of how it can move this top bit.
However our lampshade can currently just spin around indefinitely and that's going to cause us a problem
as well we want to limit its rotation.
Either way as well.
Let's whizz round to the side and let's focus on the upper arm.
At the moment we've got it being able to be rotated sort of 45 degrees one way and 45 degrees the other
of something like that.
That's what we picked.
We go to our bone properties and scroll down.
We can limit the X movement.
Notice that limit y and z is currently grayed out.
It is currently grayed out simply because at the top here we've locked it.
If we open them all up suddenly they all appear.
Now we don't want one of them to move quite as freely.
You can add a bit of stiffness to it as well the stiffness will slow down its movement rather than having
it jerk all over the places.
It's like a dampener.
Let's have a look at limiting the X movement the moment you do that.
We've got this circle that appears and this is incredibly useful you can see straight away the range
of movement that you're going to have.
So if I wanted this to lean forward a little bit more perhaps to that point there we can see that's
around minus 42 so let's type in minus 40.
And at the moment it's going to lean all the way back to there.
Now let's think about how far we might want it to be able to move.
We probably want it to align not quite with this but not too far from it.
So at this point at 90 degrees it would have gone completely straight.
So let's make sure it can't do that and maybe set it to 75 degrees.
Now what will happen is when we start moving this well we can't do it whilst we're in rest mode which
is no problem that's come out.
So who sets the constraints.
Now when we're moving it look about is preventing it from going in and through itself like it would've
done before it starts moving the bones underneath.
Now this is really critical to making sure that you don't set up a model that can go inside itself.
And of course this now needs to be repeated but with some of the other bones here as well and a great
chance to practice these skills in your challenge Okay then this should be a relatively straightforward
exercise.
We are going to basically limits all of the other bones movements.
So whilst we're using the inverse can somatic system we cannot push the model through itself.
Pause the video now and give that a go
OK.
Everybody welcome back Let's hop into a blender and finish off limiting our bones.
So we've got one of the bones sorted I'm going to now work on the next bone down again I'm going to
pop it in the rest position so I can see what's going on.
Go to the bone properties limits it on x.
I'm gonna go minus 40 and 40 the other way as well and just see what happens.
This is the key thing once you've done one of the settings I am going to highlight everything and just
clear the rotation and the movement now.
Excellent.
Now the rotation is clear.
Let's go ahead and move our lamp around.
Excellent.
So it's not allowing it to go beyond light not quite 90 degrees which I think is a good thing to do
and it's not allowing these to push into one another and where we live leant back like this.
Yes that looks pretty reasonable in terms of its range of movements.
Okay.
Pretty good.
I'm gonna.
Yeah.
I think I'm going to conquer the lamp shade last this final one here.
We want to limit it on the y axis and I'm gonna set it to minus ninety to plus 90 that basically all
that was more than 90 was an X I match the keypad.
This is going to mean that as we use this control bone and the top and move it to look around it will
naturally move to a point and then it won't go any further.
But you do have to look at that it will flip around if we're not careful so you do have to be careful
of how you position your bones or your control bones as you're moving your model around this top one
this is going to take a few more constraints we'll start in the x axis.
So let's go ahead and do that let's look at this from the side.
Here we go.
And I want to limit its movement quite significantly as it goes down.
So all X first let's move that up not too far from where it is at the moment.
Let's go ahead and test that
Kate.
This is going to be its minimum position so this is a good place to test this minimum limit.
There we go.
That's the minimum.
Allowing it to move in the x axis and then maximum all the way over here.
Let's just see what that looks like if we go ahead grab this and move it see there is.
Yeah.
It might be touching a little bit there but I think that's okay.
And leaning back it can go all the way beyond look all the way up I think straight like that is fine.
But as you can see here it likes to move all the way around as well.
We start to get it being a bit funny in which direction it wants to face.
So let's have a look at our limits again.
Let's go ahead selects our bone.
I don't feel I'm going to have it go quite as far I think I can have it go in line.
So that's one of those that one of the things to watch out for here is which axes are you talking about.
If we have a look at the bones themselves the y axis is rotation.
So it's got no need to move on the y axis I'm going to move that out straight away.
However we do want to limits on Z and look a Val gives us a 3D dome that this can move around in.
Let's see if we need to do anything or whether we can have it look around as and when we want.
Let's have it move on the x axis backwards and forwards
Yeah I think that's pretty good.
Let's see what happens with this bone selected.
I don't think it looking right back on itself.
Maybe minus 18 to plus 80.
So it's got to a reasonable field of view at the frontier.
Yeah.
And that's much much better.
And then if it needs if the lamp itself needs to look at the ground it will look down like that.
That's really neat.
I'm liking how that's coming together.
It can be a bit picky and these settings that I've chosen aren't necessarily the right ones.
It's important to just experiment with your particular lamp because you're going to have slightly different
dimensions.
Arms at different angles.
You may even have completely different properties that mean you can't follow exactly along with my numbers
but that's fine.
What we have here is a pretty awesome setup.
Our lamps coming together really well.
Think it's time to start talking about animating this and we'll start that in the next lecture.