Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to create an assets portfolio like the scene in front of us here we're going
to be able to switch backwards and forwards between scenes to show off our different work.
And this has the benefit of not only showcasing your materials your models your textures that you've
made but also it's a bit of fun as well.
Let's hop on over into blender and find out more okay.
So we have our current scene in front of us.
And to be quite honest we need to create a new scene before we start playing around any further with
this.
So in the top right we have our scene selection at the moment.
If we click on the dropdown there's only one scene.
And let's just call this playing chess so we know what this one happens to be when we click the little
copy icon add new scene by type.
We can have a blank new scene.
We can copy just the scenes settings but no models will come across.
We can do a linked copy.
The downside to doing it linked to copy is that everything that's in there.
If you change if you move it will reflect in every other linked copy as well.
So if we go ahead and move our pieces and rearrange them they we'll rearrange in this one as well which
we don't want.
So we want to do a full copy.
And that means that anything that we do in this new scene that's call this showcase will not be reflected
back in the playing scene.
So let's go back to our showcase scene.
I know straight away I'm only going to need one camera for this.
Now you might not know that that's what you want.
So that's fine.
But in this particular case we only want the one camera.
I'm going to use my wide angle near camera.
I'm also going to only need some of the pieces.
So let's have a look.
We're going to need one of every piece so we can start off here.
We've got pawn one black 001 so I'm going to delete all of the other pawns and then I'm going to do
the same on the other side says one two three four five six seven so nice and simple so far and then
we just need to remove the Bishop, Knight and rook and the same on this side so one two three and remember
the notch as well.
Now we're in the position at this point where we could probably apply the notch itself.
So let's go ahead and apply it here and here.
You can't really do it before this point because otherwise we you would have a multi-user and we'll
deal with that later on.
But simply put you can't just apply a modifier across multi-user objects.
Okay.
So you've got all the basics sorted out here.
Now if I wanted to move the board slightly down I'm going to look at it from above and let's go G,
Y all of the pieces move with it.
So that's worthwhile bearing that in mind.
The next thing that I want to do is grab all of the actual pieces themselves.
I'm going to hide the camera for the moment.
Otherwise every time I drag to select I'm going to inadvertently select it as well.
So let's just move these over here and let's do the same with these pieces as well.
Now truth be told it'd be a lot easier if I hadn't moved all of my pieces around to begin with but I have.
So this gives us an excellent opportunity to play.
Now this knight is facing a different direction.
So I'm going to open up my properties panel by hitting the correct key.
This is probably going to be minus 90 to have it facing inwards.
Okay perfect.
Let's make that disappear again.
So now we've just got to decide on the order I'm going to select my king and pop him roughly in the
middle there and I'm going to do the same for the other king.
So is that going to be enough distance apart.
We should find if we have a look that it's five centimeters in on either side.
Which it is.
So let's go to our camera view real quick, I'll go shift and the grave key.
Move round here.
Is that about the right distance or do we want them further apart as we passed them.
Good question.
I think we're fine with that distance so let's go ahead and just tweak the camera at this point because
what you will find is that it's still focusing on one of the bishops.
So when we're moving around it will start flickering out and in because of whichever Bishop we were
focused on before I think it was this black one here.
There we go starts going really funny around there.
OK.
So I'm going to go to my camera itself.
So camera to the camera properties and not set it as bishop one black but set it as perhaps 10 centimeters
in front of the camera or maybe less maybe five.
And then that means that as we move the camera forward in rendered mode it comes into focus five's far
too small at these settings.
So let's send it back to 10.
Perfect.
And one final thing before I gets into a challenge this gray background is awfully boring.
What we can do is on the right hand side go to the world properties go to the color properties under
the surface properties of the World Color and set it to something else.
In this case I'm just going to simply make it black.
But if you want to do something more creative of course you can do that as well.
And now that we've got these basic sets up it's time for your challenge and your challenge is to create
a new scene like we've already done.
But if you've not been following along at this point you will need to create yourself a new scene.
Remember to copy rather than link set up one of every piece in a showcase.
And what I'd like to do is be creative.
You don't have to do what I've done and put them all in a nice neat row perhaps there's another way
of arranging these pieces.
Pause the video now and give that a go
Hello everybody and welcome back.
Let's hope on over into blender and create our showcase.
So we've got the general stuff set up here as a matter of hopping into the top view here.
I'm just going to press the W key a couple of times to make sure I've got the right type of selection
box select I can see down in the lower left which one I've got some box select is fine now.
Which order are we going to do things in let's move these out of the way.
We're gonna need the Queen next.
And again I'm going to place this is probably going to be a little bit closer.
There we go.
Where's the other queen.
So good job that you can tell the difference from from all of these different pieces just by the top
view itself.
Otherwise it'll be very easy to get confused by them all.
I'm not sure whether it's quicker to do individual ones like I'm doing at the moment or a group move
but I am happy with how that's looking.
Okay.
And now we've got them aligned on one side it should be quite easy to align them on the other as well.
I think that looks good.
I'm going to look at them from the camera's perspective.
I'm going to go control in space to go full screen.
I want to get rid of the properties panel.
I'm going to hide all of the gizmos outlines by clicking on the display overlays toggle and then shift
and the grave key.
And let's move forward.
Wow.
Brilliant.
Now this is a great way you could screen capture this if you wanted to or indeed you could animate the
camera and then render out the animation.
We'll get to that in the next section.
Wow.
Fly away.
Cool!
Hope you've had lots of fun in this section.
Hope you've set up your two scenes, your showcase and you're playing scene perhaps you set up a different
scene as well.
Really looking forward to seeing your final chess boards please share them over in the discussions and
I'll see you all in the next lecture.