Welcome to possible construction efforts.
So before we get cracking on with any actual modelling we need to plan our journey.
And there are many ones we can take.
And has always with everything.
There is no right way.
Now we could go ahead doing box modelling we could build up the model from a primitive adding more and
more detail as we go.
We could do what's called Polly to Polly which is building up your model one polygon at a time.
And this can be.
It feels like it's going to be a slow way but it does give you a lot of control over your model.
And then finally we could sculpt the actual head and bust itself and then reet apologize.
And this can be very time consuming so there's a balance to be had.
The box modelling at the top may be great if you didn't need to animates because you're likely to end
up with your edge flows that we were talking about in the previous lecture in the wrong place you'd
have to do a lot of Rita apologizing which is where you reconstruct your mesh and in order to add that
detail and add the loops going in the right way.
Polly to Polly is great because it does allow us to create the loops from scratch and that gives us
a lot of control over the model with something as complicated as a head that might be the way to go.
Now sculpting and then reet apologizing afterwards can be very time consuming but it does give us a
high detailed model that we could potentially bape detail from back onto a lower poly model and then
that does give us some advantages.
However there is no right way so it depends what you want to achieve.
So let's hop on over in a blender and have a look at all three and see which ones we could work with.
Hey so we're back over in blender here and I've got the default cube in the scene and we have a quick
look about how we would go about just a quick rough model here how we might go about making it in a
block model style.
So I'm going to hop into edit mode on my Cuban scale it up by about two times.
So it's a bit easier to work on can always scale it backwards forwards afterwards.
I'm now going to hop back into object mode because I'm going to use the subdivision surface modifier
to actually make it more give me more polygons to work with.
Now you could use loop and slide and work from there or indeed you could just subdivide the cube.
But I'm going to go to the modifiers tab and do a subdivision surface modifier and set it to number
level two and then click apply.
Now before I go any further because that gives me a good starting point to work from I would probably
go around to the front view in orthographic projection and then either with wireframe mode turned on
or limits a selection limited selection to visible turned on.
Course we need to be in edit mode to do that which is there so we could use each other one.
It doesn't really matter I only use wireframe make sure nothing is selected and then using the board
a select highlight half the models vertices and delete them.
Now I'm going to go in and add another modifier which would be the mirror modifier and make sure clipping
is ticked so I can't cross over the barrier in the middle.
Now this gives me another turn.
Wireframe back off.
This gives me a basic head shape for I can work from.
And of course here then I would start going here and maybe it should doing vose downwards we go.
So that gives you an idea of how we can start block modelling.
I grab that and pull it slightly forward etc etc. and we can go round and use proportional editing of
course to help us out.
We of moving lots of hertz's it was easy to see how very quickly you can build up a shape from there.
But this does have loops but they're kind of in the wrong place.
This one's got all.
I say they're in the wrong place but this one has a loop around the face but it's kind of broken up.
We see here in the corner there is a Pole where three joins us not continue sedgley going round there.
The loop itself is broken by the acts of their being.
These three edges meeting one another.
So that's an example of a pole stopping an edge loop.
If I were to try and select this one just beneath it.
We can see it runs all the way round.
So in many ways that's a good starting point but it doesn't give us any flexibility straight away over
the eyes themselves or the nose we'd have to add a lot of detail in and let's have a look.
Now at Poly to poly modelling so I'll start my self up a new file and then get rid of the cube.
In this case I'm going to move around to the front view and just zoom in a little and I'm going to add
mesh and single vertex there is.
Add a single vertex and then from this single vertex you can literally extrude and start making the
shape that you want.
And of course once you've done that there is our first polygon.
Now I don't have any reference material on the screen at the moment which is something I would advise
you always have.
And of course from this point you could do things like grab the edge and extrude.
I do want to be on the front view at the moment so that not extruding into the middle of nowhere and
then I could rotate that edge extrude rotate that edge and you can probably guess what I'm building
up at the moment.
It's going to become the eye and of course we want to make sure there's a much detail in there as possible
and you can go round and you can do this unless you can see this can be a little bit time consuming
but it does give you lots of lots control of the model as we go.
And of course I do need to do things like rotate a few bits around should press rotate instead of E.
Omega rotate that one round.
Of course I can turn snapping on make it edge select.
Now let's do virtex and move it in.
That's that one done.
Going to get a furtak Select here.
Move that one across.
Now because I haven't turned on the merging vertices on the snapping at all over here I'm going to have
to just select everything and under the new space and type in doubles and remove those doubles and that's
remove those extra bits there then I can play with this to my heart's content.
Then I can select one of these outer loops perhaps extrude it by nothing and scale it out as starts
create the loops around me.
I very powerful doing it that way because it gives us a lot of control.
Of course we do need to remember this is a 3D package and we'd need to start moving these in and out
as well to get the face shape that we want.
Finally let's have a look at sculpting.
So here we are back with the standard cube in our scene now going through the sculpting method.
You could start by working with this and strain to sculpt and then obviously you can't do anything when
it's just Scott's.
These four vertices in but you could turn on dynamics apology and work from their mouth.
I wouldn't recommend doing that straight away as it somewhat destroys the mesh topology having good
topology.
You definitely have to re to apologize if you did that.
However that is good adding detail in certain areas for baking that to a lower polygon model.
So one of the first things I would do here would be to subdivide it again.
Oh I missed subdivide there.
I would subdivide it again by a couple of times just to get started from there.
I would once again go into edit mode around the front in their orthographic projection and wireframe
on to the border select off the sand deselecting everything and just getting rid of those vertices and
then adding in the mirror modifier with clippings turned on.
That's absolutely fine.
But from here because I'm sculpting I would then go and add in a multi resolution modifier and subdivided
a couple of times in object mode.
Perhaps to this level initially so you can see it pinches slightly in the corner.
It's not going to be great topology to begin with but it's somewhere to start.
Especially if you want to sculpt.
And now I can unhide that and they go there's a basic nose coming in.
And if we were to recess.
I shif.
That's moving that's just subtract.
Okay so you can see here how with a bit of care you can start building up a head and obviously heads
aren't spherical like vats so you'd change the size of your brush perhaps push in the back a bit at
the back of the neck.
And of course most people don't have a face looking support.
Height fat you'd need to pull it out down here.
Course what we're not seeing at the moment is how it's looking in this mode.
In object mode so we'd switch to that.
See here that the preview as we build it up.
When you get there and we can see that there's a seam happy down the front face as well so that something
will have to pay attention to later on.
Does it disappear with higher subdivisions.
No and that's basically the mirror modifier when it joins together it's not joined together completely
flush so would have to bear that in mind.
In fact at this point does re the mirror modifier actually make a difference.
No because the mortie Rose has to exist at the top in this case so we can't do that.
But you can then play around with this.
If we hop back into sculped mode of course we only see one half so it's worthwhile bearing in mind that
we only see one half and then you can really start to zoom in and say well let's make it easier.
It's mean that Brusher bit smaller.
In there we go very quickly you start building it up and of course this is rough and ready.
You could take a bit more care over it and I have at the moment but you can see how you could start
building up a model really quickly.
Okay guys it's challenged time.
I would like you to think about your construction.
So plan how you're going to build up your model.
Sketch out your plan whether you're using the blender itself to mock it up in 3D or using plain old
pen paper or digital pen and paper.
It's absolutely fine.
Just so you get an idea and start thinking forward about your modelling.
Now think carefully about each stage how are you going to generate the shapes that you want to generate.
Now at this stage I'd like you to keep the level of detail to a rough shape because this will be the
base mesh that we could use for other things as well.
And remember to place loops at key features.
Now at the moment you're not going to be making the detail for the eyes or things like that but you
will be keeping the general level of detail so if you.
But you will be defining where things are both horizontally and vertically across your model.
And at those points that's a good place to place the loops so balls of video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
I just like to show you my sketch of the plan.
I am going to go through it of course if you got a slightly different plan I encourage you to stick
to yours and see how it pans out as well.
So let's have a look at it.
Okay so as you can see here I am going to start with something that looks very much like a cube.
I'm then going to subdivide the cube.
Now we've been through that in the previous example and then I'm going to go ahead and get the rough
shape.
Of course I'm going to mirror it at some point I've forgotten to write down that step so I don't have
to do the same thing on both sides and the extra loops in to help define some more shape as we go No
for there and extrude down the neck area and then the final thing that I am going to do with this base
is I'm going to finalize the shape and if we have a look in at the face itself you can see I've started
think about where things are going to go.
There's going to have to be an extra couple of loop around there.
Of course I might already have placed one in the right place which is great.
I'm going to use the reference material for the position as well which is very important.
And finally just a reminder there for myself not adding too much detail at the moment so even though
we're going to define whether features will be unknot going to be defined in the actual features just
as yet.
And then of course um.
Just a reminder there to savour as.
So that's going to be my base meche done and I can obviously take that mesh and use it for other characters
as well as it's just going to be a generic shape.
Of course it is going to be based upon my particular reference material.
So if you want to use your own reference material than of course it's going to be a slightly different
shapes you go along with me.
Okay.
Brilliant right.
I think we're almost ready now to start modelling.
So please share your methodology in the discussions so we can see how your planning to get your particular
model made.
Are there any steps that you've thought about that aren't here.
As I say I've missed out mirror there.
Be interesting to see how your going to develop your model forward.
So thank you for sharing and I will see you guys in the next lecture.