Hello everybody and congratulations for completing the chess set section.
Now we've completed basic polygon modelling here you can pretty much make anything your mind comes to
in a low poly sense.
At this point we've also not only applied materials but textured materials both using procedural and
a photo or an image texture and applied it to our model.
There's much much more to learn about texturing and we'll cover that in the game asset section coming
up later in the course.
Now if you haven't shared your work already, Please do I'd love to see how you're getting on and if you're
one of the few out there that do have a 3D printer and you printed out your chess set.
I'm really looking forward to seeing those models so please do share them over in the discussions as
well.
Now it's time to hop on over into a blender and carry on this course and go straight over to section
5.