Welcome to applying a normal map in blender.
So this is going to be the continuation from the challenge in the last lecture where we create a normal
map just to remind you of that challenge we're going to take.
One of the models up to at least 10 levels say Now I've already done that because it takes quite a while
to do some modelling.
And we're going to create a normal map of that and apply it to a lower polygon model and then finally
are share the two side by side so we can see which is which.
So let's hop straight on over in a blender.
Okay so I've opened up my window and this is the file that I have been working on.
I've got my elodie B and I've also been working on an L O D C so let's enable that and this is what
it looks like he's got a few quirks here in there but overall I'm happy with the outcome.
It looks much more higgledy piggledy than another one would.
So there is a couple of things that we need to think about before I go forward and the first one is
this material now in a moment I'm about to build up a new material based upon my original wall but it
is going to be unique to this particular model.
So in that case I don't think I need it linked anymore because as soon as we apply the normal map there
is specifically for this model simply because it's got a hole in the middle.
We are well we can't link it anymore so we can actually break that link completely.
And I've clicked the little icon there so it's now local to this particular model.
Okay so now that we've done that I'm broken that's a wall link.
We can now start working on the model a little further.
The first well I'm not sure what order to do this in that it doesn't really matter in many ways but
I'm trying to go through it in a logical manner.
I think I need to deal with the multiple you v maps.
I know we with an image so let's create a new image and call it window normal 44.
Oh that's badly spelt normal.
There you go.
And if we now have a look at the U V map if we try and bake to this image it's going to cause a problem
and show you that.
Now let's see if we can bake straight away Sir elodie see to elodie B.
That's fine.
Is selected Let's scroll down here.
Go to break.
And we want normal selected to active.
And the race distance I'm going to go for points.
Not sure of it's going to be OK.
No active image found in material wall.
Okay so we run the risk here of overwriting an image.
If we're not careful so let's proceed with caution.
Okay.
It's currently assigned.
We've got the wall texture here and that possibly the wall material and the texture that we're trying
to write to is a generated texture.
So we need an image texture.
And here is the church block work.
We don't want that we want the window normal.
So I've swapped over to that that's now our active image and I'm going to hit bake.
Excellent.
So that's done exactly what I thought it was going to do.
It's updated the.
Wow that looks absolutely out of the sky but anyway so you can see here that the UV map is too big for
the image so we can go and sort that out.
That's not a problem at all.
We need to basically scale that image in.
So I'm going to go ahead or scale not the image sorry the movie map in but we need a new you v map first
so I'm going to go to you v maps in the data properties and then add a new You've come out and I'm going
to call it normal map instead.
Now that I've got a normal map there we can go ahead and just bring this up so I can see what's going
on.
I can hide elodie see from my scene for the moment so I can see what's going on and what I can do here
is stop in the edit mode real quick.
Bring this back down so I can see what's going on.
And I actually only need one of these on.
On this particular image here.
So I'm going to scale that in is snappin turned on no it's not a scale that down and move it.
So I don't need the whole image on because I actually only care about the front.
So let's move down to there.
Now when we're actually mapping I do care about these two being on top of one another so this bit here
and this one here being on top the front of the back on top of one another because they'll be projecting
different Normal's onto one another.
And now that I've rearranged that we can make no valid cited options there too there.
Make sure we can see it.
Okay.
That is exactly what I wanted.
Now that I've done that if I so wish I can go back to the U V here and move this area on top of the
other one.
So they share the same data and I'm going to do that right away.
So the select this with snapping turned on was snapping snapping to vertex a move that sits right on
top of the other one.
And that should mean that both sides now share the same normal map.
Hopefully we will see if that works.
So I think I'm done in the image editor for the moment.
Wow that does look interesting that's been mapped funnily but that's absolutely fine because that's
how the other image was mapped.
Not this one.
So that's coming along well.
And what we can do here is go to are you the image editor.
No I want the node editor.
Let's have a look at how it's set up so far.
So we've got the material outputs and the diffuse shader.
Now the diffuse shader has an image defining it which at the moment is this really wacky one and we
want to change it back to the blockwork image in a moment.
And that is being that while it's mapped according to the texture corner of a U V.
Now because we have more than one u v in our scene at the moment I want to make sure that this is more
explicit because at the moment just u v is not enough.
So I'm going to clear and remove it from our scene completely or removed from the node editor completely
and add in an input and if we scroll down we had texture cornet right down at the bottom is you've Emap.
So I'm going to select the movie map.
Um.
To duplicate that because we're going to have one for the normal map and we're going to have one for
the V map.
I'm also going to duplicate the image texture.
So we've got Windows normal here and the chop church block works.
There we go we've got the blockwork back again and I'm going to turn off hello DC for the moment.
I don't need to see it anymore so I'm going to add this movie map to these two here.
Perfect that's exactly what I want see this image.
Texture is being controlled by the normal map so we're going to plug that in.
Won't see anything yet.
It's very tempting of course it has.
Plug them in like vats.
That's going to give us an effect but not the right one.
We need to explicitly convert this into a normal map so let's go to vector and normal map.
And we can plug the colour in to the colour.
And normal in normal.
And there we go it's starting to look much better and we can see there are a few little things that
need tidying up here.
This is horrible.
This line here that doesn't gel with me at all.
Have you got anything else like that.
Not particularly.
Okay so this line here now the question is do we fix it and remake our normal map or can we fix it in
the image editor so let's give a go to the image editor that's zoom in here.
I think we can fix that so I'm going to go right in as close as possible.
And change this to paint mode.
Make that a bit smaller to work with.
Open up the tool shelf and using the colours there the primary colour Im going to pick something purple
and then literally start painting over what we've got here and and make this even smaller go turn accumulate
on so you can go backwards and forwards really quickly.
And as you can see here I am a bit clueless as to how this is going to turn out.
I'm going to assume it's going to come out okay.
I'm going to use the smear now Gia make these bits blend in so it's not so sharp.
Because I'm being careful here not to go over the lines.
I remember as a child shawn's Colour within the lines that they want to break that and the question
is after I save that save it as a window normal that's absolutely fine.
After I save this or I might as well go over that one as well.
So Image save image.
Okay.
The question is does it make a decent impact on here.
The answer is yes it does.
Brilliant.
That looks much much better.
So I'm really happy with that and how that's turned out.
Oh I haven't checked the other side of course.
How does the other side look.
I can't really see the others in the sun.
I'm going to duplicate the sun in this case.
And it doesn't actually matter where it's facing kind of irritates it.
Why 90 right 180.
I'm just going to move this around until you get extra lights.
Let's lock it to the x-axis.
Can we get it on this side as well.
Almost.
So let's see what this looks like on the other side.
Okay.
Yeah that's worked pretty well as well we've got the normal mat being applied across the other side
as well.
It looks a bit odd down here but I will forgive that.
I'm going to make sure that safety.
And of course once I've done that I can hop over into the gothic church and actually see how it's looking
in situ so into the gothic church.
And we've got a couple of windows here.
In fact I think the camera of the last camera of your had yet the switch in rendered mode.
Okay we have a series of them here around the side and I'm going to render that out and see how that
looks.
It's going to take a few moments to do but a rendering is often the best way of seeing how things are
looking.
Okay so this is rendering out one of the first things I can see is a seam joining these together.
It's not that pronounced.
I'm surprised at the I've I've actually given it no consideration.
However some of the more powerful features are standing out quite a lot and that is this area to the
lower left of the window it stands out like a sore thumb and this dark patch here.
It really does stink of repetition essentially now.
I thought this line going down here would be the worst thing completely.
But it turns out that isn't actually the giveaway.
My eye is drawn to this light spots again and again and again and again so that's something I can work
on.
And let's go take a look now and see how it's looking over in a game engine.
Okay so here I am I've not misapplied a texture.
So here I am just walking around in unity.
And we can see that the normal map has applied really well.
Now I did have a few issues trying to get it to actually adhere because it's on the second duvy channel
it doesn't look right.
Unity supports a third TV channel.
I'm open for correction on that.
I'm not a unity expert but here we go.
We've got it a plied to our model and it's looking pretty good considering that is absolutely flat.
That looks like there is detail in the wall.
And again we can see that bright area to the lower left really standing out.
Whether or not we need to do something about that at the moment I'd say no but maybe later on.
How are you guys getting on with your bump maps.
Have you decided that some of your model should be left as just geometry.
Post your results in the discussions.
And as always I will see you in the next lecture.