Welcome to texture resolution.
So in this video you will understand that resolution will control the level of detail at a particular
distance.
We'll go ahead to realize when a texture is ever going to be too large or too small.
We're going to learn about the power of two and wine.
And when it is important so let's go from the bottom up and start with the power of two.
So bit of theory for you all here.
Computers work with binaries zeros and ones a lot of external programs need power off two textures that
is important.
Now they aren't necessary in blender but are a good standard to adhere to especially when working with
external programs and they don't have to be square providing the length of the side is a power of two.
So I've been saying paratroop character in some of you will be scratching your head.
Go Mike.
I kind of get these English words you've put up here but I don't understand what the power of two is.
So which numbers are power of too severe Imagine a rectangle or a square and the length of four sides
there.
So mathematically they'll be two to the power of N..
Or as shown there two to the 5 etc equals thirty two.
So if you've been around computers for a while you recognize this sequence 2 4 8 16 and so on and you'll
notice that's your RAM will fall into those hard drives tend to fall into those lots of different things
fall into these particular numbers.
And this is where we do the power of to see you can have two five six on one length off of side by a
thousand and 24 and another.
Or you can have a thousand and twenty four by a thousand and twenty four and it be square.
Each one of those is okay.
Now it is important that you can't have it here to these standards especially if you want to export
your Textus But there is one critical thing to remember because it's very tempting to say on let's say
your diffuse smap.
I don't need much detail here so I'll make it 32 by 32.
It just needs a slight gradient change that set across it and then you go ahead and use a normal map
let's say or a bump map displacement map to add more detail but you need that super fine detail so you
do to 0 4 8 by 2 4 8.
Now that is great but you're going to have a problem when you come to textures of different sizes.
First of all they need their own you v map that is important.
If you decide to have textures of different sizes within blender they're going to need their own e.v.
Map.
They're probably not going to be exportable even due to the need for multiple UV maps.
Most programs when you import them say you're exporting as an effort because they'll take the primary
the first you've Emap you've created and use that so the other textures.
Obviously if they're a different size they won't match up with your you.
Unwrap it is best to stick to one texture size for any given unwrap.
So if you've unwrapped one particular model and you're going to give that to a 4 8 by 2 4 8 that is
great and you can of course do another model that's not doesn't have to be as detailed and do it 5 hour
by 5 12.
You're going to have to play with these and it does.
There are several things to think about when you're dealing with textures of what size you're going
to require.
I will go on sibor offer in a moment but the important thing to remember here is larger textures require
more memory.
If you had a texture that there is 256 pixels by 256 pixels and one that was 512 by 512 you may think
the difference there is two it's not.
It's quadrupled.
That's going to take up quadruple the amount of space as the two five six one is and so forth as we
go up that number change that we saw a moment ago.
Okay so what size textures and this is a very good question.
It's very tempting to just say you know what I'm going to use the largest size textures I can possibly
use.
Then nothing can go wrong.
Well as you'll learn and develop skills you'll find that you run out of memory very quickly.
If you decide to make the largest possible textures or blender will slow to a crawl or your game won't
work it won't be able to load into the graphics memory.
There's lots of different problems you can come to.
So there are two main components to how large a texture needs to be and they're quite logical when you
think about them.
So first of all how far away is the camera from the object.
Slash the texture that you were using.
Of course camera you can place that with character.
If you were in a game situation.
So if you're looking at a building that's across the street but you're never going to get any closer
to it there's going to be a finite amount of detail that you can actually resolve.
And so there would be no point for instance probably going to eight fouls and it depends on the size
of the objects as well so these two oscillate between one another.
So we do need to be careful.
I was going to say it doesn't matter you shouldn't go for an 8 k texture.
Well actually you might need to if the object is really really big of course then you may split it up
into smaller objects itself.
But for instance kitchen tiles now they're a lot smaller but you get a lot closer to them.
So what we have decided to go for here is thinking about what's that retina texture level.
Now we've all heard of Apple's retina displays where you can't see the pixels.
So we're going for a an utmost upper limits that your texture size would be and things beneath that
would be okay.
So the retina limit is really pushing it because that is when you can no longer see the pixels on your
texture.
In fact after that point you just wasting memory.
So what is the retina texture level.
Will the retina texture works out roughly to be three thousand two hundred sixty six times that tan
of the size over distance.
Now you can actually use Google you can type that into Google and replace size and distance and it will
give you a sort of a texture size as it were that you could use.
And then we need to actually round that up or down to the nearest power of two that would work for it.
Hey it's Michael from the future here and we've had quite a few questions regarding this formula.
Your calculator has been in radians in order for this to work.
If you don't have a calculator that can go into radians or you don't know what that is or how to get
there.
You can use 57 times the tan of the size from a distance and that will work it out.
If you can is in degrees.
And of course there is one final thing here and that we haven't met.
Im actually measured or spoken about and that is the importance of the texture or object.
If it's something that's not really brought into the player's attention or the camera's attention it's
something off to one side it's not the focal point of your scene.
You can probably get away with a lot lower texture quality than otherwise.
And you see this a lot in games where perhaps the scenery is not as textured in certain places as others.
And the characters tend to have a lot more detail in them then perhaps a mug that they're going to pick
up.
You see this all the time and that is important.
You don't want to make something.
Incidental on the side or you might depending on the quality level you're going for but you don't want
something that's incidental on the side.
Having the same sort of quality level as the main object and the main focal point of the scene now obviously
that's that's your discretion whether you go to that level of detail with other objects in your scene
as well.
If you're going for a more photo realistic feel where for instance a mug is completely circular you
can't see any of the jagged edges going around making up that then then that's absolutely fine.
Just bear in mind the higher level of detail the longer you're going to have to be working on that particular
model.
And let's say we do take the mulga example forward.
The last thing you want to do is spend all of your time modelling a mug when you could have been modelling
the main character that everybody's watching says worthwhile.
Bearing that in mind as well.
As with most lectures we've got a challenge.
I would like you to calculate the following.
Now I'm going to be a bit loose on this one and allow you guys to actually pick the size and distance
that some of these objects are going to be from you.
So play with them and see what you come out with.
Remember if you're going to use MM meters kilometres in the case of the moon there remember that the
size and distance have to be in the same units.
Otherwise it's not going to work out.
So balls of video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's go through and fill out this table.
Okay so the first thing the moon has a set things are going to go die and mitts of the moon.
Okay.
So we are going to look this one up.
I don't know zarmina Plock that in the table sets 3 4 7 4.
Okay.
And I'm going to change that to distance.
That's not grammatically correct.
I'm sure Google worked out for me.
So three.
Wow that's a long way away isn't it.
It's going to take us a while to get there.
So now I know that I can actually plonk in my equations that was three to six six times.
Men tan.
I can group that together there and I don't feel fancy the open book open bracket.
I need it here.
So tan and we need to go in and do size over distance.
So that's 3 4 7 4 over.
3 7 0 3 0 0 0.
That'll give us a result of 30.
So there you go.
That is quite low.
So that's going to be 32 by 30 you can actually get away with 32 by 30 to texture.
If you were standing on the planet looking at the moon because it doesn't take up much size just make
sure I got my dimensions the right way round there.
So I've got size over distance so size over distance brilliant case building.
I'm going to pick a hundred meters tall building and I'm going to be stood at a distance of a kilometre
away.
So I'm going to be stood at a foul a thousand meters and 100 meters.
So then we go up and hit the back button here and hopefully know how.
There we go.
I've got my equation so I'll be 100 over a thousand So this is one of these things we can leave open
in a tab here and we get back to it.
So that's 327.
Now this is a good one isn't it.
I've picked something where the power of two is ended up halfway in between.
So I've got to make a decision at this point.
Well not necessarily at this point but I feel at this point whether or not I'm going to get any closer
to the building if I am going to go for five 12 or I could probably get away with 2 5 6.
Remember these are retin-a pixels.
So at this point you as the viewer would not be able to see any of those pixels.
It would be perfectly resolved.
So in that case I'm going to go for two hundred and fifty six.
Okay a kitchen tile.
Well I'm going to do that in centimetres.
I'm going to remember to put my units in here as well that is very important.
Okay so a kitchen tile.
I'm looking at kitchen tiles at the moment and they're about 10 centimetres across.
So 10 centimetres and a distance Well if I was washing up I'm going to be stood roughly about 90 centimetres
away from it.
So I'm up to about a meter depending on where I am going to go for 90 to me.
So I lean forward.
Let's go for 70 centimetres.
I'm picking at a dish from the from the liquid there that's so that's going to be 10.
So I can adjust these figures here 10 over 70.
Okay.
Let's see what we've come up with here.
Okay so that's close to 512 k.
And finally a car well a car is approximately where.
Depends where you are in the world.
I've driven a smart car that's very tiny and I see some American cars like a Humvee or something like
that are huge.
So I'm going to go for a four meter car.
So for me it's a car.
Now if you let's say walking along the pavement then this is the distance thing again.
So the car's never going to be any closer to me than let's say a meter but it's four meters long.
Okay let's see what that works out to us.
So for meters and by a meter.
Okay.
This one ends up very large in fact that is closer to 4 0 9 6 than it is anything else.
So let's bring up my chart here.
Now did any of the shock you.
Did you think for instance that the moon was going to be a lot higher than 32.
By 32 in order to accomplish a sort of retina level that did shock me and the car was particularly high.
I wasn't expecting it to go quite that high.
The building didn't puzzle me too much I thought that would be around sort of 2 5 6 5 12.
I didn't anticipate the kitchen towel being quite the higher thought because it was quite a small object
be able to get away with a lot lower.
Now remember it is very important but these are retina level textures.
You could probably get away with a lot lower than these probably half of these themselves.
I hope that's you found that incredibly useful.
Did you come up with some other size and distances.
Did you come up with some crazy figures and just as a side note here most game engines at the moment
don't support over eight thousand odd by eight thousand odd pixels.
So you can't go much higher than that without causing yourself some memory problems so that's worthwhile.
Bearing that in mind I'd love you to share your results if you came out of anything wacky there.
And I will see you in the next lecture.