Welcome to baking using the multi Rose modifier in this video.
You will learn how to bake detail from the higher multi rays to a lower one and you'll realize it's
very similar to the baking you've done before but this time only one model is involved so we don't have
to have multiple models on there.
So let's go explore this now and hop on over into blender.
Okay if you remember last time we had our multi rez blob.
If you didn't save that don't worry let's go and create a new one right away.
Just a good bit of practice there.
So going to go ahead and delete my object.
There it goes.
Keep the save file there.
I'm going to add in a cube.
I'm going to go to the subdivision's surface had a couple probably three.
That's fine.
Then I'm going to simply go into sculpt mode after I've added in a multi resolution modified so let's
add that in.
I'm going to actually take it all the way up to six which should give me yep three million polygons
to play with that is lots of polygons to lower the preview setting down to 1.
And I'm going to go into sculped and I'm going to add some detail.
Then move the strength of the brush using up so I get some dimples.
Now of course these dimples are the size of them is actually the distance I am.
It's measured in pixels from the image so if I move in I can put smaller dots around.
Now obviously I can go through to my heart's content and make dots and squiggles all over here until
I don't want to do it anymore.
There you go add some fine detail in there as well as just a screen.
It's just the screen looks fine.
Okay so now we've played with VAT's unjust underskirt.
I'm actually going to put a recess in as well because we don't have a recess.
That's quite a big one.
So that's fine let's see how that has come down in the preview So if we go to object mode here we can
see that it has affected the model ever so slightly but not much.
And of course this looks nothing like.
If we go into sculpt mode again it looks nothing like that.
It's close kinda but really nowhere near it.
So we have this here.
When I said it's a smooth shade because it's going to be smooth shaded any way when it's done.
That's important because when we bake the Normal's And that's what we're going to do in a moment.
It needs to be smooth because that's the starlight going for now.
Take note of the render setting here the render setting here is going to say from which level it's going
to bake downwards.
That is very important so that before we can do any baking we need to go and add a material to our object
that material has to have something associated with it.
Um no so see an image with it now so I can bake straight to that image.
Someone I go to image texture and there isn't an image yet so let's go ahead over to the 3D editor and
a hop into edit mode and just un wrap.
I'm going to put my own seam on here.
Let's see where's all the detail.
If I'm going to use v smart you reproject to show you guys what happens hopefully what happens if it
gets it.
If it puts the scenes in the wrong place basically.
So now I've got vats I've unwrapped it.
We can go to the U.S. image editor.
Okay that's looking good.
We need a new image there.
So going to go a new image and I'm going to call this blob.
I'm struggling to see the keyboard here through a microphone but there we go blob.
Normal.
Good.
Keep it a 1 0 2 4 that's sokoban a Selecta.
Over here in the material properties.
So that's now signed.
We can go then go over to the render tab.
Now remember when you do any form of baking or rendering you are rendering and therefore blender can
be unstable and crash.
So we want to avoid that if possible.
Well certainly we want to avoid it crashing but if we can't control that we can control whether or not
we've saved our work.
So I'm going to go ahead and save.
Let's scroll all the way down to the bottom and go to the back options and scroll down a little more
in the back type here.
I'm going to go from combined to normal and I'm going to just go ahead and hit bake now.
It's at a high resolution the six subdivision resolution quite a few polygons there.
And that's going to take a while to go through.
So it's come out here and we can see it's relatively smooth.
Now before we move on I just want to show the impact of lowering this the setting so if I lower it down
to one and then go and bake.
It's a lot quicker but you're losing all of those fine details.
So is that render sitting there that you also need to keep it nice and high if you want to bake from
one level down to another.
In this case we are baking down to where it is actually zero.
So if we go ahead and go back here.
Ake.
It's going to take a while again because it's at that higher level up subdivision.
And here we go.
So we've got these normal map all made and how we can go ahead and apply it to our model.
So I'm going to leave that alone for a moment and then go to the 3D view.
Go to object modes I can see what's going on and I'm going to go to rendered mode.
So this is what happens with seams on here now at the moment.
This isn't very bright.
So I put a sunlamp in and turn it strength up to four.
So we can see here that the we've got some scenes here and the reason why you end up with some nasty
seams.
In fact it looks like it changed the direction of the Normal's there midway through.
Now the reason why these seams exist is because you need to split up the model somewhere to cut it in
half.
But the reason why it can't match them up perfectly is because it's got two different normal points
placed on top of one another.
When you wrap this image together essentially they lay on top of one another.
And of course that can cause an graphical artefact So we'll see those in action in a few moments when
we go and apply this normal map as a normal map rather than a diffused map.
So first of all I'm just going to hide my tool shell from propertys and move across and open up the
node editor so we're going to play with the materials.
Now I'm going to call it cheat hearing them call it efficiency.
We do want the image but we don't want it to control the diffuse colour.
So you can unplug it.
There we go there so that's that bit sorted but we still got the image texture in here.
Now as you remember before what we're going to have to do here is set it up to be a normal.
So we need a couple of other things in this chain.
We need it's Tell blender how to apply this image texture and also that it's a normal map and give it
some control so we can control the strength of the normal map.
And of course that leads me onto a challenge.
I would like you to go ahead and apply the normal map so finish off the node set up and use your baked
normal map to control the normal of the day few shader the normal input of the the few shader pause
video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and apply that normal map.
Okay so the first thing I'm going to do over here is hide.
That's I've got a bit more space to work with.
So we need to define how the image texture is used.
And I'm going to use a texture coordinates and link-up the U V to the vector inputs of the texture.
Now of course you could also use at this point if you have multiple uv's Maps you may have to use this
particular technique.
Now where is it hidden under input you v map.
And we could also do that and select the only you v map we've got in there and plug that in as well.
But I'm going to leave it as a text record and we need to make sure that we're not using colour that
we're using non colour data otherwise the normal map won't be interpreted properly.
Finally what we need to do is add in a vector normal map and then we can take the colour and plug it
into colour.
Colour out of image texture and plug it into the colour input of the normal map and then take the normal
output and plug it into the normal input of the diffuse shader.
Wow okay that's starting to look pretty good.
I'd like to see these two side by side at the end.
But that is really effective.
It's worked really well.
Now where that normal map was a bit funny that's also worked really well.
I mean I'm actually quite surprised that that hasn't decided to look a bit awkward.
We can see that we're working with the low poly model here because of the inclusion You see the jaggedness
around the very edge.
And of course that doesn't actually raise up as high as it would have done otherwise.
Of course we can go ahead here and add in the first level of preview and that really does accentuate
the normal map itself it adds that the geometry in there at the same time as some of these dimples.
But it doesn't give us the smoothness gives us quite jaggedness there.
So we've got two options there of which ones we can use.
I'm going to preview one here so I've got some of these high points that I've done and of course what
we can do is just render that out what we don't know what it looks like at the moment is what it looks
like when it's fully rendered.
So the first thing here is to turn down the render from six.
If we leave on six and then we go and do a full rendering it will just be the high rez model.
I can demonstrate that straightaway by going to the can review and zooming in and that yeah this one's
here is absolutely fine.
Let's try and fill up a good portion of the frame with it.
If we make the black um um just going to do this I love doing this sort of thing I'm going to make the
background completely black.
And then it does look like some sort of funky asteroid in space and I'm just going to go ahead and hit
the render again because I've got the render level set at six.
It's actually going to take a while to do all the computation it needs to do to render out those three
million polygons.
So that's quite a high level and you can appreciate that if this was something you were going to use
in a different package or only part of your scene you probably dont want it that many polygons.
So here we go it's filling out all of these things and we've got a lovely crisp outline here that's
brilliant that we've got that.
But it really comes at a cost that detail comes at a cost.
And here we go looking almost in the centre of this picture.
If you follow my cursor there you can see where there's a seam here.
That's an that's an artefact of where the seam is.
So we can control where seams go and we certainly don't want it there.
That was the bit that was facing the camera some just going to change the render slot slot so.
And I'm going to drop the render level down to 1 so still got some geometry there.
Otherwise it's just the sphere again.
And we do one without the sphere as well that's render that out now and see what that looks like and
you can see immediately how much quicker that was to do the work.
So let's go between the two slots now and just see the difference.
Okay.
There is a difference.
There definitely is a difference.
Now what we can do here of course is potentially turn the amounts of normal map up a little that is
a possibility so we can do that life over here.
I zoom in that we're on preview level 1 let's turn the normal map strength up to two.
Okay.
Now let's render that out at this lower level.
See that is nice and quick as it's lower and we can see that the shadows are darker here.
And if we switch over to slot one to compare okay.
There a little bit too dark in this case.
So once again we got some horrible artefacts going around the top there.
So perhaps this is a bit too low a poly for this particular level of detail so we can up it again and
really for render basically take upper level here and hit render again and see what we get out there.
That is starting to look much better.
Of course we can tweak these things etc. but of course we're now at 12000.
But that is a lot less of course than 3 million.
So it looks like 12000 is going to be the sort of sweet point here before we start having too much detail
in our model but that is looking really really good and obviously compared to the 3 million polygon
one I am going to try here a value a strength of one point five see will that comes out that we use
slot to again and just render that out.
Okay.
I think the shadows here are looking a bit better now so we should be able to compare slot one slot
to yet but very close.
Now in terms of their tonal quality and that is really really impressive.
Now the final thing I want to try is what does this look like when it's baked all the way down to none.
But literally as few faces as possible so this is what this looks like now on just a sphere.
You lose all of the occlusion round the outside but you still got this detail here and that in itself
is very powerful.
Now on a static image like this it doesn't really show off what is really going on.
However if we go to the 3-d view and I go and grab the lamp I'm just going to leave it like this for
the moment on this no subdivision level.
I go and grab the lamp and just randomly rotate it's for.
There we go we can see the shadows are changing.
That in itself is incredibly powerful.
That means that the light hitting that surface is being affected by our normal map.
And there we go.
That looks like the sun or whatever it is if this was an asteroid is pretty low in the sky.
Now of course if we go and select are object that we are working on again and bump that up a couple
of levels we can see that we can still use our normal map to great effect without the normal map turned
out well we can test that we can simply unplug it and you can see immediately the difference.
This is what it looks like without the normal map.
We put that normal map on and boom it suddenly comes alive.
Amazing.
How are you guys getting on.
Did you make a funky shape yourself if you did or you applied this to some other model that you're working
on.
I'd love to see the results you've come up with.
Please share in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.