Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to have a closer look at rendering out an animation into a video format
but making sure that when we render out the animation if it gets interrupted we're safe a blender crashes
or something is just not quite right for parts of your animation you don't have to re render absolutely
everything.
Now with the advent of eevee some might say that's was not important it only takes a couple of minutes
to render out.
Well even with eevee it can still take tens of minutes once you start upping the detail the quality
that's there and when you're using cycles for instance you can easily get into the tens of minutes for
each individual frame of an animation let alone the whole animation itself.
So how do we go ahead and safeguard ourselves.
Let's have a closer look at the rendering settings themselves.
So just like before we're going to have a look in the properties panel here at the outputs I'm happy
with how everything set up.
At the moment I'm going to go to my output tab.
Happy with all of this.
I'm also happy with my sample rate and everything else.
What I want to do is output it in a safe way so if blender crashes if I get a power cuts this will also
lead on to being able to render across multiple instances of Blender.
But first of all let's go down.
We've got our outputs.
I'm going to change that to test two so we can see what's going on.
Now instead of outputting a file format as a video what's we're going to do is output as a series of
images and then combine all of those images into a video later on.
So it's a multi-step process but it's often much much better.
So let's switch this out instead of being an F F MPEG video.
I'm going to go back to PMG.
They're compressed but they're lossless which is great color depth and compression.
RG B and Alpha in terms of all of these three.
I would typically just leave them as they are.
There's no real reason at the moment to change any of that out and we don't need to do anything else
but what we will do is have a look at this folder in a few moments.
And for the sake of brevity what's I'm going to do is actually lower this back down to maybe 33 percent
or something along those lines.
So it's nice and quick as it comes out.
I'm just going to go ahead now and make sure I've got this area loaded up.
There we go.
That's perfect.
Now what happens when we go ahead and render render our animation.
So it should be a lot quicker than it was before.
And when we go ahead of head here and have a look.
Oh did I really want to do that.
That will do for the moment but next time let's actually make a folder rather than just give it a new
name.
Whoops I forgot the backslash there but we'll let it run and then we'll move it in a moment.
And as you can see here what it's doing is it's outputting each individual frame as an image.
And this is great because what we can do in the moment I will put them all into one folder but we can
go and grab all of those images put them into the built in video editor with In blender and once that's
done we're laughing because we can just render out but there are a couple of gotchas.
And of course we'll cover that as we get to that point.
So you've probably only got a few minutes left.
Let's have a look.
Scroll down we're on 97 98.
So we're about halfway there at the moment.
I'll be back in a few moments.
OK.
Brilliant.
That's the last frame rendered out.
Now as I mentioned before there are a couple of other things I might want to fix on these and this is
the great thing if I decide that bounce at the end let's just load one of these up quickly and move
it into the right place so you guys can see it's what we will see here is the lamp itself is in the
floor.
Now the great thing about this is I don't need to re render the rest of my video I can just find a frame
before we go to the floor so probably one of one of the ones around here around lamp 1 6 4.
Yeah.
One of these ones around 150.
Yeah it looks like around here where it hits the ground.
So around 150 if we rendered from there onwards with the new positions it should be pretty good.
Of course we need to make sure that everything before that doesn't get altered.
But that's just one example how rendering out in these individual frames you're able to make edits as
well.
In the future anyway.
Let's go back from here we've finished rendering that out.
That's all well and good.
What we now need to do is switch our view.
We're going to go over to the plus at the very end.
Click the plus button here.
Go down to the video editing workspaces and go to video editing.
It will change the view ever so slightly.
Completely new to you.
So this is gonna be a bit of monkey see monkey do to make sure that you can follow along with what's
going on.
So we need to add into our new timeline into our sequencer at the bottom.
We need to add in our pictures essentially.
So I'm going to make sure that I go back to the first frame because this will have the same number of
frames as our animation did 200 and then I'm going to go ahead and add we're going to add an image slash
sequence.
That's the important thing because it's a sequence of images.
At this point we need to find where it is.
So in this particular case I'm going to have to go up a couple of times and then back down into videos.
Excellent.
So here are all of the frames.
Now I did say I was gonna put it in one folder that would be helpful here if there were other things.
But fortunately for us in this particular instance all of these images are the only things in this folder
that is a video.
The previous video we did but we're currently looking specifically at images and nothing else.
Now this file browser that's built into blender is not your typical file browser you can't just hold
down shift and select the first and last one.
But in this particular case what I can do is press a to select everything that's there and then just
add the image strip.
So in general I would make sure that you output into an individual folder so that isn't an issue in
this case it was absolutely fine anyway.
And there we go.
That's the main thing we need to have done that.
Now that we have this loaded and ready to go what we can now do is go to render this out again.
And of course we need to change our render settings is gonna be a bit tight at the top here but the
output will scroll down a little bit further.
We've got our test to output here.
This is where we can switch it back to the FFR MPEG video.
It's not remembered our previous settings so we can come here empty for and we're not going to fiddle
with the video settings itself.
Okay so now that we've got everything here it's not going to work straight away and there's a couple
of reasons for that but if we go off to render and render animation we're gonna get a couple of issues.
The first one here is the border rendering is not supported by sequence it's just hidden at the very
bottom here.
If I shift this up to see the error properly.
Nope it's just gone as I went to show a border rendering is not supported by the sequencer.
Now if we go to our properties panel over here what that simply means is we've got render region ticked.
So I'm going to unpick that and when we go back to render again and when we render animation we get
another era which is not divisible by two.
So we cannot just output the video like this.
I know it sounds really weird that we can't do this when we could before but that's simply because of
the settings we've got here.
So I'm going to set that 50 percent of 10 ATP and go ahead and render the animation.
And now because we're reading from those images look how much quicker that happens to be always simply
doing at this moment in time is putting all of those images into video format and that's essentially
all a video is anyway so let's go and have a look about output render Okay so we're in the right folder
at the moment.
Here's our lamp 180 test to see the one we've just made.
As you can see here is rented out incredibly quickly and by some rough and ready.
So that's the way of making sure that when you render out your lamps that you're able to do it just
by images.
It's far better doing it this way especially when your render times are long but in general this those
few extra steps of combining it together is well worth just going ahead and doing it this way from the
very beginning.
That's my general tip there.
Now personally what I will do is I tend to render out directly to a video when it's something really
quick and short.
So we're even able to pretty much output it in real time.
That's fine.
Anything longer than that it's worth the effort.
Just outputting to images and certainly for me because I often take the employment of another computer
or two in the house in order to render them out because they often take quite a few minutes per frame
and that is the topic of the next lecture.
So if you've got more than one computer there's some top tips coming up.
And one thing before I go because I didn't want to miss this out.
If you happen to have something loaded into your timeline and then you're going back to layout and you
go to render render animation you'll have it rendering out the timeline.
It's something that catches a load of people out.
So the easiest thing of course to leap delete those images from the sequencer view.
So if we go back to video editing we can just delete this clip and then we'll go back to rendering out
the animation.
That's absolutely fine.
They'll certainly catch you out at some point if you haven't seen it before.
OK.
So that's pretty much everything I wanted to cover in this particular lecture.
In general what I would do is if it's a small render that your output is something like Facebook and
it is pretty much real time to render out then just go ahead output it directly to video for anything
more intensive especially those that are taking a minute or two per frame which does sound like a lot.
But if you want a really crisp image you often do have to render for multiple minutes especially with
cycles on a dark scene like we've got in front of us.
Now this is also going to pave the way for using multiple computers because that's what I would do is
I would employ the other computers in my household in order to do some rendering and we'll talk all
about that in the next lecture.
See you there.