Hello everybody and welcome to this lecture.
We are going to learn a couple of things first of all that you can merge vertices together this was
once four vertices at the top and now it is one vertex and you can see it's linked to all of the ones
underneath.
The other thing that we will learn is how to select things and make things individual i.e. unlinked
or have the mesh linked together so that we can select everything at once.
All things individually and we will delve into some of the reasons why you may want something separated
like that or as one solid mesh.
So let's go find out more Okay everybody Welcome to the default blend scene.
I'm going to go straight into edit mode and select these top vertices to make sure that I've got border
select turned on I'm going to select everything and you can do that in two ways you can double press
the A key and a will obviously select everything if you want to d select rather than selecting all you
can use alternate I'm going to then use the border select tool that's already enabled and just select
these top vertices.
Now you may have already experienced this.
You can scale that down to zero.
And when you do that you get a single point at the top that immediately you can start moving around
and you may think at this point it has collapsed all of those four vertices down into one.
I'm afraid you would be wrong if I was to just then click to select a vertex you can see that that's
not the case we've got one two three and this fourth one so far.
Undo all of that stretching about how do we merge these all together.
Well there are a couple ways of doing it and there are reasons why you may or may not want to do it
as well.
So the first one why you might not want to do it well in this case I can't think of a very good reason
because they're all in one individual place.
However if you've got separate paths that a co-exist in the same place that's when you may want to keep
it the same and I'll show you an example in a few moments.
Now you think we'd be able to just draw a border around to select all of those vertices.
Unfortunately that doesn't work.
Can you hold down shift and keep selecting.
No that doesn't work either.
The reason for that is because geometry is on top of itself and it can be very frustrating and difficult
when that happens.
How do we select everything that's here.
Well there are a couple of ways we can put our view into wireframe mode which is the first one along
here that when we draw a border around we see that the four edges connected to that have starts become
highlighted and we can go back to solid mode and then manipulate it all together.
We can see that's there.
Alternatively what we could have done is click this show whole scene transparent next to the shading
options if we turn that's on then I can do exactly the same thing and I can turn that off again.
That may be more useful if you if you need the context of shape because the moment you switch the wireframe
mode it can get a bit iffy as to where things are I'm going to turn that back off again because it's
very easy to leave it on and end up selecting through a model when you don't want to do that.
So now I've got all of those vertices selected.
How do I saw that.
How how do we keep it in one place.
The first way is go into the vertex menu at the top and going to merge vertices.
Now you see here it's got a shortcut key as well.
An M.
Now what it will do is it will collapse all of those vertices at the center of them all.
So if I was to go out and am because they exist in the same place we get an option here at Center at
cursor and collapse.
Now I'm going to choose at center in this case.
And there we go.
It's all merged down into one.
And if you weren't sure you can glance down at the lower right notice it says here we got the cube which
is the objects we're working on.
The vertices one is selected out of five.
If I undo what we've just done it was for I selected out of eight.
So going alternate M and at center has done that.
Now you may be thinking and you'd be right thinking this if we go all the way back.
If I can with my undo levels.
Nope.
If we go ahead and just load up out the false scene again go into edit mode clearer selection and select
the top slots and then merge them at center.
We had it got to the same point much much quicker so you can see sometimes.
Whereas you would have taken two or three steps to get there.
You can actually do the same thing in one step if that was the shape you were trying to create ultimately
with this top vertex all connected.
The other thing that you can do is if you had scaled it down by zero is you can select everything in
your scene press F three to search and then tie pin remove and doubles.
You can also type in doubles and it would have probably found it quicker.
And then we can see down at the bottom right is removed three vertices and we're back down to having
five in total.
In our scene
Hey guys Mark here are an update to select here for those using newer version than Mikey remove doubles
has been renamed merged by distance and the menu is slightly changed the old remove doubles option that
used to reside under the merge vertices menu now sits within its southern menu and is named by distance
this has also been renamed in the search box with the f k and is now found by typing merge by distance.
Or you can just type merge so any time Mikey refers to and remove doubles.
Just search will use the alternative menu to make a so the final thing to discuss is where and when
and why would you want to do that.
Well for a start if you with 3D printing something or exporting this elsewhere or just following good
practice it's a good idea to have topology where your vertices edges and faces are.
That makes sense and having 4 groups at the very top of our pyramid makes no sense whatsoever.
While some here by the way I'm just gonna call this pyramid is always a good idea to name your objects
early on rather than forgetting about it and getting in a pickle later.
There are some cases however where you don't want things linked together.
So if I go ahead and shift this entire object up by 1 so it's on the 0 plain.
Excellent.
Okay.
And then I'm going to add another primitive into this mesh object so I'm going to add a cube bits of
mesh data into our pyramid mesh objects.
I'm gonna move it down by minus one.
And there we go.
Now we may want to keep these two bits of mesh data separate from one another so that this vertex in
the corner is separate from the other vertex which is part of our pyramid at the top.
Our good reason for this is if I had different materials or you wanted to apply different properties
to each individual section there is a point at which you'd make them completely separate mesh objects
as well.
Bear that in mind both are all part of a one mesh object.
You can also do really cool things like in this case I'm going to have a face select enables is nice
and easy to do if I just press the L key it selects all linked mesh data with the face that my cursor
was over the same if I go to the very top and this can make selecting parts of an object really really
easy whereas otherwise it could have been really painful to do and I can do shift and L to D select
those groupings as well so that's a really useful way of selecting large parts of your objects at one
go and of course finally if we did want all of these to become one mesh objects I can select all and
remove doubles notice that I remembered my last search very useful and that will remove the four that
are in the middle.
Now if we didn't want to do that because we've got other doubles in our scene that we do want to keep.
I'm just going to undo what we did.
I'm going to d select everything I'm going to turn on transparency and just select those individual
vertices that I want select making sure I'm on vertex selecting modes I'm going to clear my selection
again select all of those.
Now I know that they're all selected then go to our menu and this time just remove double vertices and
there we go those individual ones have gone perfect and now it's time for your challenge.
Okay so your challenge delete a cube.
Yes we're finally getting rid of that the fault cube and working with something else at a u v sphere
with 16 segments and eight rings in order to specify that you will need to have your operator panel
open after you've added the movie sphere and then I'd like you to delete the lower half the sphere to
make it a dome.
Now it's easy to do this if you've gone around into one of the side views and with wireframe or transparency
on selected the vertices you want to delete then go ahead and add a cylinder was 16 vertices and again
you're going to need the operator panel to do that.
Now once you've gone ahead and done that place the dome on top of the cylinder or the cylinder underneath
the dome they should align perfectly and finally have your new tower set where z equals zero.
So on that ground plane as we discussed before you could even add a plane there if you want for reference
and let's give you a quick idea of what it should look like at the end.
So here we go here's our domed tower and if I go into edit mode because see we have our 16 segments
and 16 vertices around our cylinder aligning perfectly half your new tower set where z equals zero.
So on that virtual ground plane if you want to add a plane there and call it ground feel free to do
so.
And no double vertices.
So where the Dome and the cylinder join you need to remove those doubled vertices and before I tell
you to pause the video let's have a look.
This is what we're aiming for by the end of the challenge.
So we've got a nice dome on top of a cylinder and as we can see here one final thing.
If you haven't named it it's still called sphere.
Make sure you go ahead and name that something like domed tower so that you know that you've named things
as you've gone along.
There we go.
That's all sorted.
I'm going to save my work and now pulls video and give that a go Hey guys.
Mark here with just a little reminder don't forget did this in edit mode not object mode.
Back to Mikey Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and make this domed tower okay.
So here we go.
Let's delete our cube and add in a U V sphere.
I'm going to open up b operates a panel and set that at 16 and 8.
Oh my number pad was turned off.
Here we go.
Sixteen an eight.
And there we go.
I'm going to look at it from the side.
Make it transparent D select everything and just select these bottom vertices I want to select the middle
ones because if I did that they would disappear as well and I deleted vertices.
So there we go we've got a basic dome pretty good so far.
And now I'm going to add in a cylinder.
There we go with 16 vertices so what we should find as they line up perfectly with the segments and
we'll go GZ minus one effects and that starts to look really neat.
The other thing we need to make sure here and I'm going to look at it from the side again is making
sure that this middle selection I'm going to go to vertex and remove double vertices or root the 16
around the edge there.
The final thing for me to do is go GZ too.
Oh no.
Was it just one.
There we go.
I must have hit three instead.
My apologies.
And there we go the dome is sat on the surface perfect.
And there we go we've got Aunt domed tower.
Now did you create this a different way.
Did you get stuck at any part as we were going through.
Remember if you do get stuck to reach out either on the discussions or in the Q and A so we can lend
a hand.
Now even though this is a simple dome tower you can see this might be the start of something much more
interesting perhaps a silo a farm an engine for a jumbo jet or the nose cone of a plane or a rocket.
There are so many things that this could start to become.
I'm starting to get quite excited here thinking about what we can make this into but as you can see
we've now started to hone the skills of putting different mesh objects together and getting to grips
with these segments of the sphere and the vertices of the cylinder.
They are lined perfectly and allow us to create really neat objects like this.
Remember to share your work over in these discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.