Hello again and welcome.
I think it's important that if we're talking about sculpting we have at least one go at sculpting a
human head.
So this is no this is not the output of meat sculpting a human head.
We can do a little bit better than that.
This is me getting myself set up ready so we can sculpt the human head.
We're going to bring in some reference images and I'm just going to do a little bit of scribbling on
here with the grease pencil so that I've got some starting reference points on how to go about shaping
my head.
I'm going to say thank you to Frank and Caterpillar.
He served as purpose of allowing me just to play around with the sculpting tools and to start a new
file so file new and this will be sculpting.
This brings us into a sculpting view.
You can see we've got mirroring on already as we move out mouse around and you can see we've got a ball.
If I click on wire mesh molding see it's got lots and lots of detail in there.
And as I move around we've got mirroring set already which is super if I wanted to look had that kind
of studio Clay type look then which I do I'm going to go up to my shading click on the arrow next to
shading to the right of that make sure I'm selected on match cap.
Click on the ball.
And from here I can select a different look.
I'm going to select this kind of red clay type look.
That's the traditional look when we're doing this sort of modelling.
And then as I model here.
Yep.
Hey presto.
Wonderful.
Now I find it really challenging just to kind of start going for it and to turn this into a head.
I need some reference I need to make some notes on what I'm doing here.
So let's go through that process together and I'll give this to you straight up as a challenge.
The challenge is to grab some reference images so you get an image for the front view and side view
of a human head.
I will share the ones that I'm using this somewhat dubious ones that I'm using for this lecture I'll
share that with you so you can use that if you want.
Otherwise find your own and set them up either on your second monitor if you've got one or on a tablet
or a phone or as I'm going to show you a separate window in Blender which I think works quite well for
what we're doing.
I'm sharing the challenge with you now so you can do that as we're going through this process do that
as at your leisure.
OK.
So what we need to do first of all is go to edit preferences.
Look at our add ons selected add on and make sure that we have images.
So import images as planes selected.
Yes.
And then to save that as we've done before save preferences.
Excellent.
Now what that will allow me to do is jump up into file import images as planes.
When I do that it will ask me to find where these images are and like I said before somewhat dodgy looking
character I can I can use as my images here at the front view first.
You can see we have highlighted when it changed the name of that now because often forget to change
the name or call this flat.
Nice and clear.
I will hit G and then Z to move it up out of the way and then are on the x axis and 90 to rotate it
but we don't see anything that's a bit of a bummer.
Well if I click on the next view along viewport shading now I can see it.
However I've lost my nifty color ization because the cut the colonization was in solid mode so it will
deal with that in a moment first of all I'll bring in the side view file import images as planes navigate
g I'm gonna x to pop to the side a little bit.
G z move it up R to rotate X axis and then 90.
Okay I have my two images what I'll do is I'll just arrange them side by side grab the first image which
I called front and put it just let's see maybe above just above the side image.
Excellent.
And then let's find the side image and I'm just going to rename this to these.
I'd good naming is handy now so that it plays nicely we can jump up into the very left corner where
you see a little crosshair thing change it's underneath the blender symbol changes to be a crosshair
bring that in BPP poop from left to right.
Okay.
It's already if I slide it a long way it's already in the material preview which is great.
I can see my images there.
I'm going to select one of them and then hit period on the keyboard or full stop as the case might be
just to zoom in on it and then I can position that exactly where maybe I mean a little bit closer.
There we go.
So we've got that fine fellow.
Now back over into my main window I'm going to click back on my solid shading and I can see I'm going
to be a little bit distracted by these just behind me so I'll move those over to the left oriented from
the front.
Zoom in get a position where I want it to be.
There we go.
Then we've got ahead.
Okay.
And now in this view those guys aren't getting in the way.
So if you have a second monitor obviously you just pop it on the second monitor.
But I know a lot of people don't so I like this workflow I can see it right there.
I guess the other thing that I like to do is just at the very start is to draw a little bit of detail
on my my head here because as I'm rotating around I want to know exactly where the front of it is.
That gets a little bit challenging as you do that on like where where exactly is the front.
Oh you know I need to go back from object mode or select my rename this to be head actually and then
jump back over into sculpt mode.
I just quickly want to show you a technique you may or may not want to use this but I'll show you this
technique of using the grease pencil just to put a few annotations onto your head here.
I'm gonna jump back out of sculpt mode into object mode.
Hit shift a fine grease pencil add in blank and you can see we've now got the little squiggly lines
with the grease pencil settings I need to come back over into draw mode and in draw mode I can draw
on the screen.
Excellent.
When I do that you can see it's going right through the middle of my object which is not precisely what
I want.
So up in the middle of the screen you can see where it says Origin instead of origin I'd like for that
to be surface and so that it's not going through the surface of I draw right now you can see it kind
of gets eaten up a little bit by the object which is not what I want.
So within service I'm going to push that out point 0 5 I think should be pretty good now when I draw.
You can see it's being pushed out a little bit off the surface of the object.
So undo that.
Now what I'm going to do is just say well roughly where's the middle of my face going to be.
I think it's gonna be a roundabout here.
Where's the center line going to be is Gary a round about there where do I want the eyes to be.
Probably generally in this position looking at the beady eyes on my reference and then the nose that
big old nose is going to be somewhere in here and then we've got a mouth just in there and then the
shape of the head needs to be a little bit square a little bit more popped up at the top there.
Nice bold kind of head.
So this isn't I'm not trying to get this precise.
This is not exact it's just giving me a little bit of an early indication of the shape so I know then
what to stop pulling.
I think this is great particularly when you're learning the tools and you're not super comfortable or
familiar with how to pull and stretch and push.
I think this is a good way to say okay that's the shape I'm going for.
You can see it's not too bad it doesn't matter it's a little bit wonky around the side there and we
have our object ready to go.
This is basically saying you are ready to sculpt me.
So that's all I wanted to do in this video just get ourselves ready to sculpt so we can be sculpting
our head in the next video.
See you in the next video.