Hello everybody and well done you have completed this section of course it's been quite a big section
and what you guys have shown me so far.
Absolutely phenomenal.
Thank you very much for sharing your work.
Now what I will say is if you're one of those people who's been waiting to perhaps more of the end so
you've got more of a finished product to show off now would be a great time to do so.
I'm really looking forward to jumping into the next lecture with you rather the next section where we're
going to start making game assets.
We've had a taste in this section at the very end we've made our model compatible with a game engine
in the next section that's all about game assets themselves.
And I'll see you all over in that next section.
Take care.