Congratulations you have now completed this section.
The game ascent pack.
Now there's still lots lots more that you can do to reapply the knowledge you've just learned.
And I suggest that is one of the things you do almost immediately is jump straight in and do a another
asset.
Now I must impress.
Make sure that you make your challenges as small and succinct as possible.
To make things that are simple to make.
I know we all want to jam now and make a spaceship or make an aircraft or make a fast car.
I mean all of these things are noble goals.
However they are monumental.
A car is made up of what.
Oh hundreds of pieces.
So you don't want to start with something that's made up of hundreds of pieces.
Start with things that are made up of one maybe even two or three pieces at most and see if you can
get those imported into your assets and that is one of the best things to do with any modelling as you
develop your skills is to make sure you can actually achieve your goals in the first place.
So congratulations on getting this far.
So of course after this we're moving on shortly to modelling a human head.
So if you feel that you've absolutely mastered everything in this section and if you say yes immediately
you're an absolute pro.
If you're saying yes otherwise then perhaps you've got to go back and try some of things.
And of course don't forget you could go back to some of the earliest sections of the course and reapply
your knowledge.
A lot of the time we find that students that have done that have learnt even more because they're no
longer thinking about the lessons they were taught in taught in that particular lecture.
They're actually now focussed on other more advanced things and work out different ways of doing things
with simple models.
We were doing early on in the course.
Now of course once you're ready hop straight back into blender get onto the next section and carry straight
on and I will see you in that next section.
Take care.