Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to talk about extracting extraditing is a novel way of creating additional
geometry in your objects.
Here we can see a very basic church like building and these very very straightforward to put together
through simple extrusion and also building upon everything else we've learned so far.
So let's go find out more and hop on over into blender.
Hello everybody and welcome.
So let's talk about extrusion.
Now you can extrude vertices edges and faces.
We'll start off with faces.
So I go ahead here and hit the tab key to go into edit mode what we can do is making sure I'm going
to select all of these for the moment so I can just select each one individually to demonstrate.
If I go ahead and select the vertex and press the key it generates an edge.
But this is what we call loose geometry.
It doesn't actually form a face.
And this can cause problems if it's not kept under control.
If you ever think you might have loose geometry like this which does tend to happen if you're working
on more complex models what you can do is select everything Go F three to search and type pin loose.
And one of the options will be to select a loose geometry which identifies it here.
Hey guy you might have noticed that there's a bit of a difference when Mikey used the F3 menu to bring
up select news geometry.
It didn't actually work for you ask because the actual geometry is still connected to this to see if
we were to extrude this second that C and removed the now central that C by deleting with the leak case.
And that's C..
Now we have a lose that C..
So when we go to F3 and select to use loose geometry then we'll see that that vertices.
Ultimately though if we delete that vertices array throughout this from the key as we had before and
select all go into A3 and delete loops it will still delete that vertices as if it's loose geometry.
So something to watch out for when you get to this lecture.
The other thing we can do here is if we go back to searching for loose is the least loose geometry and
get rid of that.
So you may think that's extruded a vertex is not useful then.
Well it is.
Let me show you how so we can go ahead and let's say look at our model from the top extrude.
So that say over here extrude again to over there and then extrude again so we're close to this individual
vertex.
Now it's tempting to then link these together maybe snap them in the same place and merge the vertex
and at that point you may think Ah I can fill in the gap between those two.
See.
Press escape to stop but you still have a duplicate vertex there.
It's very easy to get caught out of that.
If I press the GK You will see that it is in fact still there.
So I look at press X and delete that Vertex are going to select this new vertex here make sure it is
by itself and then shift select this vertex here and press F to fill in select the other two vertices
and press F and we filled in a new face.
Okay so let's move on to edges.
Then I can go ahead and select an edge and extrude that and that will generate a new face.
So what happens when you extrude a whole face then.
Well what will happen there is we will end up with some new edges and a new face appearing from its
pretty cool high.
This is an incredibly useful technique for building up a block model of whatever you are trying to make.
I'm not sure what this is here.
It started off looking like some sort of tents or shelter but this could quite easily be the floor plan
to a building or an area that you want to create perhaps.
This is a factory and this is a filling station or whatever it happens to be.
You can very quickly block out an idea without having to worry too much about putting things together
appropriately you're just blocking something out at this time.
And that's essentially how I made the church at the very beginning.
And a lot of models will start off like this even if later on they end up with hundreds of details on
them.
So this if you will is like sketching.
But in three days.
And with that comes your challenge.
Okay so your challenge use extracting to create a simple building you can use any of the other techniques
learned so far as well so it's not just excreting use everything you've learned so far.
Now don't focus on realism We're focused at the moment on just a representation very much like the background
that you can see here very much like the church you saw earlier as well.
It's just a representation a 3D sketch of an object used some reference material.
That's something that people tend to forget if you are unsure if you want to go Oh I fancy making a
bomb.
Well Google a bomb.
Look at the images there and then just make a rough outline a representation of that building.
Now you can pick any building you like pulls a video now and give that a go.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and make a simple building okay.
So we're over in Blender now and I'm going to create a couple of simple buildings because I want to
really just make a very basic one and show you guys how I would do that and then move on from there.
So I'm going to go into edit mode here and lift it up by one unit.
I'm going to grab the face at the end.
It's going to make sure that I've got all of these selected and I'm going to go g x two.
So you end up with a shape like that.
I'm going to grab this top face should that be selected this I'm going to grab this top face and extrude
up by hitting the right key.
Apologies I've clicked the wrong key there.
Let's try the OECD.
Lift it up slightly and I'm going to scale that but lock that scale to just the Y axis to zero.
And there we go we go off first house almost.
I'm going to go whilst those are all selected vertex and remove double vertices.
So we know that the roof is sorted and I'm going to go over and make sure I've named my objects so easy
to forget what you're working on.
So that's my basic house.
I'm going to come out of there and go Gee y and just shift it over there for the moment and then I'm
going to add a new mesh object.
I'm going to start again with a cube.
This time I'm going to make the church that you guys saw earlier.
I don't go into edit mode lift the whole mesh up and I'm going to play with the cube here and I'm going
to think carefully about where I want things to be.
So this part here is the tower I can extrude that up I can extrude it again and scale it by 0 or as
we learned earlier.
I'm going to go controlling Z on that and just go Alton am emerge at the center.
So there we go.
There's a nice tower that we've got there.
And then I can go ahead press E. and extrude along here.
E to extrude out here and then it's just a matter of lifting these two up to various heights that different
from one another.
And then we should be able to on the y axis here and on the x axis here.
So it's going to scale X sorry y 0.
And whilst those two are selected I'm going to go to vertex and remove double vertices which is good.
Then this face at the top here scale x 0 move in together.
And there we go we've got a representation of a church and that's probably pretty accurate compared
to the house next to it.
Okay.
So there we go.
Those are my two models.
The one thing I haven't done before song goes are my.
You forgot to name something.
There we go.
We've got the church and the House named appropriately.
Brilliant.
How did you guys get on.
What did you end up making please do share your work over and discussions.
I'm looking forward to seeing you develop now because we're starting to get things that look pretty
decent.
Do share them over on the forum and I'll see you all in the next lecture.