Hello everybody and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to do a couple of things.
The first thing is create a place holder for our image so we can scale our image appropriately.
Once we've done that you can also see over on the side here we've made a note that we can refer to all
the time rather than having to hop in and out of blender to another place.
So let's go find out more.
OK so this is where we left off before and what we need to do is make sure that we've got something
that says actually squash this reference image into.
So actually is the right size so we can start using it as proper reference material.
Now arguably at this point in time you could just leave it as it is and then scale everything at the
very end.
But I like doing things this way round.
So that's the way we're doing it today.
So the first thing I'm going to do is use my cube and rename my cube to place holder and the whole point
of this is it's going to represent our pin in its simplest possible form if there's going to be a bounding
box to make sure that our pin ends up the right size.
Now first of all this cube is two meters by two meters by two meters.
And that's the wrong size.
We need the right size.
And what I'm gonna do is I'm going to bring in my notes that I've got from elsewhere.
So I'm going to change my editor type in the outline.
It doesn't matter where you do this you could do it elsewhere you create a new window if you wanted
to.
In this case I'm just going to change it from the outline to a text editor.
You can see the shortcut keys there shift F 11 if I wanted to and it will change it to a text editor.
Now I'm going to scroll along here and click new.
Now this is a good tip for you.
If for some reason you are working in the text window or any other window and you can't see parts of
the header you can use your scroll wheels go backwards and forwards as well as of course making the
whole window larger and smaller.
I'm just going to scroll along hearing press knew it's going to create a new bit of text.
I can name that text file like any other objects in blender.
I can name its pin specs or something along those lines.
Now with my cursor in here I can start typing.
If you move your cursor elsewhere it will stop typing in the text box.
Now I've already got in my pace buffer the actual specs of our pens.
Now what we can do is use this and go back and forwards to this whenever I need any reference material
either within blender.
Any text information.
Now this is also useful if you need to make notes about your models you can store them within blender
themselves so you don't have to refer to external files all the time that can be very confusing.
One thing that you may have to do is if you have a look here there are a couple of different options
it's got formatting of numbers and text.
That's good if you're doing some coding within blender as you can see here our text just keeps on going.
So this middle one here will automatically wrap the text along which is pretty useful.
I'm just going to save my file as I am at the moment so I know that we're ready to work.
OK so we've got all of our information and we need to adjust this cube so it's the correct size.
And I'm going to do a couple of things here and this is hopefully going to show you can do things various
ways when it comes to these fields within blender so if this transform window is not here you need to
make sure you're over the 3-D Ed window and press the end key if you do that.
This properties window will come up and I've also got my cube selected not the empty but the cube itself.
You'll notice that these have different things with in them depending on what type of object is selected.
Most notably is dimensions when it comes to a mesh object.
So what I'm gonna do here is I'm going to go to these dimensions and actually type in what we need.
So it's going to be 380 millimeters to remember I'm working in metric.
If you're working in imperial units use the inches.
So I'm gonna go to my Z which is the vertical component of our model and type in 380 millimeters.
So even though that I'm working in meters I can still type millimeters in here and it will also formats
and we've got 121 whites some can go into here and go 1 2 1 millimeters and that's worked.
Now you may notice that the scale has changed so that's something that we will need to apply go control
at a and apply the scale.
Now the next thing that you may notice is that this is not sat on where z equals zero.
There are a couple of ways that we can go around sorting that out.
The easiest way at the moment is just thinking that the middle where the origin of our object is is
halfway up the total height and we've already got the total height over here.
So I'm going to copy that information highlighting it go control C go to its location and paste that
in but then go divided by two and if you do that you can do mathematical calculations inside these fields.
That is really useful.
So if you're not quite sure what one number take another actually is you don't have to go outside of
blender you can literally type the equation or the maths in any of these fields and it's not just simple
addition multiplication you can also use trigonometry etc. and we might get to that later on in the
course.
Okay so now we've got our a place holder object in the correct place and it's the correct scale.
It's just a matter of tweaking our outer objects in this case our pin to the appropriate size.
And yes that's going to be your challenge.
Okay see your challenge.
Pretty straightforward is the set your reference image to the right size at the moment is probably far
too large.
And remember you can use pivot points to help you with where things are scaling supposedly.
Now and give that a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go to our reference image to the correct size.
Okay so you'd like me might have a reference image is too small or in this case too large.
I'm going to just scale this down to begin with to some sense of scale.
So it's roughly right.
Okay that's looking good.
Now the origin of this is going to be once everything's in the correct location at the same place as
the other one which was point one 9 I remember that.
So there we go.
So that's everything set there and then I'm just going to scale this down until hopefully it fits into
the right place.
Boom.
That's pretty much close together.
So that's one way of going about this.
Now I'm going to just undo everything I've done and just approach it in a different way.
So another way that you might approach this is setting your pivot points to the 3d cursor so we can
scale in towards it which is fine.
But as you start getting closer and closer what we then can do is go GZ lift this up so that it is sitting
roughly on the floor because we are dealing with roughly and to be quite honest if you've had to zoom
in this close to adjust something then you've probably gone over the top so class me as going in and
over the top.
There we go.
So now that it's on the bottom that was scaling it so we can then just scale it back down and roughly
fits it into the right place.
Again you can come in and you can tweak it but to be quite honest that's pretty much spot on that's
exactly what I want.
Now you may notice here as you've done this and you're now aligning IT to a real world objects the center
of our objects is a bit off.
So perhaps we need to rotate its ever so slightly around as well because it's not center aligned you
can see that's at the top here is definitely leant over to one side often goes.
Okay.
So you can definitely align that much better than it was before.
And this is something you've got to bear in mind.
Sometimes your reference material will be slightly wonky.
Is that fine.
Yes of course it is.
Because it's just reference material we're not going to copy this exactly we're going to use it as a
basis for everything else that we're doing.
Okay.
So I'm going to save my work there Brian.
That's all aligned and ready to work with and we can start playing with curves and that will be over
in the next lecture.