Hello everybody.
By the end of this lecture we're going to learn how to move rotate and scale any object within blender.
And it's not just useful for mesh objects like this but we can also have fun with lights in scenes as
well.
Of course this will come much later on in the course when we start rendering out our models.
Let's find out more and hop on over into blender OK.
So we are over in the default blend file at the moment.
If you're not here, you've been playing around you can get back to here by going to file new and going
to general and you'll get a scene very much like this.
So we're talking about transforms in this lecture and transforms are key.
They allow us to move things around they allow us to scale things make them bigger and smaller.
And they also allow us to rotate them and that is really really paramount and useful when you're working
within the 3D editor because you need to be able to do these things.
They also apply elsewhere in Blender as well which can be really useful with the shortcut keys remain
the same.
So the first place I want to draw your attention to is the left hand side of the screen.
We have a toolbar on the left hand side of the screen.
If you don't see it you can use the shortcut key T to make it appear and there's also little arrow of
you look there in the top left that you can open up.
Now the second group of icons relates to transforming.
You can turn on a couple of widgets that will appear on the screen.
So we've got move rotate and scale.
And we've also got a widget that does all three.
So if we enable that we've see that suddenly our cube ends up with these control points around it.
Now noticed that they're color coded as well the color coded in green blue and red representing X Y
and Z Y being the green X being the red and Z being the blue.
And we can confirm that as well in the top right.
We've got those colors and letters as well.
Now if this didn't happen perhaps you'd deselected from the cube because in order to transform something
you need to tell blender what you want to transform.
Now if you click anywhere else in the scene it would deselect an object.
If I left click again in this case and I select the cube you see that it now it has the outline around
it again the orange outline means it's selected and it's also got these tools around it's a scale with
these blocks to rotates and also just to move really useful being able to just grab those and move them
around.
Now if we had something else selected maybe the camera over here or the lights at the top then the tool
moves to those places.
Now the other place that you could manipulate these is over in the properties panel now similar to the
tools on the left hand side on the right hand side there's a properties panel there's a little arrow
that you can open it up with and you also have the N key.
Now the N Key will bring open this properties panel and it will change depending on what you're doing
and which window, which editor you're in but we're in the 3D editor at the moment.
So what else can we do here.
Well we can be more precise with where we want this light.
We can click and drag.
We can even type in here.
So if I wanted to set that's a one meter in this case I could do so I could highlight by clicking and
dragging over all of these fields and change them all to the same value that can be incredibly useful
as well such as if you've rotated something I mean you want to set the rotation all back to zero.
We can highlight it all and press zero and there you go it's cleared the rotation that was once there.
There is another way that we can do it and that's already we can see that in the right hand side the
far right hand side we have the object properties so we've got the properties in the 3D window and we
can close that down but we also have the object properties going to make this area here wider by moving
my cursor between these windows to get that double headed arrow and I can make this wider as I want
more much much more narrow about there is can be fine for the moment.
And here is the properties panel.
This is here by default.
We hover over this little icon at the very top of this window.
We can see that the editor type is properties.
In fact these exist all over the place within blender.
We go to this one at the top here we've got outliner.
We go over to the far left we've got a 3D viewport that's the main one we're working in and at the very
bottom we have one called the timeline and these can be changed out and manipulated.
We'll learn about that more later on but we can also set the object properties, the objects transform
properties and it's neatly under the transform dropdown so we've played with these and we can click
and drag and move around and that's that's great.
We can set things up.
But how does this really help us or what we can do is we can start putting things together and rotating
them and moving them around.
But for the moment what's I'd like you to do is get the hang of doing this now.
I'm a big fan of shortcut keys but they can be a bit overwhelming from time to time and I don't exclusively
use them.
So I will often use N and T to bring open these areas on the left them right.
I like N and T simply because it's a pain to click on the little arrows.
So I go to that and I also use shortcut keys.
I use the menu options.
I use the property panels.
It just depends on what I'm doing if I need something precise.
I'm not going to do it by hand but what I can do is get rid of all of those.
And there are three shortcut keys that you can use as well.
I'm going to open up the tool shelf and just go at the very top again and go to our normal select mode.
Now if I've done that what I can do is I can press the G key the G key is all about moving around pretty
cool Hey now what was missing when we were moving before is these arrows.
That's very useful to be able to move something on the x y or z axis.
So how do we manage that.
Well what we can very easily do let's make that gizmo disappear again.
If I press G to move it then I can simply press the letter in the direction I want to lock the movement
so I can get X and it will lock in the X axis Y in the Y axis and Z in the Z axis.
Now if I didn't want to move up or down and just around the X Y plane what I can do is press G to say
that I want to move it and then say shift in Z to say not on the Z axis.
Now if you were to just go shift and Z you turn on what's called wireframe mode and we can turn that
off again we shift and Z so if it's going like this.
That means that you've not pressed G first or perhaps you've not pressed one of the other modifier keys
S for scaling.
And again we can lock that on X Y and Z or R for rotation and again X Y and Z.
Okay.
So the final thing to touch upon is applying transforms if we open up the properties panel again we
can see that it's location is relative to the world origin which is 0 0 and 0 so its 5 meters in the x axis
point four meters in the Y axis and point two six in the Z and that's to do this orange dot in the middle
of our object would talk about the origin points later on we have a rotation and a scale applied to
our model.
Now there are plenty of operations in Blender where if you do not apply the rotation and scale you can
end up with some really weird effects going on.
So it's often a good idea to apply the rotation and scale following doing a transform the location however
is often just left as is.
Unless you've got a very specific case.
So we can do that by going to the very top of the 3D Editor window to the object's menu going to apply and
we can see the shortcut key there is control and A and if we use control and we'll get the same window
up let's try that now control and A there we go and we want to apply the rotation and scale and we find
then that the rotation is set to 0 0 0 and the scale has been reset to 1.
Now that's a really useful thing to do and there's something that I'm going to remind you about throughout
the course as we go.
And now we've learnt about transforms what I'd like to do is reinforce that knowledge with a little
challenge. OK so your challenge starts a new blend file.
Once you've done that move the default cube one meter on the Z axis.
So that will be moving it up.
Then rotate the default cube 45 degrees on the z axis again once you've done that.
I'd like you to make a diamond shape by scaling it by 2 on the Y axis.
Now you will notice at this point if you scale it by two on either the X or Y axis it's not gonna make
a diamond shape straight away.
So what I'd like you to do is play and think about when you might need to apply a transform.
Here's a clue.
It's going to be more than once and the other thing that you can play with if say you're moving something
on the Z axis by 1.
You could press G to move Z to lock it to the z axis and immediately press the number one press enter
and it's moved by one meter on the z axis so it can even be quicker to move things around.
And let me just show you the end state what we're trying to achieve.
So this is the final shape that will end up with as you can see here.
I've applied all of my transforms except the location 1 so we've got it sitting with orange dots one
meter above the zero point of the world.
Okay so this is what we're going for.
Go ahead pause the video now and give that a go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
So I'm going to start off by starting a brand new scene so new.
General Okay so we've got our default scene in front of us I'm gonna press G to move it Z to lock it
to the Z axis and I'm going to press the number one and that's lifted it up one meter and we can confirm
that over in the properties panel here we can see that it has been shifted on the Z axis by one meter
and we can also open up the 3D editor properties window and see exactly the same information.
I'm gonna leave this open and then rotate it by 45 degrees on the Z axis.
I'm then going to scale it on the X axis.
Now this is where it starts getting a bit weird.
So if we scale it's in the 3D window itself and on just locking into the X axis we get it scaling
like this it's pretty cool it's making a flat a square of the height one meter.
Okay.
Oh sorry 2 meters there'll be 2 meters high.
Okay that's not what we want we can see here it's scaled on the X and Y axis.
Okay.
So if I set out back to 1.
Okay so we can set these independently now you might think oh OK.
Is that because I didn't apply the the rotation that we have there.
Well let's try it.
Let's see what happens.
And this is what I want to encourage you to do is to play in blender.
What happens if I apply the rotation first and then try and scale it on the X axis.
Oh that looks completely different and if I scale on the X axis here it does the same thing.
So because the rotation wasn't applied it was doing something completely different in the 3D viewport.
But as soon as that rotation was applied then it starts behaving differently.
Again pretty cool Hey but it just shows you the difference that applying or not applying a transform
can have and that's just at this stage later on it can really impact your work and even destroy your
models if you don't get that right.
So is worthwhile right from the very beginning even at this stage applying those transforms and now
I've just scaled it up on the scale and make that diamond I'm going to then go Alt and A and I'm going
to apply that scale.
This is our new object.
It's really this dimensions is not being transformed into a different shape.
I'm going to finally save my work with file save and I'm going to call this transforms diamond Excellent.
Okay.
How did you guys get on.
I know this is a very straightforward start but these are some key skills that you're going to need
as we progressed through the course and so we're going to start with these small steps.
And by the end of this section you'll be amazed at what you can achieve with just these simple tools
that I'm now giving you.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.