Hello everybody and welcome to this quick tip of solidifying the grease pencil as you can see here by
the end of this lecture you'll be able to make your grease pencil sketch into some real geometry.
It's a great start when you need to create a place holder that it's not just a boring cone bit more
true to the final product.
Let's find out more.
Okay so let's start out by just cleaning up a little here I'm going to press the end key to get rid
of the properties panel and the tall shelf out of the way as well.
So I'm going to remove the cone that we've just added.
Now it does feel like a consulate's it.
Yes there we go.
I'm literally get into later.
I could hide it but since we're going to have a place holder that's our sketch I think that will be
fine.
So with our sketch selected just the lamp objects here what I can do is go ahead right click and convert.
Now you think it might be two mesh but no we want to convert it to busier curves because what we can
then do is have a look.
It's created this thing called primitives.
And I can call that lamp as well.
Now if I do call that lamp because you can't have two objects both called lamp name to the other one
lamp 0 0 1.
So I'm going to go in here and change that to say something like lamp sketch or something along those
lines.
So we've kept the original date.
I'm going to hide that out of the way and then we've just got this rough outline in place.
Okay.
Now before we go and make that solid what I'm going to do is add a light into the scene I'm going to
add in in this case as some lamp so we can lights at the scene.
I'm going to press the Archy twice to rotate it round and to roughly the right location about there
because you can hop into rendered mode to see where the shadow is falling.
That's a good start.
We can refine that later.
Let's go back into solid shading selects our object here which is now a curve object and then go to
the curve properties so we scroll down these tabs here we get this green one of course this now color
coded which is really useful and we go to the curve properties.
Now this could be lamp properties or mesh properties depending on what type of objects you've got selected.
And then we'd scroll down here and go to where it says geometry.
If we open up that drop down and then continue down to where it says Bevel we've got a depth that we
can use we just increase that slightly.
Look at that we've got ourselves a 3D object.
Now it won't be absolutely perfect but it's a brilliant start to making sure that things look really
nice.
Now we've got a couple of options here we can turn down the resolution and if you turn down the resolution
down to zero it's going to be as simple as it can be.
And if you ramp that up a little of course it's going to look more and more cylindrical.
Of course we can change the depth here to make it more of a wire or more like an inflatable lamp but
I'm happy with the default of around point nought one which is just what you get when you click it just
the once.
Now the resolution itself I think having a simple one like that is absolutely fine.
Of course if you bump up massively all you're doing is adding extra unnecessary geometry into the scene
at this particular point.
So when we go for maybe one that's a good compromise between the two options there then finally I'm
going to go back to rendered mode and have a look.
Now the shadow doesn't look perfect and we know we can play with the contact shadows and other things
along those lines but because we got a sun lamp here one of the things to remind you of is unlike cycles
the sun lamp if it's a be owned if we just move this this way you can see that the shadow just disappears.
That wouldn't happen in cycles it does matter if you're using eevee where you put the look of how that
makes a huge difference where you put your some lamp so just bear that in mind when you're working so
focus on the direction of this case the directions all the way over there.
Go rotate that round ever so slightly press the AHA twice to have this trackable rotation.
I prefer that we're mucking around with shadows and let's place it about there it just moved it across
slightly and there we go we've got our scene set up a bit more geometry here and this is the great thing
it will now look like shadows there as well which is a really really good start.
We've got a place holder now that's much more representative of the final product.
Now if you've followed along with this instead of using a blank place holder I'd like to see how yours
looked when you went ahead and converted your grease pencil into real geometry please share your work
over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.