In this video we're gonna be adding some eyes and sculpting the area around the eyes.
I'm gonna break down in a fit of sobbing every now and again realizing how old and how good I look.
But for now let's jump in and talk about modeling the eye area.
Okay back to my starting point just a quick note I've renamed a couple of things in my same collection
removed the camera and removed the light.
I just tidied it up a little bit and just done a little bit of tweaking off camera to the bridge of
my nose.
Right now we want to add some eyes.
First thing we want to do is jump over into object mode.
I'm going to shift a to add a mesh which I will make a u v sphere on a side view move it forward a bit
so we can see what's going on.
I'm going to rotate this eyeballs so I think it's X 90 we'll see how that looks.
My goal here is to have the sickly Iris bit in the middle that looks like job done.
I will get straight on front view s to scale.
Let's scale it down down down down okay about yay big hoping a wireframe mode here so I can see exactly
what's going on.
Now one of the things you want to look for is that you can make five eyeballs from left side to right
side so the moment we're getting 1 2 3 which indicates that it's too big so far but generally in the
middle.
Hit scale again scale it down.
Let's see if we reckon this is going to be and 2 that's getting in this the right ish kind of ballpark
is going to duplicate do this little test and test again.
There we go.
It looks like we've got five eyeballs.
Now obviously I'd put the other one two over there.
When I delete these ones that I just made that was just for illustrative purposes out of wireframe mode.
Onto the side bring it forward so I can see how it's looking.
Where we're going sphere.
Let's rename it AI ball while we're here.
I call Rick learn how to type.
Which I bowl forward.
I want to bring it back.
So a little bit of his poking through this is wrong in a scrolling in a whole bunch.
On my side image.
Let's have a look to see what we want to hear.
There's just a little bit of the eyeball poking through look at those luscious eyelashes and let's see
in our eyelids.
We're gonna push this back a little bit.
Don't need to finesse it too much just yet because what we will be doing is pushing and prodding the
geometry around our eyeballs.
I found in the past that I put the eyeballs a little bit too far out so I'll move it in a little bit.
Don't look too beady eyed doing now.
We want to have a look like this and good lord look at all those wrinkles.
Okay.
We have very harsh sun in Australia.
So not looking too bad for a 25 year old.
But you know the sun puts a little bit of damage and gives a little bit wrinkles but deliberately chosen
this so that we can work with our crease tool.
What a joy that's gonna be to make all Rick's wrinkles.
Got one eyeball let's go to our modifiers add modifier we will do what we will mirror this exactly.
I'm going to find the object to click on so here mirror object when I click on the eyedropper.
Click on the head.
Now the head is being used as our way that we're mirroring.
Let's click on one of the eyeballs or the eyeball.
I guess it is do you do.
Yep looks good it is being successfully mirrored.
I'm looking at the middle of the eyeball here not the outline because the outline is going to be a little
bit misleading Oh look at that it's Gandhi.
These little Gandhi eye glasses.
Awesome.
Okay.
Now let's jump onto click back on head into sculpt mode.
We'll get rid of a little bit of this geometry and here and we're using the draw tool quite a lot so
let's use the draw tool now just to can control and to eat away some of this geometry Well we're actually
pushing it back when I'm eating it a while we push back push it back push it back.
The idea is to get enough of the eyeballs so that in a moment we're going to paint over the top of the
eyeball and then we're going to carve out an eyelid.
I know that all sounds a little bit weird and gross.
Now at this point I'm going to give you a challenge so you know what on earth is supposed to be doing
you've probably figured out X I know you're a smart individual that way sculpting the eyes.
I would like you to add a sphere as I just did rotate it so that we had the Irish Sea looking thing
at this at the front position and mirror it scope over the eyeballs then remove a strip to create the
eyelids.
I'll do that in just a moment so you can follow along with me or you can wait until I'm done and then
go through at your own pace and we're going to add creases more creases if you're an old look and do
like me to get your medium level of detail so I don't want you to get to the pristine done completely
done finished done just get it's a pretty good detail so that's that's your challenge and that's what
I'm going to be going through for the remainder of this video.
Next step is for us to as I say before is to say draw over the eyeballs completely so with your draw
tool just draw over the draw.
There we go trying to get it fairly uniform.
Now I'm going to hold down control probably make my brush Lou what's wrong brush but make my brush a
little bit smaller and holding down control.
I'm going to dig out the eyeball.
Okay.
Our goal is to create the eyelids.
Let's even get both eyelids in shot at once.
I'm just gonna hop back into object mode.
Change around the positioning of my images a little bit.
So the two eyes are a bit closer together because we're focusing just on the eyes and as we go you can
do a little bit tightening up to the nose area the eyebrows area that's important it's all part of the
island with the cheekbones but resist the temptation to go through the mouth and the nose and the ease
with focusing just on the eyes at the moment.
So I've dug out a little bit of my eye now you can see we've got more of a almond shape it pinches down
to the end so I want to try to recreate that effect first of all I need to get some more detail so I'm
going to fall back into sculpt mode while clicking on the head sculpt mode now top Tab I'm going to
click on dyeing Topo the detail I have in here as before I'm going to make this constant detail and
increase it for now run about twenty five so getting a lot of detail is tons detail around the eyes
so you want to keep adjusting that as works for you.
So I'm going to be just digging in through here.
As I said before I'm mostly using the draw tool and then I'll be using the crease quite a bit and feel
free to skip ahead or fast forward the video or go at whatever pace is appropriate for you.
I'm going to be talking through my movements here and going at a reasonably slow pace I tend to do this
the eyes pretty slowly partially because I'm a bit slow partially because this is the tough bit.
If you want to watch them follow along as I'm chatting gathering them please do.
Otherwise feel free to skip this bit and just work on yours at your own leisure.
So my goal here is to flatten out the eyelids.
Don't worry about the kind of the weird geometry will smooth that out later on we'll get some more detail
in there later on what is getting the shape as we've done before pushing and pulling and getting enough
kind of padding in there for now for the eyelids.
The other is a little bit fatter than you think.
A lot of people forget to put a nice big chunky eyelids because they're so focused on the eyebrows perhaps
but for me look at those bags under the eyes.
Good lord that's what happens when you have children my friends
okay.
Detail detail looks like whatever's going on here is not too bad of a little bit of a bump.
That's what happens when you play football as a child and you get you know smacked a few too many times.
I'm just gonna add a little bit more football smack around onto the nose there.
There we go.
Lovely handsome.
I'm just using shift every now and again just to smooth things out.
Being careful that I'm not overly smoothing as I've done previously.
Make sure that our smooth level is.
Yeah that's not too bad.
Point three.
I don't like when I smooth in it it's too aggressive with the smoothing and get a little bit of crease
to the head start.
Oh goodness me this is going to be painful.
If you hear me sobbing as I'm using the crease tool then they worry everything's okay.
It's all a natural part of ageing okay.
A little bit of Crow's feet in there.
Let's just focus on this right eye for now right.
Okay.
Oh that's my left eye I should say are in the right side of my screen.
There's little not just there.
That's what happens when you pierce your eyebrow.
Kids don't do that.
That's not the wisest of things to do.
It's kind of cool for about five minutes but then afterwards you think why did I do that.
I did that so that in some years time I can be doing a blender video and have a little bit of detail
on the eyebrow to sculpt an eyebrow ring piercing to remind me of my good choices in my youth.
Okay so I'm putting creases under the eyes and give you a little bit of an ask for random commentary
as well as we go.
Okay.
Looking a little bit more wrinkly now as I said before I really it bugs me a lot that the geometry in
here isn't quite all that smooth looking yet but that's fine.
We got to resist the temptation in at the moment we're putting in these macro details.
Let's get a little bit more of the detail in.
You can see there's a you can kind of see a little bit more of the eyeball peeking down into there.
I've got that happening I think.
Not too bad with this crease.
And then we and offer him whatever that thing he's cold down there.
The tea Doctor maybe use that as well once you have kids as well.
Tears of joy.
It is it's turning into Rick's comedy hour isn't it.
OK let's get some more of these crises definition pushing up into the dark rings around the lines.
Yet looking pretty sadly accurate now.
Let's have a look.
This is the photo is not too bad he because you can see the iris the middle the dark part of my eye
I think is roughly the same size as the initial ring around my sphere.
But it's not quite right.
I need to pull my top eyelid down a little bit so I'm gonna grab that we'll see if the grab tools what
I want here grab tool or this snake hook tool or there is I think is gonna be okay.
Just pull the eyelid down a little bit a little bit.
Now for your image your reference image you're using you might have a totally different look.
You might have the eyes open more or close more or any sort of different way of doing it.
I'm going to talk you through what I'm seeing in mine but obviously Please follow along with what you
see in yours.
Get the angles right.
So it's important to get the idea going up and then down.
I've accidentally gone and put in some of the bumps and details that I actually do have in there.
Okay.
As always zoom out check how things are guys progressing pretty quickly actually it's easy to model
a wrinkly old man.
I think he is doing something that's looking a bit smoother.
Well these imperfections is adding to the character the charisma of old Rick Cam going to fit out the
eyelid a little bit more.
So we have to put in whatever that sort of creases in there.
That's an old man increase as well
okay.
It's mostly going to be me just pushing and pulling things around at the moment if you want to stay
and hang out together listen to my witty commentary.
Then please do otherwise feel free to fast forward skip the video.
Jump forward to see if you can find a bit that's relevant to the bit you're working on at the moment
while I do my old man crow's feet around the edges here.
Pretty more of this detail starting to look where I want it to be more like at some point you might
want to increase your resolution as well say up to 30 or 35 if you're starting to get into these into
the minutiae of these details as I said in my challenge.
We're aiming for medium level of detail not super slickly finished.
We want to get it pretty good.
I want to try to get that extra crease in there I think I will move it skeptical that I can pull it
off because it's kind of running out of detail a little bit in here but let's give it a shot.
So getting that extra eyebrow crease thing now look at the side haven't looked at the side for a little
bit.
Make sure that matches
I need to put back this way a little bit more.
That's good snake hook tool just put back a little bit back a little bit.
Okay.
And then back to what I was saying before about those extra creases around the eyelids.
Just still loop still a little bit of smoothing in here.
So we're ready for that detail.
I've got my higher resolution going on back onto crease.
I just increase the power a little bit on crease okay.
I think for me to pull this off I don't have to put in a lot more because it nearly goes up to my eyebrow
doesn't it.
It's kind of weird double crease action sir.
I know this is a little bit maybe a little bit more detail a little bit more intimate of Rick's face
than we wanted to go for but let's let's get this.
It's gonna plague me if I don't get this working the way I want it so I'm just gonna add a little bit
more fatness in here.
One thing we could do instead of all this drawing is I could add some clay strips or I could add some
clay which is more of a popping things on top I think that's what I do like I'm going to turn the strength
of that bunch down but that has given me a little bit more to play with.
Now we'll see as we crease this we'll see if it gives us the desired effect
read the crease first and then we'll maybe pull some of that geometry from the top to cover the geometry
at the bottom
OK.
How we look and said that's how we're looking in the right ballpark.
Harry Stannard looks down and looks like a wrinkly old man.
Her so I won't spend forever on this.
Honestly a little bit of a not a perfectionist.
That's not the right word I think.
Perfectionist has a little bit of a negative connotation it says that you you can't leave something
when it's good enough.
That's not what it is I'm more of a an enthusiast.
I'm excited to get it looking like.
Can I can I represent this how I want it to be represented so I tend to continue maybe a little bit
longer than I should on some of these details but that's all part of the fun it's all part of getting
better learning what we're doing here.
But generally my goal is to make it look all kind of wrinkly and a little bit haggard and I think that's
working out as intended so I just do a little bit of a final crease through all this stuff might put
my detail up just a tiny bit more for what we're doing here
because you see we've got that sharp line at the front of the eyelid and then there's a little bit of
a little bit of a landing a little bit of a platform to jump on underneath the eyes.
They're as a game developer joke
maybe open up the eyes a little bit to make me look a little bit more awake and alert while keeping
the general shape of it.
Okay.
I have one more shot at getting these double eyelids looking like I want them to literally smoothing
just up above their
crease too I think I need to pinch some of this out because I've pushed it all back too far the crease
tool is gonna do a good job of retreating the those faces and vertices there but I want to also make
it nice and pronounce
Okay so there's some I'm pretty happy with mine.
Hopefully yours went well.
That looks awkward having high detail in the rest of it's not but in next video we'll put some more
detail into another part of our human head.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next video.