Hello everybody and welcome to level of detail.
So this is one of the last in a series of kind of theory lectures.
But I think this is really important to understand so that you don't end up in a rut of trying to model
one thing really well.
When that perhaps isn't the best thing you can do.
So my advice here and it sounds very straightforward when you hear it is start basic so focus on representations
of the right size and shape but just block work models.
This is really important especially when you're starting to map out to see inmates make sure things
fit where you think they're going to fit the real heartache is when you decide to model something you
spent ages modeling it's it's great if you've learned new techniques whilst you've been doing it and
you've got another reason for doing it.
However if you're making up a scene and you spend hours modelling that say an alter or a sarcophagus
and it turns out that you're not going to use that you've effectively wasted that time and if you're
trying to create assets for a game it's better to have many assets that your game team or even yourself
can pick from and then you can work on those in much more detail.
It allows quick iterations of your model.
So if someone says to you oh I want it wide or longer or could you do this here then you're able to
do that really quickly.
In fact you could give several variations on a model because you're doing them at such a low level of
detail initially.
Now remember the higher detail often requires more processing time.
So so we're not just talking about your timing creating but if there are more vertices in a scene is
going to take up more resources of your computer and often take a lot longer to render as well.
Okay.
So one of the biggest things here is watching your time and how it applies to level of detail.
Okay so the level of detail and the time taken are usually directly proportional to one another.
What do we mean by that.
Well if I asked you to model a simple building you could probably do that in under a minute if I asked
you to model a building with all the intricacies of the guttering and the window trim and the door trim
and individual bricks need to be slightly out of place.
So it looks more realistic.
Well it's going to take you a lot longer to level of detail and the time taken and I say I usually directly
proportional to one another because you can add detail very quickly using other techniques like sculpting
add detail incredibly quickly but in general the detail level is proportional to the time taken.
Now when fleshing out the scene and prototyping you probably want quite a few assets.
So making sure the low detail to begin with is a great way of achieving that goal.
And you can test models and your scene really quickly being able to swap things around scale things
to different sizes because they don't have details and yet that will be distorted if you just did that
so the various ways of approaching this task and I would recommend getting comfortable with rough assets.
It's a great way of getting a scene nailed very quickly.
So let's just have a look at a quick charts.
Now these numbers are plucked out of the air but they're just highlighting a fundamental point.
So we've got level of detail here and you may wonder why it says ABC.
Because if you've done some reading in the past Ello D is usually 0 1 2 3 4 etc..
So the way that in a game engine level of detail tends to work is that you will have Level of Detail
zero which is your base model the highest quality model and then some game engines like Unreal will
auto lot.
And they will cut down the level of polygons and the text to detail the further you are away from a
model or you can explicitly say I want to preserve these details the further something gets away.
And so you can load in individual models.
So in order to avoid that confusion I'm going to use the terminology ABC D so we can actually go up
in our polygon counts as we go now polygon count is just one example here.
It could be texture detail as well.
It doesn't really matter.
Basically the complexity of your model.
So for instance here at 200 polygon model is probably only going to take you on average 15 minutes to
do.
Once you've added materials and played around with a few things you may find that something with a bit
more detail in it takes you up to an hour to do so in that same time it's taking you to make that Elodie
be model you could potentially put out four different models in the same time.
So this is the power of what we're talking about here as we go up the scale we end up on a cloudy day.
And the reason why I've put that in there at 2 in 2008 could be 20 million.
It really doesn't matter but it's the time it takes to do that.
You will find that some carrots are artists or environment artists.
Once that's nailed down and they really start focusing on the detail it can take them a week to complete
a project.
We want to be the other end of the scale at the moment we want to produce many asset reasonably quickly
so we can scale up.
If you're just focusing on one thing for a long time you're going to learn a lot more the other way
round.
And finally let's look at the two asterisks down at the bottom we've got every polygon counts what do
I mean by that.
Well it's simply if you were to apply a subdivision surface modifier onto a model that's not really
a counting polygon you've just increased the polygon count and not really added much to the model.
So we're talking about polygons that actually matter and counts towards your model.
And then finally the time included.
Yes that includes the other word artwork too as I've hinted.
Your textures your materials your u v unwrapping which we'll get to shortly.
All of those things are important and do count towards that time.
And the more simple your model is the less time you'll be unwrapping is going to take the less detailed
you're worried about your textures being etc..
Enough of words on a screen let's look at a practical example.
So in front of us here we have a sarcophagus.
This took no time for me to model up so then we move on.
I've started adding detail.
This is about the right level for Elodie.
Now you can see some facets there that I'm not happy with but I also rejected the idea of sorting the
mounts at this stage because that doesn't add anything to the model itself.
And then we go a bit further and we add more detail on and this could be the ELODIE level C as it will.
And then just for fun I added a few more details on there some worn edges and then smooth them out and
created finer detail across the model.
And this is the sort of thing that starts to take a lot of time.
If I'd gone straight for something like this then we end up in a situation where if this is rejected
I've potentially wasted all of that time.
Now this doesn't line up this didn't take me a week to do but the first model here in this particular
scene.
This took about a minute two minutes to do but 10 minutes faffing around playing with shapes.
This didn't take much longer.
On top of that but just contains more detail on it and to get the point across quickly I very quickly
sculpted some extra detail on here.
Some wearing on the edges.
And then I tidied that up a little to make it look that much better.
And this is just an analogy to the extra time you could spend on a model.
Okay so that wraps up this lecture.
The important takeaway is watch your level of detail.
The last thing you want to do is spend all that time working on something that you're not going to use.
So make sure you're making lots of low poly models to begin with and then later on when we pick the
ones that are necessary for your scene you know those are the ones that you want to focus on increasing
the level of detail on and we'll also go how we can fake some level of detail later in the section through
the use of normal maps.
But let's not get too far ahead of ourselves and I'll see you all in the next lecture.