Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to talk about our first materials.
Now you may have something like this more complex or even simpler.
It doesn't really matter which model we've got at the moment.
It's a bit plain and boring.
How about if we change it slightly.
So we have some colors much much better straight away.
Let's hop over into blender and find out some more.
OK so over in the default blender file at the moment and we've got a cube in front of us.
Now the first thing we're going to have to do is make sure that we can see any of the material changes
we make at the moment.
Our view is in what's called Solid mode which means that we're not really going to be able to see any
colors that we applied to our model.
So how do we go and change that so we can see what's going on.
Well at the very top of the 3D view we have our toolbar and we've got these three spheres to the right
hand side.
We've got wireframe mode solid mode which means it's going to not have any color.
Look Dev and rendered we want to be looked dev for the moment which is the third one along.
Once that's set we're ready to make our first material on a wide in this area to the right.
So with our cube selected and we know it's selected because it's got this light orange border around
it I'm going to go to the materials properties.
So going to go over to our properties window and if you can't see everything here I'm just going to
condense this as if you're on a smaller screen or maybe you've move these around you can use the scroll
wheel to go up and down on this tab system on the left hand side.
To make that launcher again and if we go down nearly at the bottom we've got this sphere.
If we go ahead hover over it says material click on it.
It takes us to our material properties.
So at the moment this cube has a material called material assigned to it.
Now you can have more than one material assigned to an object but we're just going to stay with one
for the moment.
Now I can rename that material by even double clicking as the hover over actually showed all going down
here and I'm going to type in red here and you can see it's updated at the top here.
Now if you've got more than one material in your scene what you can do is use this dropdown to select
a different material that's very useful if you've built up a repertoire of materials that you've stored
or you've already set the material up and you want so apply it to a new object.
Right.
Let's go down a little further.
If your use nodes is not blue it will be turned off for this section and most sections we're going to
have to make sure use nodes is turned on you will then see we're using the Surface shader principled
B SDF.
Don't worry about that.
We'll cover that in much more detail later on.
But that's essentially what's producing all of this detail down here.
Now this is the setup of how the light is interacting with the surface of our cube and it can get quite
complex.
And again don't worry we'll break this down later on in the course.
You have a much deeper understanding for the moment though.
We just want to focus on the base color.
So go ahead and click the colored area to the right of base color and we can pick a different color
in this case is going to be a red color because that's what we selected.
So on the color well I've selected a hue.
That's kind of ready now going to drag the slider down on the side here.
So it's a darker red.
Now you can select them in this way which is B were either with hue saturation and value as well so
we can change the hue with this slider here.
The saturation is how much color there is and the value is light and dark and that's roughly in the
middle for the moment not 50 percent but we'll cover that later as well.
Okay.
So that's our material assigned.
So let's go and add another objects to our scene shift in a adding an object in a mesh object u v sphere
and I'm going to press the GK and just move over here now because the materials properties were selected
before we see the our sphere has been added but it doesn't have a default property like the default
cube did.
So that's something to bear in mind that things that you add don't necessarily come with the material
already assigned to them.
So what we can do is go to the dropdown and pick red pretty cool.
Hey let's say we didn't one red what can we do.
Well if we go ahead and rename it let's say yellow and then go and change the base color down here to
a yellow 0.
Both of them have changed and that's because both of them are sharing the same material which is really
really useful.
But you can get caught out like this.
So what's I'm going to do is I'm no go controlling Z and undo both of those steps.
Now notice that the moment we gave this the red material and number two appeared this number two shows
us that two objects in our entire scene share that material.
Now we duplicated these objects.
Let's do it.
Now let's draw a box around them duplicate them yes I know you've created the lamp as well but we can
see that the numbers now for items in our scene noticed that we've now got two objects selected we've
got one with a light orange border and one with a dark orange border.
When you're looking at the properties of something you're looking at the properties of the wall the
lighter orange border around it.
So if we were to go ahead and click on this for it will make a single user copy so it's taken all of
the settings that we already had with that red and made a new material in this case called Red 0 0 1.
Now I can call it yellow and switch out the color to something else independently of everything on here.
The other thing that we can do is just create a new material so I select this other cube I can delete
the red material or delete the red slot and then it will go back to the defaults or plain white color
and create a new material and call it blue whatever you want here and come to our base color and make
it black.
So there's a couple of different ways of changing around materials.
Now I do want to show you one final thing before I crack onto your challenge and that's with something
a bit more complex.
Let's call it complex for the moment.
So I'm going to go and open up my well that I had before.
Okay.
So with the well opened up here I produced in the last lecture.
This is quite a complex objects.
And I want to show you one of the ways that you could deal with having a mistake made.
Obviously are going to learn from this as we go.
But I didn't rename or give any of these materials as I was going they're all individual objects.
So it's gonna be a real pain if I have to go through whole down shift and select multiple ones of these.
So selecting multiple ones and going new material calling it's going to make a pink roof tile here to
really highlights and make sure and look Dev mode but only one of those tiles is actually selected and
only one of them has been changed to pink all of the others as they were before.
Is there a quick way of transferring the material on one object to many others.
Well yes there is.
So I'm going to box select everything because these tiles are the most numerous and it'll be the most
tricky things to pick with perhaps the exception that the slats holding up the roof.
OK.
So with everything selected what we can do is we can have everything else inherits the properties of
that one selected item by holding down control and pressing the L key so we're going to make links to
all of the other selected objects to the active selected.
So if I go materials or.
Okay the whole thing's gone pink I'm going to change that to something a little less offensive to my
eyes because that was really bright and now we've got everything.
Sharing one material and we can do the same if we came down to let's say these bricks down here and
then I will show you one final thing so I'm going to highlight all of these bricks.
And notice that the ground has also been selected but nothing else has got a hold down shift and clicked
the ground twice twice because I needed to select it once to make it the actors selected and then click
it again to D select it I'm going to select with the shift key held down.
One other brick and we can see that's become the active item now from this what I can do is I'm going
to delete that pink slots and I'm going to introduce a new material called brick and I'm going to immediately
inherits I'm going to go control an L so all of these dark orange ones are going to inherits the active
selected material I control an L materials.
Now they all share the brick I can change them to any color I want.
Hey guys.
Mark here with just a little update for you I want to come in here and give you a little bit of insight
into collections here because they can't be used and be really really helpful when you're selecting
things in things like these what you've got here is my scene I've got a little bit of a difference where
my train being a bit bumpy Why do I like you to do it's cauterized the right my screen and the outline
here where you can see I've got my well in a collection and what I've done differently to Mikey is I've
got my tiles my brakes and all of my framework in separate collections underneath the collection now
I'd like to show you is it say we want to select all of the tiles in my thing this is going to take
a while doing it this way what you can do is you can go to your tiles right click and you can select
objects on this will select everything underneath that collection and then we have all our tile selected
and you can do the same for the bricks.
Make sure you have the breaks selected right click and then select objects.
And it will add to the selection as well so you can add the bricks to the selection you already had
with the tiles.
Hope this helps.
And now back to my key.
One final thing if I wanted to select all of these that share the same material I can simply go shift
and L and select material.
So there we go.
There's a really quick way that you can go ahead and select anything that shares the same material.
And now as a matter of going around the rest of your model and sorting that out which is a perfect time
for your challenge.
Okay.
So your challenge a nice straightforward one.
I'd like you to coloring your model and make at least three materials and apply them to your model so
it's not just one color.
It's gonna be at least three if you have more on your model.
That's absolutely fine as well.
Pause a video and give that's a go okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's hop over now and color in our model.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Okay so we're we're pretty far on at the moment.
Couple of other things that I need to do I need to do the tiles at some point and these wooden beams
so often it's easier to get this going from the word go with the correct materials so that as I duplicated
them they would have the materials attached to them.
So that's a learning point from us moving on.
So I've got the tiles here.
I think I'm going to call this pink tiles so I know that the tiles are now all sorted and I can go in
and make them dark or lights or different color later on.
It doesn't matter.
Well let's set it.
Now let's set to maybe a slight to light color.
Okay let's select the ground delete the material slot that says tiles new material and it's gonna be
called ground I'm going to make it a green for the moment a darker green Okay so the next thing are
these wooden beams I'm going to go in and I should if we look at it from the right angle be able to
just select the main beams.
Excellent.
So I'm gonna delete and add in a new material.
What shall we call it.
Let's call this beams and then we'll call the other ones slats.
I don't know what the technical term is.
So this is gonna be a oh not a pink a brown.
So we're gonna go out there and I'm gonna have its inherits all of these other ones.
Now I've missed a couple of extra ones.
I'm going to select those making sure that this top one is the last one that's selected go control L
and link in those materials.
Perfect.
Now the next one are these here.
Now do these share the same.
No.
They're not linked duplicates.
Okay it's going to look at the straights on and then go up this way I think that's gonna be the easiest
way of doing this.
Now one thing to bear in mind is whenever you're doing a big selection like this I keep accidentally
selecting this big one so I'm just gonna ignore it and remove it at the very end so there's that.
No I'm not going to attempt to do the other side at the moment.
It's so easy for me to inadvertently select the other end.
Oh here we go.
I've accidentally selected one there straightaway but it's very easy for me to accidentally select something
and ruin my selection overall.
Something to keep it as it is there.
I'm going to go into my material slots.
I don't have an active one selected at the moment.
Let's make one of these active.
There we go.
Materials delete that add in the new material.
I'm going to call it a slot.
I'm not even sure how you spell slats.
I think it's like that.
Anyway I'm sure one of you will correct me if I'm wrong and I'm going to make this sort of a lighter
yellow just so I can see the difference and then control an l I'm going to inherit those material properties
and then if you wanted to you could go down each one of these individually as well and add in slats
but I can't be bothered to do it like that so I'm going to select all the these other ones.
Plus it's a really inefficient way of doing it and control l materials.
Okay.
So we've got all of our materials separated out.
Hey I'm pretty happy with it apart from this kind of Pinkie brick color.
So let's come in make it a darker orange.
It's almost like it's Harry Potter Well at this point.
Sure we have terracotta tiles.
Instead let's call these terror terror tiles
and then what we should be able to do is select all of these with the same materials to shift an L material.
There we go.
I'm going to select one of these bricks down here.
Control an L and inherit the materials.
There we go.
So we've got a terracotta tile and then I should be able to just switch this over to tiles.
That's what I want to highlight everything.
These select the ground select this brick and control and l think materials.
Okay.
So that looks to me a little bit better and I can make this terracotta style tile a little bit redder
and a little bit darker.
Anyway I could faffing around now for the rest of the day just tweaking this but it's not worth investing
that much more time in this particular model.
We've got a very basic well here.
Does it work.
Does it stand as it is.
I'm happy with it.
I wouldn't want to start adding more detail to it because it's just not necessary at this point in time.
And that is something that you'll have to hold yourself back from it's just going to file with your
models sometimes by all means.
I'm not saying don't but just be aware of the time you're investing in a single model where you could
produce five or six different models and learn a lot more in the process.
So there we go.
There's my colored in Well I'm looking forward to seeing what Ali you've made all coloured in and if
yours hasn't been as complex as this one.
That's okay.
I probably have gone a bit overboard with the amount of objects in this scene so I'm really happy with
how minds worked out here if I had wanted to criticisms I'd probably say that I've perhaps gotten a
bit carried away with making mine but if you've done that as well you know that's absolutely fine if
you're enjoying the process just go with the flow.
Now we're not quite there yet but we're almost to the point where we can start sharing our models but
we need to learn to render and we need to learn to light task seen a little bit as well.
And those will be in the next lectures.
See you soon.