Hello everybody and welcome.
In this lecture it's purely for those using a Mac because cycles is just a little bit different now.
I have a Mac Mini so it doesn't have a dedicated graphics card but some Macs do have.
And if you've if you're fortunate enough to have one of the older ones that has an end video graphics
card you should be okay still but the modern systems even you if you attach an external graphics card
to it it just won't play nicely with any video graphics cards and the other thing that's sad at the
moment but unfortunately GPA accelerated cycles isn't going to be problem free.
Back in April issue Apple dropped support a Mac OS for open JL open C.L. pushing more towards their
metal too.
And what's that's called is a few issues when it comes to using blender and cycles.
So blenders actually finished downloading here which is good.
So I'm going to go ahead and open that upsets blender 2.8 and this will be a sort of a little bit of
an overview of how to set it up and use it on a Mac.
We'll delve into a bit more details in the upcoming videos which you can follow along on whatever platform
you are.
But of course this is going to be purely Mac based.
Okay.
So on the Mac the first thing I'm going to do here is go to edit and preferences and I'll do a couple
of things.
The first thing I'm going to do is go to interface and turn the resolution scale up to one point two
five.
Just it's a bit easier to read.
And with the preferences open if we go down to system we get a couple of options under the cycles render
devices.
So we've got none CUDA and open CRL.
Now unfortunately what you tend to find with CUDA and open S.L. if you don't have a compatible GPA which
this computer doesn't it's only got a built in one.
It won't actually give you any options there but you may also find that if you do have an option here
it doesn't render as quick as your CPA does.
That's something to bear in mind when you're rendering and would talk about assessing rendering speed
in a bit in an upcoming lecture.
So on this particular computer I'm going to make sure that none is ticked in there.
And what that means is when we use cycles we're going to use our CPE you add in general Max certainly
at the moment at the time of recording which is May 2019 you're likely to when you're using a Mac have
to use the CPSU rather than a graphics card accelerated experience.
So that just means that when we go into rendered mode which you can very easily do here if we go to
our render a tab and switch that from rendering engine evey two cycles we'll be using the CPO now.
If this changes at some point and I haven't caught it please do reach out to me even in the Q and A's
or over on the forum or over on the Facebook group and let me know that blender is now working with
dedicated graphics cards on Macs I've not experienced that yet I've played with a couple of my friends
and colleagues Max as well and unfortunately they don't support GP you accelerated rendering without
multiple issues.
So that's it for this quick lecture on cycles on a Mac.
Hopefully things will improve over time but for the moment the best advice I can give you is to set
your device to CPSU when you're working on a Mac and I'll see you all in the next lecture.