Welcome to repetitive tasks in blender.
In this video you will learn how to manage repetitive tasks.
There are lots we do over and over again and sometimes we just want to repeat the same action we've
just done.
But in a different location now we're going to also understand good uses for appending a blend file
into our scene.
So let's go hop straight on over into a blender.
Okay so we're back over in blender.
The first thing I'm going to do is just remove everything in the scene to keep it nice and straight
forward.
Now when you're spending far into a scene you want to do that whenever you basically want to completely
forget all the history of that and use it as a base to generate something new from it.
And so in order to do this we're going to go and use one of the basic objects that we've got so we're
going to go and spend we can see a short cut there is shift in EF 1.
I'm going to go to my assets and in meshes and I'm going to use the square the two by two by pointing
five.
Now we need to go to the object I want to bring the whole object in in all of its properties and just
pick up the square.
And that's a pen that in.
So there we go we have our new object in the scene and it's not linked at all.
So I'm now going to first of all change the name before we do anything else.
And I'm going to call this square the tail.
I think that would be appropriate if I could spell detail of course.
There we go.
Square the tail.
And I'm going to copy that.
Go to save make sure I'm in the ascites folder and paste that in.
So we're working on a brandy blender far based upon the other ones who've appended it in.
Any changes we make here or to the other blend file.
I'm not going to impact the that's more important.
Any changes we've made to the other blend file.
So with this we can now go ahead and create some detail I'm going to make some very basic detail here.
I'm going to take this top face and subdivide it.
So let's go into edit mode and then select face.
It's going to subdivide that.
Now lemme have this face here and inset it's by I don't know.
Point two.
There we go.
So that looks good.
Now I want to do that to the rest of these faces and of course this isn't that trivial doing it to a
few of these faces here.
However I can quite easily end up having a very repetitive task going on and the easy way to do that
is shift and ah.
So if I select this next phase and go shift and ah it just repeats exactly the task I did moments ago
and that is incredibly powerful.
If I can just keep doing it and doing it because it will invert.
In this case I don't want to go quite that far.
Of course then I can decide right.
I've repeated that along there.
And I want to extrude ever so slightly by point one that's to say.
And again I can select that one shift shift shift.
And there we go we've got a a wall with a panelled wall if you will.
Very very powerful feature.
Be able to repeat things over and over again.
Of course I can go ahead and save that file an I've got that ready to use in this scene later Ron.
Okay guys it's Challenge time.
I'd like you to add some detail.
So spend a few of the existing modules into new blender files create some geometric patterns on them
or add a bit more detail.
Save them as new individual blend files.
And of course make a commit.
So balls are video now and give that a go.
Okay guys welcome back.
Let's go hop straight on over in a blender.
OK so back over in blender.
I've done my square the tell.
Let's go ahead and.
Start a brandley blend far.
And again I'm going to remove everything from the scene.
I am tempted to set up my basic scene without anything in it at this point.
Let's go.
Pen.
An I'm going to work on the door.
I think that I've made early I'm not sure actually at the moment let's go see what I've got as I've
done my door with Herbert the one with the window on it underneath.
Add some detail to that.
So we've got this window in the wall here let's go ahead and edit it.
Focus on it as well so you can see what's going on.
And I think it would look quite nice with a couple of detailed edges to it so I'm going to this time
use a couple of loop cuts to help frame the wall a little.
Would it help if I knew where that was.
No I'm going to do that by I.
I'm going to put a loop cut round the top here.
GROSS I could be more precise if I wanted to as well but if that looks right by I that's all good for
me and I'm going to go ahead here and win this case.
I'm going to select them all individually and move up rather than repeating.
Although arguably I think it would be just as quick to do both of those.
And I'm going to pull that out ever so slightly.
Or are there by how much.
I'm looking down there.
Not by much hyped or by about point nor five I think to add a bit more detail around there.
So that's a new level of detail I suppose with our window that's useful to know.
And whilst I'm here adding detail that now looks like I can pull this up ever so slightly.
Not by much just a little bit again by about porton point not 5.
And pull it out and that will start to give us a bit of a window ledge which is quite nice.
Again I'm going to extrude that out by about point 1 and I'm going to do it on the other side as well.
It's always very useful so extrude by about point 1.
So then I can have an inside of the wall and then outside.
Really good.
So I'm going to now save this.
I'm going to make sure it's named appropriately so.
Wall window
underscore the tell.
Copy that so it's exactly the same over here and save as.
Place that in and save.
Okay so the final thing to do is hop over to our repository.
So just opened up where we are and I've got uncommitted changes going on from our first commit.
So this allows me of course if I make a complete Booboo and change things up I can always hop back in
time.
So I want to make this commit now that I've added two new models I could have done just at every stage
but I haven't changed any of the other models at the moment.
So you can consider when you actually change something from how it was previously That would be a good
time to make.
Commit Sonor click click here on uncommitted changes.
I'm going to have a look down here at my unstaged files.
Now I'm just going to try to find the little widget to pull this window up.
Okay so now I've done that.
I've got two files here ready for staging which of the two that I've done I'm going to put a tick in
the box there which I'm happy with and I'm going to commit those and I'm going to put here.
I've added detail to window and wall.
And press commit now I've not got any particular.
Text File going on in here but of course before doing that comic you could have appended your text file
as well.
How did you guys get on.
What detail did you add to your models.
Please share in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.