In this video we're sculpting the nose and I'm going to start straightaway with a challenge for you
to sculpt the nose so using the knowledge that you've got already and the practice that we've been doing.
Have a go at sculpting the nose on your head all on your own without any input from me.
If it gets dark then you can come back and watch as I go through the process of creating the nose for
my head.
But I love you just to do this on your own and give it your best shot.
Use your reference material and have a go at sculpting the nose of your head so pause the video now
and come back when you've given it your best shot.
OK.
Welcome back.
If you're really happy with what you've achieved with the nose then you can just watch this very quickly.
Chin up to two times perhaps and see how I go about doing it.
If you got stuck then I'll give you some ideas on how I've gone about doing it for my nose and I'll
speed the video up a bunch.
Here we've been through a lot of sculpting now so I know that we can speed things up a little bit more
and use the crystal as a starting point shift see to get to my crease to just put a little bit of creasing
to bring the side of the face up into closer into the nose.
Yes narrow narrow.
Good.
And then there's a couple of really good lines for us to follow and here one is this line that comes
out of the nostril and the other will go to a side view and some very good side view of God here is
this line that curves around the nose.
So there two of the ones that we're going to be paying particular attention to as we go through this
process.
And I'm going to take a lot of time I think to finesse the placement of the nostrils I find them a little
bit tricky to get right.
So I'm just going a little bit and grabbing a little bit pulling around and I'll spit out the video
here.
My goal is just to grab out the shape of the nostrils and the pointy bit of the front of the nose I'm
mostly bouncing between the grab tool and the crease to crease to make the lines the grab just to nudge
things around haven't worn out where I want it to line up.
This little of a gap between the nostril and my face here that you see coming up that I was trying to
fill in with the fill tool just to fill the gap between those two areas the side of the nostril and
the side of the face.
The next step is to drill some nostrils.
Let's get in there and do some drilling only use draw.
Make it nice and small and then control to just poke my way up into the nostrils there a little bit
more power on this.
Get up in there and I'll speed up the video a bit as I play with my nostril is just digging out control.
Plus the draw tool.
And then if I dig it out too much just using the draw tool on the inside just to give it a bit more
fatness as you doing in this if you just kind of use your finger I know this sounds a little bit weird
and gross.
Use a finger to see just how close that lip is from your top lip to your nose.
It tends to kind of we don't have so much of a little reach there it's very small that ridge is used
shift to smooth things down here.
We increase told to get a bit of line underneath there a little bit of no separation
as I did before just trying to get the outside of the nostrils right using the draw tool to line the
inside give it a bit more thickness undoing pulling it around just playing until I get it the shape
that I'm happy with.
So the size and position is fine for now.
Come back to the nozzle is going to be it later on going to crack out the crease to do with a little
bit more of the creasing I'll speed up the rest of the video.
The feedback I get from folks is that they want to see generally what I'm doing but not necessarily
sit through hours and hours and me babbling about what's going on so we'll speed it up.
You can see I'm just doing a lot of which tools should I use playing around with the grab trying to
grab a lot of these nostrils get the shape in their thinking it up because you're your outer nostril
area isn't thin and tiny there's a substance to it.
Just pull the bridge of the nose out to get the shape constantly looking at the front view the side
view rotating around going to make sure that we're rotating around all the time.
Make sure it looks the way we want it to look.
Get some more of this crease in here crease and then smooth crease and then smooth.
If any of your creasing or smoothing is too powerful then adjusting the power of it to make it stronger
or softer just at the end of my nose is a little bit of that give it thing going on so put a little
bit of detail at the front there.
Back over to the wrinkles on the side.
Sometimes when you've got the structure of a thing right.
So you're happy with the nose but you don't have all the lines around it it doesn't quite feel the way
it should.
So it's good to get in those details as you're going when we're working in the broad strokes you use
two broad strokes but now we're into the medium to fine detail.
We've got our Diane topper resolution I've pumped it up to about 60 you could have it lower if your
computer is struggling a little bit with the the higher resolution.
That's totally fine.
This is not something we're going to be putting into a game like this so if we have tons of extra resolution
tons of extra quads and triangles that's not a problem.
It doesn't matter for now.
This is an exercise in sculpting and practicing sculpting so you can see you just trying to line up
where we are with the nose.
Does it look right.
I'm really bugging me that side of the nose that you can see the the angle of it doesn't quite feel
right you can sometimes just see it and feel it but it doesn't quite feel right.
So constantly looking the angles the positions getting a good upshot of the nose there.
Again I think it needs to be a little bit fatter.
This is the sort of finessing that you don't need to necessarily do that.
I like to do because it is fun that definitely looks like a nose it's pretty close to that honkin big
nose I've got over there so I'm going to declare that finished and not spend a million hours on it.
So hopefully you went well with your nose.
As always I'd love to see if you'd like to share your progress please do share in the community forum
so we can see how you're going.
I've got a nose that you're particularly proud of.
Or if you're struggling with the technical detail then please to ask as a question and I'll see you
in the next lecture.