Hello and welcome to the very first practical tutorial for this course and this is from this point that
we're going to build this very powerful but very simple model an artificial intelligence which I'm still
blown away to see the insane results it is able to perform.
I remind that this mall was made just recently.
You know the research paper appeared in March in late March 2018 and it surpasses any other AI algorithm
that we've worked on in the year 2017.
So it is a big deal.
What we're about to implement and the double good news is that we don't need any library.
You know it manages to beat the AI models we built on tend of flow or by torch.
It's crazy it's just pure logic and that's why we will be able to implement it with only the non-pay
library.
We will not need any sense of flow or pie torch or any sort of advanced AI framework we will just need
them by.
You will see the results will be insane.
All right.
But let's start by installing an icon that's why right now I'm on Google.
Let's dive here.
Anaconda you can just type panic on that.
Will get you the first link instead of the steak.
Here we go.
And on the cloud.
And now you just need to go here to download Anaconda.
And here we go now choose Anaconda for the system you're having.
Windows Mac OS or Linux.
I'm a Mac OS so I'm going to write and make sure to download five 3.6 instead of pipe and 2.7.
Right.
So if you're ready let's click on download then we'll get the file and we will just install an icon
that will just take one or two minutes and then we'll be ready to start the implementation.
All right so two seconds left.
Here we go.
Perfect We have an account.
So now I'm going to jump to my downloads folder here it is.
And here is the file I've just downloaded.
Let's double click on it.
Here you just need to click on continue continue continue continue.
You can read if you want and agree and install.
And there we go.
The installation is on its way.
We'll just take a few seconds or maybe one or two minutes but not more.
So while it's installing I can tell you a few words about Anaconda and I can do is basically a platform
that contains several IDs integrated development environments on which you can code and program anything
you want doesn't have to be any IDE can be you know some basic tools and deterministic tools but of
course on one of those frameworks and one of those ideas will build an AI.
And this idea will be spider as in every of our courses.
Spider is the best for me at least when you're beginning or when you need a nice interface because indeed
it's really like you're in a studio and you can visualize the data easily.
You can open some files from the file explorer you can debug easily.
Anyway it's a great tool to implement anything you want.
So we'll go for spider.
I'll show you Spider very soon.
Here we go.
The installation is over.
You don't have to install Microsoft.
Yes code you can just click Continue close and you can choose to keep the file the downloading felt
or not perfect.
So now for those of you who are on Windows go at the bottom left of your monitor to go into the list
of program and find Anaconda.
For those of you who are on Linux you will find an icon then same in the list of programs.
And for those of you who are on Mac like me you just need to get applications and double click on this
anaconda Navigator.
It will open this whole Anaconda framework that contains several ideas.
I will show you the ideas.
Here they are.
So Jupiter notebook is one ID.
One great idea actually if you want to combine you know programming and mathematics written in lasic
for example if you're writing a research paper that combines some code in math and you have spider as
I told you about you also have our studio if you want to code in are you can code in our any.
That's totally possible or some deep variables but I mostly use are for statistics.
And now as far as we are concerned we are going to work on spiders.
You just need to click on launch and there we go.
Spider is opening sending up main window and here you go.
Welcome to Spider.
This is the spider ID interface.
So the first thing you need to understand when you open Spier is that you'll get this temporary tender
wife out and we will not be using that file at all.
It's just a temporary felt like there has to be a fall in here.
That's the editor that a window which can combine File Explorer will you have all your files.
Variable Explorer which will contain all the variables you create and help which can give you some information
on the different objects and classes that you're using while building any I remind that for our age
I will not be using any library so we will probably not use the help but it's very helpful.
All right.
And then this is the Council meaning that when we execute our code our code will be running inside this
console and will execute the training of the AI for what we're going to do.
Perfect.
So that spider and now the first thing we're going to do is go to falx poor and I'm going to go to my
desktop because in my desktop I created this 8:28 in folder that will contain all the code will be implementing
in this course.
Right now this folder is empty but it is this folder that will contain the file that we're about to
create and which will contain the whole artificial intelligence.
We will build in this course we will actually build several ones but we will start with the main one
that will contain the heart of the artificial intelligence following exactly this new research paper
that just came out in 2018 in March 2018 and then we'll connect the AI to the environment to train it
to accomplish what we want to do.
I'll get to there soon.
But we will build the AI here and our file will be saved in this folder.
I.
So feel free to do the same.
And if that's the case you're ready to click on file at the top.
Click on new file.
This will be the pipe and file this will contain the AI implementations.
Now you can close that.
And now you can select all this delete then added Tyrel we're going to get to this implementation the
following title.
So you have to put a hash tag first because the title has to be in a comment hash tag.
And then let's just call it a 20:18.
All right.
We're going to build the AI 20:18 the most powerful AI 2018.
And actually I think it is the most powerful AI AI mole ever built because you're going to see how it
surpasses any score at least on the environment that we're going to try.
All right.
So that's the title.
Let's just start with this and then we're going to save.
And we can just call it a r s because indeed the ideas we're going to build is called commented random
search.
So let's save that.
And here we go.
We are ready to start the Egmond and random search.
So we'll stop here for this to toile then in the next one hour introduce you to the environment.
I'll introduce you to the research paper Kiril explain the whole intuition behind it.
But since you know we're going to go back and forth jumping from the research paper into the code because
I want to show you exactly what we're coding with respect to the research paper.
I prefer to already introduce it to you so that we can already get familiar with it.
Perfect.
So I'll see you in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy AI.