Hello and welcome back to the course on augmented random search in today's tutorial We quickly go and
have a look at where you can find the supplementary materials for this course.
So if you open up your browser and go to Supertech science dot com slash a r s That's a superset of
science is one word dot com slash Erris you will find the page that is dedicated to specifically this
course.
And here is where we have shared all of the supplementary materials for this training and that includes
all of the additional reading that we have listed for instance blog posts or articles or research papers
that are highly relevant to what we discuss and search intervals or that we found interesting and insightful.
And you can find all the links here.
And also you will be able to find the code that we will be creating the practical side of the tutorials
so you will be coding along with that line and you'll be able to create that code yourself.
But if you'd like to download it and follow along that way or compared to your code maybe just make
adjustments to it.
Then we're also sharing here and you can download it and keep it as a template that's really for you
to explore.
So on that note I really hope you enjoy the course and check out this page to make sure you download
all the materials for your training to have your training.
And I look forward to seeing you on the next tutorial.
Until then enjoy.