[Autogenerated] Welcome to the kubernetes for developers moving
from Docker Compose to Kubernetes course.
My name's Dan Wall Lean, and I'm a software developer,
architect and trainer specializing in development
container and cloud technologies.
I'm really excited to talk with you about different techniques that could be
used to move your containers from Docker Compose to Kubernetes.
So we'll start off the course with a quick review of Docker Compose
and Kubernetes concepts and see how Docker Compose services map two
different kubernetes resource is.
From there you'll learn about Docker stack commands and how they can
be used with Docker desktop to deploy containers to kubernetes using
an existing Docker Compose YAML file.
This is one of the easiest ways to get started moving your
containers from Docker Compose to Cooper Nets.
Next,
you'll learn about an open source project called Composed that could be used
to convert Docker Compose files into Kubernetes manifest.
Using only a single command,
you learn about the Kubernetes XAML that's generated and modifications
that you may end up making as the course progresses.
You'll also learn about a tool called scaffold that could be used
to convert a Docker Compose YAML file into Kubernetes manifest
files and how it can also be used to do live development against
the Kubernetes cluster.
Finally,
we'll put all these concepts together and demonstrate using
Docker stack commands composed and scaffold to move an
application from Docker Compose to Kubernetes.
So with that,
let's get started with a quick review and learn how Docker Compose maps to kubernetes.