[Autogenerated] in this final module.
We're gonna put everything together that we've learned up to this point.
I'm gonna walk you through a different application,
though that has more services and see how we could
still use Docker stacks with it,
as well as the composed tool to do our conversions.
So we're going to start this module off with a review of using Docker stacks,
but with a different application.
Once we get that application up and running and kubernetes,
then we're gonna review how we can use composed convert to actually convert
more complex Docker Compose file into kubernetes XAML files.
And then we're going to revisit the scaffold tool that we looked at
earlier and see how it could be used again for live development and
moving from Docker Compose right into Kubernetes.
Now,
the application that I'm gonna walk you through has been used in
my Docker for web developers course and also throughout the
Kubernetes for developers learning path.
And you can get to it here.
GitHub dot com slash dan wall lean code with Dan Docker services.
Really,
all you need to do is clone it or download and extract the zip file and
you have everything that I'll be showing momentarily.
Let's go ahead and get started by reviewing how to use Docker stacks with this new application.