[Autogenerated] let's get started talking about what we're
gonna be covering throughout this course.
So we're going to start things off by talking about Docker Compose and
kubernetes and mapping those two technologies together.
If you've worked with Docker Compose,
then you're probably familiar with Docker Compose services
and some of the YAML file you can write.
But how does that actually map up against kubernetes re
sources such as deployments and pods?
Different networking techniques, services, things like that.
We'll talk about that,
and I'll provide a visual to help you map those two together.
From there,
we're gonna talk about how we can move from Docker Compose to Kubernetes
using Docker desktop and something called Docker Stat.
And you might have heard of Docker swore more swarm mode before.
But if not, I'm gonna show you a really simple setting.
You could enable in Docker desktop That'll make it so they
could just use Docker Compose Azure source but actually
run your app in kubernetes.
Next up is gonna be talking about moving from Docker Compose
to kubernetes using a tool called composed,
but you'll notice this has a K.
This is an open source tool that will actually
translate your Docker Compose services.
Yamil into Kubernetes manifest file YAML file.
So it'll do all that translation that we're gonna talk about early
on in the course and kind of map that for you,
you're more than likely have to go in and change it as I'll talk about,
do a few tweaks here and there.
But it provides a great way to get started and will save you a lot of time.
From there.
We're gonna talk about a really cool,
open source tool from Google called Scaffold and Scaffold.
Actually,
uses compose under the covers so it can move from Docker Compose kubernetes.
But it allows you to do live development against Kubernetes.
So, for example, I could actually make a change to code scaffold can detect that,
automatically rebuild the image and then deploy it up to kubernetes.
Now there's gonna be some use cases where maybe rebuilding
the image is just too time consuming.
So I'll show you a few tricks, such as file sinking that we can do.
This is a feature of scaffold and other features that it offers.
Once we've gone through, all those modules will go ahead and put it all together.
I'll review using Docker stack composed and scaffold with some different
projects so that you can get a nice review of the role they can play and how
they can help you move from Docker Compose to Kubernetes.
So now let's move on to talking about the target audience
for the course prerequisite knowledge.
You need to have to get the most out of the course
software that you're going to need, as well as where you can get the code samples.