[Autogenerated] Docker desktop makes it really easy to run
kubernetes on any developer machine that supports it.
And we've covered that and how to enable it in
previous courses in this learning path.
But I'm going to show you how we can not only enable
kubernetes but also override the default behavior of Docker
stat commands Very simple to get enabled.
And I'll show you that process here momentarily.
Now let's ask a couple questions, though, before we go down this route.
So question number one can Docker Compose files be used to
run containers directly in kubernetes?
And the short answer there is not natively?
No.
So if you're not using Docker desktop,
then what I'm gonna show you here is really not gonna
be in the realm of possibilities.
You know, if you're on mini kubectl or even kubectl them the full kubernetes.
This won't work, but the answer is yes.
When Docker desktop is being used and all we have to do is enable a setting in
Docker desktop so that when these Docker stack commands run,
it translates the Docker Compose services into Kubernetes.
Resource is and that all happens like magic.
Really very simple.
And I'll show you that process coming up now.
Question number two What are Docker stacks or what's the Docker Stack Command?
You may have never heard of that one,
especially if you've never used the older term was Docker
Swarm or the newer one is swarm mode now.
Docker swarm.
The original version of all This was a way to do what Kubernetes does,
and it's still available.
It's now swarm mode, as I mentioned,
but it allows us to create a cluster and run our
containers across multiple nodes.
We can scale them.
They could be monitored.
They could be healed all those type of things that
you see with kubernetes in general.
So Docker stack commands out of the box are used to manage this swarm mode.
Clustering, however, with the check of a check box we can switch it.
So instead of creating a swarm cluster,
it can actually put all of our containers into pods within kubernetes.
Create the necessary services for communication and all of that type of thing.
So it actually allows you to keep using your standard Docker Compose file,
but actually run that app up in kubernetes on your machine.
So it's a nice little compromise approach.
You could take if you don't want to take the time to translate
Docker Compose all the way to the Kubernetes resource files Now I'll
show you how to do this on Mac and windows.
They look pretty much identical these days.
And all we have to do is go into the coup Pernetti settings and
check a check box which will see right here for deployed Docker
stacks to kubernetes by default again.
Normally you have to do a swarm initializer phase,
run a command and get your Docker swarm configured and enabled.
But by checking this check box,
you can override that default behavior and make it so
it runs these up in kubernetes.
Now let me jump over to macOS are and show you and you'll
notice when I go up to the wail icon we can,
come on into the preferences and go down to kubernetes and all
you have to do is check this box right here.
Now this one If you watched any of the prior courses in this learning path,
this is what you, of course, enable to get Kubernetes going.
But this one will allow us to actually run Docker Compose files
against kubernetes using these Docker stat commands that I'll be
showing you coming up here now, on Windows,
it looks almost identical.
We can come down into our tray right-click on the Docker
icon and go to settings in this case.
And then from here it's gonna look identical to what you saw on the Mac side.
We can come down to kubernetes and then enable kubernetes.
And then, of course, check the box from here We apply and restart.
That'll start everything back up.
But it's pretty quick normally and you're ready to do so.
That's all we would need to do in Docker desktop to do this.
Now, if you are on something else aside from Docker desktop,
unfortunately, you're not gonna have this option. So for this particular module, you are gonna need Docker desktop, Of course.