[Autogenerated] So what is scaffold?
Well, based on what you've heard so far,
you probably know that it could be used to convert
from Docker Compose to Kubernetes.
Otherwise, it probably wouldn't be in this course,
but it could do some other things as well.
I like to think of it this way.
Scaffold equals local kubernetes development.
Now, what I mean by that is when you use Docker Compose on its own,
it just runs containers locally and handles orchestrating those containers.
But it has nothing to do with kubernetes now.
What's nice about it, though, is it can automatically build the images,
run the containers and help you out that way,
what scaffold does is very similar.
It can also build your images and deploy your containers.
But it will deploy those containers to the Kubernetes
cluster that you choose now by default if you're running
something like Docker desktop,
which I'll be doing or mini cube and it's just going to
use your local Kubernetes cluster.
But there are additional configuration options for running in a
different cluster that might be located somewhere off Prem,
for example, here's how they officially define it.
Scaffold handles the workflow for building,
pushing and deploying your application,
allowing you to focus on what matters most riding code.
And that's what this is all about.
If you, for instance,
had a micro service type scenario and you want to run a
bunch of containers simultaneously but maybe only develop
against one or two of those,
then scaffold would make it where you could still run everything in
kubernetes as it would be more a production scenario.
But as you change your code, it can redeploy those change containers,
and it even has some sinking features to speed that up.
If you just need to redeploy some files and I'll
walk you through some of that now, when it comes to Docker Compose and scaffold,
Scaffold actually uses the composed tool,
the one that we covered previously.
The starts with the K,
and we know that that composed tool could be used to convert from
Docker Compose to kubernetes manifest files.
Well, to do that, there's a command we're gonna cover called Scaffold in it.
And it has a command line flag where we can defined the
Docker Compose file under the covers.
It will then run a process,
which is gonna be the composed process we covered earlier and then
there going to output those Yamil files for kubernetes.
Now it's also going to generate a type of build artifact file.
We call it scaffold dot YAML file.
And this is gonna be the file that will monitor your local code for changes,
automatically rerun the Docker bill process and then even handle
the deployment of that updated image to get that container for the
image running in a pot in kubernetes.
So you can think of this as someone analogous to the
YAML file you'll see in kubernetes.
But it's very specific to building your scaffolding artifacts.
So here's what a scaffold IT YAML file might look like.
First off,
you'll notice it has an API version a kind and metadata much
like you'd see with Kubernetes manifest.
And we're gonna define whatever the latest version is
of scaffold in the API versioning.
Now moving on down to the build section, you'll notice that we have artifacts.
In this case,
we're gonna have an image called engine NICs jumpstart the context
of where it's gonna be watching for changes to,
for instance,
source code files is gonna be the local folder
wherever the scaffold that YAML file is,
and then our Docker file is also located in that location,
at least in this example.
Now what will happen there is as we change our code,
it will detect that and then automatically rebuild the
image and deploy that to kubernetes.
Now, how does it know how to deploy the kubernetes, though?
Well, as I mentioned earlier, under the covers,
these scaffolding Nick cmdlet,
are going to Learn more about uses these composed tool to convert your
Docker Compose file to kubernetes manifest files.
So by running that it will generate the files and then we can
point it to those with the manifest property that you see at the
bottom here and now under the covers,
it will run a kubectl command against the K S folder and all
the Yamil files that are inside of it.
So here's how this whole process kind of breaks down more visually.
First off, it can detect source code changes,
and it has a built in file sync to monitor those changes.
Then we'll go ahead and build your artifacts,
make sure they're working properly,
even tagged them and then render the manifest that are
needed so that they could be deployed.
Once that happens,
then we would have an actual pod with containers in kubernetes.
And then it can even tell the logs and even do port 40.
Now telling the logs, if you're not familiar with that,
it basically exposes the logs to us so that we can see those directly,
for example, in a console if we wanted.
Now, once we're done with this, if you just hit control C to stop the console,
then it will automatically do a kubectl delete type process and clean
up all the different resource is that we might have.
And that's actually really, really nice.
So you can get more information about this at the pipeline stages
link that you're going to see towards the bottom.
But everything I'm gonna be showing you is gonna go through this process,
and it happens kind of automatically again just by running a single command. So before we look at those commands, let's see how we can get scaffold installed