[Autogenerated] getting the composed tool installed is a really
straightforward process on Mac windows or Linux.
So I'm gonna walk you through that process,
show you the docks and you'll see that literally within a few
minutes you can have it up and running.
So currently I'm on Mac and I've gone to the composed iOS website.
This will give you some basic information,
help get you started and even have installation instructions.
But what I found is that sometimes it could be out of sync with the GitHub repo.
Normally, the GitHub repose up to date on the installation,
and this one might lag a little bit.
So I'm gonna recommend you actually click on the GitHub repository link,
and we're gonna go to that instead.
And if I scroll on down,
you'll see that we have installation instructions and
specifically for Linux and Max.
Your going to do almost the same thing.
You're gonna do a curl command on Linux or on Mac do a commode,
and then you're gonna copy that binary over to a specific folder,
and then you could use the tool.
Very simple.
Once we're done getting that going on my Mac here.
Well, then do the same thing for Windows,
but I'll show you what is required there.
So the first thing I'm gonna do is grab the curl command syntax here and
copy it into my clipboard and then go to a command prompt.
And we're just gonna run this to download the binary that we need.
Somebody pace that in.
We'll hit in her.
And this will take just a second or two to get this downloaded.
All right, Now, the next step will be the charm.
Odd command.
So we're gonna run that.
Now that that's done, we're going to copy it over with the pseudo command.
So we're gonna do a move of composed to usr slash local bin composed.
So you could see I'm basically just following the
instructions that you see right here.
All right, so we'll go ahead and do that.
Enter my password, and we're done.
So let me go ahead and clear this.
And now what we can do is type compose,
and this should show us the initial help documentation for how to use the tool.
All right.
And there we go.
Let me go ahead and go full screen on that.
And if we scroll on down.
You're going to notice there's several different commands up here.
We're gonna be looking at the convert one specifically,
but notice there's a help as well.
So let's do that.
And you're going to see us the same thing we just got.
So that command will give you inside into the other commands.
You can run now.
The version obviously will change as time progresses.
But if you want to see what you're on we can do composed version,
and there's the version I'm currently on.
But that would probably be out of date in a week or two.
All right, so that's how we get it going on, Mac.
Now, for Linux, it would be the same exact instructions.
Just make sure you use the Linux and 64 command for curling,
and that would get that binary downloaded.
Then you run the same instructions that you see right here.
Now let's move over to windows.
So on the windows side, you'll see that we're not gonna do a kernel command.
We're actually gonna download Obayan are e from GitHub.
We're gonna add it to our path.
So I'm gonna go ahead and download that and that will just take a second or two.
Looks like it prompted me to try to block it.
In this case, I'm gonna trust it.
So we'll say keep.
And that will take me to here.
I'm gonna go ahead and say, Yeah, I trust it And keep it.
We're gonna do keep anywhere.
Now you're may or may not be prompted on that I'm currently an edge,
and that's what it obviously showed.
So if you do get that, just go through that process,
otherwise it should just download it with a different browser.
So I'm gonna go to the folder of the downloads and what I'm gonna do
here first is rename it to just compose .NET y-axis.
Now, the next thing I'm gonna do is cut it from here and I have a tools folder.
I'm gonna put it in just for this demo.
You might have a different folder where you wanna put it.
I'll go ahead and paste it into the tools folder in order to
get to this from anywhere on my machine,
I need to add this.
See Docker tools path that you see up top here into my path.
So to do that,
I'm gonna come down to the search and I'm gonna type E n v and
we can edit the system environment variables.
So I'll go ahead and click on that.
Well, then click on the environment Variables button.
And now you need to make a choice.
You can either update the path for just your account or
you could do it for the entire system.
It really depends if it's just your machine or other people are using it.
I normally update the system once because this is my machine.
I'm going to select path and click at it and notice I've already added it.
But from here,
we could do new and then just type C Docker slash or whatever your path is
right there and save it just like you see I did here.
Now that should be in my path.
And if I type composed, which we're gonna do in a moment,
I should build to get to the tool as well.
Let's go ahead and close out of here and we're ready to go.
So now let me open a command problem.
Now I'm gonna open the windows terminal.
This is something you can download from the windows store or online,
and this is multiple shells in one.
Right now, it's defaulting a PowerShell,
but you'll see that I can do the typical command PowerShell.
I have a window subsystem for Linux going even Azure cloud shell,
and it's really nice if you haven't seen it.
So let's try this out.
You'll notice I am not in the Sea Docker Tools folder.
But go ahead and clear this.
I'm gonna tie it, compose,
and there we do I can do compose version and there's my versioning.
So now we're ready to go.
We can now use this tool with the convert command you'll see in the help there, and that's what we're gonna look at next.