[Autogenerated] Now that we've seen how to enable
Docker stack support for kubernetes,
you might be wondering what are Docker stack commands in the first place?
After all,
if you haven't used them before and you've only
done the standard Docker commands, these might be something that you're going.
I don't even know what that is, Dan.
Well, I'm here to tell you, so let's jump on in.
So, Docker stat commands have been around for quite a while,
but if you haven't been using swarm mode before then
you probably haven't used them.
But they allow you to take a Docker Compose file with
services in it and deploy that to a swarm.
Basically a cluster somewhat like kubernetes.
Actually.
Now, the first command you'd want to know about is called Docker Stack deploy,
and this command allows you to pass it a Docker Compose file.
It will then parse out all the services in that file
and then deploy those to a swarm.
Now, that's the normal mode.
When we check the check box to override Docker stack
commands and run them in kubernetes.
Then of course, it will parse that Yamil from Docker Compose get the services,
but translate all of that to kubernetes resource is which is
actually a really cool way to kind of try your app out without
having to translate all that Docker Compose stuff over to
Kubernetes XAML now another commanders Docker stack ls we can list
the stacks that have been deployed.
We can also see the different tasks that are running with E.
P s command.
We can remove a stack with RM and we can actually just
list all the services in a given stack.
And that's the Docker Stack services Command.
Now, one thing to understand when I say services at this level,
we're talking Docker Compose services because,
of course, if you do kubernetes,
we know KUBERNETES also has services and that's related to networking.
Very different use cases for those terms,
so kind of make sure that's clear in your mind.
We have Docker Compose services,
and that would be like you're running ASP.NET core Node.js a database
that'd be a service that you want to contain arise.
And then, of course, we have kubernetes services, which are for networking.
All right, so now that we've seen some of that,
let's dive in a little bit deeper to the key commands here.
The main one you need to know about is Docker Stack
deploy and then we can give it this dash.
See,
now this represents the composed file and we simply
give it the name of that file.
In this case, I'm using the standard name Docker Compose XAML.
Then after that, we put the name of the stack.
Now, this could be any valid names,
so you can put food fo fum or maybe more valid name than that.
And assuming that you've checked that box that I showed earlier,
what will happen is it will translate the Docker Compose file and
run it in your local kubernetes on Docker desktop.
It makes it really easy again to just keep a
Docker Compose file in your project,
but still run that in kubernetes without having to be a kubernetes guru.
Now, once you've deployed a stack, you can run Docker stack ls.
And that would simply list all the deployed stacks that we have running.
And you can also now run to kubernetes and you could do kubectl
commands and you could do kubectl get all,
for example or kubectl get pods.
And if you had, you know, five services,
then you're probably at a minimum going to C five pods deployed into kubernetes.
And then finally, when you're done,
just like you could do Docker Compose up and Docker Compose down and
then you can even remove You could do Docker stack,
remove RM and then give it that name of the stack that you used when
you first deployed it when you first created it,
that will take care of them.
Cleaning up all those services that we have in our Docker Compose
file from our kubernetes resource is so you could see that doing
this is actually pretty straightforward.
And like I said,
if you're not looking to translate Docker Compose into
all the cooper nadie XAML files,
then this is certainly an option you could consider if you just want to see
how your app runs in kubernetes with those containers.
So now that we've talked about some of these commands, let's put them into action.