[Autogenerated] All right, well,
now let's switch our focus to using composed convert,
and let's see it in action.
So I'm gonna use the same demonstration app that I showed in earlier module.
You can get to it here on GitHub, and it already has a Docker Compose YAML file.
It also already has some kubernetes files as well.
In fact, if you just want to get it up and running,
you could check out the README.
But I'm gonna start from scratch and convert that Docker Compose file
into kubernetes XAML files using the composed tool.
So as a quick review from the previous module,
the Docker Compose file is right here.
You'll see.
And this has two main things inside of it.
It has an engine ex container,
and this will be used to serve up a front end JavaScript type application.
And then that calls into a back end API, which is note and then optionally.
If you're on Linux or Mac, you can uncommon at this.
See advisor, that's a container monitoring type tool.
And you could run that as well.
But I'm just gonna run the top two,
and what we're gonna do is convert this over these to services to
our Kubernetes services and deployment files.
So the first thing I'm gonna do is make a directory in here.
You'll see I already have one called .NET V8 s,
and that's where the existing Kubernetes files are.
But let's say we wanted to start from scratch and work with this.
So I'm gonna come on in and we'll just click on new folder.
We'll give this a name.
I'm just going to call it output.
But you can name it, whatever you want.
And then we're gonna go ahead and from the root of this project,
you'll see I'm already in that.
I'm gonna go ahead and run the composed command and
show you what it generates by default.
Now, if I just do this, if I do compose,
convert and just hit inner, it's gonna add files at the root of this directory.
So let me go ahead and do that and you'll notice it gives me the output.
And then if we go to source control here,
you'll see that all these got to added So we have a network policy
of deployment of service and then that's for Engine X and then one
for note as well now that's great.
That's working.
But that's not what I want because it's not in my folder.
So let me go ahead and undo that and let's go back now and let's do it again.
But this time we're gonna use the dash O or dash Dash out,
and that will allow us to say where we want the output
to be written as a quick review.
If we do compose, convert, Dash H we can,
get all the different command line flags you could see here.
And if we come up top, you'll notice I can do like helm charts we talked about.
We could control what type of controller gets generated.
Deployment is the default,
but you could also do Damon sets or replication controllers.
Do I want JSON data?
There's the Dachau or out.
Do I just want to do standard out?
It really depends on what you want to do.
In fact, let's do a standard out real quick.
We'll go back up to compose, convert and let's do dash,
dash STD out and there we go,
so you'll notice it just kind of dumps that to the standard out in this case,
happens to be my console and now you can kind of scroll
through and see what is going to generate.
Now what I'm gonna do, though,
is we're gonna write it to this output folder that you saw.
So instead of doing that, we're gonna say Dash,
dash out or Dachau would work as well.
Then I'm gonna say output or you might even be more official and say dot,
slash output.
We'll go ahead and hit.
Enter and there we do.
Now you'll notice that all of these were not written to the output folder.
Okay, so let's go take a look at that folder here and there we go.
We have all those and we'll take a closer look a little bit later here.
Now, if I didn't want a folder instead, I wanted to write these just to a file.
Then we could do the same thing.
But I could put the name of the file.
Let's just say we want to call it out.
Put .NET XAML.
So now, instead of going to a folder,
it'll pipe that output to this particular file,
which works out really well.
If you like that again, I like to have.
The separate resource is like you see here, but everybody is different.
So let's come on down and there we do.
There's an output .NET XAML Let's go ahead and open that and it's
basically going to stack all of these together.
All right, now to review one that I do find myself using a fair amount.
Let's go ahead and we'll clean this up here.
Delete that, and we'll leave our output for now.
What happens when you have a Docker Compose file that's named differently?
Well, that's where we could do dash F or dash cache file.
You might have done this before because it's not knew you
could do this with Docker Compose as well,
because when you do a Docker Compose build or up or down,
or whatever it may be,
sometimes your file might be named different from the default.
So you have to tell it, of course.
So we do the same thing here we could say composed,
convert, dash F or dash cache file.
And then maybe it was Docker Compose dot staging.
Let's just say got to XAML and maybe we have multiple.
We could just do another dash F if we had multiple Well,
now this will are because I don't have that file,
so you'll see un able to load the YAML file.
But that's what you would do if you had a separate type of file.
That's not following the default naming convention now.
What's so great about all of this, obviously,
is that now we have a really good starting point.
It may not be exactly what you want.
In fact, I can almost guarantee it won't be exactly what you want,
but it gives you a great starting point.
Now you can go in to lead the stuff you don't want, tweak the stuff you need.
It's a lot better than starting from scratch.
So to wrap up any time you want to do this conversion
to remember what you need to do, remember,
there's the Dash H and that will give me all these
different flags that we can work with.
And I didn't show everyone that we covered earlier like replicas or volumes.
But those are options you'll see down here.
So now that we've seen this in action, let's take a closer look at these XAML. It generates