[Autogenerated] Now let's do a quick review of Kubernetes.
So we know that Kubernetes is an open source system and it
really is all about automating deployments,
scaling and then managing your containers.
They're running within your pots.
So Kubernetes itself has a master node and that kind
of access the main command center, if you will.
That communicates out to the worker nodes that you see down here below.
And they, of course, run the pods, which run the containers.
Now the way we can send commands into the Master Control center or
the master node is through the kubectl command,
and we'll be talking about just a few of those basic
commands as a quick review here.
Now,
where Kubernetes provides a ton of value is in the
different resource types that it has.
So the lowest level resource is a pod,
and we know that that's where our containers run.
And then, of course, we have different ways to deploy these pods.
We can do blue green deployments and canary deployments and
rolling update deployments and all kinds of fun stuff
through the deployment resource.
Then that relies on replica sets to ensure that the desired
number of pods and the current number of pods match up when it
comes to network communication.
We have services that handles knowing the IP address of the different
pots so that if they get removed and a new one comes up,
we don't have to change anything in our application.
It just knows about what's called the Cluster IP.
And then, of course, we can also work with storage,
we can, store, key value pairs and CONFIG.
Maps and we can even store secrets.
Sensitive data.
Now that's a quick review of the main resource is that
we've covered in the prior courses in this learning path
on Kubernetes for developers.
When it comes to the Yamil in Kubernetes,
there's quite a bit because each of these resource
is could have its own YAML file.
But the main one will typically work with is Deployments.
Here's an example of a deployment for an engine X front end server.
So we have our API and our type.
We have our metadata.
Our labels, of course,
are how we can hook different Kubernetes Resource is together,
so because this has a label of my engine X,
a service could target that label And that app My engine
X would now be part of that service.
That way,
the cluster IP s of the different pods deployed here would be known Now.
The selector, of course, is how we say,
here's our specifications are spec for our deployment.
That, of course, jumps down into the pod template.
Select the tear front end in this case.
And then we've already talked about how we have the internet,
Alpine as the image, and that's the type of gamble that will be seen.
So whether you've worked a lot with kubernetes or
you're a little bit newer to it,
we'll see quite a bit of this as we move along throughout the course,
a quick review of the commands would give us these.
We'd have our kubectl get and the get could get pods,
get deployments, get replica sets services,
or we could just get everything get all we can create.
Resource is from scratch.
And then, in this case,
we're using the dash F switch to to find a YAML file to create that resource.
And then, of course,
we could update a resource or create it using the kubectl apply command.
Same scenario.
Here we have the dash F that we're capturing now.
From there we can also do things like port forward.
We know that in Kubernetes our pods get cluster IP s and
those are internal by default to the cluster.
So outside of the cluster, we can't get to those by default.
But we can use the kubectl Port forward Command to handle
that type of scenario if we'd like.
And then, of course,
we could even set up load balancer services and other types of
services to get into our different pods as well.
So the different resource is that we just talked about are
gonna be pretty critical when we talk about moving from
Docker Compose to Kubernetes.
That's why earlier I mentioned that having some background
knowledge on these resource is will really help you out because
now we'll start diving into the map VPNs between Docker Compose
and Kubernetes resources. Let's go ahead and look at that next