[Autogenerated] All right,
So now that we've reviewed the Docker Compose
concepts and the kubernetes concepts,
it's time to start talking about kind of mapping between those two worlds.
So if you're currently on Docker Compose,
then you're gonna have your Docker Compose YAML file,
of course.
And if you want to go to KUBERNETES,
then we need to convert at least part of that file into a
deployment because that will create the pods,
which then run the containers.
We also need networking, though,
so we're gonna have services and then potentially in your Docker Compose,
you might have things like volumes, environment,
variables and other things.
And we could use some of our storage and config maps and
potentially secrets to handle that.
So one of the big changes is gonna be Instead of having this one main file,
you're gonna be converting that generally into multiple files.
Of course, with kubernetes, you could put all your resource is in one huge file.
If you wanted ID,
argue that it might be a little more difficult to find
things as that file gets really large.
But you could do that.
So to go from Yamil over to Kubernetes, at a minimum,
we need deployments and services, but we certainly may need some of the other.
Resource is as well,
and that means that we're gonna have to take that
Yamil from the Docker Compose file,
translate it to whatever Kubernetes has for deployments,
services, the pod template and anything else that's involved.
So let's take a look at a Docker Compose XAML file and see what the
mapping would look like to kubernetes resources.
So in this example, we have the standard suspects we have.
Our version are services.
In this case, we just have a node services and notice.
We have a container name image, ports volumes,
some environment variables being loaded from a file,
and then we have our bridge network.
Now that's enough to get us thinking about how this would map over and
which parts of the kubernetes XAML files would be involved.
Let's take the first part of this.
If we were to to find the container name,
the image and the ports, Well, that's something that,
if you know,
deployments it all in pod templates we could put inside of
the deployment Yamil and then in our speck,
we point to the pod template and this type of information
highlighted here could be put in that Yamil.
So that be one of the first things now?
Volumes.
Okay, well, in Kubernetes, there's a lot of different volumes,
so it really depends on the type of volume you want.
But we'll sum it up by saying that would be a storage type of
concept when it comes to the Yamil for kubernetes.
What about environment variables?
Well,
config maps can do handle that and you can store that config
map data in kubernetes and then have it exposed it either as
files or environment variables.
So we could also say that storage slash config maps would
be used for that particular scenario.
Of course, we need networking between multiple containers.
I'm only showing one hair,
but let's assume that we could have many services like we showed earlier.
And so that would be, of course, the service concept.
And instead of having the bridge network by default, we have our cluster IP s.
But then we could have our Notepad services,
load balancer services or whatever it may be that your application needs.
So that's the type of process we're gonna have to think
through as we convert Docker Compose into kubernetes
because there is gonna be some work.
Now, the good news is to do this locally,
we can actually use some features in Docker desktop,
and I'm gonna show you that coming up in the next module Later on,
we're gonna talk about the tool called Composed that I mentioned in the
course agenda and it would convert What you see here on the left over to
the appropriate resource is on the right.
So this composed tool can really help you out with that move
so that you don't have to know all the map ings and write all
that Yamil and get it right.
It'll get you started in the right direction.
So that's a wrap on this first module to review Docker Compose,
review kubernetes and then start to discuss how we would map
Docker Compose sections to our different Kubernetes resources.
So let's go ahead and wrap up with the summary and then we'll move on from there.