[Autogenerated] virtual private cloud allows developers to create a virtual
network where they can launch resources and have them logically isolated from
other V P C s and the outside world with a VPc.
Your resources have private iP addresses with which
they can communicate with each other.
You can control access to all of the resources inside a VPc
and route outgoing traffic as you'd like.
VPC is also a free service in AWS,
although you can only have a maximum of five iPcs on one account.
The only charges are if you need a special VPN connection,
which we won't be doing in this course,
there are several key structures used in VPc s to configure access.
So let's take a look at them.
The most important and widely used tool that VPC s
introduce our security groups.
A security group defines a collection of pipes that are allowed to connect to
your instance and IPs that instance is allowed to connect to.
Security groups are attached at the instance level and
can be shared among many instances.
You can even set security group rules to allow access from other
security groups instead of by IP We are going to be using security
groups a lot as we start creating instances.
So we'll talk more about them in the coming modules.
Bp CSU's routing tables to configure routing
destinations for traffic coming out of the VPC.
Each VPC has one routing table which declares attempted
destination IPs and where they should be routed to.
For instance, if you want to run all outgoing traffic through a proxy.
You can set a routing table rule to automatically send traffic to that IP This
can be a powerful tool for security as you can inspect outgoing traffic and
only white lists safe destinations for traffic.
Another tool the VPC is used for networking control is
the network access control list.
Each VPC has one access control list and this acts as an IP
filtering table saying which pipes are allowed through the VPc
for both incoming and outgoing traffic.
Access control lists are kind of like super powered security
groups that apply rules for the entire VPc.
I don't typically mess with network access control lists as I
much prefer the flexibility of security groups,
but they are an important aspect of a VPc configuration.
A VPC defines a private, logically isolated area,
for instance,
is but a sub net is where things really get interesting
instances cannot be launched into just a VPc.
They must also be launched into a sub Net that is inside a VPc.
A sub net is an additional isolated area that has its own cider
block routing table and access control list.
Sub nets enable you to create different behavior in the same VPc,
for instance,
creating a public subnets that can be accessed and have access to
the public internet and a private sub net that is not accessible
from the internet and must go through a nat gateway to access to
the outside world with sub nets. You can achieve very secure infrastructure for your instances