[Autogenerated] Aws is a collection of over 170 services to choose
from and develop with most services can operate independently or by
integrating with other services with so many choices and
overlapping levels of functionality.
It can definitely get confusing I don't think calling it a web of
services is that much of a stretch considering how you can easily
get stuck in trying to understand it all.
And the more you thrash around, the more confusing it gets in this course,
we're going to move calmly through this web and avoid getting caught in it.
Instead,
we're going to look at a W S as a whole to understand how everything
interacts together most services in a W S R access with a TCP
connection often this might simply be HTTP but sometimes can use a
designated port based on the service.
Each instance of a service oftentimes called a resources given a local
IP address with which other services can communicate with it.
This IP is not connected to the outside world,
although you can also assign an external IP if needed.
Alternately,
some services should be referenced by their amazon resource
names instead of IP like dynamodb for instance,
and I should say this setup is true for most services where there is a
resource created some of amazon services aren't resource based and so
won't be used this way being able to connect to resources this way means
that there isn't any magic going on.
The connection may just be an http request,
which you should be familiar with already.
The core of the web of amazon web services is elastic.
Cloud compute also called EC two.
You can think of this as a service that provides servers
where your application will be running.
You see to actually forms the basis of many other services as well,
such as relational database service and elastic beanstalk.
We'll spend plenty of time on ec two and learn all the ins and outs
of the service as well as many more in this class.
although seemingly complex at first,
once you start working with some of these services,
the true nature of this web will become clear each
service interacts slightly different,
but the core principles of how AWS functions will become familiar as you work with them.