[Autogenerated] elastic compute cloud or EC two is one of the longest
running services on AWS and it powers many of the other service innovations
that amazon has created an EC two instance is just a virtual machine
provisioned with a certain amount of CPU cores,
gigabytes of memory, storage, space and network performance.
Because of this,
you can install essentially any type of operating
system or software on it that you want.
Typical options are Linux or Windows keeping in mind that any operating
system that requires a license will cost more per hour.
Amazon's own flavor of Linux is definitely the cheapest and
is well maintained and updated regularly.
The operating system and software that is installed on an EC two instance is
also called an amazon machine image or am I The easiest AM eyes to install
are just Linux or Windows operating systems.
But beyond that,
AMS can also be customized by you with your own software installed
or you can use images from the AWS marketplace,
some of the types of images on the AWS marketplace.
Our security appliance like firewalls and anti virus software
or business intelligence applications that would consume and
analyzed data from RDS or dynamo DB.
Each ec two instance has a certain group of technical specifications
and Amazon charges you based on what type of instance you're running
instances that have more CPUS or memory will cost more than those
with less if you're running an application that needs more memory
like a web application.
For instance,
there is a family of instances called memory optimized that have a
certain ratio of CPU to memory that favors more memory.
On the other hand,
the compute optimized instances have a ratio more
favorable to CPU units with these options.
You should decide what your application needs when creating
your instance and provisions accordingly.
EC two instances also require some storage for things like the
operating system and any application code you expect to upload
storage for ec two instances uses another AWS service called
elastic block store or E B S.
E B S allows the storage of your EC two instance to live
independently of the instance itself.
This means that if configured correctly,
your ebs storage volumes can be transferred between
different sized Ec two instances or continue to exist even
after an instance has been terminated.
Now let's take a quick look at the pieces of the ec two dashboard.
This section gives you a snapshot of your resources that you've
created instances are the ec two instances that you have volumes
are the elastic block store volumes.
The launch instance button is the quickest route to launching a new eC.
Two instance on the left side is the menu of ec two features and
there are even more than you can see here.
So you'll need to scroll down but you can at least see the instant section.
Am I.
S for your custom amazon machine images and the elastic
block store volumes in the next clip.
We're going to start using most of the options in this dashboard, so let's get to it.