[Autogenerated] Dynamodb is amazon's other solution for
storing data in AWS as you saw with RDS.
There are many options for relational type databases,
but what if you want to use a data storage type that is not
relational dynamodb is your best choice for this in AWS.
What do I mean by not relational?
Well, in relational databases,
they're built in ways to relate different tables in the database.
Usually by using keys.
This makes querying and storing data very structured and in some ways modular.
In addition,
each table has a strict schema that must be followed for each row of data.
No SQL or non relational databases,
throw all that out the window and just store data in
tables without much configuration.
There is no set schema.
So you can change what data you're storing at any time.
The main structure and dynamo dB is a table.
A table contains many rows of data called items that have whatever schema
you give them at the time of putting them in the table.
The one set aspect of your items is that they do need
to include the same primary key.
This is used to index the data and make it efficient
to query items based on that key.
You've only got a few different types to choose from.
For this primary key string number or binary.
Besides the key options,
the only other really configurable property of a table is
the provision through put capacity.
This defines how many read or write operations can happen in a given second and
tells a W S how much hardware to provision for your table.
Since there's no instance option for a dynamodb table provisioned
throughput is how you prepare your table to take load.
The number represented on the read write throughput capacity is based
on a read or write unit which is four kB in size.
If the item you're reading or writing is larger than that,
it will consume more units.
If you're read, write throughput exceeds the provision amount, A W.
S may throttle the requests to read, write or even deny them.
It's important to right size the provisioned throughput capacity
for your table and since it's a configuration factor that you
can modify on your table as needed,
a Ws makes it easy to get it right over the past few years.
AWS has continued to add features to dynamodb to make it even more usable.
two main features have been added in relation to the
throughput capacity for your tables.
The first is on demand capacity mode which is a set it and
forget it capacity mode and the second is auto scaling for
the provisioned capacity mode,
which will increase or decrease the provision capacity numbers based on demand.
Let's take a look at both of these by setting your table
or index to the on demand capacity,
mode AWS will provide whatever capacity is needed for your table.
There are few limits to how much capacity can be provided.
So this is a good option if you aren't really sure what your capacity needs.
Maybe the pricing models different with this mode as you'll pay per
request instead of based on a configuration setting for your table
but the flexibility of this capacity.
mode makes it way more expensive as you can imagine.
So I really recommend only using it for analysis purposes.
Then there's the auto scaling feature for provision capacity.
Remember provision capacity is where you explicitly configure how many
capacity units you'll need for reading and writing Auto scaling enables you
to add additional rules that increase or decrease that configured number if
demand increases or decreases just like an auto scaling group for ec two
instances this is much more appropriate for production workloads as it
maintains the lower cost of the provisioned capacity mode but it gives you
more flexibility.
Azure demand needs change my recommendation when you're working with the new
application is to just set it to on demand capacity mode.
In the very beginning this helps you understand the real world needs of
your project but then after you've been gathering data for a few weeks then
change your tables to provision capacity mode.
Configure appropriate auto scaling rules based on the information
that you've gathered that will set you up for the most cost effective and performance usage of dynamodb