[Autogenerated] in order to develop an AWS, we first need to create an account.
If you have an existing account,
just follow along to make sure all steps have been completed
navigating your browser to the console,
login page at console dot aWS dot amazon dot com.
After creating your account, this is where you will also log in,
click the, create a new AWS account button in the next screen.
You'll enter the email address you want associated with the account,
a password and a name for the account.
The following screen will be for contact information,
which will be a physical address that AWS can have on file
for you after that is the payment information where you'll
need to enter a credit card number.
Most of the activities in this course will be covered under
the free tier and you can view the details of what's covered
with that by following this link.
Next amazon will want to confirm your identity by sending you an sMS
with a code and to your phone number fell out the capture and then
enter the code you receive in the next screen.
Then you'll need to select a support plan.
So just select the free one.
Once the account creation is completed, you'll be given the option to log in,
log in here with the credentials you just created.
The next step to initializing your AWS account is to configure the AWS cli,
we need to first generate an access key.
This will enable our AWS cli and SDK to correctly access our
account in the top right of the screen.
You should see the name that you created the AWS account with click on
this which opens a menu and select security credentials,
click on the access keys, menu option to expand that section,
it should currently be empty as this is a new account with no access keys.
So click the create new access key button which will pop
up the confirmation box from here.
You can either view the key and secret to copy or download a CSV version.
This key can only be viewed or downloaded once.
So you may want to just download the C.
S.
V.
File.
However, it's easy enough to delete a key and create a new one.
So don't feel too conflicted.
If you just copy it here.
Either way make sure to preserve both the key and secret so that we can
use it to configure our cli And once you're done here,
click the close button now we'll configure the AWS Cli go back
to your command line and enter the command.
AWS configure the first prompt is for the AWS access key.
IDE This is the first string that we copied from the access key window,
paste or type it here.
Hit enter and then we'll be prompted for the AWS secret access key.
This is the second string so paste it here.
The next prompt is for your default region.
This is entirely up to you.
If you want to enter anything here.
Next is the default output format.
You can enter something like Jason or text here.
This is how the output from AWS Cli commands will appear in your command line.
Now we're all set and everything is configured
correctly for the AWS Cli and the AWS SDK.
We can test out a command to see if everything is wired
up correctly in the same command line, execute the command,
a W S E C to describe dash instances and this is going to tell you what ec,
two instances you have in your account.
Well, we shouldn't have any yet.
So the output will be a JSON object with an empty reservations property.
As long as you see something similar to this output,
it means that everything is configured correctly for future development.
I want to add a note here about the AWS demo resources
will be creating in this course.
AWS offers a free tier that allows you to use some resources
for a certain period of time for free, for the 1st 12 months of your account.
This free tier changes regularly what's offered.
So it's important that you take a look at the
documentation before creating resources,
if you're concerned about cost.
I've designed this course so that everything should be in the free tier,
but because you're charged based on how long you are using a resource,
you need to be aware of how long you're leaving those
demo resources running in your account.
If you left,
all the demo resources will create in this course running for an entire month.
He would exhaust the free tier limits and incur charges to help with this.
I've added a video at the end of this course that goes through all the
resources you need to tear down from the course.
Also, if you're taking a break between watching parts of the course,
be aware that any resources that you leave running could end
up charging you because of the nature of A.
W.
S.
And cloud services.
I can't make any guarantees about charges if you
follow the exercises in this course, but with that being said, let's get cloudy.