[Autogenerated] now let's set up our load balancer from the ec two dashboard,
click on load balancers in the resources section and
then click create load balancer.
First we need to select the load balancer type application load
balancers are for web applications that use http and https.
Just like our Pizza lovers application,
there's also network load balancers which focus on lower
level web protocols like TCP and UDP.
And then there's the classic load balancers which are an older
type of load balancer that aWS used to support but that aren't
particularly relevant anymore.
Click the create button in the application load balancer
section Now we need to get the load balancer a name which
will of course be Pizza loader, this will be an internet facing load balancer.
So leave that radio button selected And we'll use IPV4 for our IP address types.
The listener configuration section is basically saying which
ports you want the load balance are listening on.
Usually you'll have two entries,
one for http on port 80 and one for https on port 443.
We don't have an ssl certificate for HTTPS So we'll just go with
regular http on port 80 for our app Next select our Pizza VPc from
the drop-down indicating we want to create the load balancer
inside of our Pizza VPc here.
We need to select two availability zones to enable our load balance are in,
you should have two availability zones to check which are available
here because we created two sub nets and our VPc,
select both of them Now, click next this warning,
lets you know that you aren't using a secure listener like
HTTPS that's fine for us for this demo, go ahead and hit next in the next screen.
We want to make a new security group for our load balancer.
So select that radio button name the security group.
Pizza L B S G.
There is an existing rule accepting connections on Port 80 from anywhere,
which is exactly what we want.
So go ahead and click the next button in this screen will configure how the
load balancer will send requests to our application instances.
It does this by defining a target group and rounding to any instances in
that target group will start by naming the target group.
Pizza T G.
The target type is an ec.
two instance.
So leave the instance radio button selected.
Our protocol is http.
So leave that option selected but our application is
listening on port 3000 not poor 80.
So change the port in this field to 3000 load balancers know
which instances to send requests to by checking their status
with a health check these fields.
Let you configure what protocol to use and the path to hit.
Sometimes applications will have a dedicated health check path but
for our app we can just use the root index page which will be hit by
leaving this slash in the path field.
Now we can click next.
This page will let us register instances with the target group.
You can see it shows that there are currently no
registered targets and the group, If you scroll down,
you should see a short list of instances including your pizza dash oge instance,
select that and since and then click add to registered now our load
balancer will send requests to our Pizza Hoagie instance,
click next to review and then create.
Now there is one last configuration step we need with the load balancer,
we need to ensure that if a user logs into our app in one
easy to instance that they continue to connect to that same
instance with subsequent requests.
If we didn't do this,
there's a possibility that they would hit an instance where they don't
have a session to avoid this situation entirely.
Let's enable stickiness on the load balancer.
The load balancer will use a cookie to keep track of which
users should be sent to which instances click close and will
be taken back to the load balancer.
List sessions, stickiness is configured in the target group,
so click on the target groups, menu option on the left,
select the Pizza T G target group you created and in the group
details at the bottom there is an attribute section,
click edit and then select the checkbox next to stickiness.
The duration for instance,
stickiness is set at one day by default which is the same as our app,
so leave it as is now click save changes and session stickiness is set up on our load balancer