[Autogenerated] CloudFormation is a tool offered by amazon to use
configuration data to create and configure resources in AWS.
Almost any AWS resource can be created using CloudFormation from a
security group to Annecy to auto scaling group.
CloudFormation allows you to perfectly create groups of resources over and
over again due to the static nature of the templates used to create those
resources you've seen in this course already,
how many different resources we've created databases,
I am rolls launch configurations ec,
two instances the list goes on and on and all of this
just to support one application,
what if we needed to create a development stack to mirror our production stack.
Doing this process by hand would be error prone and time intensive.
If we use CloudFormation to provision those resources,
we can recreate the infrastructure to support pizza
lovers anytime we want the key tool.
And CloudFormation is a template.
A CloudFormation template is just a JSON document that contains the
configuration information for AWS resources and how they relate,
you can create this template document as a file and check it
into version control to track changes to your infrastructure and
make it easy to roll back if needed.
These templates can often be massive documents when you have a
large amount of infrastructure to create.
The great thing about CloudFormation is that there is no limit to how many or
few resources a template can be used to create for instance,
if you just wanted to create a CloudFormation template to create one Ec.
Two instance with an I AM role and a security group.
CloudFormation can do that.
This could be useful when you already have a VPC created but
just need to create some resources in it.
In fact using CloudFormation in this way,
ensures that you will be able to create the same resources again,
especially since even the best among us will forget which _______ they clicked.
The other unique CloudFormation concept is the idea of a stack.
A stack is essentially a group of AWS resources created
by a single CloudFormation template.
A template can be used to create more than one stack but
each stack needs to be named uniquely.
In addition to CloudFormation being able to create a stack,
it can also update and delete a given stack.
Updating allows you to modify your CloudFormation
template and resubmit it to the stack.
Some examples of this are if you need to increase the size of an ec two
instance or change the rules and a security group,
CloudFormation will attempt to process the update without even restarting your
resources if it's possible once a stack isn't needed anymore,
CloudFormation can delete it,
which removes all of the resources created in that stack,
it's a very powerful operation.
One important thing to know is that CloudFormation doesn't hold
your hand the same way the AWS console wizards,
we've used do whatever resources are configured in
your template will be created, but nothing else.
Sometimes there can be a bit of trial and arrow in creating a CloudFormation template to get it exactly right