[Autogenerated] simple storage service shortened to S3
is one of the oldest services in A W.
S alongside E C.
Two, the longevity and appeal of the service is in its simple utility,
S3 stores objects whatever they may be and allows you to
easily configure who can see them as three stores your
objects in whichever region you select,
which can be important for legal or regulatory reasons.
With the amount of regions available this type of specificity in
storage location should satisfy any concern and as three objects
are the fundamental storage structure.
An object is basically a file and metadata.
The metadata is used by S3 and includes things like file type and
modified date as well as any custom metadata added.
S3 doesn't care what type of object it is and the maximum file
size limit is essentially a joke except in the most extraordinary
circumstances in case you ever need it.
The maximum object size that can be stored currently in S3 is
five terabytes there is an upload limit as well for a single
put operation at five gigabytes.
So to get to the five terabyte limit,
you would need to use the S3 multipart upload tool.
I personally never even come close to approaching that type
of storage and S3 objects in S3 are stored in another
fundamental structure called buckets.
A bucket serves a few purposes in S3 The first is to
store your objects simple as that.
The second is to create a URL name space for those objects.
For instance if we created a bucket in the organ region and named it
Pizza Lovers S3 would assign this URL as the root for any objects
because of this the bucket name needs to be unique throughout all of
S3 not just in your account,
objects are uniquely identified in S3 via their key which is the path
and file name excluding the bucket name for instance an object with
the file name image dot PNG in the folder.
Images would have a key of images slash image dot PNG when
interacting with S3 via the Cli or SDK s.
The term key is used often so just keep in mind that it
includes the path as well as the file name.
There are a few different ways that you can configure who can
access your buckets and objects and how they can access them
but I want to focus on just two.
In this course the first is permissions for the bucket or object by default.
S three buckets and objects are only viewable by the AWS account which
created them permissions enable you to grant access to another AWS
account or anyone usually for web resources you would want them to be
viewable by everyone but not modifiable.
The other access mechanism is using S3 or I am policies,
we discussed policies in the clip on I am and by using those policies
you can enable a user on your account to interact with S3 The policies
and s3 or I am are modeled the same with some slight differences and we
will try out both in this module.
One thing you may be thinking is that storing all your objects in a
single region may increase latency for users making web requests from
other locations in the world and that is correct.
Users from Australia for instance,
requesting an object from a bucket in say Oregon will
experience more latency than if they were requesting the same
object from a bucket in the Sydney region.
One solution for this issue is cross region replication.
This is a configured feature of S3 that will automatically copy any files
added or modified in an S three bucket to a different region.
This feature can be used to reduce latency or to
increase redundancy of the data.
One consideration though,
is that cross region replication will copy to only one other region.
If you want to have a worldwide reduction of latency,
your best option is cloudfront, which we'll discuss in a later module.
S3 definitely has a lot going on, but as we begin working with it, the concepts will definitely begin to stick