[Autogenerated] one thing that I love about cloudfront is that
it works with any existing applications,
there's no changes required at the code level to
benefit from what cloudfront offers.
As you'll see there is enough fine grain control when configuring a
cloudfront distribution that you can achieve very impressive results
by just setting up a few behaviors.
So let's get started open the AWS management console
and go to the cloud front dashboard.
We're going to create a cloudfront distribution to cash our
entire elastic beanstalk application,
click on the create a cloudfront distribution button.
We'll start by choosing the origin for the distribution,
click into the input field and look for the elastic load balancer section.
Then choose the load balancer with a name that
starts with something like a W S E B.
This is how elastic beanstalk names the load balancers that it creates.
The rest of these default origin settings will work for us.
So scroll down to the default cache behavior setting.
This is going to define how cloudfront responds to requests,
caches,
content and handles cookies will be able to set up additional behaviors after
the distribution is created which we will but this one will be the default
behavior for the viewer protocol policy option.
We want to redirect any http requests to HTTPS to
make our application more secure.
So select that option allowed.
Http methods is an important setting because Pizza lovers will respond
to many different http methods like get and post So click the radio
button for get head options put post patch and delete now we need to
create a custom cache policy mostly because we need to cash based on our
application cookie click this create policy link and it'll open the form
in a new tab.
You can name the policy,
Pizza Dash Lovers dash cache then scroll to the cash key setting section.
We do use query strings in some places in the apps,
so go ahead and choose all in the drop-down Next in the cookies drop down,
choose includes specified cookies and in the input field that pops up under
allow type P Z Z the number four and life with a Y L Y F E.
Pizza for life another benefit of forwarding this cookie is that if it
changes cloudfront will treat that as a different request than the one
before which will be important for dynamic content.
Now you can click create,
go back to the distribution creation tab and click the
refresh button next to the cash policy,
drop-down then choose the Pizza Lovers cache policy and that drop-down now
scroll down to the setting section for the price class option,
you can select the cloudfront edge locations that will be used,
there aren't a ton of options as you can see but each have
a different price associated with them.
So keep that in mind when selecting one for your production applications,
it is the most expensive class but just leave it as use all edge
locations Now all the other defaults here are good so go ahead and
scroll to the bottom and click create distribution.
Now, cloudfront does take some time to set everything up,
about 10 minutes per distribution.
I found in the next clip,
we're going to configure some settings and then see what our app finally looks like being served with cloudfront.