[Autogenerated] we didn't really write any code in this module but the services
that we learned about may have an even bigger impact on the experience than any
functions we could have possibly written both.
CloudFormation and elastic beanstalk allow you to take your
web application to the next level by standardizing resource
creation and application deployment.
Let's recap what we covered in this module.
We started by discussing CloudFormation and learned about how to use a
template to provision resources Then we use the CloudFormation template to
create a replica of our Pizza Lovers infrastructure.
Next I introduce elastic beanstalk and explain how to use
environments to easily deploy your application.
Then we zipped up Pizza Lovers and deployed it using a new elastic
beanstalk environment that we configured in the next module we're
going to look at to services provided by amazon that will increase
the speed of our application cloud front and elastic cache cloudfront
is a Cdn service that can be used to edge your application content
closer to users,
thereby reducing geographic latency cloudfront will work with our
existing storage and S3 So configuring it will be a cinch.
Alaska.
cache is a caching service that enables you to use a
caching technology like readiness or meme.
cache de amazon handles the creation and management of cache clusters
to improve the performance of your applications. See you in the next module