[Autogenerated] policies are the fundamental building blocks of I am
permissions policies have one or more statements that declare whether a
user is allowed to do something or not by default,
users have no permission.
So you'll almost always want to apply at least one policy to user
policies can be applied to individual users or two groups,
which users will then be added to.
A policy statement has three properties that give or restrict access.
The first is the simplest and effect.
This will be either allow or deny and controls how the policy
will respond when a user requests access.
All AWS permissions are denied by default.
So this will typically be allowed.
Second is the action that the user can perform.
Each service has a set list of actions that can be performed on it.
And this property says what the user is able to perform.
The last property is a resource.
User can request to perform the action on the
resource property should have the A.
R, N or amazon resource name entered for the given resource.
Alternately you can use an asterisk for this property to
give the user access to any resource.
There are plenty of pre created policies that AWS has
available and most of the permissions you'll want to apply
already have policies created for them.
However, if required, you can create your own policies.
If you want to give a user access to a specific resource only,
you will need to create a custom policy.
An example of this as if you want to allow user to upload files to a specific S3
bucket but don't want them to have access to anything else.
Let's take a look at a policy in your AWS management console,
go to the I AM dashboard in the left hand menu,
click the policies option.
The policies list shows all available policies and
sends here working in a new account.
All of the policies will be a Ws managed policies.
Let's take a look at the Administrator access policy type
Administrator into the search box and hit enter,
then find the administrator access policy in the list and click on the name.
This will open up a window to show the policies details.
The permissions tab is the important part of this policy.
It will show you the permissions that an attached entity will receive.
If you click on the JSON button, you'll see the policy document.
The part we care about in this policy document is a property named statements,
which is basically it's just an array of access objects.
The administrator access policy gives access to
perform any action to any service.
So the action and resource fields are both assigned an asterisk.
Now, let's take a look at another policy, One that has more refined permissions.
Click on the policies linked towards the top of the screen
In the filter and put field type EC two and then hit enter
Once the list is filtered, click on the Amazon.
Ec two.
Full access policy.
This policy document is just a little bit more complex and
you can see that there are several statements being
declared in the statements property.
The first shows the action as E C two colon asterisk,
which gives the permission to perform any action on Ec.
Two.
The next few statements are for ancillary services that interact with EC.
Two, such as elastic load balancing,
CloudWatch and auto scaling attaching this policy to a user
will give them full access to create,
modify or destroy EC two instances load balancers or auto scaling groups
policies are incredibly deep ways to give users permissions.
Amazon provides plenty for you to easily apply to get started,
but also gives you the flexibility to design your own with I AM.
And policies you can achieve fine grain control over all your services and resources.