Congratulations, you've finished this course and I hope you learned a lot about web components and you
now feel confident creating your own web components. Simply dive in and practice, practice, practice.
This is the best way of becoming better,
play around with the different features you learned about in this course,
also consider building native web components without stencil
again, play around with that but I would strongly recommend using a tool like stencil.js because it
is just so awesome
and then build web components for your own projects or also to share them with the public.
So feel free to share your web components on npm or at least across your own projects.
Dive into web component libraries like Ionic as a next step,
stencil.js was actually developed by the team behind Ionic and Ionic is a set of web components
that quickly turn your web app into a modern automatic adapting web application that looks great on
mobile devices.
Also, try out web components together with frameworks,
I showed you how to use web components with Angular, with React and so on,
so give this a try and start implementing web components into your next projects
there, you might be able to save a lot of time by reusing your web components across projects
after all, you don't have to rewrite that modal all the time and you will refine your web components
as you do so because in one project, you might need one extra functionality, you add it to the web component
and suddenly, you have that available in all your projects too.
Awesome.
Now last but not least, stay up to date. With technologies like web components,
you should simply dig into additional resources like MDN, the Mozilla Developer Network that is or other
blocks, Google Developer pages where you can learn more about these features that make up web components,
how they evolve and how browser support evolves,
that is also something you can check on stencil.js's home page for example. Attached to this lecture,
you will find some links that will allow you to dive deeper and learn more about web components and
stay up to date.
Now one thing I want to mention right away is that for stencil.js,
so a tool that helps you with creating web components,
there are alternatives.
For example when you search for lit element, this is another solution that also allows you to create
web components, native web components with some extra help,
so with an extra tool or package and you can learn more about that on its official page, attached to
this video you also find a link to it of course.
Now I absolutely love stencil.js and going with it is certainly not wrong but it's always important
to also know that there are alternatives and if you search for web component compiler and so on, you will
find more alternatives,
so also feel free to have a look at those.