To understand the shadow DOM, let's understand how the normal DOM, also sometimes called the light DOM works.
For that in your developer tools, you can click on the elements tab,
this is your DOM tree essentially.
You see that paragraph and in there, you also see your custom component.
Now when you expand your custom component, you also see that span that was added
and when you hover over the question mark, you'll see that this div gets added here too.
Now there is one important thing to note here,
the span with the question mark and that overlay div are all added to the normal, to the light
DOM here. We are not using anything special,
we're not using the shadow DOM.
So our custom component here in the end has a child which is this span with the question mark.
Now what would be nice is if in a normal, in the light DOM, we had our custom component and the span
or anything else like this overlay div which gets added is kind of hidden away behind that and is not
added to the normal DOM because that would then mean that any styles we set up in a normal DOM would
not affect our nested custom component DOM.
So basically our custom component here should have its own DOM tree which is not mixed or which is not
kind of affected by the normal DOM tree and that would be the definition of the shadow DOM, our element
should have its own DOM behind it which kind of makes up what we see on the page but which is not directly
connected to the real DOM, which is not affected by global styles
and the other way around. Now we have a specification in the browser that allows us to add such a functionality
and we can unlock it in a very easy way. In the constructor,
we simply call this attachShadow and there, we pass a Javascript object where we simply set the mode
to open.
Now you can set it to closed and this simply defines whether you can access your shadow DOM tree from outside
this component or not.
Now closing is something you will typically not do because even if it is closed, there are ways to still
access it and it's simply not worth the effort,
after all you are the developer and if you don't want to access it from outside, you simply don't do
it.
So we'll set it to open throughout the rest of this course.
Now this element has its own shadow DOM tree attached to it,
we now just have to make sure that whenever we add new DOM elements with append child, we don't append
them to our HTML element which is still part of the light DOM but to the shadow DOM of that
HTML element and for that when I call append child, I will first of all access the shadow root and that
is now set since we set up a shadow DOM here in the constructor.
So this will now access the shadow DOM tree and append the child to it. Visually, this will not change
much but you will see that this will have a great impact and I do the same here where I append this tooltipContainer
.
I access my shadow root and also of course when I remove it, I access my shadow root,
so I access the shadow DOM. With that you can now save that
and if you now reload the page, you will notice one important thing right away. The text which was written
between our opening and closing tags here,
so web components and here we go,
that text is gone now and the reason for that can be seen when we inspect our custom element here. You'll
see it
now all of a sudden has a shadow root element which it didn't have before
and there, we see the shadow DOM. Now
conveniently we can see it here in the developer tools
but thanks to that shadow root, this is now detached from the main DOM
and we can prove that by hovering over the question mark, you see the orange border of the div is now gone
even though we still have that rule here. We still have that styling rule
but now with that shadow root being set up, this is gone.
Now obviously as I just mentioned, our text between the opening and closing tags is also gone,
so we have to bring that back and to bring it back,
we'll use the other feature I mentioned, templates.
Now what's up with templates?