Now this was again a lot of new information. In the next module we'll practice this a bit more when we
build a more complex web component that will take a lot of the things you learned into account, giving
you a great chance of practicing it but we'll also introduce new things.
I want to wrap this up now, I want to wrap up this module
now and there's one thing I just want to do quickly.
I promised that we would change the way we set our position for our entire web component
instead of setting it to the style, to the inline style of our web component, of our custom element here,
I will remove it here in the connectedCallback,
this is a relict from times when we didn't know how to style our element correctly.
Now we know we can use the host selector,
so let's use host without any condition to set our position to relative. Just a little change that makes
a lot of sense with all the knowledge we have now, works as before
but now we have this little improvement here, a better way of styling our web component.
We still have the relative style here
or the relative position but now applied through the host instead of by setting the inline style as
it did before.
But with that, we learned a lot about styling in general, about the host, the host with condition, the
host context and the slotted special selectors that allow you to style your slot content, your element
and your element with certain condition attached to it.
You learned about CSS variables,
very helpful for setting up some themes
your component uses, so the developers using your component can choose from.
You learned about how you can listen to changes in your attributes with the attributeChangedCallback
and observedAttributes.
You learned how to use the disconnectedCallback for cleanup and I hopefully got you thinking about at least
using or considering this render method for all your DOM updates, so that the rest of your component
can focus on changing the data
whilst this is the only place interested in changing your shadow DOM. And now with all that knowledge,
let's move on and let's build a more complex web component in the next module where we will see many
of these things again
but where we will also dive into some other new interesting features or functionalities you can implement with
web components.