Let's now work on that list of elements we're outputting here.
I want to have both the symbol and the name,
so let's say here we have the symbol between strong tags to make it bold,
we have result symbol here
and then after this, we have a dash with the result name. We could have more fancy styling of course,
I'll not make it too fancy,
I'll just do a little bit of styling here.
On the unordered list, I'll remove the margin and I'll set the list style to none and on the list items,
I'll also set margin and padding to zero or to be precise, margin top and bottom should be .5rem
and I give this a border of let's say 1px solid and a light gray maybe and, well give them
some padding, let's say .5rem and on the unordered list, let's remove all padding. With that if we go back,
yeah that looks better,
now we have these list items and now we have a way of finding new tickers which we can use in our other component
up there.
Now we have some very nice components here,
we can use each of them standalone or together to find tickers here, for example search for Facebook
and find the ticker and then we can use that ticker up here.
So that is very convenient but it would be nice if we could also just click on one of the elements
and then emit some custom event to which we can listen in this component, in this first component for
example, to then automatically update the price.
So we don't want to specifically target that first component from the second one because we don't know
if the first component will be there,
each component should work standalone but we can simply emit an event to anyone who's interested can
listen and that will cover something we haven't seen yet,
custom events and how we can listen to them conveniently in another component.