We're coming to a close of this module and we learned loads of new things in this module already.
Now I want to close this module by diving back into styling and CSS properties again. You obviously
noticed that for the spinner, the styles there, here for example we're using some colors, for the stock
finder we're using colors and the buttons and so we are for the stock price,
now these colors are all hardcoded into these components.
Now obviously, we can make these settable from outside by using CSS properties just as we did with
our own native web components which we wrote earlier in this course.
For example here the stock finder for the border,
we can accept a CSS property, maybe named color-primary and we have our fallback value of this
purple color or maybe of just, copy that,
maybe of just black and then we can use that down there too.
So here we could have our color-primary, whoops, should be color-primary and our fallback value of black then.
Same for the background
and of course then for the text, we also want to have let's say
color-primary inverse because maybe we have a primary color where black would be the better text color, default
value is white though and so on.
And then we can go into the index.html
file
or anywhere in our main app we're building, in a style.css file and we can add our styles here
and we can set the CSS properties, for example color-primary would be this purple here,
we do that directly on the HTML selector.
We also need color-primary inverse here which should be white in our case because white looks
good on this dark purple and now we can migrate the other colors, like this
background here
where we hover over the button, we will use color,
let's say primary highlight and normally, this would be like a grey-ish hair color, maybe
color-primary highlight grey but of course we can now set our own color here.
Color-primary highlight,
you can name these custom properties,
these CSS variables whatever you want and with that, you can step by step get there. Now I'll just
work on that background of the list item would I hover over it, there
I want to have my color-primary again and the default value of black and then down there, I'll have
my color-primary inverse and a default value of white. And now if I save that, you will see that I
have all my values, all the same
look for this stock finder as I had before but if I get into the head section and I remove my styles
where I set these CSS properties, then you see we go to black and white.
So this is now giving us again the possibility of adjusting the look especially the colors
but you can set anything with CSS properties, so adjusting the look of our components from outside
of them
even though we're using the shadow DOM because properties, CSS properties, CSS variables
as I also call them are a way of breaking through the shadow DOM because they are allowed into the shadow
DOM so to say.
Now I will not bore you by adjusting all the styles,
you can definitely do this if you want to,
I'll just do it here to complete this component but this is immensely useful for you to know hopefully
and again, feel free to adjust the other components too if you want to do this as a practice.