So with the backdrop added, let's work on modal, so #modal selects the element with the ID modal
and just to reiterate on that because we're in the shadow DOM, this only affects elements with the ID
modal that are inside of our template here,
so basically only,
well this element here.
And for the modal, I want to have that in the foreground, so I'll actually give my backdrop a set index of let's
say 10 and the modal will have a set index of 100 because it should have a higher set index
so that the backdrop is in the background of the modal.
I'll also give it a position of fixed to position it in a fixed way, in our viewport, in our document.
From the top let's say we have a distance of 15vh,
.
and from the left, we have a distance of let's say 25% and then we have a width of 50%
because we have 25 distance from the left, then a width a 50%
and then also 25% from the right which is the leftover space,
therefore this should be nicely centered. And you can set different styles, optimize this for mobile,
I'm not caring so much about the styling here,
I just want to focus on the general functionality and not write a ton of styles.
You could add media queries in here, whatever you need for the right styling.
I'll go with this styling and I'll give it a background of white and to ensure that we can see something
for now,
I'll give it a height of let's say 30rem and we might be able to get rid of this later once we have
some content in there.
I also want to have a border radius of let's say 3px and I'll give it a box shadow of 02px
8px and then let's say this style here, some transparent box shadow, drop shadow
and with all of that in place, let's head over and reload this page
and here is our modal
and obviously, this is missing all the content but we're getting there.
Now we have the modal container, we have the backdrop behind it,
now we want to populate that modal with some content of course and I want to have some static content
in there and
I also want to have some slot content in there, so let's add that next.