Now we can generate our project and you do this by simply running npm run build and this executes a
script that is already built into the package.json file,
this build script using stencil build behind the scenes and this will now generate your code bundles,
your component bundles and because I left the default settings, it stores them in a dist folder and
there you actually got a bunch of files as you can see.
Now how can you use that, how can you deploy and share all these files?
That of course is the interesting question and I will show you different ways of using these packages
or using these files step by step.
Let's start with the most simplest use case, we simply want a file which we can drop into one of our
projects and have working components. For that,
I created a new project and you can find that attached to this lecture where I get a couple of different
scenarios, a basic scenario where I just have an index.html file, then an advanced or a server side
language scenario where I have a Node application, a very simple one of course with only one route which
uses the ejs Vue engine
and if this doesn't tell you anything, you can of course ignore that or learn NodeJS and I'm rendering
this single Vue which I have in there,
output some default message and let's say I also want to use one of my components in there. Then I
have a React, Vue and an Angular app and we will go through all these use cases step by step.
Here is the dist folder with the generated output so that we can well, just start using that.
Now let's start with the basic use case, here this index.html file.
There we could have a script folder
and in that script folder, I want to put my component or the code which is responsible for loading my
component.
Now it is best if you simply move your entire code here or your entire code pakage here into the script
folder, maybe simply into a sub-folder which could be named uc-components.
So let me grab all these files and folders and move them into uc-components or copy them in there
and now in the index.html file here,
let's generate a new document here with this HTML5 skeleton and in here, I can now add a script
tag
and as a source, I referenced this script folder, uc-components and then you use that
udemycourse.js file
and now in here, let's use that uc-stock-price component
and now please note that I'm not in my stencil project anymore,
I don't have that stencil development server up and running,
we're not building this project in memory behind the scenes anymore.
Instead I can now reveal this in the finder so that I can double click it and once you do double click
it,
here is your component and you can again use it as before with your different stock symbols.
And of course, we could also use that other component, we could add the uc-stock-finder here, like this,
if we reload this page,
here is our finder
and if I search for BMW, here is BMW, if you click that, it gets loaded up there.
So we get the same behavior as before but we're not in this stencil development environment anymore,
instead I'm simply using my components. And if we inspect the network tab and I reload this page, you'll
see what gets loaded up front and you can see here, we got this udemycourse.js file being loaded and
thereafter a couple of chunks
and this is this code splitting done by stencil.
Here it loads all these chunks because I'm basically loading all my components, the finder and the stock
price and the spinner,
I will show you code splitting in action in the more visible way in a different project.
But this is one of the easiest way of using your files, simply import them as script dependencies like
this after dragging and dropping the generated build files into your project.
Now this is great if you have a project you're working on and you also build your web component
library on your own.