So let's dive into styling now and again you can skip this lecture if you're not interested, simply take
the finished code you find attached to this lecture then to proceed with the styling edit here.
So I want to give this component we created here some basic styling and in that styling here,
I want to work on the input, the button and also on the way we present the output. For that I'll go
into the css file and first of all, I'll select the host element,
so the overall element and I'll set the font family to sans-serif.
Often you might not want to do that,
you want to not set your own font family here in this component but instead let the user manage this in
the global styling for the entire app
but here, just to mix it up, I will set it here in the host element
and after reloading, after the style changes, you often need to reload,
we see that having an effect.
And now of course, I also want to work on my form and the elements in the form and on the output of the
price and the overall container because for the overall container,
so on the host element itself, I will give this a border of let's say 2px solid and a nice
purple
look, let me hover over that and choose a darker purple, maybe something like this. I'll also set a margin of
2rem in all directions
just to have some spacing between this component and other components
and you can always adjust this to your liking of course
and I'll give this as a padding of 1rem. With that,
we actually have a broken component and
the reason for that is that components by default are of type inline.
So to take a fact of margin, padding and have the right border and so on, I will set the display of this
host element and this has to go on to the host element to target our component itself,
I'll set this to block because this should become a block level element and now it indeed is.
Now however, I don't like the width of it, so I will set the width here to let's say 20rem and give it
a max width of 100% to never be wider than the surrounding viewport or container to be precise.
So now we have that style here,
now I also want to work on the input and the button,
so let me select my form in here and always remember, these styles here will be scoped to this component
because we set shadow to true. On the form,
I don't really want to style the form itself for now but I want to style my input in the form. Here
I want to inherit the form settings we have in the rest of the app or in the rest of the component,
I also want to use set the text color to the same purple color we're using for the border of this component
and of course it's not text color, it's just color.
I also want to set some padding here,
.15rem to top and bottom, .25rem to left and right, there we go with .1rem top and
bottom. If we reload, this is how it looks like,
now let me also remove the focus here.
So on the input, when it's focused, I'll set the outline to none.
So I'm removing the outline of course not the focus and let's also work on the button now. For the button
in the form element here, I want to have also an inherited font and the padding of let's say .25rem
from top to bottom and .5rem  from left and right. Let's have a look, doesn't look too bad.
I'll give this a border of 1px solid
and my purple look here and I'll set the background color to that same purple and give it a text color
of white therefore and with that, get this nice button.
Now one last thing I want to add is I'll set my input to display block so that the button actually goes
onto a new line and I'll then give my input a margin bottom of let's say .5rem to have some distance.
And on the button, I want to set the cursor to a pointer and I also there want to add a hover effect
and an active effect.
So on my button here, I'll add a hover effect and I'll set the same styling for an active effect and
there, I simply want to change the background color a little bit,
so I'll start with that purple we have
and I'll just change it to be a little bit brighter, maybe something like this
and the same for the border color,
so on border color here, I'll set this same brighter purple. With that saved,
I like that look
and now if I have a hover over this, that looks quite good.
So now we have everything we need,
we have a nice styling, we can submit this.
One last thing which I forgot, on the button, the focus event also should have no outline just as my input
and yes, we could merge these two rules into one therefore, so let's quickly do that.
Let's move over here and
let's add form button focus here,
both don't have an outline
and now I'm really done.
Now this is the state with which I want to continue
and now we'll dive into adding some API or using that API to get our stock data.