So we added our very basic first component in the last lecture,
let's now tweak it.
What we want to achieve here is or what we want to build here is a side drawer, a side menu.
So first thing is I will actually change this div to an aside, this is totally optional but semantically,
this makes more sense,
an aside is a default HTML element.
More importantly, I want to add my own styles and in our own vanilla component, we did this as part of
this innerHTML template.
Now in stencil, we don't do it as part of that JSX template,
instead stencil has a more convenient feature,
we can point at an external CSS file which styles will be pulled into this file at build time, so we
will still kind of end up with something like this
but we build it in a more convenient way. And for that, I'll add a new file in that folder and I'll name
it side-drawer.css and stencil actually also supports SASS
if you want to use it, in the official stencil docs you can find more about that, a link to those can
be found at the end of this module.
So here I got the side drawer file,
now to use that, I just have to inform stencil where to find that file and that it should use such an external
CSS style by adding another configuration to this object we pass to component
and this is the style URL configuration.
Now you see we got multiple style related configurations we can pass actually, style
URLs
would allow you to define an array of paths to external files and they would all be pulled together
to form one stylesheet for this component, in case you want to split your styles across multiple files
and styles allows you to write inline styles.
So here, you could again use a template string and write your styles without style tags, so simply just
directly the CSS definitions inside of this file
but here, I want to point at one single external file,
so I will use style URL and then this takes a string with a relative path to your CSS file. Such
a relative path is constructed by adding ./ which means from the current folder on,
so from the folder this TSX file lives on and then simply, it's the side-drawer.css file.
This is how we point at this file and how we tell stencil to import this file.
And now there's one other thing we can add,
one other configuration, there is this shadow and this scoped property.
Now scoped allows us to tell stencil that all the styles it finds in the external stylesheet or that
are defined for this common component
in general should be scoped to this component only and it does so but it does not use the shadow DOM,
it basically adds an attribute to all our elements and changes all our CSS styles to take that attribute
into account.
This is an emulated way or this is an emulation of the shadow DOM
and this does offer a great support for older browsers because it doesn't rely on the shadow DOM
but I will set shadow to true here to use the native shadow DOM because stencil will automatically provide
polyfills for older browsers, so this should work in older browsers too
and then we simply save all these extra attributes and hence, we shrink our code a little bit,
the code we ship in the end and it also should be a little bit more performant.
Now with that, we can start defining styles in that side-drawer.css file
and I'll start by giving my aside a style,
so this aside.html element selected by its tag here and this should effectively be an overlay that slides
in from the left.
So I'll give it a position of fixed because it should be fixed to my page, that even when I scroll it
always stays in the same position, from the top it will have a distance of 0 and from the left, it will
have a distance of 0.
I'll have a width here of let's say 30rem but maybe a max width of 90 or of 80% so that on smaller
screens, it doesn't overlap the page width.
I want to have a height of 100vh to take the full page height.
I'll give it a background of a slight grey,
maybe a little bit brighter,
somewhere around this and I'll give it a box shadow
with this configuration here, so that we have a nice little visual effect or elevation effect and
if I save that and we go back, we should see it here,
maybe you need to reload. I'll actually turned this background into a more whitish color,
looks better
and if we inspect this on a mobile device which you can do by opening up your developer tools in Chrome
and clicking that toggle device toolbar mode here, there you can simulate different phones,
then this looks good on mobile too.
Let me zoom in a little bit there.
Ok,
so this is our side drawer, obviously right now we can't toggle it
and the way we display content in it isn't great but this is our first step,
we added styling.
Now let's make sure we can pass in different kinds of content from outside.