So what's in this course in detail?
Well we're pretty much done getting started, in the next module,
you will get a Javascript refresher. Now important,
this is totally optional,
you can skip that next module if you already are up-to-date with next gen Javascript features like arrow
functions, let and const,
if you're not aware of this, you should take this refresher,
also important,
this does not start with the basics of Javascript,
it's about modern Javascript.
If you don't know what the DOM is, how you can select elements in the DOM and how Javascript works, you
definitely have to learn that first before proceeding with that course because I require that basic Javascript
knowledge in the course. Now after this optional refresher, we'll dive into the basics of web components
with vanilla Javascript.
You will learn step-by-step how you can create your own custom HTML elements, your own custom web components
therefore. After the basics,
we dive into the more advanced features. We'll build up on these basics and we will learn how to build
more exciting web components with more interesting features and then, we'll go one level further and
we'll build even more complex web components with even more interesting features giving us everything
we need to build a really awesome web components already.
Now after that, we'll dive into a tool that helps us with building these web components
because thus far, we'll have used vanilla Javascript only
and whilst this is all you need,
you will already see kind of limitations or like
what's hard about that and you will learn about a tool that makes creating web components easier and
that tool is called stencil.js.
I will introduce you to it and show you the advantages of it in this introduction module and thereafter,
we'll dive into the basics and then also in advanced stencil.js.
Now after this advanced stencil.js module,
you will have everything to build amazing modern web components that run in any browser including Internet
Explorer 11.
You will be super fast about building these web components
thanks to stencil and the sky will be the limit regarding what you can build there because we'll dive
into all the awesome features you can combine and mix and match as needed throughout this course.
So we'll learn how to publish and share our web components thereafter, how you can publish them to npm
or drag and drop them into other projects
so that not just you can benefit from that but that potentially, you and all your projects, your teammates,
your entire organization or the whole world could use your components.