The implementation we're currently using is absolutely fine,
it opens the modal but we could also add another way of using our modal. We get access to it here in
code, in our Javascript code and it's always important to remember that what you get here is a full Javascript
object, the Javascript object representing this DOM node and this object can be used to set the attribute,
we could also set classes there,
we could even remove it from the DOM and since it is an object, it is an object based on our class here.
This is in the end the object that was generated for us by the browser,
it has all the default properties of HTML element which we extend here and it has its default methods
and actually, set attribute is just a default method of every HTML
element
and since we extend HTML elements here, our own modal object also has set attribute available. But
this means that if we add any new properties or methods in our class, we can also access these from outside
and therefore, one thing we could add here is an open method.
Now please note that I did not add an underscore at the beginning here because I don't want to mark
this as private,
it should indeed be accessible from outside
and what I do in here is here,
I add some code to show my modal and again, this could be the code we used here before
or I set my attribute
inside here.
Now what this allows me to do with this open method added is that I go back to my index.html
HTML file and instead of setting the attribute here which I absolutely can do, I can call open here
on my modal object because I just added this open method and if you're wondering why I would do it like
this,
well I can abstract complexity away from my main document, from me as a component user and manage it inside
of my component.
Now obviously, the complexity is not very large here but if we were adding different elements or anything
like that, then all we have to do outside is call open and we do all the magic inside of this open method
inside of our component.
So this is not a strictly better approach than setting the attribute manually as we did before
outside of the component, it's just an alternative, an alternative of which you should be aware.
And actually it's perfectly fine to handle both cases,
the case that we add opened manually from outside
or that we call open
and you do find built-in elements where you can call a method to do something or where you can call
a method from outside to do something.
Now with this adjusted, I can reload my page and still open a modal because it has still the same
mechanism,
still the open attribute gets added
but now we're not doing this manually with our own code,
we're calling open outside instead and this is just one alternative
I wanted to show you here.
Also be aware that you cannot just call methods from outside, if you had some public properties, so any
other properties like let's say this.isOpen and you set this to false initially and we change this
to true here,
then you can access this from outside too.
So now we have isOpen here and now after calling modal open, if I console log modal isOpen here
from outside my component, you will see that if I open the console and I reload and I click this button,
we see false here because I should set it to true in open and not leave it as false.
So let's give this another try,
reload,
now we see true here.
So we can also access properties from outside our component and we might have some useful information
in there which we now can extract and use programmatically from our main document, from our main application
logic which would be this one and which we still manage inside of our modem.
Now a little side note, if we do expose this isOpen formation,
then we all of a sudden need to re-add our attributeChangedCallback, not change the styles here
but certainly change this.isOpen to true here. And on the other hand, if we don't have that open attribute,
we want to change isOpen to false here and
by the way, we can get rid of that outer check,
we can always check for the existence of this attribute even if this attributeChangedCallback was triggered
due to the change in some totally different attribute.
So now this is totally optional, just to show you that you can access properties from outside too
but now we have this extra functionality added where we can always access this information too through
this public property.
Now with this isOpen property exposed,
we can actually enhance our logic out here
and we can check that if this button gets clicked,
we only want to open a modal if modal is open is not true.
So if it is not true,
hence an exclamation mark at the beginning,
otherwise we don't have to call open because it already seems to be open.
I'm not sure how we could click this but if we did something fishy, well then we would block this.
So here I can show console log opening
and now if I reload, we see opening here
but now if I hack this and I manually remove the backdrop,
now I all of a sudden can click this button again
but now you will see if I do
so, we don't see opening again because of this extra check.
So now we have this extra check which is a little bit useful here
but it's easy to imagine either components where you would need to get some information from inside
to prevent strange logic from running outside,
so in your main application and then public properties like isOpen can be very helpful.