So now that we're able to fetch data and that I showed you how this works with this promise in the fetch
API, we can use our own API key so that as a next step, we can actually have a look at what the user entered
and use that data instead of always using Microsoft.
Now for that, I will create a new file here in the source folder, in a sub-folder which I'll name global,
you can name it whatever you want and I'll name that global.ts,
I want to store some global data in there which I can import into any component that needs it
and I could put it directly into this stock-price.tsx file but this allows me to manage my API key in
a central place instead of in a component.
So if I would use it in different components, I could always just import it from that file and when I ever
change it, I need to change it in one file only.
So here I'll export a constant which I'll name AV for alphavantage, API_KEY and then I will add
my API key there
and again I showed you how to request one,
make sure you do have an API key,
you will need one if you want to use different user inputs than the dummy data.
So I added my API key here, with that, I can just import it into my stock-price.tsx file or into any other
file and when stencil builds that component, it will merge the data into that file of course,
so we don't need to ship that global.ts file. When we share our components with other users,
it will be all included in the final build file here.
So here I will just import from that global, global files, so the global file in the global folder and
there, I will import my AV_API_KEY and I will use that instead of demo.
Now I will just change this from a string surrounded by single quotes to a string surrounded by back ticks
because back ticks allow me to use that dollar sign curly brace injection syntax and I will insert my
AV_API_KEY here
and of course remove demo, so that my API key is used as the API_KEY
and now we want to in our next step, fetch the user input of course.