Now with the lifecycle methods of your elements explained, it should be clear why append child causes
an error here. In the constructor,
the element has been created but it has not been added to the DOM yet and therefore, trying to append
a child which tries to append it to the real DOM will fail.
Instead you should add the connectedCallback method here and make sure you spell this right because
the browser will look for exactly that method, spelled exactly like that,
it is case sensitive so make sure you have a capital C in there
but a lower case c at the beginning. And now we can grab all that code here where we want to append a
child or where we create the child,
we can move that into the connectedCallback. Now with that and no other changes, if we now save that and I then reload
this page,
now you see we get no error and we see our question mark being rendered here at the beginning.
Now obviously, it's added in front of our web component's text and not after it
and that is not the place where we want to have it. I'll come back to how it ends up there later
but at least we can see we can now render something without errors and the key takeaway which already
shows a little bit of the use custom components give us is that this question mark is not part of our
HTML
markup here
but it's really something that is controlled by our web component
and again, we'll add more usefulness to that and more features over the next lectures.
But this is now a crucial first step and it's also important to understand that we are using the
connectedCallback here because we are accessing the DOM and our element has only been mounted onto the
real DOM
when this method gets called.