Well before we finish this getting started
module, I want to ensure that you're getting the most out of this course because there are a couple
of tricks and steps you should follow to make sure you really get the most value for your money.
Now this is a video based on-demand course,
you can go through it at your pace and you really should do that.
Watch the videos and watch them at your speed,
you can use the video player to increase or decrease the playback speed,
you can pause
when I'm going too fast and you want to code along, I try to balance my speed but a lot of students
want to code along and therefore I have to find the right talking speed
somewhere in the middle.
Definitely pause if needed, slow me down or speed me up when I'm going too slow,
watch the videos at your pace, at your speed and make sure you get the most out of them.
You will also get the most out of them if you code along,
so that is the part with pausing the videos potentially, do the assignments you find in this course but
also take all the other code as a big assignment.
I also sometimes mention here you can pause to video and you should take advantage of this and try something
on your own before you follow along with my solution.
Neither do I have the only correct solution nor would it be a problem if you come up with a different
solution that doesn't work because then, you will learn a lot
and that is why you're taking that course, right.
So besides that and doing that whilst watching the videos, also make sure you use the course resources.
To the last lecture of every module, you find helpful links as well as the source code for this module
attached, the source code is also attached to multiple lectures inside of module, so not just to the last
one, to the last one you always find all the code for the module though. Take this code to compare
it to yours
if you're facing any problems, if something is unclear, if you have any bugs. By comparing my code or
even replacing parts of your code with it temporarily, you can solve a lot of the issues and by solving
them like this, you will learn a lot because you solve your problems on your own,
there's no better way to learn.
Now if there is something where you get stuck or if a concept is unclear which I explain, don't hesitate
to ask in the
Q&A section and I'll do my best to help you there.
Now important, asking is simple,
also consider helping your fellow students.
Answering is much harder but there is no problem
if your answer should be wrong, at least you tried and you will learn a lot by answering
no matter if you're right or wrong. If you're wrong, you'll get corrected, if you're right,
hey you helped another student and you are challenged to think about a problem and solve it.
So really consider answering in the Q&A section,
this is the best practice you can get because solving problems, solving complex problems, that is what
makes you a pro developer.