Now you conclude special selectors.
We learn about there's one average special selector that is worth pointing out and that is the host
context selector.
Now let's say and that is actually the case here.
We only want to apply a certain style to our custom element when it is inside of a paragraph.
As our first tooltip as right here our first tool tip is out of a paragraph.
The second one is not.
So in this case you might want to set a certain style and for that there is never a special selector
Kolin host dash context.
This also has this function for him with parentheses after it is selector and then the function arguments.
So with when the parentheses use specify the surrounding conditions you want to have around your element.
So in this case we could add the P selector So the tax collector for a paragraph element but you could
also have something like.
It should be a paragraph with the Hello class like this or a paragraph with a nested element of hello
which surrounds our custom element all is possible.
Here I'll just go for.
And if that is the case let's say then we want to have a font weight that is bold.
So we want to have bold text and if we do that and we reload we see for the first web component we have
bold text for the second we don't and we have that because of this rule which kicks in due to our paragraph
around our custom element and for a second web component for our second tooltip this rule does simply
not apply because there is no paragraph around it.
And if we would nest is inside of a paragraph so it would move it.
And you can drag it in the developer tools.
So if I drag it here into my paragraph you see this gets bold too because it's now all the inside of
a paragraph and hence Now this whole context here also applies that moved out of there again.
Then again it's not bold anymore.
So this is really really cool.
Gives us a lot of flexibility here.
And with host hosts in combination with this function for him to set conditions host context and slot
it you have a lot of powerful tools to style the content on your web components in exactly the way you
want.