Now with named slots explored, let's dig a bit deeper into slots and let's see how we could actually get access
to the content we pass in our slot, in our code in the component
and with that I don't mean get access in the sense of render it, what we do here automatically by simply
using the slot
but what if we would need to kind of read our list of data, our list of HTML nodes that
gets passed into our slots?
Now for that, let me first of all show you something else.
After setting up my innerHTML template here,
so in the next line after this statement basically, I want to get access to all my slots and I'll store
them in a constant and
we can simply query for them on our shadow root with the query selector all method and then querying
for a slot element because this is in a normal HTML tag by which we can query of course.
Now here, we can access our slots,
this will basically be an array or a node list of HTML elements and we have two slots.
The first one will be at index 0,
the second one at index 1.
Now let's say we want to have a look at our second slot,
so the one with index one
and then we can add an event listener here and the event to which we can listen is the slot change event
and that will be triggered whenever new content arrives, which will happen at least once when our shadow
DOM basically is used to render our component into the real DOM and we project the content we pass into
our component into our slot,
this will be the first time this triggers but then also if we would updated programmatically from outside
and the content we pass in would change, then slot change for this given slot would also trigger again
and in this function which then triggers, we get an event object and in here most importantly, we'll be
able to analyze the content that's inside of our slot.
So here, I will actually console dir, dir prints an object in the console which we can inspect instead
of the
HTML element console
log would print
and there, I will print that slot we're listening to.
So now, if I save this and I reload, you'll see we now have a slot output here and that gets printed by
this line,
so that means that the slot change event did indeed fire which it, as I mentioned does when you render
this component to the screen because that is when the slot here will be replaced with the projected content
for the first time
and if we now have a look in to this slot here, we can see a couple of interesting elements but some
very interesting data can be seen if we call the assigned nodes method on our slot.
So this is not a property, this is a method.
If we do that and we go back, if I reload, then we see an array of all the content that was projected
into our slot.
Now you might be wondering why we have four elements instead of just one paragraph tag.
The reason for that simply is that the whitespace in front of the paragraph tag and after paragraph
tag also is treated as text. In the end, we have this paragraph tag we're interested in and if we would
optimize our code here and basically write this all in line which is harder to read but gets rid of
all the excess whitespace,
if we would do that here for our component in the html file, then you would see we only have the paragraph
element in there and this is now the paragraph DOM node which gets projected into our slot.
So this is also not part of the shadow DOM but still of the light DOM, just the content at which our
slot points
so to say. Now I do now restructure this again to make it easier to read
but now if I reload, I get these four elements again but again, it is the paragraph tag which we get
in the end here.
And if you ever need to get access to the content that is projected into your slot, then this is how
you can do it,
you can use assigned nodes. And as a little side note, on the projected element, you also find this
assigned slot property here which you can on the other hand use to find out into which slot this was projected,
so this also maybe an interesting information depending on which kind of application you are writing.
So slot change combined with a side note can be very helpful if you for example also have an application
where the content in your slot might change at runtime too,
so not just this initial change which we have here, but also a change at a later point of time,
maybe because you loaded some data from the web and you want to change something in your modal when
that is done.
So this is just another thing I wanted to show you which can be helpful when you're working with slots.