So we saw how we use our own custom components in Angular and React apps,
maybe you are a VueJS developer though so let's also see it there.
Navigate into that Vue folder
and there, first of all run npm install to install all the package this Vue project generated with
the Vue CLI by the way, requires
and once this installation process here finishes, we can install our own package from the npm registry.
So let's wait for that to finish
and thereafter run install --save uc-components to again use that package of components
you published to npm earlier in this module.
Now with this installed, how do we enable our elements in a Vue app?
Well we need to go into that source folder and there in the main.js file or in general, the file
where you
mount your root component to the DOM
and in this case, this is the main.js file. In there, you now want to add import from your uc-components
/dist/loader folder and you want to import define custom elements.
Now you need to call that function here and you want to do that before you call new Vue
and there, you pass the window object into this, the default window object which is globally available
in Javascript and that will then register all your components and their tags in that browser window
so to say, so in this
app they are then available. And now you can use them in your Vue templates, like here in
the starting template, I'll delete the default content which was in there
and instead I'll add uc-stock-price and now you can run npm run serve to bring up that development
server for this application.
It'll run on this location which gets printed here,
in my case http://www.localhost:8080
so let's visit this page, here it is.
Now here you see, let's first of all test it,
does it work?
That looks good.
Now in the network tab, we see a bunch of requests being made, a bunch of bundles being called
but I want to draw your attention to that 0.js
file at the very bottom before these other imports here.
Now let's see how that changes when we add the uc-stock-finder, so that other web component which we
published. Make sure to also close this
and then reload this page and you will see that the besides the 0.js,
we have the 2.js at the end
and if you click into them, you will see that this is the uc-stock-finder, if you scroll through it, somewhere
you will see that tag name in there.
So essentially we now got one extra bundle and the bundle size is very large here because this is development
mode, in production mode,
it would be smaller here too.
So we have both bundles loaded which makes sense because we have both components doing their job here
and they work just fine as you can see.
Now let me show you lazy loading here by not always rendering this, instead
here I will add the data method, this is how you can manage changeable data that will have an effect
on the template in Vue
and there we return an object where I have showStockFinder which is false initially and I can bind
this with V-if
which is like ngIf in Angular and I bind to showStockFinder, like that.
If I do that, this component is missing and therefore 0.js is the last bundle we load here, we don't
load the other bundle for the other component.
Now that will change as soon as I add a button there and on this button, I say load finder or whatever
you want and I will add a click listener and there, I will just set showStockFinder equal to true.
And what this will do is when I reload,
we still have only one bundle
but if I clear my network tab now and I click load finder, it now loads this other package because now
we're using that other component.
And here again, we are taking advantage of the built-in lazy loading the components built with stencil
have,
they're still native web components that just got this extra magic added on top of them making it possible
to use them very efficiently.