Now using props is one great way of interacting with the DOM or with the outside world and of getting data
into your component.
Now of course there are other ways as well,
one way is a slot and slots work exactly in the same way as they do in vanilla Javascript. You can also
have name slots as we did there and you set up named slots in exactly the same way because stencil
uses exactly the same API in the end.
Now here I got a slot and this of course enables us to add something between the opening and closing
tag of our side drawer
and there we could have an unordered list with some list items, maybe all wrapped in a nav item because it
is a navigation we might be adding here but this gives us the flexibility to use the side drawer for
anything, doesn't have to be a side navigation, could also be an info screen that is added to some page
but here, we could have content like this, a link, another link, a third link.
This is all passed in from outside
and if we come back, we see this gets displayed there and we still change the title after three seconds,
I guess.
So this is another way of passing in data and just as before, we can of course also style this slotted
content, however we can't style the nested slot content,
so if we want to kind of style all the links in our side drawer here, we can't really do that
through the slotted special selector because as you learned, you can only change the top level element
there,
so the general styling of your content has to be done outside of your component in the light DOM.
Now lets still do some styling here.
One styling I want to do in general here in my light
DOM and I'll use style tags,
we could also import a CSS file but I'll simply do it here,
I want to set a base font-family of sans-serif because I prefer that.
But now for the content in the side drawer to style that, I could only target the nav item here, the other
content is hidden away from me.
So if I want to style that, then I have to do it here in the light DOM.
So there I could give this a class of side nav for example and then we could assign some style here,
side nav and for example ensure that the unordered list in there has a list style of none to remove
these bullets
and that my links in there have no text decoration to remove the underlining and maybe a color of orange,
something like that,
now we would have this side menu. Let me turn this from orange to dark orange
maybe, yes like that.
Now you can style this way more,
this is not really about web component, so I don't want to do that,
I just want to highlight and that is not a restriction of stencil but of slots in general,
you can style the contents you pass in through slots from inside component,
you only have access to the top level element, so you could style the nav element in your component
through this special slotted selector.
You can't style the nested content though, so you have to do that from the light DOM. And with that, let me also comment out
this code that changed the title because I don't want to do that anymore.
Now one thing we can of course change is the position of the title in the drawer because that is of course
part of the side drawer,
this header. So we can go into our drawer and in there, add the header style and maybe add a padding of 1rem
to all directions and also ensure that the header h1 tag maybe has a font size of 1.5rem
and now this certainly looks different and maybe we also want to give it the header a certain background
color of black and give our text here a color of white
then, looks nice
and now let's also remove the margin on the h1 tag because I added a padding to the header already
and now this looks quite decent
in my opinion.
Now let me just style the links a little bit more so that they look a little bit better,
I will actually change the color to black and I will add a style here,
side nav list item style where I set a margin top and bottom to 1rem and left and right to zero so
that there is some spacing between the links.
Now I don't have any hover effect or anything
but now this doesn't look too bad, doesn't look too shabby
and we now had a look at the slots again and improve the styling a little bit as well.