So in this module,
I did a lot of talking, right?
I did a lot of talking about stencil and how we install it and what it does for us.
Now I really want to sum up the advantages again.
We use stencil because even though this syntax might look very strange to you right now, it actually
gives us a very nice way of creating components as you will learn over the next modules,
it might look strange at the beginning but it will make a lot of sense at the end.
This code here for sure
also would have looked strange if I would have shown it to you all at once
right at the start of the course.
So this will actually become pretty clear and pretty easy to understand
and then we get a highly optimized and fast web component, a native web component so we don't ship this
code,
we ship code that will in the end just look like this code, just in a bit more condensed and optimized
version and we'll have a tiny bit of extra code being shipped which will look for the browser that
is getting used by the user and that will automatically load any polyfills we might need to make our
web component work in older browsers too,
so we got this out of the box working functionality built in.
So we got an easier way of building web components because this syntax here will turn out to be much easier
to understand than having large components built like this and we'll get components that work in all
browsers with zero extra content from our side and these are two awesome reasons to use stencil.
Now with that, let's dive into stencil and its syntax and what all these strange @ things here mean in
the next modules.