Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're gonna be working with pixel curses.
So here we've got the cursor here which is my movement cursor I hover over God.
You see I've got an attack cursor if I hover over nothingness where I cannot move no attack then I get
nothing cursor that's all gonna be working at and we're going to have these mappings exposed in the
editor so that you can see the types that all of action that happen and what cursor texture they actually
map to.
So let's dive in and see how to implement it so we'd like to create some cursor affordable says for
being able to mouse over objects.
So for example we've got these pickups.
That's how I got pickups over here.
We'll get no afford it so we can pick them up.
God no Faunce that we're gonna attack when we click over there or that we're going to walk over here
or that certain areas are gonna be out of bounds.
All this we'd like to fix with some cursor affords.
And how is this going to look what kind of situations do we need to look out for it with curses.
So first of all I'd like it to be design a configurable so we're gonna have certain types of curses
such as walkable areas and at enemies we want to attack and we want to be able to get the designer to
say OK well when we want to attack want to use this cursor we want to be able to easily add more types.
So as we progress and develop the game we'd like to be able to add in new things like I don't know intractable
objects such as a door that we could open we might want to have dialog boxes and for when we can talk
to employees and so on and so forth.
So we want this to be easily extensible and we want to just have one method for it to be set to set
the cursor.
So what do I mean by that.
Well what I mean is that in interact with combat at the point where we know that we can interact with
combat which is here when we're returning true from interact with combat we'd brush off our knowledge
of this how it works is that every update we check what we can interact with.
We return early if we can interact with something so combat we return early movement we return early
if we can do that.
So what we want to do is with combat we know that we're doing combat because we're returning true at
this point and we know that it hasn't returned before this point.
So what we want to do is set the cursor and I don't want to have different methods so I don't want to
set attack cursor for example I want to go set attack cursor Well I want to do is just have one function
set cursor in here and for it to take an enum to basically say what kind of cursor that's going to allow
us to make it easily extensible we can add to this enum I'm gonna make the enum within the play controller
class for now and I'm going to call it the cursor type and inside this curse type we're gonna have to
start off with just some basic ones.
So we're going to have none as the kind of default.
No no action possible here now we're gonna have movement and then we're going to have combat so these
different curses and what we're going to do is just pass into the set cursor the cursor type in.
So I'm gonna have cursor type dot combat in this case.
Now the other case is we're going to use this fact let's just go ahead and create a default definition
for set cursor so control dot generate the method where has it put my method down here I'm just gonna
move it the low interacts with movement it's going to set the right there and then what I want to do
is call a similar method in just before we return true in interact with movement and it's going to set
the cursor type to movement and now quick little mini quiz where will you put setting the cursor type
to none Well so where I'm gonna put it is it at the end of update if we reach the end of update we know
that we aren't able to interact with combat or movement or any of the other things that we update here
and update.
So the cursor type that needs to come back is going to be none like so.
So the next thing we need is for this to be easily designed configurable and for that we need to understand
a little bit more about how we're going to get these curses to be set.
Now if we go down to asset cursor method the thing we're going to be using is Unity's cursor dot set.
Cursor.
And this takes in a texture to 2D and a vector to hotspot the hotspot is the location within that vector
image which should be active which should be basically the mouse.
And then we have a cursor mode.
We're just gonna be using cursor mode.
Also it really depends on the platform that you're using but auto is probably the best choice unless
you have some specific requirements otherwise.
So to bundle together this configuration for the designer and for our editor we're gonna create a struct
and particularly a C realizable struct.
So it's going to be struct and I'm going to call it a cursor mapping and we'll see why in just a second.
So the first type I'm gonna have in here is going to be the cursor type very much the same as we are
doing with the progression system.
This is going to be a mapping object from the cursor type to that configuration.
So we're gonna have an array of it in just a second so I'll just finish off my type declaration here.
I'm gonna make it public so we can access this external well within our play a class at least.
And then I'm going to have a serialized field here.
So it's going to be serialize field and it's going to be a cursor mapping array called cursor mappings
and we're going to d follow initialize that to know the unity serialization system will take care of
the rest.
And the final piece is we need to do a system dot see realizable on our cursor mapping struct.
Now there's gonna be more stuff going into this struct which you're going to fill out in a second but
for now what I want to do is create an empty method a little private method down here which is going
to return at cursor mapping from that array and we're just gonna call it gets cursor mapping it is going
to take a curse type which I'll call just type and do something with it which is going to be your job.
And over here in the set cursor we can do a cursor mapping get a local variable here called cursor mapping
and we'll just call it the mapping.
We're going to do that by calling get cursor mapping with the argument here which I'm going to rename
to type and pass that in as well.
And then what we can do is use this mapping to pass arguments to set cursor so we can do things like
mapping dot texture and mapping dot hotspot to get what we want there.
And finally the cursor mode as I said we're just going to use auto cursor mode to auto it's an enum
that we can use like so.
So there's a few bits in here to fill out for you folks.
That's gonna be in the challenge in just a second but first I want to show you the asset pack we're
going to be using.
So I'm gonna be using this pixel cursors asset pack by the very awesome folks at Clayman studios.
And if you go ahead and get this it's just free you can go ahead and import into your own project which
is what I'm doing now then.
This is a great start but I also recommend some other great packs by claimant's studio which are not
free.
In fact many of them you can see down in the recommendations here from this pack is stuff like the old
style curses fantasy pack and there's more and more of them.
They all cost just you know a few euros.
It's really not a law if you like the look at the pack do support claim on studio and go and get one
of those pay packs.
They're gonna be very easy to integrate just the same as the pack that we're using.
So the asset pack I just downloaded is in the root of my assets.
I want to put it under asset packs like we do that's our convention so let's go ahead move that across.
Like so and then one more thing we have to do with these curses in order to actually be able to use
them as textured curses for our cursor.
Very circular that you have to go ahead and select these curses and change their texture type from sprite
2D over to the cars of type and that will just make sure there aren't any weird rendering glitches when
you do that.
Do use it as a cursor.
So now it is challenge time for you to complete that get cursor mapping.
So you're going to be adding fields to the struct to support the cursor mapping you're going to add
mappings to the player prefab so editing that serialized field of mappings and then you're going to
be finding the right mapping using something algorithmic maybe like a for loop to return the right sorts
of mapping and setting the cursor so hopefully what you'll end up with is when you play the game you'll
be able to hover over enemies and see at a cursor for attacking when you hover over something else like
the ground you see a cursor for walking.
And when you hover over something that you can't click on you see the non cursor pause video and have
a go at the challenge.
Welcome back.
So let's fill out that last little bit of code.
So in get cursor mapping we're just going to start off with a range based for loop.
So we're going to be going over that sort of for loop the other one for each.
That's the one I want.
That's where I spent my head in C++ land a little bit recently.
So the cursor mappings is an array that we want to iterate over and the type is going to have look for
cursor mappings so I'm just going to call it a mapping and all we want to do with this cursor mapping
is just check mapping dots and then we want to check the type is equal to the type that we got passed
in if so.
Well go ahead and return that mapping because it's the right one.
Obviously it's going to find the first matching one if it doesn't find anything at the moment or we're
going to do is just try and return the first element from this array.
Now obviously in practice you don't want to have this to happen you want your mapping to be complete
and the first element from my array is actually this custom custom mapping array is one I should be
looking at.
So then we want to fill out these two parameters so I can actually auto complete that control dots generate
the variable field in yet in the cursor mapping do the same with hotspot generated and then we can go
ahead and skip over to that using F 12 and we can see that it is create them as internal I actually
want them just as public for simplicity's sake like so and that should allow us to access them and it
will also make them serialize the ball so that unity will show them in the editor.
So let's go over to our character prefab.
I'm gonna go to core player and then I am going to look at my play a prefab down in the cursor mappings
I want to create three cursor mappings the first one is going to be for none the second one is gonna
be for movement the third one is going to be for combat and we can bring in the appropriate curses.
So I like this one for combat which is a little X symbol then for movement I quite like just this basic
blue and then for combat what could you choose you could choose all sorts of things.
I'm gonna go for one which has got a little sword icon obviously make your own choices you might bring
in your own asset packs you might even have some gimp skills or whatever it is a photoshop skills you
might be able to create some of your own icons as well.
So if you go ahead and hit play then you can see that we've got our movement cursor when we're moving
around a hover over the enemy and sure enough I have got an attack cursor and I start attacking when
I hit him we don't have anything for our pickups as of yet because they are not kind of clickable I
type items but if I hover over somewhere where I cannot go then basically off the edge of the world
you can see I get that none icon as well.
So we got our basics in place of mapping curses to the actions that we want in the next lecture we're
going to be looking at how UI can block our cursor and be the first thing we can interact with because
it later on in this game we are going to want to include some UI and that's going to be the way that
we can do it and then we're gonna move on to more generic right testable components so that we can do
actually have a pickup cursor as well so let's dive onwards and upwards.