Hello and welcome it's a new section and following on from the last section that we were doing our first
moment.
Now we're going to learn how we can string those moments together in separate levels.
So we're going to be having a section all about scene management and loading scenes.
Let's dive in and see what the prototype has to offer us.
So here this prototype is looking different from the scene that you've just created because it was based
off the previous section.
But if I run in this direction Fade out fade in and we're now in a different scene.
We're gonna be learning to do this and creating portals in the levels.
So here I'm in a transitionary level.
If I go to the portal at the end of it which is just a basic corridor then I fade out fading and I come
back actually to the top of the previous level so if I zoom out what we've got is a situation where
there's a portal here at the end and a portal here.
At the beginning that's where I just came in.
So we're gonna add multiple portals that take you to different parts of different levels.
And that's going to allow me to teach you about co routines that run between levels asynchronous seen
loading to allow us to say hey wait for the scene to load then fade back in and how do those fades in
the first place or the scene management stuff.
Quite cool.
Let's dive in and get started with implementing scene management in this section.