Hello again my friend welcome to the next section of the course in this section we are implementing
weapons.
Sam has been working his patootie off to get in a whole bunch of really cool basic weaponry for us when
I run into this next level you can see I've got a sword now.
What's really cool when I run a little bit to the right you'll see what the enemy is doing.
He is shooting an arrow at us which is really cool very exciting.
If I run up to the enemy I've got a different animation for the sword.
Super cool the player can run over pickups and with the pickups we can do things like throw a fireball.
So that's switched my weapon to a fireball which is casting call it a weapon.
In this instance casting a weapon fireball so we can switch between weapons when we run over pickups
we're not implementing full inventory in this section or even in this part of the course.
For now we want to make sure that we can have different weapons that we just run over on the ground.
Different animations different ways of killing the enemies and different ways of the enemies to hit
us as well.
So let's jump in and create some weapons for our game.