Hello and welcome to the cause.
I'm Rick.
This is Sam.
And from time to time you might see Ben as well.
We are remastering this entire course.
Super excited.
We got a lot of feedback from our students for how it could improve this course in particular too.
Well to get to the point to have less refactoring and to get to the best way to make an RPG.
So unity I've released Unity 2000 eighteen point three now which includes nested prefabs which is a
really awesome feature that's going to completely change the way we make our RPG.
That's another great reason that we want to remaster is to show you how to use nested prefects to the
best effect and it'll save us a lot of time in the course process.
And that will mean that we'll be able to include new features that weren't in the previous iteration
such as saving such as World progression and such as player progression through increasing of experience
points and increasing stats.
So that's all stuff that wasn't in there before that we can now include as well.
Awesome.
And just a reminder this is an intermediate course which means we're not going to go through the Unity
interface and show you what a hierarchy means and what the inspectors are all about.
I'm not going to be going through the basics of C sharp in terms of this is what a function is and this
is what it means to have a return type.
If you have a foundation in unity you do understand some C sharp then dive in.
Have a great time.
If at any point you get a little bit stuck then you might want to go and check out our complete unity
3D course for a bit of a refresher on a catch up or to get up to speed and then come back into this
course to continue onwards and upwards.
Yep.
And so in this section Rick and I are going to be taking you through the setup you're going to need
getting all the tools installed that you need if you don't have them already we're just gonna be double
checking that we're all in the right place ready to get started.
And I'm also gonna be giving you an overview of the architecture of the whole RPG that we're going to
aim towards so that you know where everything fits into the bigger picture.
And then in Section 2 Rick's gonna get you started with actually creating the movement of our RPG a
very cool mechanic.
Cool.
And one last piece of logistics is where moving the existing content the content that is there now in
the course ever an archive course which you will have access to forever.
And if you've been taking the course in the past all that content is still there.
As we produce the new content will be unpublished in the old content.
So as we create Section 1 we'll turn off the old section one as we create Section 2 we'll turn off the
old content as things go along at some point you're going to bump into where our new content is being
created.
And the old content exists and we'll have a couple of videos in there just explaining you've reached
the point you've reached the point of no return which is where our new content is ending.
Rest assured we're adding new content every day we're pumping it out as quickly as we can so that this
new amazing content is fully fleshed out as soon as possible so that I think is all for now.
So let's jump in and get started.