In this video we're gonna be shooting at our enemies.
Look at this we've got a bow and arrow and a shooting out project dollars I've trained them pretty slow
so that we can see them on screen but we have started our journey of launching projectiles.
It's jumping to get started.
They start with a high level breakdown of what we're trying to do in this video.
These are the main steps to launching the projectile in our fighter script.
We need to launch the projectiles.
This is where we actively launch it.
We need a pass in the target from Fighter X fighter knows who the target is within our weapon script.
We need to instantiate the projectile game object to bring it to life.
And then in our projectile script we need to set the projectiles target based upon the health component
that it received from the fighter.
There's a few more bits and pieces we need to do but I just want to give you a view that we have to
jump into each of these scripts and hook it all together.
So let's open up our fighter weapon and projectile scripts.
I'm going to start in projectile kind of do the easy thing first which is to make sure that we're using
the health for our target rather than using the target transform as a serialized field.
So I'm going to change the type of target from transform to health and remove the serialized field and
health.
And I'm just going to grab it and stick it down below.
And now we're getting the squiggly line.
That's because we're not using the right namespace control period using RPG core.
Excellent.
We scroll down here you can see Target dot position is no longer valid because we've changed from type
transform to type health which means we need to have target dot France form dot position.
And as with the line below target dot transform dot position.
Now one other thing I do in projectile alarm here is make a public method that allows us to from elsewhere
to say what the target is to set targets.
So new line.
Public void.
This we will call set target.
We want to pass in the target of type health so health target then what do we want to do with that.
Well we need to say this target that our projectile knows once it's instantiated it knows Aha.
This is my target.
We need to be assigning the target that's been passed in into the target.
That is the instance variable.
So pretty easy we just say this referring to this game object this instance target equals target which
is referring to the target that was just passed in.
Let's go to our weapon class now and give the weapon knowledge that there is potentially that it could
potentially be a projectile.
And that's pretty simple.
What is that a new serialized field that will be of type Prue Jack dial and we will call this projectile
rejects Sol and we'll initialize that at no.
So some weapons will have a projectile and some weapons won't have a projectile.
In other words the bow and arrow vs. a sword.
And now we need to give our other classes a mechanism for knowing.
Do I have a projectile or not.
So make it simple get a method down underneath spawn let's make a new method it will be public and it
needs to return a ball and we'll call this has projectile and it's simply going to return projectile
is not equal to no OK.
That's going to give us a ball that allows us to say do we have a projectile equipped.
Yes or no that we can be calling from fighter to know whether we should be launching a projectile or
we should be hitting with our hand weapon.
And while we're here we may as well instantiate our projectile so actually create the game object.
So another public method public void launch projectile.
And we need to be passing in again the right hand and left hand so we know what those are.
And also the health for the target.
So the target which will be a type health so similar to our spawn.
But this is going to be for projectile not just for weapon so launch projectile transform right hand
come out transform and left hand.
And also we want to know the target which will be of type health.
So when launch projectile is cold what do we want to have happen.
Well we want to instantiate our projectile so we'll create this as a new variable type projectile we'll
call this projectile instance and then we dance Shiite.
Hopefully this fits on my line here.
Projectile projectile and then where.
Well we need to get the transform and we've got this information in here.
You know what it's time for us to break this out.
Remember we created this couple of videos ago so that we have our mechanism for saying Are you in the
right hand or are you in the left hand we want to do that here as well.
But we don't to put all that code in so it is refactor this grab that those three lines that our transform
and then our if and else we will hit control and period extract method that we will rename our new method
we'll rename get transform.
Okay.
Right hand left hand right.
That's all contained in there so back down to our launching of projectile so the projectile is the what
the where is going to be get transform and we need a pass in when we're calling our launch projectile
we're providing the right hand and left hand information.
So let's pass that in right hand come a left hand dot position sorry.
This is getting quite massive across our screen here comma and this is where we do the rotation which
is just simply quote Turning in dot identity and then semicolon okay.
That's quite a massive line then let me just scroll across it so you can see it.
Projectile projectile instance equals instantiate projectile which is the what get transformed right
hand left hand which is the weird position and then Quattrone an identity which is the rotation of our
instantiation and just back to the red squiggly line on health that looks like we need to be control
period using RPG core that's in a different namespace.
So that's added that RPG core up in using up at the very top.
Okay.
And now while we're here in launching projectile we need to say where's it going to.
So if you remember within projectile we've created set target which is looking for target that has a
health component on it.
And that's that setting it as the target for this projectile.
So within weapon when we instantiate this is the point where we want to say Go get him.
Here's your target sets as simply a case of typing projectile instance dot set target and then what
do we pass in passing target.
So I know I'm working backwards here but it's one of those things where I can work backwards or forward
a little bit of a web where it's all linked together so launch projectile we're going to get into that
in a second we're actually going to launch it but I wanted to create the functionality in projectile
first where it knows how to set the target and then when we jump into weapon the weapon is going to
call set target and pass in the target.
And when we coal launch projectile we need to be passing in the target and the different hand options
for the position of the left hand the right hand.
So before we bring it all together in fight or only show you one thing on our animation now this is
particular to the animation set that we have.
We've seen this before on the attack animations if I go and find animations by explosive 2 handed bow.
Open this up click on the bow attack on it to go window animation do animation.
Finally see you can see that we have our animation event in this instance it's been labelled a shoot.
Now unfortunately we don't have access to change this because we don't we don't have the animator on
our team.
This is an asset pack so we need to deal with the fact that it's called Shoot whereas when we were working
with our other weapons our melee weapons it is cold.
That's not what I want to do it is cold with my window gone it is cold so it's hit with my light and
shoot we don't want to be trying to figure out is it hit is it shoot.
So what we're going to do is just wrap shoot within heat.
No I would do that is we'll find our animation event way down.
This is in fighting not CSI.
You can see we've given a little note here hit this is out of our control.
That's why it's a little bit clunky right underneath that we are going to have a new method which we
will have void shoot.
That's the method that is sitting on our animation as an animation event.
What happens when we co shoot.
What do you think we do here.
Well we simply just call hit.
So this is a way for us just to have all this code in one place and not having to try to figure out
all the different things each time another animation event is named differently we can just point it
all towards hit.
If that is relevant so to wrap all this together I want to give this to you as a challenge.
No slide on this one but the challenge is a verbal one it's contained within hit.
So within here we need to give a mechanism that says if the current weapon has a projectile then launch
the projectile and passing the information that it needs particularly the target.
Otherwise if there is no projectile then just cold get damage and do what you do when you've just got
a sword etc..
So sitting figure that out take on that challenge now to put in our mechanism to shoot or to not shoot
Oh can I was a little bit trickier when I didn't have a slide but I like to try these things that keep
you on your toes.
Sometimes it's very verbal sometimes it's very visual.
This one we are going to implement underneath our if the target is now we'll leave that there.
We'll start by saying if current weapon member we've defined that in our fighter we have a current weapon.
DOT has projectile we've created that as a method to say do I have a projectile returnable yay or nay.
True or false.
If we do have a projectile if it's true then current weapon dot what are we going to do here.
Well we need to launch the projectile launch projectile.
We have to pass on what's it looking for transform right hand transform left hand and the target so
we know that we have a right hand transform.
We know that we have a left hand transform comma target.
So we're going to launch otherwise.
Else what are we going to do.
Well we put in our line from below target take damage current weapon.
There we go.
Current weapon get damage should be the same as it was before.
Tidy up our lines a little bit.
What have I done wrong here it's got to squarely line.
Oh I forgot a semicolon of course.
My apologies for that.
Save everything up and this is all looking pretty sharp.
OK.
So that was a ton of code.
Hopefully you followed along there.
Let's jump back over into unity.
See what we've got.
We will give the player a bow.
Whereas the play here.
Default weapon bow Great let's go have a look at the bow make sure it's doing what it needs to be doing
scroll down.
Game weapons bow there's the bow projectile we need to give it a projectile the projectile is going
to be in our projectiles photo arrow projectile drag that over in so now have an arrow projectile.
OK and we've still got the arrow in the same we don't need it anymore it's not going to know what to
do.
Our arrow projectile excellent gonna jump into this prefab changed the speed to our former and we'll
make it six for now so we can see it going through the air hopefully jump on back click on play okay
people fear could our big old bow back to here click on an enemy and am okay has gone pretty slow but
looks I reckon pretty epic and awesome blue this is projectiles you can speed it up to your heart's
content to make fast the arrows we're going to be out of ad trails on the back of it we had a substitute
instead of bows and arrows going to fireballs but this is the start of it we can have the enemy shooting
at us super pumped super excited that we now have shooting of projectiles in our game in upcoming videos
we need to destroy the arrows we need to decrease the health of the person you clunk into and we'll
add all that sparkle as well.
So great work thanks for your patience I know this was a big video and I'll see you in an upcoming lecture.