Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We aren't going to be visualizing waypoint loops so that you can see the path that your enemy is going
to take we're gonna be doing this by drawing lines between them and everything that we need to know
in order to do that.
Let's dive in and see how so the issue with these waypoints at the moment is they don't give us any
indication of what comes when.
Right.
Do I start on this waypoints and then go over to that one then I to that one then back to this one and
then back to that one.
Is it.
There's no indication at the moment what the path is we've got waypoints but no path.
So how are we going to visualize the path.
Well we've already seen that we can draw.
We want to draw lines between these now drawing lines is fairly straightforward.
We do something like gizmos dot draw the line and we need to tell it where to start the line and where
to end the line.
So that seems pretty straightforward.
We've got this transform get child position currently and we want to get the next position as well.
So how is that going to work.
Well I'm going to start off by extracting this because we're using it in more than one place already.
And usually we wait for three places but I think it's going to be sensible to extract at this stage
so I'm going to extract it says it's automatically named to get position I want to call it get waypoints
and that's getting us the position of the waypoint with index i.
Now actually this is going to be useful later on when we are trying to access this from the A.I. in
order to move to our different waypoints but we'll make it public at that point.
Not yet.
Okay.
So we're going to get the waypoint I.
That's the first thing right.
We were going to draw a line from waypoint AI and then we're going to do it to waypoint b basically
waypoints.
I'm going to call it waypoint J.
OK.
So I and J.
Now the problem here is that we don't have a J.
So I'm going to have to have an int j.
And you might be tempted to say that J is I plus 1 OK so that is a good start but not quite good enough.
It's not going to be the solution to our problem.
So I'm just going to encapsulate this into a function extract the method out called get J.
We're gonna call it get next index like so.
So we pass in the current index and it returns as the next index and at the moment it's told that it
could be static which is quite cool that it could figure that out for itself.
Okay so that's great.
But as I said this already has a problem and I think you might be able to work that out for yourself.
So as we said the basic case is fairly easy just plus one to I.
But what is the corner case.
Think about it.
Where is that not going to be correct.
Whereas that's not going to create the loop that we want because by the end of the challenge what I
would like to see is that your patrol path looks something like this one pulls a video and see if you
can implement get index get next index.
So it works like this okay.
Welcome back.
So the corner case that we're thinking about is if this is the first one then it's got a next right.
Zero goes to one.
One goes to two.
Two goes to three but then three has to go to zero so that's not plus one anymore.
Now those of you who know about modulo arithmetic might be screaming that that is the perfect time to
use modulo arithmetic.
I don't want to confuse those of you who don't know what that is.
So there is a simple way of doing this that is to say well if we are currently at the child transform
count.
So if the index plus 1 is equal to and we could probably just say for safety is greater than or equal
to the transform dot child count then what we want to actually return is zero.
In fact that's not quite correct for greater than equal to so I'm going to go with equal to.
So if I plus one is equal to the child count.
So for example if I've got three children and the eye I've got is two.
That means it's the last element.
Right.
It's the last child.
So the next element has to be zero.
You have to start from scratch again.
Now notice it's saying I can't use transform in here.
So I need to remove that static because I need to be able to say how many children I've gotten.
Repeat round that loop accurately and so will return zero.
Otherwise we're just going to return a plus one.
So that should do the trick.
Let's see if it is working.
Okay.
So this is now showing us the path and it's not the path we were expecting is it.
There's the waypoints one if I go into my scene view we can see that waypoint one is this one here then
waypoint two goes over here then waypoint 3 I'm naming them wrong ready waypoint 0 is here waypoint
one is here waypoint 2 is here and waypoint 3 is here so it kind of it's it's a zigzag patrol what about
this set of waypoints over here so what waypoint one here waypoint two there three there and four is
in the same location so if I pull that out you can see how the path is following in the right way that's
exactly what we would like it to do so we can now create our waypoints the more items we add the more
waypoints we add I can duplicate and add another waypoint item in here knows it's an addition to our
prefab which is fine you can go ahead and modify the path in this way you can select a waypoint not
very easily I think you have to do it from the hierarchy but if you do do it from the hierarchy then
you are golden you're able to select a waypoint this waypoint zero and I want to add one between here
and here I can just duplicate it mood shift it in the order of the hierarchy which is a little bit hard
to do and you can basically modify things around you might want to take things out of prefabs or break
the prefabs if you must but basically you can create the waypoints that you want so I'm sure at this
point you're saying okay Sam I've had up to here with waypoints I want to actually implement some guard
behaviour and that's gonna be the subject of the next lecture so join me that.