Hello again my friend and this video we're starting the process of what I think is pretty critical call
to an RPG is some mac and someone in the face.
So let's jump in and implement an attack animation state.
OK.
First thing for us to do is to grab some animation so I've given you an animation pack that you can
download animations by explosive.
So just unzip that once you've done that drag that over into your project.
From here we can click on import and that brings in animations by explosive you can see the read me
with usage rights.
This is another one of those for noncommercial use you can use it as a student however you like but
please don't try to sell it and to make money out of it if you want to do that you can buy.
Yes it's from this creator.
I just want to show you quickly what they've got some really cool stuff there's a free animation pack
that they provide RPG character Magnum animation pack free.
I've given you a link against this lecture for that.
And also if you want to have a look at their full animations like the full kit and caboodle then there
is their full pack RPG character mechanism animation pack lots of really really useful animations in
there for an RPG.
Now if you're curious I wonder what's in this asset pack.
Then you can have a look at by clicking on the package preview.
This is in the free pack and then opening it up to see what's going on in the animations you can see
all these or the two handed animation.
So in other words if the characters running around with the two handed sword or there's the unarmed
animations as well and you can see that there's a whole variety of stuff in here things that we don't
need what are we using John Paul or rolling or strafing but there great animations for you to have access
to so just again thanks to these guys for letting us use their animations.
And the one that I've given you is a tiny tiny little subset of the paid for PAC that they've allowed
us to use.
So what we need to do here is to create ourselves a new animation state to create a trigger by clicking
on the little plus sign here.
So make sure you're on the parameters tab and selecting trigger and then to hook up some transitions
and that is a little summary of the challenge for you.
So ad and attack state in the animated controller create transitions in and out of attack and to create
a trigger called attack and then to test that that trigger works.
So there's a challenge.
Jump in I'll see you back here when you done Okay first thing let's create a state right click bit too
hasty there click on empty.
Change the name so tap on it and then tap up here again.
And then what should we call this attack.
A double T AC K attack.
And then we need to select an animation.
You know what.
Let's preview it first let's see what they're about.
So how do we do that.
Well find the animations and I'll look in the unarmed because we don't have a weapon at the moment so
I'm looking unarmed.
We will have a weapon soon but that's coming in upcoming elections.
Now look here if I want a preview say this one I open it up find the gray symbol with the the white
arrow.
That's the animation symbol.
Now over on the right hand side the inspector you can see down the bottom.
It's been hidden for me.
Drag that up when you click play nothing happens.
But if we drag in our player into the preview window we get our player in there now and I can click
on play and preview the animation.
And then what.
That looks pretty good.
It kind of looks like he's punching in the midsection.
That's a bit of a dirty low blow.
I think that matches our character nicely crotchety old man.
That's going to be doing a groin punch.
OK.
Fantastic.
So we have an animation that I like so click back on the animation state click on our selector and then
unarmed attack L3.
That's the one we want.
Leave all the other intel as it is.
Now we need to make some transitions.
So click on locomotion right click and make transition to attack and then again right click from attack
make transition back to locomotion.
Now I'm going to click on the Arrow or the line that's coming from locomotion to attack just put my
preview out of the way.
And we need to have some mechanism from getting from locomotion to attack and that mechanism is going
to be a trigger.
So click on the plus over here and we find trigger mean of course attack with a small a and then still
while clicked on our transition line here I click the plus under conditions it's not forward speed.
It is attack.
We're looking for.
And that will be the trigger because we have this trigger condition.
I'm going to turn off has exit time.
We don't need an exit time from locomotion exit time basically means when the animation has finished
doing its thing.
But if we're constantly in the Locomotion state until we trigger an attack then this exit time will
never happen.
So going back the other way however we want exit time to be clicked because we say once the attack is
finished then go back to locomotion for now.
That's the way we'll do it.
So let's click on play see if this has worked.
How do we preview it when we don't have any code.
Well we clicked a little button here boink good punch and you click off it again and then click on and
that triggers the punch on and off.
Excellent.
Now I want to show you something very quickly Warren here.
If you look at the transition going from locomotion to attack you can see under settings that we've
got a transition duration of point two five.
I'm gonna change that to zero.
Get out of play mode so it sticks.
Change it to zero.
And now when I click on play and click on my trigger it's going immediately into both into the punch.
So does that look good it kind of snaps in if you wanted to have that snap look about it then that's
all cool.
Yeah I think I'm gonna have this snap.
I think that looks good.
Now if we're transitioning out you can see that we've got a under settings we've got a point to 5 transition
if I was to put that to zero and to snap straight from attack back to like locomotion or back to idle
you can see that snap looks a little bit yucky.
So I'm going to leave this as the point to five that it was so that it's a little bit more blending
this is the blend from attack to locomotion is blending between those two animations that it blends
back nicely.
I think that looks pretty solid in the next video we'll hook it up so we can trigger this from our code.
Great work and I'll see you again soon.