Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be polishing off the section by having our fades happen between AC loads like so and
to do that we're going to have to persist.
The Fader between scenes so that it can remember whether it was faded down or faded up and we don't
have to do anything complicated there.
So we are going to find a way of doing this without using the Singleton pattern which has many disadvantages.
And we're going to do this in a nice way instead.
So let's dive in and see what that way is so at the moment our theta is not prefab and not shared between
scenes that's on it we're going to fix.
So I'm gonna go and select the game core folder and prefab theta into there.
And I'm also going to go ahead and prefab the whole of this core under core because I want to do is
make sure that that is in every scene so that we don't have to make sure that as a player there's a
camera there's a fade all these things that we're going to have to have in every scene.
We can just plonk in the core prefab and we can see now that this is a nested prefab like we've got
before I open up the core prefab you can see it has the player's prefab in it has the faders pleat prefab
and it hasn't gone and flatten things out.
Now if I go ahead and open up sandbox to Yeah I'm gonna save my changes and I am going to find the game
core folder and drag in the core prefab in the place of the player to help if I'm in the same view.
So let's go ahead and find the player in the scene double click and locate him then drag in our core
into here.
So and you can see my play is not located at the center of core I think that's a bit well we'll update
it here in this scene anyway.
So I'm going to set the position of my play to 0 0 0 so he's there and I'm going to delete that original
core folder.
So that's not a duplicate and just rename the prefab to one.
So we've got consistency as my player.
So if I go into the scene now we should see that it all plays perfectly and we've got the fader automatically
in our second scene as well which is essentially what we wanted to be able to do.
However you will notice that with this Fader if I go between levels it resets and starts again and that's
not what we want.
We want this Fader to hold its state between levels because what we're going to be doing is as we walk
through reports we're going to be fading out and then we want it to fade back into the new level.
So wants to be able to remember that we had faded out and there's no glitching no loading no problems
like that.
Now this is the point at which most people tend to reach for the Singleton pattern.
However there's a few reasons I really dislike the Singleton pattern now the first one is that it leads
to really tight coupling because with a singleton pattern you can always access the class from anywhere
which means that you tend to access it from anywhere.
And that means that any class is going to rely on it so often very tightly coupled.
It also is too much responsibility for one class because the class has to be responsible for making
sure that it's the only instance around as well as doing its normal job.
And it removes our flexibility because what if we decide that all of a sudden we don't want our fate
to be a singleton anymore it's going to change everything that depends on it because it all everything
thought that it was the only thing around everything thought that you would get it by getting there
faded for instance and if that is not the case then how are we going to do it properly.
So I'm going to propose an alternative to using the Singleton pattern where we instead have a prefab
of objects that we want to persist between levels and I'm going to call these The persistent objects.
So I'm going to create a new empty game object and call it persistent objects and under that I'm going
to drag our fade object.
Now notice because I've just prefab it I'm gonna have to go into the core prefab remove the fader from
the core prefab and I'm going to drop it on to the persistent objects and I'm going to make a prefab
of the persistent objects.
Now what I want to do is not actually have this persistent objects in the scene but have it spawned
in by a class and I'm going to call that class the persistent object spawner.
So I'm going to create a new class over in Visual Studio I'm going to have it under Cor you just see
a code rather.
Going to create a new class called persistent object spawner.
Don't say yes and I am going to create the mono behaviour and I'm going to namespace it to core RPG
core and what I'm going to do with this spawner lesson while we've got it created let's just go ahead
and I'm going to go into the core prefab because we want this spawner in every scene we wanted wherever
whichever scene we start in we want the persistent objects to get spawned.
So I'm going to add this core persistent object spawner onto the core prefab the root of that don't
really matter where it goes and then what I'm gonna want is a reference to the serialize field a game
object because basically I want a prefab here and I want to know what is the persistent object prefab.
So that's what I'm going to call this object here and then we can implement an awake method and we want
to do is basically instantiate the persistent object prefab but how do we know if this is the first
scene how do we know we haven't already created this persistent object prefab and as the name suggests
it has persisted from the previous scene well the way I'm gonna do this is with a static variable it's
going to be a bool has spawned so if you never come across a static variable before he has a quick description
a normal variable usually lives and dies with the class.
So in the case of our spawner between scenes you would lose the state of the boolean whether it has
spawned or not with a static variable however it lives and dies with the application rather than with
the instance of the class which means that once we have set this boolean in one instance of the class
in a future scene where we've got a new instance of the persistent object spawner that is going to remember
the value that it was set before.
Now generally this is a bad idea because it's a global variable but in this case we've got very few
options with the way unity is structured and we're gonna default it to false.
So by default we haven't spawned.
So in a way I'm going to say if has spawned then we're just going to return and not do anything.
And otherwise we are going to say it has spawned true.
And we're going to call the spawn persistent objects function which I'm going to create now so controlled
dot to generate that.
And that should basically do the trick.
So what we're going to do here is create that prefab and set it to do not destroy on load like you can
take that as a little mini challenge for you.
So what we're gonna get back.
Once we instantiate is a game object and I'm going to call this the persistent object like so and we're
going to instantiate the prefab which is the persistent object prefab which we've got now sterilized
field here like so.
And then what.
So once we've got that instantiated we want to make sure that it won't be destroyed on load so that
it hangs around.
Simple as that.
So let's see whether this has worked out our core now has this persistent object spawner.
It's asking for a prefab let's drop in the prefab that we created over game core which is our position
objects and that basically has all the objects we want to hang around.
So if I go ahead and hit play Let's see if it's doing what we'd expect.
We've got this don't destroy and load part of the scene which is a persistent object clone and it has
got the fader under it.
So if I go through the portal notice it doesn't spawn another fader.
We don't get any more fading but we still got the fader from the previous scene hanging around.
So that's done the job and we haven't had to use a single Singleton but the astute among you will have
noticed that we did use a static.
So it is sort of like a singleton but not quite.
And it's certainly not a way of getting access to the persistent objects for that we have to rely on
things like find objects and tags and all those other mechanisms that we know and love.
So with all that done we can now actually access the fader from our transition and doing that we can
very easily just do it with a C the fader are gonna have a fade object to store here and I'm just going
do I find objects by type and that's going to be of type Fader like so and with this we can now call
all of its public methods which are the fade out in the fading and in fact I'm going to remove this
co routine now because we no longer need that we're just using that for testing purposes to show you
how you can cool coatings within coatings which you're going to use now in your challenge to fade between
scenes.
So you want to fade out completely before the scene load then fade back in afterwards and maybe you
want to have a little wait while the screen is completely fade out to allow the camera to settle and
for the play and not to see any jiggling around the camera or the player which is of a good idea and
make it all configurable so the designer can change the parameters of how long it is.
Fade out fade in and wait.
Pause video and have a go at this challenge okay.
Welcome back.
So hopefully that wasn't too tricky.
Let's give it a shot.
So we've got this don't destroy our load.
We're doing a finding our fader.
Now I'm actually going to go ahead and put some line breaks in here and just before I yield return to
load the scene asynchronously I'm going to make sure that we are completely faded out.
Which basically means that we're going to do a yield return to make sure that occur routine has finished
and we're going to call the fade a dot fade out routine with a time that I want to have configurable
so to make these times configurable I'm going to add some serialized fields so first serialized field
is going to be float and the fade out time and I'm going to default this to two seconds maybe two seconds
might be a bit long.
We probably want to fade out quite quickly.
So then I'm going to copy and have a fade in time and that can be a bit longer and then we'll have a
fade wait time I'll call it and I'll be like very small point five or something like that.
So now we can use those variables our fade out we're going to have a fade out time as we fade out and
then once the scene comes back up we are going to make sure we've done all of our setup.
So we've got the other portal updated our player then we are going to do our yield return.
And I'm just gonna do a wait for seconds.
So that's going to be new.
Wait four seconds and we're going to use the fade wait time there.
And the idea there is that we've done all last set up we've moved the player and then the waiting we're
just gonna wait five seconds or point five seconds for the camera to stabilize and things like that
and then once we've done that we can start the process of yield return fade a dot fade in and that's
gonna be the fade in time like so and then when that's finally finished the job of this current portal
is done so we can go ahead and destroy it and you can see how this is all happening asynchronously we're
not having to pause the whole game we're just being I would say fade out over a series of frames then
load over a series of five frames update the player and wait for a series of frames and then fade in
over a series of frames so this whole function can take many frames to run that's the whole beauty of
the cover routine so let's go ahead and give us a shot we're gonna go ahead and hit play and see if
our character.
No fade happening right now if I go through the portal fades down fades back up slowly in the New World.
Now this is all configurable I felt that first fade was a little bit slow.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go to the fader prefab and just change it for all the instances of
the fader nope sorry I need to get to the portal prefab and change it for all the instances of the portal
because we put our fade out times on the portal so the fade out I'm gonna make point five seconds really
quick fade in time just one second long and the wait time.
Point five let's give that shot I go and play fades out pretty quickly so that my running animation
doesn't look like it comes to an end so it looks like he's just running on into the next level and then
the fading looked pretty good.
So to recap what we've achieved in this lecture is the ability to call our fader in transition period
and we've done that by allowing our Fader to live between scenes and essentially be a singleton without
using the Singleton pattern by using this persistent object spawner instead.
And hopefully you see how that's nice and neat and persistent object spawner is a small class and the
fader itself managed to say so.
Small class 2 and each is responsible for its own job.
So that brings us to the end of this scene management section I hope you agree that it's quite fun to
be able to transition between scenes with this fading visualization and be able to go through multiple
portals and appear at the other side of a level and that gives you lots of levers to pull and position
and put together many levels in a quite a wide and large world.
I really look forward to seeing what maps of worlds you come up with please go and share them over on
the forum linked against this lecture.