Hello and welcome in this lecture, we are going to be hooking into the play and stop events of the
playbill director so that when we walk into our trigger, we get a disabled control lock message showing
up.
And when we get to the end of the timeline, which is just going to happen after we see this God, we
then get a re-enable control log message.
So we're getting events coming through at the right time.
We're gonna learn a little bit about what C sharp events are and also how we can use them to implement
the observer pattern.
So we're gonna learn about the observer pattern and a little bit about C shape events so that we can
implement it.
Let's dive right in.
So as Rick pointed out, last lecture, we have an issue where if I go into the cinematics, you can
see I'm still able to control the character and get him into all sorts of trouble while I'm holding
my mouse down there as my character.
He was running all the time and got himself into trouble.
So we want to be able to remove that control.
The way we're gonna do this is to add a new components to the intro sequence game objects that's under
cinematics interest sequence.
And we're going to want to add a new component here called the Cinematic Control Remover.
And the job of this components is that when the cinematic sequence is running is going to remove the
control from the player.
I'm gonna go ahead and create it in a visual studio code and I'm going to create a new file.
It's gonna be the cinematics control.
Remove remover dot C.
S.
So go ahead and create that.
I'm gonna add a mono behavior in here and I'm gonna wrap this in a namespace like I can do it properly,
like.
So it's gonna be RPG cinematics like we've had before.
Boom.
Now in order for this components to its job properly, it's going to need to run code when it needs
to enable control.
And when it needs to disable control, which is gonna happen when we're starting the sequence and stopping
at the sequence.
So we've got two cases where we need a method in this script.
One case is going to be one, one to disable control.
At that point, we're going to want to do something in this function.
And the other time is when we want to re-enable control.
And the stuff that goes on in here we could easily figure out how to do involves a play controller,
involves cancelling actions and so on and so forth.
But how we gonna get these functions called in the first place?
When are they gonna be cool?
How can we work that out?
Well, does able control.
You might say, okay, easy enough.
When we call the trigger and we start play on the playback director, we could call disable control.
Sure.
But how do we re-enable control?
How do we know when the cinematic has finished?
And in actual fact, that can knowing when the cinematic is finished, we can then do an even cleaner
solution for disabled control.
And the thing here is that we want to be notified of a given event.
I'm going to put a start method in here because we're going to need this in a bit.
So imagine we have a situation like this one.
We've got playable director and it wants to notify the control remover, maybe a particle effect, maybe
some music changes.
It wants to notify somethings of the fact that the playable has finished playing.
The timeline in our instance has finished playing.
Now, the playable director can't make direct method calls to these different components because unity,
when they coded the playbill director, didn't know that you might need these components.
So they can't have had a direct method call to them.
So we have to have some other way of telling the playbill director that we'd like to know that the timeline
has finished play.
Now, typically what we've seen, for example, and things like the cinematic trigger is that if you
want some code to run when a collide is on trigger enter event happens, then you can just use a special
method name and it will automatically be called by unity.
That's one way of doing it.
But it's a bit of a messy way because you need to use the exact right method name.
And it can get a bit messy in terms of you have to have your component on the right game object and
it's just not as flexible and it's not as clear and straightforward.
And it's especially obvious when you have things like our fighter with our hit event.
Right.
We've even had to at annotate this as being an animation event because it's so unclear who is calling
this, because it's just being called because of the special name that's so unobvious and not very nice.
So there is a nice way of doing this in C Sharp, and that is to use events to essentially implement
the observer pattern.
What is the observer pattern?
Well, basically, instead of the playable director calling down to the control, remove a particle
effects music, change all stuff that has nothing at all to do with, really, it can just keep a list
of things of observers, things that want to observe an event happening in the play above playable director.
In this case, the on Finnish event that say so what can happen is the controller mover can register
itself, the particle effect, the music change can all register themselves to this list.
So notice the arrows are going this way round.
It's another dependancy inversion, if you like.
And so what you end up with in this list is a list of the observers, the control remover, the particle
effect, the music change, cetera.
So now when the playbill director decides to finish playing boom, it calls to its observer list and
the observer list calls out to all the controller movies.
But notice in this process, the playbill director didn't have to know who any of the observers were.
It's kind of like our interfaces that we've already seen.
The difference being that for.
Interfaces, the arrow gets flipped typically between one class that's calling one other class.
Whereas here with the observer pattern and events, these arrows can be flipped from one class calling
to many classes.
So back in our control, remove a class.
I'm going to add some print statements to help us basically figure out when these methods are being
called.
So I had to say, well, control method, for example, is going to be one print statement and I'll
put a similar print statement in enable control.
Now I'm going to introduce a component called a fake playable director, which is going to give us an
indication of how unity might be doing this under the hood, how it's working under the hood.
You don't have to create this yourself.
Just follow along with the video to understand the concepts.
And let's take a second.
Now that we've created these two to actually go and stick them onto the intro sequence.
So the fake play director.
And the cinematic disabling remove a component.
So as both go on the intro sequence.
Now I'm going to flesh out the fake playbill director with a start method that is going to call to an
on finished method after having played for three seconds.
This is going to simulate what the playable director does, which is wait until the clip has finished
playing before calling the on finished method.
What do we want to do in here?
To notify all these cinematic control removers, et cetera?
Well, I'm going to write a line and then I'm going to explain it to you.
So what we've got here is a C sharp event, and it's essentially the C sharp way of implementing that
observer list from the slides.
Don't worry about the specifics of how this is implemented and used in the playable direct aside, as
we won't be doing that in our own code.
But what we're interested in is knowing how we can add ourselves as an observer to this list.
So I'm gonna do this in the cinematic control remover.
So I'm going to do to get components of the fake playable director and I can access it on finished notice
here how the on finish has a little lightning bolt.
This is because of the keyword event.
Basically events allows us to add some protections to these kinds of variables that store functions
our lists of functions in them.
But don't worry about the key words.
And this line too much right now because we will have a static, catered lecture on declaring and using
events and delegates in a few sections time.
So what I want to do is on finish.
Here we are going to plus equals.
This is basically adding ourselves as one of the observers in this observer pattern list.
And then we need to put in the method that we wanted to call.
Now, notice, I'm calling a table control because it's finished.
But notice that we don't want to use the round brackets because we're not calling it here in START.
We're telling on finish to call it.
We're telling the playbill director that it can call it.
So we just need to give the name of the method.
Now, one more thing.
It says, No Overload Matches, Action Float.
Now, the reason for this is because I deliberately made this action take a variable.
And that means that our callback, just like, for example, you're on trigger, has to take a collider
out on enable control, has to take what was it, a float.
Now, I've just done this to show you how this works is basically nonsense float, but it has to take
some float value.
And then what's it saying?
Just that it wants a semicolon at the end of the line, obviously.
So that's how you use them.
How are they then called?
Well, basically on Finnish now would call to this delegate on Finnish.
And that's where the round brackets come back in.
So basically on finish is a variable that represents a list of different callbacks, a list of different
functions that have registered themselves.
And when we call on finish actually calls all of the things in the list.
So if I'd gone on to do on finish disabled control as well, both of these gonna get called.
Let me show you that that is an option that see this yet just saying that we don't have the nonsense
float again.
And so that and also there's an error here because we haven't put any floats in.
Let's put like four point three or something is the float that comes in four point three F.
And let's actually go ahead and play and just show you that in the console we should be getting both
the enable and disable control coming through.
Go to the console, wait for three seconds and we get enable and disable come through actually in the
order that we added them.
That's kind of interesting.
If we reverse the order, you might see that the order of them getting called is also changed.
So it's time for your challenge to find the real events.
Looking the docs or auto complete in this case, instead of using the fake playable director, let's
use the real playable directors.
I'll just show you Playbill director.
And I think I need to include a different namespace yet unity engine playbills in order to do this.
And so I'll need to be able to find in here the real event so you can do a dot and then auto complete
to find events.
Remember that lightning bolt signals up events for you or you can look in the docs using a different
editor.
When does the director start playing?
When does it finish playing?
See if you can find events for both of those and test with print statements to see whether your disabling
control in enabling control at the right moment.
So pause the video and have a go at the challenge.
OK, welcome back.
So hopefully you're getting to grips a little bit with the idea of events and how they can help us with
the observer pattern.
So do a dot.
And we'll look through this list for anything that has add a little lightning bolt.
There's a few of them paused, played and stopped.
Perfect.
I think we want played for one so played and we can then do our plus equals to add one of the methods
to the list of callbacks that should come through this.
And what we to do when it's played is when to disable control, maybe slightly counterintuitively.
Now there's an error there, but I'm going to come back to it in a second because the other callback
we wanted was dot stopped like so.
And then we can do plus equals enable control instead.
OK, now what it's complaining about if we hover over it, is it saying no overload for disabled control.
Match's delegate action, playable director.
So you can see that it's changed here.
The action, instead of being an action float, is an action playable director.
So hopefully you realize that the these methods need to take a playable director as the argument in
here.
And I'm just gonna call this PD because we don't even use it.
But basically, this is saying this is the playable director that is calling us that is calling this
action.
And if I do that, then hopefully you will be able to see that I can hit play.
And I would expect to get our callbacks when we start playing, when we stop playing.
We can safely ignore this null reference exception.
It's coming from our fake playable director, which we're soon going to delete.
If I go into the zone, you can say disabled control because we have gone into the trigger and the playable
director has started playing.
And then when it stopped, we should enable control again.
And that has happened in the right print statement.
So you can see how we're able to use events to hook into different moments in other classes lifecycle
and understood a little bit how that's working behind the scenes.
You don't have to fully understand this class.
The important thing is that you know how to use these events and how to subscribe to them over here
and the cinematic control ruber.
So just to reinforce that, I'm actually gonna go ahead and delete the fake playable director that was
only there to show us how the playable director might be working behind the scenes.
Now, in this video, I actually forget to remove it from the object in the scene, which obviously
leads to warnings.
If you go and remove it, you'll get rid of those warning.
But if you see that on my screen, that's what's going on.
Hopefully you're a bit more enlightened about events.
And in the next lecture, we're gonna go ahead and make these disable and enable control things, actually
do something.