Hello and welcome in this lecture we are with me Sam.
Rather than Rick and we're gonna be talking about folder structures and the folder structure that we're
gonna be using throughout this course and why it makes sense for us so at the end we're gonna end up
with a nice clean folder structure.
You can see the top level of our assets folder structure is pretty neat and not very many folders and
even the second levels as you can see over here in this left hand side of the page is looking pretty
good and sensible.
And I'll also explain why it is laid out this way and what's the reasoning behind it was for us and
how you might come up with your own folder structures for your own projects.
Ivan so over the course of the past section we have got to this folder structure is kind of evolved
out and Rick has been heading in this sort of direction.
I just want to take a minute to step back and tidy it up a little bit and talk about some of the decisions
that we're making here and why we're going down this route with the folder structure.
So first of all let's have a little chat about why you'd have different folders at the top level by
the top level I mean here at the root of assets we've got things like asset pack characters game scenes.
What's a good reason to have a folder up here at this top level.
So one good reason is if it is for a decent different discipline for example our scripts folder has
a good reason to exist here because it is for programmers.
For example you might have a different folder for models for designers et cetera.
Also different organization usually different disciplines require different organizations within the
folder structure.
So you start with a different folder at the top level and then within that you can have a different
layout depending on the different disciplines and needs.
That's what I mean by different organization of folders and then another good reason is if there's too
much nesting if you have got to go folder within folder within folder to find an asset that you use
very very regularly it's a good idea to bring some folders out to bring it out to the top level so that
you can more easily access stuff you don't want to be going drilling down all the time.
It's no good just having one folder at the top level if you have to always click into it for example.
So these are the reasons behind our folder structure I'd like to take a sec to have a look at the particular
folder choices that we've made.
The first one that stands out is the script as I've said this is for programmers and the content of
it is code.
So let's have a look at that.
Let's check this is correct.
We've got scripts and inside it we've got code that seems right enough but then I've said the structure
is by namespace or by feature.
So we'll talk about namespace is later on don't worry about this.
But by now we'll just think about features.
So what kind of features have we got here at the moment we've got a movement feature a movement kind
of feature space and we've got the follow camera which is more to do with.
Well I do know it's more of a kind of core of an RPG.
So I'm going to move these into folders already I'm going to create some folders one for movement and
all the scripts to do with the movement feature will go in there at the moment we've only got one but
we will have more and a word of warning.
At this stage because if you have this script that we're moving around open in Visual Studio code while
you're moving it somewhere else it can lead to you saving in Visual Studio code into the old location
so make sure you close any scripts and Visual Studio code before you start moving them around.
And then we're going to add a new one for kind of core features of the new folder called core and I'm
going to move the follow camera into that.
So that's what I meant by that layout.
We're gonna have scripts program at content and the namespace feature.
So the idea here the reason we're dividing it by features is because we want to minimize the dependency
between different features.
We don't want movement having to depend on lots of other features because it makes it a nightmare for
us to code when we need to go and change how movement works if we have to be thinking about how combat
works and how all these other things work.
So that's the reason for splitting it down by feature.
And it's also logical and an easy way to find your scripts.
Then we have got the game folder which is going to be mainly for the designer.
If you don't have a design if you're the same person it's when you're putting on your designer hat and
deciding to do some design work and the contents of this is gonna be prefabs and scriptural objects
and other unity configurable type things.
Stuff that you create in the Unity Editor basically.
So we've got this game folder.
And at the moment it has got prefabs in it's got a follow camera and it's got the player.
And what else have we got.
We've got these characters folder which at the moment contains the character controller Well I would
say that is something the designer creates as well particularly the animation flow and things like that.
So I'm going to stick that character's folder under the game folder to tidy up a little bit then you'll
notice the player is also a character and what I've said on this line is that the structure should be
by entity previously with the scripts we're doing it by features and movements et cetera by entity is
more like saying by the characters by the weapons by the players and so on and so forth.
So at this level of structure in the game we're gonna have the characters we might have another folder
for weapons like that and then potions cetera and things like that.
And also I'm gonna have a kind of core folder because we want to put our follow camera in core and our
player in characters because that's the logical place for it to be.
Now you can organize characters further if you've got lots of assets that are relating to the play you
might put it in a player folder but we're gonna leave that until a little bit later.
Now the next thing is the scenes folder.
This is where the level designer lives again.
Maybe if it's just you putting on your level designer hat when you're going to do some level design
that's where you can put scenes to terrains NAF measures things relating to a particular scene or used
by just the scenes not used kind of across scenes and things like that and the structure here is pretty
simply going to be by scene.
So we've got our scenes folder and under that we've got a sandbox folder the scene sandbox is not in
the sandbox folder.
I think that's fine again because too much nesting means that when we need to get to the common things
like the sandbox scene it can make it hard to get to.
So I'm leaving the scene which is most access outside but any assets relating to that scene go inside
the sandbox folder and there is one asset that has slipped the net.
It's this new terrain asset which is actually should be called something like the sandbox terrain and
we can put that sandbox terrain in the sandbox folder of the scenes folder.
So if we added more scenes in here we would add more folders.
I think that makes quite a lot of sense.
Let me know what you think then the next choice is for the for having a UI folder.
I'm going to create this UI folder even though we don't have any UI to put in it yet.
This is where we're going to put different screens so inside the UI folder you might have a folder for
the pause menu you might have a folder for the what else we might have.
The in venturing and so on and so forth.
That's what I mean by organizing it by the different screens then the asset packs.
This is pretty self-explanatory when you important asset pack our asset packs will automatically go
into the asset pack folder if you bring in your own asset packs I recommend you move them into the asset
pack folder.
The idea here is that we don't touch anything that goes within these asset pack folders.
We don't add anything we don't remove anything we don't change anything because if we do when we want
to update asset packs it'll be really hard for us and we have accidentally done this with the terrain
textures asset pack.
So you see these four assets here are layers they're layers for our terrain and because they relate
to the scenes I'm gonna take them over to a common folder.
In scenes we might want to use it between scenes for example I'm going to create a folder called shared
in the scenes folder and go back to those terrain textures and pull them over into that shared folder.
So now we've left our asset packs untouched in their original state which means that if you need to
update them because we will provide updates to these packs we'll be providing more textures more animations
et cetera then you can go ahead and do that and finally a note about audio and models we're not producing
them as part of the course.
So we're not going to be putting them in these audio and models folders but for example if we go up
to the rate of assets you might create a folder for models you might create a folder for audio and if
you create any of your own voice acting you might put stuff in audio.
If you do any of your own modelling you might put stuff in models and leave the layout of those folders
entirely to you whatever makes sense.
I'm going to delete them though because we don't have anything to put in there and we're likely not
gonna be using them ourselves in this course okay.
So that is the summary of our choices.
Hopefully you're following along maybe you did some reorganizing of your own stuff but now is the time
for you to really think about the organization of your own project.
So I'd like you to take a moment to tidy up your own project look through see if anything is different
from ours maybe if you have another project somewhere sitting around that you think was really messy
you'll go and try and apply some principles to that.
So not even the project we've done so far but a different Unity project you've had.
What structure works for you.
Think about the particular project think about the particular needs of the project.
I strongly recommend you don't touch assets though especially for this course because we will be updating
things like animation packs and it'll just make your life easier and then celebrate being organized
than you maybe you go and share your organization over on the forum what you've chosen.
Give us some feedback about what you think about our folder structure and whether you've chosen to do
anything different and the reasoning behind that.
So I'm just gonna go straight on to the next video here.
So after this video has finished go and do your organization and come back and follow the rest of the
course.