Welcome again my friend in this video.
We're gonna make an art show.
We're going to shoot arrows and those arrows are gonna have a spiffy trials coming out the back of them
to make them really easy to see on our screen.
So let's jump in and get started.
Okay.
Just to recap where we are now.
This is our arrow.
We shoot.
Balance pretty bland.
Not very exciting so let's resolve that the first thing I'm going do is you know I need to get my speed
of my arrow how I want it so I'm gonna go into my arrow projectile prefab and turn the speed.
I think I can turn off to 20 and then just check that this is good because when we're creating a trail
to come flying off our arrow we want to know that we've got our speed settled in a way we're happy with
it.
So yeah it feels like a good I can see it flying across the screen.
It feels pretty quick.
I like it.
Okay.
So I'm gonna have my arrow speed my projectile speed at 20.
Now within my arrow myself a bit of space here that will click on simple arrow.
Okay.
So within here we've got our arrow we've got our collision boxing to add as a new child under arrow
projectile right click and go into effect and we have something here called trail.
So we have our trail first we're going to do is turn down the time because this is like a particle system.
This is how long things will be emitted for on our trial.
Before I show you exactly what's going on the trial will turn it down to say point to.
Yeah that looks.
Now if I grab the handle this is selected on trial so I grab my selection handle here move it right
and left.
You can see as I move along there's a trial that comes flying along behind doesn't look very arrow only
at the moment.
So what we want to do is decrease the width of it it's to be at the moment so the width at the moment
you can see here and our selection is one we can change the curve on it.
I'm going to have this starting point down at say point three.
Now when I move it around I get still pretty big but that's okay.
So I want to have the middle of my trail a bit fatter.
So on ours our curve graph here I'm going to double click to make a new point in the middle and then
double click to make a new point down at the end drag the first point down to around about point 1 and
drag the middle point down a little bit and drag the end point all the way down to the end see how that
looks when I slide it along so simulate how the arrow would go like bells we shoot along the screen.
Okay.
That's looking okay.
I think I want to make sure that it's back in the zero point on my Z axis or wherever it is that I want
the trail to be appearing if I want the child to be at the back of the arrow.
You might want to have it a little bit forward so you can see the front the shaft of the arrow maybe
the trial is coming out over the feathers however you want to do that.
But now when we get back into the game and click on play Let's see if this is worked.
Run run run run run over to my enemies I might move an enemy so I don't have to run so far and click
shoot and you can see this trial's coming out the back of my arrow which is really cool and you can
shoot it at the moment you can see I've got a kind of narrow and then a little bit of fat in the middle
you can tune it to your heart's content and you can make it a little bit shorter or a little bit longer.
I would change that by decreasing or increasing the time I'll just while I'm here.
I don't think we need to receive shadow so we'll click that off doesn't really matter but we'll click
it off just so we're not putting a bit more strain on the system.
Next thing I'm going to do in this lecture is make ourselves an answer and then we're gonna make ourselves
a different variant of the arrow so that the Archer has he's shooting a different arrow that we're shooting
at him just to give a little response to the game and it gives us a chance to do a little bit more with
prefab variant.
So scroll down to the game folder find characters open that up looks like some of these things on in
their photos.
Tsk tsk because that may or Sam probably Sam he tends to do these things doesn't he.
Okay.
Drag them into their photos.
The truth is it's me and we all know it.
I might make a will leave characters where it is okay.
So within enemies this is our enemy prefab we know what our enemy prefab looks like.
Just drop it in there to show you again what I'm going to do is right click and find where are we upping
create.
And we will create a prefab variant to your character.
Then we go enemy and we have this enemy variant which I will call ARCHER Okay.
So just to be clear Archer is a prefab variant of enemy.
Let's open up our Archer have a look at the arch I'll do two main things in here.
One will give the Archer a different color just so we can distinguish it from the other enemies.
So where are we.
There we're looking at now Sinti assets.
Let's see Sinti assets.
Where are you.
There we go.
Sinti looking for materials and I think I will make this guy black.
No make it red.
You can change whatever you want to your heart's content and then the other thing we're going to do
obviously is to do.
To give the Archer a bow.
Okay.
Now the Archer has a bow.
Cool now back over into the game.
Let us drop in one of these new awesome arches into our world.
Standing here.
Front and center so we can have a little battle with the archer.
Okay cool.
He's got a bow we've got a bow.
Let's just check that all the things work properly.
Run run run run run and he's going to shoot me.
BROWN Yeah you can see his trial happening.
Bit of a problem when I stand here he's like oh I guess I shouldn't shoot anymore but how we can shoot
you and you can't shoot us.
That is pretty cool for about two seconds but the player would be I think get pretty bored with that.
So there are a few things here I want to give you as a challenge to tighten up this whole archery experience.
Basically make out Archer more rad so to create two projectile variants.
So each script hated a variant of an enemy one to have a base projectile and have two variants of that
for me.
I'm going to make one of them read and one of them blues so if you want to figure out how to make your
trails red and blue you can you can do other sorts of variance if you want.
We've got just a white trail on our arrows at the moment.
I'm gonna make one red and one blue and then to create a second bow scripted I'll object and to give
the enemy Archer one of the bows and the play the other bow obviously one bow is going to have one of
your projectiles associated with it.
The other bow is gonna have the other one and then finally to tune the enemy archers shooting behavior.
So he's a little bit cleverer about how he behaves when he's got his bow and arrow and shooting and
so there is your challenge.
Take that on.
See you back here when you are done.
First step is I'll find my projectiles.
We've got our arrow project dong and a right click Create prefab variant.
I will call this arrow projectile red and then same thing again on Arrow projectile right click.
Create prefab variant and I will call this arrow projectile blue.
Let's double click on one of these I'll start with blue.
What do I mean by blue.
Well we'll find our trail and you can see here color.
I'm gonna have my color go from the first point so I double click on the little what's he said.
Dude Dad I think that's technically a dude down the bottom there and we'll make it bluish in color and
just move it a little bit long so it stays blue blue blue blue and then fades away into white I think
is going to look neat.
And speaking of fade the top one I'll double click on this single click on that sorry and make a little
bit more transparent so it's going from a solid to more of a see through trial and down the back of
the arrow.
Okay that looks pretty good.
Now I'll go over and do similar on the red arrow double click on that into the trail.
Okay change the first part.
Click on that double click on that.
Make it more of a red color and then move it along a little bit and then give a little bit of transparency
up at the top.
Okay cool.
So now we have a red projectile and a blue projectile.
They're exactly the same except for their color trail.
Now over into weapons we've got Bo.
I'm going to rename this first scripted object to Bo with blue projectile projectile Bo blue projectile
and then I'm going to control D to duplicate.
And Bo red projectile.
Okay.
And then on the blue projectile clicking on that we can go and find where our projectiles dragging blue
projectile and then on our both red projectile.
We will drag in our red arrow.
There we go.
Now we need to go back to our player and the players default weapon is blue projectile so bow with blue
projectile.
Cool.
That's the one that we'd renamed jump over to our Archer.
Where are you Archer.
Boo right TV show Archer.
Have you watched that show.
One of my favorites characters enemies Archer double click on Archer to get into the prefab.
We don't want the blue.
We want to change that to be the red bow red projectile.
Awesome.
Okay now let's see what happens here when we run up to the enemy.
He shoots at us bound that's a red projectile we should hit him but it's a blue projectile.
Yes the battle of good and evil evil.
A song of ice and fire if you will.
Fantastic.
Okay.
And then the other thing we're going to do is make out after a little bit clever with how he behaves.
Let's have a look in the arch a prefab one thing we want to do where are we looking here at the A.I.
control Chase distance.
I'm gonna put that really high and put it's a 25.
Now it's probably a bit too much 20 which says Chase distance if you had a weapon he'd run towards us
get to the point where his weapon range says you can now attack and then he would attack.
If we put a massive Chase distance and we also have the same weapon distance the same then he's not
going to actually run it'll just be he starts shooting because the moment he starts his chase I says
Yes chase that will be yes.
Not shooting.
So he's now 20 which is cool we need to go and find the bow that he's wielding so bow with the red projectile
and change the weapon range there to 20.
Okay.
Why didn't I call it enemy bow and play a bow.
Well we might want to give the player the red bow at some point.
So I wanted to keep it specific to the weapon as opposed to specific to the use because the use itself
might change whereas the color is not going to change or the structure of the weapon itself.
Okay.
So now is shooting and is run all the way back here.
Oh boy.
Yeah.
Can I shoot at him.
Who's got the big Ranger because the enemy has a slightly bigger range.
That way we can't just sit there and pick him off.
But now we can have this epic battle.
The trials look a little bit hokey a little bit overdone but I like that I can see them on the screen
now.
I might consider making the trail a little bit shorter.
Let's just do that now so I can show you that when we change the trail the the arrow projectile that's
gonna change both of our prefab variants.
So the trail just gonna pop this down to point 1 5.
I think they're just us not quite so massive on the screen.
Now when I go to shoot at the enemy we both should have a slightly shorter trail.
Yeah looks pretty consistent.
I think.
Shoot that guy over there OK.
Excellent.
So I think that's cool.
I like it and the homing missile it's a little bit we'd have a homing missile missile.
I really personally love it.
To be honest but you could add a little bit of logic so that you can dodge the arrows but you know I
like the idea of not being out of dodge the arrows.
I think that is a better way for our gameplay point of view.
We might need to speed them up a little bit so it doesn't look quite so homing missile ish but it's
as designed at the moment so awesome.
Great work.
Hope you enjoyed this video.
If you came up with some nifty arrows that you'd like to share with us please do share in the community
and I'll see you upcoming video.