Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be generating new ideas such that if we are in a prefab the EU idea
does not get generated so that we don't accidentally end up with duplicate EU ideas when we drop things
into the sea.
But when we are in the same file they do get generated and you can see that they show up as modifications
and they will get saved correctly into the scene file so that every enemy every player every entity
that we want to save in the scene has got its unique identifier so it can be correctly restored from
the save file.
Let's dive in and see how we can edit these properties in a scene file so in the last lecture we got
to the stage of being able to run stuffer edit time but not actually updating this unique identifier.
Now you might think it's as easy as saying hey why don't I just change the value of the unique identifier
here where and I go unique identifier equals system.
Dots go is dot new grid and then turn that into a string.
Why didn't I do that here.
Or even if I am astute I might say Hey I only want to do this if we don't already have a value for this
unique identifier so that we aren't regenerating them remember that we said one of the requirements
was that they are persistent.
So if we were to regenerate them every time in this update loop they're not persistent are they.
So again say if it's actually equal to the empty string which is the default value then hey why don't
you go ahead and do this.
Well this is the pseudocode if you like but not the correct way of doing it because if we go and change
properties like this it's only changing them in memory in unity and unity has got no way of knowing
that you've changed this property at edit time so it can't keep track of the changes to the save file
and it can't say that this has been overriding a prefab and all that good stuff that it needs to know.
So this stuff doesn't necessarily get saved to the file or it gets saved to the scene file on reliably
which is definitely not what you want.
We don't want unreliable code so the correct way to access the serialized information that is in this
unique identifier is to use a different API.
And the API is called a serialized object.
Now for this we need to include the using Unity Editor namespace.
Now just a quick gotcha with this namespace because the editor namespace is not available when you build
the game.
So if you try to build the game you will get errors because it has no access to this.
So we are going to fix this but later on and so just for now until the end of the section don't try
and build a game it won't work.
And with this serialized objects we can create the object far which is going to represent the serialization
of this mono behavior.
To do that we do a new serialized object and we need to pass in the objects that we want to find a serialized
object for.
So just this.
So what does this line do.
It goes and finds the serialization of this mono behavior and gives us this in a property called B and
in a variable called the object now it gives me an error here because I can't use object so I'm going
to call this serialized object like so and then the errors go away.
So you might then think OK well we've got the serialized object I can do serialize objects dots unique
identifier no slowdown.
We can't do it like that because the serialized object is a generic thing for all types of serialization.
So if we want to find a particular field in this particular serialized object then we need to a find
property like so and then we do it by string reference unfortunately.
But hey that is how we need to work with it in unity.
So what comes back from the find property is a new type again called a serialized property.
So we create a new variable for that serialized property and just gonna call this from the property
and I think there's no C sharp key word for that hopefully.
So that is going to be our property that we want to edit now because we don't know the type of this
property again.
There's a problem with it being dynamic and at runtime you have a few options.
You can do for example dots and then you could have the double value or the float value.
So if this were a floating point variable then we could set its value with a float value you could say
Hey set this to point to F for example but it's not a float value.
So I think this would just give you errors or if it doesn't give you error has it's at least going to
not make sense when it loads it in it's gonna say Hey.
This needs to be a string.
But what I've got in my scene file is a float value what's going on and things will not work or it just
won't load the end.
So that's not how we want to do it.
That's right correct code where we're going to use the string value instead.
So instead of using the unique identifier here I can go ahead and use the string value.
So I'm going to cut this out and paste it in here instead so I can say hey is this string value empty
in which case generate a new unity.
Now this in and of itself isn't going to just work because after you've made a change to the serialized
object you have to tell unity that you've made that change.
So what you do is with your serialized object you do a dot apply modify properties now notes I'm doing
this inside the if statement because we've only modified the property if the value was empty so otherwise
we don't have to notify unity about any changes because we haven't made any.
So if I go over to unity now what we should be seeing apart from the log messages going away hopefully
if I've got rid of the log.
Then if I go and find my player for example and look at his inspector you can see that his unique identifier
is showing up and that unique identifier is now an override.
So it has actually noticed that some override it's also noticed that my scene file has got changes in
it that haven't been saved.
And if I go and have a look at any of my enemies you will notice that they have got different unique
identifies as well.
So you might be thinking Hey fantastic.
We have got a job well done.
Yes and no.
Unfortunately what the problem is that we have got if I go up to an enemy prefab for example you can
see that it has generated a unique identifier our code has faithfully said hey I'm an update I'm not
playing I'm gonna get the serialized object here.
I mean a specific scene just for the prefab editing but that's okay.
And I'm just gonna check whether it's got a value.
No it hasn't.
I'm gonna set one.
So it set one.
Which means that if I save this I've made a change to the prefab and if I go and drop new enemies into
my scene.
So if I go to game characters and drop a couple of enemies in here and have a look at those enemies
you will notice that they already have unique identifiers and they are the same because they took their
value from that unique identifier in the prefab and our code being very faithful that it is has said
hey let me get the serialized object for this thing in the scene for this instantiation of the prefab
and hey this string value has already got a value so I don't have to do any work.
Now obviously this is not wrong this statement should do that but in our case we don't.
Well basically what we want to avoid is the prefabs trying to generate unique identifiers that they
should not get unique identifiers they are not unique entities until they have been placed in the scene.
We only want these unique identifiers to crop up if we have manually put them in a prefab or they should
automatically be generated and saved into the scene file only.
So how do we make sure that we are in the scene file.
Well here is a little challenge for you I'm just gonna give you a hint and there's no challenge slide
for this but if you were to have a look at the game object dot scene have a look and see if there are
any properties on this that give you an inkling and tell you whether you are in a scene file or whether
you are in a prefab you can do that by just printing out some of these properties and seeing whether
there's anything that's helpful in here.
So post a video and have a go at that challenge Okay so let's see as a few candidates there is the name
that could be useful.
There's another one I think the path maybe the path will be useful.
There is also the build index.
But if we haven't got something in the build index that's not going to be very helpful so I'm not gonna
go with that route count.
Mm not particularly helpful might be if we do a hacky thing that says if there's only one route then
it's a prefab but you could have one route in a scene as well.
So let's just print these out and let's see if I go back into the scene.
Hip well don't you need to hit play.
We just need to be doing this at edit time right.
So I want to see as any of these useful.
So it's saying the name is sandbox.
The path is assets seen sandbox unity.
What if I go into the prefab.
What's it saying then.
Okay then we've got the enemy is the name of the scene and there's no path.
Is that true generally of all prefabs it seems like if we're going to the character level it's trying
to say that this is a sandbox scene but I think we're not actually on the sandbox scene.
I think character here is giving me empty.
So for some reason it had the sandbox they're open has it open as well.
But the character it's saying that it's still empty so I'm noticing that an empty path tends to mean
that we are actually in a prefab.
So let's try that as our criteria we're going to say if the application seemed up path is equal to empty
then we should return maybe it's empty maybe it's no I'm not sure about that.
We've got to test that out.
So let's go back into the editor and if I go to my enemy and just clear out its unique identifier what's
going to happen there is it going to try and reload it.
Let's go back to the scene back to the prefab.
See if it tried to reload.
No.
That seemed to have done the trick.
And if we wanted to be sure just in case what I'm going to do here is have as a special cool little
method called string dot if is null or empty.
And this basically allows us to say hey is this string now all empty it's all in one go and it's so
common that you want to do that that they've just rolled it up into one.
So what we're saying is if the path is empty then we're in a prefab so we'll return and not try and
do any of our logic.
And just to be super safe I'm going to use the same is null or empty for if the properties string is
empty.
So if it were null for some reason as well that is when we'll also update the good.
OK.
So hopefully now we have not got a unique identifier for the enemy.
And I want to cancel the unique identifier that we've got here for the character and save that.
So the enemy should now not be we can just revert it.
So it's not got a unique identifier.
And I want to go to the player and make sure he's not got a unique identifier so that now if we look
at either of these two enemies in the scene you can see that they get generated these new ones that
we dropped in they get generated new unique identifiers.
If I were to drop in a few more enemies you can see this one's got a different unique identifier.
And this one's got another unique identifier.
I'm going to remove these and so that Rick doesn't get angry with me for messing up his scene.
So there we go.
So we've added enemies they've all got different unique identifiers.
And it's changed the sandbox.
In fact I want to show you that it has changed the sandbox you can have a look and get for yourself
here that basically the sandbox is the only thing that's changed by look at the character as an enemy
prefabs you can see the characters just got this empty unique identifier just of a scene to have done
that but maybe we can go and just completely set that back to default.
If I right click on the unique identifier No it just wants to have it as empty as fine.
But we've got no change to the enemy really it's done some other change here not to our unique identifier.
There's no unique identifier for the player and all the changes are actually in the sandbox scene exactly
where we wanted them to be.
As you can see against each of the different entities it has got a different unique identifier so that
is going to be unique across scenes but it's also persistent because it's saved in the sandbox scene
which means that when we close and reload the game it's going to get them back from the sandbox scene
and we're going to be able to match that up with our save file and restore the correct state which is
exactly what we want to be happening so phew.
That was quite a lot in that lecture.
What we covered.
Well we've found that in order to change the values that are being stored into the scene file or prefab
we need to use a serialized object and serialized property in tandem and modify those rather than modifying
the values directly on our objects.
We've seen how we can do that by creating a new serialized object from this.
We have also seen how we can check whether we are in a scene file versus being in a prefab as well as
in the previous lecture we saw how we could check whether we were playing.
So this is basically where we've got up to we have able to generate new gourds for things in the scene
file so they get saved reliably in to that file however we have introduced a little bit of a bug in
that if you try to package your project at this point you will find that it will give you a weird error
about not being able to find the serialized object.
And that's because this code is not available to package projects.
Makes sense right because this has stuff to do with the editor.
So what you need to do if you want to package this is to wrap it all in this if Unity Editor little
macro so hash if then Unity Editor with The underscores in all caps and then at the end you have this
hash end F and basically what this does it says everything between these two statements is not going
to be included in the C shop build for a project that is not being built for the editor.
So if you go and packages projects up this code is essentially removed entirely which is just what we
want cool stuff in the next lecture.
We're going to be concentrating on getting these capture and restore state methods to actually work
and do their job again.
See you there.