Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we aren't going to be applying damage to an enemy capsule.
So what happens is I walk up to it and I punch it.
And you can see it's printing out how much health it has got left.
In fact I could even show you on the enemy itself or have to restock.
I think we've killed it.
Let's go over.
And if you look at the enemy we've got this health attribute.
If I go and punch the enemy it's going down in fact it's happening exactly when the fist contacts the
enemy.
So we're going to show you how to do that as well.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So I think the least fun bit of our game at the moment is that when we punch that capsule we can keep
doing it.
That the capsule doesn't take any damage it doesn't actually progress anyway.
So what we want to do is implement a kind of damage on that capsule.
Now there's many places you could choose to keep the health of the capsule but I think the best thing
given that we are using this component pattern and I've got a link to what I actually mean by the component
pattern against this letter for you to take a read of in your own time.
And the idea is that we should keep things as separate as possible among components are not going to
put the health into the fighter or into any other kind of class because I want to be able to potentially
damage things that can't fight back such as this capsule.
So we've got our enemy and what we want to do to this is add a component to it a health component.
So I'm actually gonna go ahead and create the health components in the combat portion of our scripts
folder to create a new file in there and call it health C S and I'm going to make a model behavior and
I'm going to put it in a namespace.
So it's gonna be a namespace RPG.
Dot combat and boom we've got our health.
So the first thing that we need for health is going to be a health variable to keep track of things
which is going to be a float in our case.
And I'm just gonna call it the health and we can get a starting value of say 100 F for example.
Now what's interesting about this is that it's not configurable so we could make it actually configurable
by doing a serialized field in front of it.
Now this won't work eventually because we want to know at some point in the future what a maximum health
was versus what our current health is.
But for now this will work.
And then the other thing that is interesting about health is that it gives you the possibility to take
damage.
So we're going to add a public field here.
Void take damage but we've got to give it the amount of damage that we want.
So it's going to be a float damage.
That's the amount of damage we're taking.
Now little mini challenge for you if you want it to actually reduce this health but making sure that
the health can't go below zero.
So you can implement this whatever way you like.
It's fairly straightforward okay.
So if you've tried that or if you just want to go ahead and see how I'm doing it this is how I'm doing
it.
So the health is going to be equal to the essentially the health minus the damage but obviously that's
not going to work because the health months the damage could go below zero if say for example the health
was at 1 and the damage we got was 2.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to put a lower bound on this by saying that I want to take the maximum
of this value and zero.
So it's gonna be math f dot Max and it's gonna be the health minus the damage or zero.
So if it goes below zero then zero is gonna be higher so we'll take the value of zero.
Like so and because we currently don't have a way don't have a health bar to see our current health.
I'm just gonna print out the health of this particular components as we go as a kind of debugging measure
so we need to use this component somewhere.
So let's go over to our enemy I'm inside the enemy prefab.
I'm gonna add a component down in the inspector here and look for the health component so we can give
it a default health for the enemy.
I'm going to make it a bit lower so we can test this out quickly.
So we're gonna have a health of 20 and then it is time for your challenge to actually do the damage
and we'll leave this one up to you we've got a public interface we've got a component you need to get
hold of that component and use the public interface.
So where should it be called and when should it be called.
And how will you get that component.
Think about these two head scratchers try and implement them and pause a video and have a go okay.
Welcome back.
Hopefully you didn't have too much trouble.
Let's see how I'm gonna do it huh.
By the way I don't necessarily know how I'm going to do the challenges I'm kind of figuring it out with
you guys.
So there is the fighter component seems like the logical place to do the damage.
And in fact here we've got this attack behavior where we're doing this time since Las attack and then
we're gonna set the trigger set the time since last attack and probably in here we're also going to
do the damage.
Now there is a little question though of perhaps doing the damage after a delay.
So if you'd done it in here that's absolutely fine if I were going to start off by doing in here.
So we're going to get hold of the health component so it can be health health components is equal to
and then what's it going to be the target dot health.
They get components and they health components.
Right.
So.
So we got hold of our health component.
Now we can just do some damage to it.
So take damage.
Now I'm not worrying about any null checks at this stage.
Notice we need to tell it how much damage so how much damage.
Well we don't know.
So I'm going to add a serialized field up at the top of the fighter class to be the weapon damage you
can see we're getting quite a few things here which are really to do with the weapon and not the fighter.
But we're going to deal with that soon and don't worry so we've got the weapon damage.
And I'm going to use the weapon damage in the take damage call.
We've got a default for it.
So that's all good.
Now that should do the damage at the moment I'm not going to worry about where the target is now or
health component is null.
But those are potential worries that we're gonna have to deal with later on and we might get some errors
at some points in our runtime about that go to it.
I do.
Attacking and you can see down here in the console is logging out that we've gone from 15 10 5 0 0 0
0 because you can't go below zero and it doesn't try to.
Which is nice and easy okay.
But what I was saying is we might not necessarily want to do the damage as soon as the attack starts.
Because what you might be noticing is if I go over he starts the attack and instantly I've done damage.
What I want to do is actually use that animation event that we had from before.
So I'm going to bring the animation events a little bit higher because it's quite important.
I'm going to put it just below the attack behavior because it kind of makes sense that it will trigger
off the animation event.
And I'm going to put the damage in there and I'm going to leave a comment in attack behavior saying
that that's where it's going to go to in fact I'm going to put this just after all in fact just before
our attack trigger.
So it says this will trigger the hit event and then the hit when is further down here and I might even
just use the right syntax because then sometimes it can be really clever and allow you just to follow
links in comments it doesn't in this case but sometimes that can be the case and it's just less ambiguous.
So this should mean that now if we go and hit play and we click on our capsule the damage isn't actually
done until the punch lands which is perfect.
That's exactly the kind of behavior we want.
And depending on what animation we choose that time is going to be variable depending on the animation.
And that's pretty cool because then we'll play all the effects of taking damage after the punch has
landed.
For example the animation of the character dying.
So I think that's enough for this lecture in the next lecture we're going to be looking at how we can
make that capsule more like the player and in fact make them share the same base prefab and make each
of them variants of it so that we can essentially have the same sets of components and configure them
slightly differently depending on whether it's a player or an enemy.
So I'll see you in that lecture.