Hello and welcome internet show.
We're gonna be looking at how we can create unity events that actually pass through some data such as
the amount of damage that has been taken.
We're going to be doing that to allow us to spawn the damaged text with the correct amount of damage.
So if I grab my sword dive on into battle you can see if I get hits I'm getting twelves and eights from
the different types of arrow.
And if I hit you with my sword I'm doing 14 damage each time and you can see more people are attacking
me.
I'm getting loads of text sporting above my head and eventually die.
So let's dive in and see how we can use it.
Unity events in that way.
So the final piece of this puzzle is going to be to get our damaged text to display the actual damage
that the enemy took.
As you can see we've got these print statements that do it but we aren't currently able to do it in
that damage text because we have no way of passing that argument through a unity event.
So how do we do that.
In fact let's just have a look at the situation we're in.
If we go to our characters prefab then you can see that at the moment in our health script we are hooking
up to that spawn function.
But we are passing a constant 13 value what we want to happen is that that take damage event actually
comes with the damage that was being dealt.
Now unity events do have a way of tackling this but it's slightly convoluted.
So let me show you if we go over to our health script you'll see that the unity event can actually take
a generic argument very much like an action delegate did as well so we could say this takes a float
argument with it and this would all look just fine but if you go over into the inspector you're going
to notice something.
Well first of all it's saying that the invoke needs to take an event which needs to take a float which
currently doesn't.
So that's quite easy or we need it to do is take the damage as the float in there to make sure that
you update that in your code as well.
And then basically what that's going to do is remove that serialize field.
Why is it removing a serious field.
Well the reason is that serialized fields in Unity can't really handle generics like this as special
cases for lists.
But in general you have a class that has some generics in it.
It's not going to work as a serialized field.
So what we have to do is quite simply that we need to create a subclass of this unity event float.
And I'm just going to do this here inside of the health class.
But you could do outside if you wanted to.
So we're going to do a public class and I'm going to call it the take damage event like so and that
is just going to inherit from the unity event that takes a single float like so.
And then the body of our class we're just going to leave empty.
So I'll just leave no space between these two brackets.
Now this take damage event.
We want to use instead of the type for take damage.
So that basically this is almost the same as saying that we are having a serious field of the unity
event that has the float generic.
But we this actually works.
That's the difference.
Because sterilized field can work with a simple class like this.
Now if we go back over into unity and just have a look.
It's still not popping up.
And the reason it's not popping let's see if there's any hints to this in the console here I'm not particularly
being helpful here.
So the console is not helping.
But the reason is that we've got this serialized field but this class is not marked as itself system
not serialized.
So let's just add the annotation of system dot serialize.
So that just make sure that the take damage event can indeed be serialized.
So let's hop on over and see and see and see whether it's going to show up now.
Our event in here so once it's reloaded it has indeed shown up with this list.
Now how do we go about binding it.
Well many challenge for you.
Have a go and see if you can bind it such that the actual float value is going to be used when spawning
pools billion have a go OK.
So we're going to go hit the ad button and see what happens.
I'm just going to follow the same process I did before and if I go to functions go to damage spawner
and just select the spawn.
You can see that it's working the same way as before I have to enter the float Valley.
That's because if you go to that function dropdown one more time and have a look at the damage tech
spawner you'll notice there's actually two sections in this dropdown there is one which has the dynamic
float and one which has static parameters.
So the dynamic floats if you select spawn that is under the dynamic float section then you'll notice
that static area goes away.
And now it's using the float from take damage in the float parameter or argument of spawn.
So if you go ahead and hit play now what we should be seeing is that I go and deal some damage to the
enemy and the damage value should be correct.
I think that is actually 13 is the damage I'm doing.
Yes.
Because if he goes and attacks me I get damage of eight and I attack him I do damage of 13.
If I change my weapon do I also get different damage amounts.
Yes I do damage a 14 instead.
So you can see that now actually we are being able to show the correct amount by passing it through
the unity event.
And to summarize we just had to do that little bit of a convolution We couldn't use the unity event
chevrons float directly because serialize field doesn't really allow us to use generics.
So we had to create a serialized will subclass of it so that we could just use that as the type instead.
So that wraps up a little mini series on the damaged text.
And now you can see that if I dive on into battle and start to get hit by volleys of arrows that the
damage text is showing up above my head above the enemy's heads as I attack them and everything is working
perfectly.
Next we're going to be looking at health balls see that.