Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're gonna be looking at how we can fix our health system and the saving system to
avoid a bug where enemies come back to life at some particular and weird incantations of saving and
reloading.
So let's dive in and see what the bug is in the first place and then how to fix it.
So we got a bug in health.
Let's see how this is currently manifesting.
The easiest way is gonna be for me to first delete my save file so I can show you all the reproduction
steps.
Then we're gonna go over into unity and hit play and what we're gonna notice is that if I go and kill
this god or any god particularly it doesn't really matter anything with a health component really is
going to do the trick.
He gets killed.
Fine.
That's okay.
Now what happens is I can save this and then leave the game and then reload.
And obviously the God is dead.
Seems normal right.
But what happens now.
If I hit save again and then reload the game one more time what's going to happen.
Well the god is actually alive again.
Why was that the case.
Well let me run through this one more time so if I delete save and then go and hit play obviously I
start off my default location lock and pick up the sword.
That's the quickest way of killing this God.
And then I whack the God a few times.
And sure enough I think if we go and find this god go to the scene and go to enemies in which enemy
are we talking about is this enemy.
Yes it is and have a look at his health component.
You can see his health points zero as we would expect.
So sure enough in the game we go ahead and save and we quit and then come back and we should be back
to the god being dead.
But actually if we go and have a look at our health component you will notice.
Whereas the health component for our enemy that select the enemy's health components here it is.
You can see that its health points are faulty.
So what's going on there.
Why are its health points 40.
That explains why if we save and quit again.
He's alive because he's not got zero health points.
So what's actually going on is if we go and have a look at our health component going to close all the
others just to make it super clear in the health component we've got two places the or few places that
update our health points.
So where could these health points be set to forty one places and start in fact this is quite a likely
candidate.
That's the first option take damage.
Could we have taken negative damage.
Seems unlikely is no point where we're doing that.
We aren't modifying it and get percentage not doing at modifying and capture state but we are modifying
and restore state.
So the two places that could modify the health points are restore state and start and what we've actually
got here is a race condition happening between the two.
So what's happening when we load from our save file in the first instance is that we are getting restore
state called First it is setting zero health points because the enemy is dead but then start gets called
afterwards and it sets the maximum health points.
Mind you because restore state actually set the health points first and checked whether they were lessons
zero and then died if appropriate.
We saw the dying animation we saw that the God was dead even though it had 40 health points thereafter
because the start reset it to 40.
So that's a really weird bug and that should definitely not be happening like this.
So have a think if you can think of a way If start is always called after the restore state just no
challenge like this.
See if you can think of a way of making sure we don't set the health points.
If we have already restored the health points pause a video and have a go OK.
So one way you could've done this is with a boolean you could have said hey we've got a restore state
it's happened so we're not going to set the health points we could have a boolean specially for that.
What I'm gonna do is actually turn our health points not into a serialized field because actually we
don't need them there we can visualize the health points through our UI.
I'm going to set the default health points to B minus one f so a negative health value which you should
never be able to obtain unless it's just this on initialized value.
So what I'm going to do is say well if we've restored health points then they are going to be greater
than minus one.
So that's fine.
But if we haven't then they are going to be less than less than 0 0 minus 1.
So I'm going to say if health points are less than zero we know that we haven't been restoring them
yet they haven't been restored and that we need to set up some default health points in which case we
can get those default health points from base stat.
So let's give this a go.
I'm gonna go back over into unity and again I'm just going to clear out my save file to make it super
clear in fact because we're deleting the save file so often I'm going to make a key binding for it in
our game.
So if I go to our saving wrapper I want to be able to call into the saving system to delete.
So I'm going to create a public void delete method in the saving wrapper and we are going to do a get
components saving system a saving system that would go and we're gonna call dot delete which does not
exist at present and we're going to call delete on that default save file and we're going to set up
a key binding in update.
So it's gonna be if the input gets key down is gonna be the key code I'm gonna use delete the delete
key because you don't really use it for anything else in the game we're going to cool that delete method
and then if you want to try and fill out the delete method if you know the saving system or you've done
the saving system section then go ahead.
If you haven't and don't want to then just follow along and type what I type so I'm going to go over
to our savings system.
Saving.
Saving system here it is.
And I'm gonna create a new public and load.
So it's gonna be public void.
Delete string save file and it's not even going to do anything particularly clever.
We're just gonna use the file dot delete method that is provided by C shop and we're going to build
the path from let's have a look where do we get our path.
If we do load file what has load file getting the path.
Here we go.
Get path from save file so we tell it to save file name.
And it finds the whole file system path.
By that and actually pretty much do delete.
So now hopefully if I just reload I'd expect to hit delete and see it disappear from the file system
which it has.
Fantastic.
So now I can delete the save file without having to go to this folder which is nice.
So if you restart the game at this point we should be from scratch.
Fantastic.
So I'm gonna get the sword go and kill the enemy and check that our bug has disappeared so remember
it was reproduced by killing the enemy.
Saving reloading the game which point the enemy should look dead.
Yep looks dead.
And just to check what we were seeing is that if we have the enemy selected in the hierarchy and look
at their health components they actually had 40 health points in this case we can't see the health points
because well we've removed them from being a sterilized field so we're just gonna go ahead and hit save
and then recycle one more time and this time the enemy should still be dead Hopefully indeed the enemy
is still dead.
So we haven't successfully fixed that race condition in the health system and along the way we also
added a function to delete and clear our save file for debugging purposes in the next video we're gonna
look at how we can use Unity or C sharp events actually in order to save us from having to recalculate
the level every single frame.
I'll see you there.