Hello and welcome to part two of our saving system lecture.
So what we're doing here is we are trying to let's see merge these two scenes we're trying to be able
to save in one file save on another and be able to load in both files and not to lose any data.
So we want to merge.
So this means that when we are in scene one we can save our scene one you I.D. into the safe save file
in scene two we can save the scene to you you I.D. and they don't overwrite each other.
And then when we go back to scene one again we can do serialized scene ones you I.D..
Now the key here is that before we save in say scene two is you your I.D. We need to first look load
the dictionary from Scene 1 update that dictionary and then save it back.
So that's fairly straightforward.
What we want to do is in save we want to first of all load the original state.
So let's do that.
So we're going to take a load file that's why we separated them out to make this kind of stuff nice
and easy.
And this is going to be saved into a state dictionary.
So it's going to be a type of dictionary string to object and call it state.
And that's going to be the value from Load File.
So this is us loading in and then the final step is going to be for us to save that state back to the
save file.
But in between we need to change something in between these two we need to capture the state into the
state file.
So what we've currently got is the capture state returns a dictionary and it creates that dictionary
from scratch.
Now what I'm gonna do is I'm going to flip this round so instead of returning the dictionary it's going
to take in the dictionary and it's going to add to it.
So it's going to take in a dictionary called state add to it's going to return void.
And then what we can do is we can remove this line at the beginning of capture a state that actually
creates the new dictionary because we can just update the dictionary that's passed in.
And similarly we don't need to return the state anymore because we are just updating it.
The state is already in that dictionary that was passed in.
So now what we can do is we can do a capture state in save between loading and saving.
So we have taken the state from the old file updated the state and then written it overwritten it in
the file so that the resultant state contains the merge of all the state that we have seen so far OK.
So that's clear enough but there is a problem because if I don't have a save file yet because I've deleted
it or for whatever reason and I go ahead and hit play and the first thing I want to do is perhaps I
want to save Oh dear.
That doesn't seem to be working.
So what's going on here is saying hey no file found and the reason for that is because we are trying
to load from the file and the file does not exist yet which is a bit of a problem.
I'll have to say now there is another issue as well which is that if the file doesn't exist yet we also
can't load from it.
Maybe that's something that you'd say well that's not a problem but really we would want to be able
to load and for nothing no state to come in.
So that is also an exception that I don't like the look of.
So that's going to be your challenge to implement or to fix the saving and loading.
So you should be able to save when there is no file presence.
And my hint to you is that you can check whether there is no file presence using the file dot exists
and then you want to be able to return something out of load file instead of trying to load the actual
file.
Have a think about what that should be that you should return out of load file when there is no file
and you should be able to load with no file.
So already this first step is going to help with that checking whether the file exists and returning
something out of load file.
But beyond that you may need to check whether the dictionary contains a certain key before trying to
restore the state before trying to access that key.
So these two hints should help you along your journey of making save and load work perfectly when there
is no save file pause video and have a go OK.
So the first thing is going to be with our saving the actual problem comes from loading.
So what we're going to do is we're going to remove this print line I no longer need that and instead
we're going to do an f file dot exists then we are going to see whether this path that we have created
here exists or not.
So if it does not exist then we don't want to go ahead with the rest of this of this load file method
because that is going to try and open a file that doesn't exist which is the thing that was causing
the exception.
So what we're going to try and do here instead is just return a new dictionary because a new dictionary
will basically be an empty state.
There's no state there.
So we're gonna say net new dictionary from string to object type parentheses and then semicolon and
that should basically do the trick.
We're no longer going to open the file we're just gonna end up with a new dictionary.
So let's give that a shot.
If I go back over to unity and reload then I'm going to go ahead and hit save and it saved correctly
and it will load correctly as well because now we have a save file.
But what if I got rid of my save file and go back into unity and tried loading just like that.
Now you see it doesn't give me anymore a problem about the path not existing.
Instead what it's saying is that as a key not present in the dictionary and if I go to the line that's
being referenced here I believe it is talking about our saving system line twenty one in restore states
but worth further down there do we have something yet the saving system CBS Sixty one line sixty one
we have.
Okay we are getting the restore state and we are doing that from the state dictionary but we're accessing
this unique identifier.
So what if the state dictionary doesn't have the unique identifier in the case that we're loading from
that empty dictionary it won't have a unique identifier.
So what I'm gonna do just to make sure we don't get that exception is I am going to extract this unique
identifier first into a local variable to make this a little bit more readable.
I'm going to call it I.D. And then what we're going to do is going to say if the dictionary.
The state DOT contains key.
So we want to see if the state dictionary contains our unique identifier and if it does well then we
can go ahead and just restore that state country like so okay.
So that's pretty much all done now there's just one little thing here that we've got this space between
the cast on my dictionary object where I'm DC realizing so in the load file I don't like having the
space there just for consistency I'm going to remove it.
And that's about it.
We have got ourselves a saving system that should work between scenes so let's go ahead and check it
out.
If we go ahead and play I go over to the bridge in this scene and hit save and that should take me back
to the bridge when I hit low.
Yes it does.
So then if I go over into my other scene and go in through the gates and then I am going to move over
towards this tree and save near this tree then loading here takes me back to that tree fantastic that
all worked that way before but now if I go back to scene one and hit load I am back on the bridge which
was the state that I had originally saved in season one.
Great stuff in the next lecture.
We are going to look at Checkpoint thing.
So when we go between scenes will automatically save and automatically load.
That's going to make it much easier to just restore the state and make the illusion that everything
is exactly as we left it before.
Let's dive onto that later and see how it's done.