Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're going to be fixing a bug so that when we play we always reliably have the level
that was last saved rather than sometimes it not getting calculated as is currently the case.
Let's dive in and see why that bug is happening and how we can fix it.
So let's see how to reproduce this bug I'm starting from a completely clean slate here with no state
whatsoever so I'm going to show you how we can create the state that will reproduce it.
So if I go and kill this God and then once he's dead I'm going to go ahead and save so you can say I've
got 10 experience points and level two calculated from the experience points I'll save this and then
exits and restart the game.
And what we will see is that my experience points are still 10 but the level this time hasn't been recalculated
yet and is stuck at one.
Now what will actually happen is sometimes this will happen.
But actually if I were to start from a different scene so I'll start from the sandbox to scene instead
and I go ahead and hit play then our code and then the saving system is going to load up scene one because
that's the last scene we were saved in and noticed that this time actually the level was correctly calculated.
So what's going on here.
Well you can go ahead and try and debug this for yourself particularly.
I think what you're going to need to do is put some print statements in the start of base stats and
in the restore of experience and see what's happening which ones getting called first.
In each instance now if you go ahead and do that I'm not gonna do it on screen but imagine that you
had gone ahead and done that process.
You will see that in the case where our level is not getting updated.
We are actually restoring the state of the experience points after start which means that we've already
calculated the level and we're not going to recalculate the level until experience has changed again.
So that's a bit of a problem.
And in general also weird because we thought that start usually gets called after the restore state.
So what's going on there.
Well if we dig into it a little bit what you're going to notice is that in some cases this is true because
the restore state is getting called in a wake.
And if we look very specifically at some of the cases here.
So we've got our savings system and what's going on with the savings system is when we've got load last
seen so that's what we just did we were in a different scene and it loaded us into Scene 1 what it was
doing is it was saying hey look the scene that was last saved is different.
So and it's not the one that's currently loaded.
So go ahead and load that with a load scene async and because this is in a car routine that yield returns
when the scene has finished loading and that actually in terms of timeline is after all the awakes have
been called in the scene.
But before all the starts.
So essentially it's like being called on a wake or just after a wake that we will have restore state
called however if that isn't the case then it's going to depend when load last seen was called.
And I just want to point out actually if you go through a portal the same sort of stuff is happening.
We've got load seen async happening and obviously all the awakes will be called but starts won't have
been called yet.
And then we're loading from the saving wrapper so we're loading the scene at this stage again just after
a wake.
But before all the starts have been called.
However if we have a look at our saving wrapper we have got the load.
Last scene is happening inside start.
So this means that depending on the order of execution of your scripts and this start method might be
called after the start method of base stats which means that our state is going to be restored after
we have calculated the level which is no good at all.
So pause for a mini challenge here where I just wanted to see if you can figure out how to fix it so
that START is always called after ask date has been restored post video and have a go OK.
So what we're gonna have to do is we're going to have to call all of this.
I enumerated this code routine is going to need to be called in awake instead of start so I'm going
to rename the iron numerator to load last seen instead like so and we're going to cool this iron numerator
in the awake method.
So let's create an awake method GET OUR curly brackets on different lines curly braces on different
lines and then we are going to do a start co routine with the carotene of load.
Last scene we'll start the load last seen carotene.
Now hopefully that should fix our bug.
We go in it to the original sandbox so that we're actually circumventing the loading of any scenes I
see.
That was the problem that we were going into load last seen.
It was happening immediately immediately restoring because it didn't have to load the scene because
we were already in the correct scene.
So if I go ahead and hit play now then you'll notice that my level is correct it has been calculated
correctly because start has been called after restore and you can go and put log messages in it to verify
that you understand that and then everything's working.
OK so to summarize in this lecture what we have learnt we have learnt that we want our start and restore
to happen in a predictable order.
We want restore to happen before start so that in start we can rely on the state having been restored
and we've got the state already set up.
That's the first thing we learned.
The second thing we learnt is that our function called load seen async finishes or yield returns after
everything has been awoken.
But before all this starts have been called which is great because that's what we need in order to have
restore state happen before all the starts.
But we also saw that we had a problem where we were actually calling this sometimes in start which was
no good and meant that order was unpredictable with base stats and we fixed that so in the next lecture
we're going to be looking at how we can use instead of having this print statement called levelled up.
We're going to be looking at how we can have another event to allow us to do things and also spawn spawn
some particle effects see that.