Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be fixing a pesky feeder bug in which you can easily get stuck with
a fader that is completely white.
Now currently I have got that fixed.
So what should happen is if you go through even if while the fader is still Fading Out you go back through
the portal to another level.
Then you'll see that the fader still works the fade out is happening very slowly because we wanted to
reproduce the bug.
Let's dive in and see what that bug is what's causing it and how we can fix it.
So before we can fix the shader bug we need to fix another bug which comes about because we haven't
got an event system in the second scene.
Now if you've already fixed this then you're not gonna be able to reproduce this bug.
But if you don't know what I'm talking about then do follow along.
First of all I'm going to go ahead and delete my save file to make sure that we're all starting from
the same place and maybe go ahead and do the same thing yourself.
Now if I go and play and go over in to my second sandbox level then we are going to get an error right
off the bat that is saying that there is a null reference here.
This interacts with UI call is basically saying this event system not current is null.
There is no event system.
And the reason for that is that at some point when we added UI in it added an event system into our
sandbox level but it didn't do it into all of our levels.
So we want this to be in all our levels.
The easiest way to do that is to add that to the persistent object prefab.
So I'm going to copy the event system and go and find that persistent object prefab and paste it in
as a child of that prefab there.
Make sure that saved and now we can delete it from our sandbox level because if we go ahead and hit
play it will be added in two events system mega.
You can see we've loaded into our second season with no problems.
So now I want to show you a problem that we're having with the fader that many of you have noticed and
I'm going to show you how we can exacerbate this problem first of all.
So if I go to my portable prefab and have a look at the object there we've got some failed times and
we've got a fade out time and a fade in time and particularly the fade in time is the one I'm interested
in I'm going to extend this to 10 seconds to make this bug really really obvious.
And if I go ahead and hit play then what we should see is that when we go across to the other level
and to the sandbox level then it is fading very very slowly over 10 seconds which is what we would expect.
And now this should make the issue really really obvious.
If we go over back into sandbox too and while that fade is still happening we go back to sandbox one
you will notice that the fade back down doesn't actually finish doesn't occur and we stay get stuck
with this white screen.
So what is going on here.
Well if I close all of my tabs so we've got a clean slate I'm going to show you that in The Fader we
have a potential issue What happens if while we are fading in we call fade out.
Well both of these code routines will be running at the same time which is problematic because they'll
both be trying to increase or decrease the alpha and neither of them will ever finish because they're
cancelling out each other.
And one of them may win or may not win but they're trying to work against each other.
And this while condition will never be true because they'll never get to their target values over time
which is sad and not really what we want.
So what we do want to do actually is to make sure that when one fate is called any previous fade ins
or fade outs that were in progress get canceled that the last one basically gets cancelled and the latest
call is always what is going to happen.
So we can achieve this by turning this body of fade out in to a car routine that we start here in the
fade.
So we start the fader car routine in here and we store that car routine and we store the reference to
the car routine that's running so that in subsequent calls we can make sure that we cancel it before
starting.
That's the idea here.
So how is that going to work.
Well we have to pull out something that we can actually start here.
First of all because if I just comment this out for the time being what we want it to look like at the
top level is that first of all we cancel any running code routines then we are going to run the fade
out code routine and that's it.
That's what it should be doing.
So the fade out code routine should be doing this bunch of stuff but we know that to start a car routine
we have to call start code routine and pass in something that's a is an I in numerator returns and I
numerator.
So that's what we're going to do as we go to create a new private function that returns in numerator
and it is going to be called fade out routine again taking the float time as we have done before and
we'll just take that body that's basically going to be and new fade out routine.
So basically wrapping that functionality into a car routine and keeping track of the car routine here
locally so we can cancel it.
So we need to call to fade out routine with our time and notice that start routine actually return something
we've rarely done anything with the handled is routine returned here but the return type of start carotene
is something called Car routine.
So we can store that we can keep a member variable on Fader called Code routine and this can be the
currently active fade like so and we're going to set the currently active fade to start car routine.
It'll start off as being null though however.
So we set the currently active fade like so and that is the first comment done we're starting the car
routine but we need to be able to cancel this car routine as well if it exists.
So this we're going to do as follows we gonna say if the currently active fade is not.
No because we don't want to be doing anything with a no car routine.
If it is not now then we want to stop said car routine in its tracks.
So current act fade we stopping and then we're going to go ahead and replace it with the new car routine
that we're starting that is this fade out routine.
And finally because our fade out returns and I in numerator we need to wait for that car routine to
finish which is easy because all we have to do is yield return the current active fait so that fixes
the issue and is gonna remove the comment it fixes the issue for fade out.
Now your challenge is to go ahead and make it work for fade in in exactly the same way pose a video.
Have a go OK.
Welcome back.
So we're going to give this a shot.
So the you could just do it by copying and pasting.
But what I want to show you is a way that we can make this a little bit less code repetition.
So I'm just gonna call this fade out routine just fade routine instead and we're going to have a float
target which is going to be our alpha target.
And so in our while loop we're basically saying while the alpha target is not approximately equal to
this the alpha is not approximately equal to the target.
So we've seen approximately equal before it's math f dot approximately like so.
So what we're saying is the alpha needs to be approximately equal to the target.
While it's not in fact approximately equal to the target that is when we are going to stop.
And I also want to do is make it so that we are moving towards our target at all times.
Again there's a math f function to this called move towards.
And what it takes is the current value.
So we can take the alpha as current value and then it takes the target value which is in our case the
target here that we've given it and then it takes the max delta.
And that max delta is what we've got here is the delta time divided by time.
So it will stick that in here and then we can just assign it rather than doing a plus equal just assign
it to the alpha.
So now this function will work in both directions if we set a target of zero.
It is going to move towards zero if we set a target of 1 it's going to move towards 1 it it's going
to do this at the delta time divided by time so that now can be used as private routine can be used
in both of our fade functions.
So I'm going to have a look and see well okay.
So now this code is pretty much identical.
We need to make sure that we're calling and new fade routine with the target and the time.
But we want to actually pull all of this out in to just a simple public function that returns I numerator
public I in numerator and it's just going to be fade and it's going to take a again the float target
and the time again which is a float like say and that is going to be the body of it.
And we can pass.
Now we have the target to pass into the routine you see.
So this does automatically stop the car routine before going on and that just meant that we didn't have
to duplicate this code lots of times.
And now in our fade out and fade in all we need to do is return not yield return because the result
is going to be an eye numerator of fade.
Again with that this time if it's a fade outs we're going to have one and it is long time.
So we're targeting one which is maximum alpha so that basically we are completely the fade cameras are
completely visible and then fade in is going to Target Zero.
So that should now do the trick with less code repetition and also making sure that our Fader does not
get stuck like it was getting stuck here so let's jump into the ante and give it a go.
If I go across the scene and while it's still fading go try and go back you'll see that it canceled
the fade did my fade up and now it's doing the fade down with no problems whatsoever so in review what
we have seen in this video is how we can keep track of car routines that are running so that we can
cancel them if needs be that's helped us fix the fader.
We've also seen how we could merge together our two failed routines and remove some duplicate code by
using the math f move towards function.
Now there is still some issues that can happen if you go between portals quickly and we're going to
deal with that and see what that issue is in the next lecture.
See you then.