Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be adding particle effects when we level up as you will see in just
a second.
And we're also going to regenerate our health percentage.
So even though that God had done a fair bit of damage to me when I leveled up I will no matter what
have my health regenerated 270 or greater.
If I had more to begin with.
So let's dive in and see how we're going to achieve those two feats so we'd like to replace this print
statement the leveled up print statement with something more flashy more like a particle effect.
So fortunately I have a particle effect for you here.
The self heal VFX is a package against its lecture.
You can import it as you would with packages.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I import it goes under the game dev TV assets folder and it is called self heal.
So what does it look like.
Let's go ahead and open the prefab and zoom in on the prefab and let's just restart it since this bunch
of plus icons that just evaporate into the air.
That's what we're going to use as a basis but I'm going to create a new prefab in our effects folder
to do this.
So I'm gonna go back to my scene create an empty I'm going to call this the level
and then I'm going to make that effect in the game effects folder and then I'm going to delete it from
the scene then I'm gonna go and open that up and I just want to check.
Yep.
The position has been set to something weird.
Let's just reset the position so we make sure we've got a clean starting points and I am going to go
ahead and set this up.
Now if you feel like you can do this challenge for yourself then do pause a video and just have a go
at spawning whatever particle effect you would like in this update level.
Otherwise I'm just gonna walk you through.
So we're going to go to the asset packs the game dev self heal and drag in under our level up under
that root.
We're going to drag in this VFX particle OK so we've got this VFX particle we have got it set up it's
got rotation and stuff which is cool.
I'm gonna change the color to a blue for the particles themselves.
So it looks more to me like a spawning like a levelling up kind of signal.
And then what we're gonna do is I want to change the simulation space from local to world so that as
we move around the emits from us but it also kind of floats around.
And then what we're going to do well we want to be able to clear up this particle system when it's finished.
So we're gonna add the destroy after effect but there is a restriction with this destroy after effect.
Currently if I have a look at how the script works it works on the current particle system and it destroys
the current game object which isn't gonna be sufficient because we actually want to destroy the parents
as well.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just gonna extend this class a little bit and give it a serialize field
where the game object called target to destroy which is going to default to no.
And what we're gonna do is if we have a target to destroy so if target to destroy is not equal to now
it's been set in the inspector then we are going to destroy the target and otherwise so else destroy
the game object that we're currently on.
So put that one in there like so.
So destroy the game object currently on.
Otherwise the target destroy if there is one available.
That means that in this particular VFX we can drag in the parent in the target to destroy and it will
when the particle system finishes destroy the parents basically the whole prefab which is just what
we would like.
So I'm gonna see whether this is sufficient.
Let's go over to base stats and the update level script and where we have this print statement.
I am going to create I'm going to call a new function which I'm gonna call level up effect.
So let's create it control dots generate the method and then a case it's private.
Yeah that makes more or less enough sense whereas put it I'm gonna do an instantiate.
Now we need a prefab to actually instantiate so let's have a new serialized field and it's going to
be if type game objects and it is going to be the level up particle effect
initialized to No.
But obviously going to be set in the inspector then we can instantiate the level of particle effect
and we are going to set its position.
No we are going to use one of these other overloads of instantiate.
We're going to use the one that has the transform parents so that this effect is going to be parentage
to the spawner and we'll follow it around.
So the plus icons are going to float offers very nicely.
So we're gonna do a transform like so and let's see whether that's going to work.
I just need to find our player prefab so that's an end game player.
Open up the play a prefab and then we are going to do what we're going to go and find base stats and
the level up particle effect we need to set from our effects folder.
Drag it in and let's go ahead and hit play.
Okay.
So I need to go and level up so I'm actually going to delete the save file because I think the easiest
way to level up is just to kill this guard bash him about a bit.
And then okay.
We have leveled up and they go.
We got a nice particle effect.
Now I didn't get to see whether it follows us around nicely when we move.
So I want to just try that one more time so get the sword.
Kill the guard and if we move around you can see the plus icons are following us around but are also
world space.
So the ones that have already spawned state where they work were fantastic.
So that's the level up effect.
Hopefully you had a go at that yourself and were not too trapped in figuring that out.
So that's all well and good but one thing I'm noticing that is a bit frustrating and we could perhaps
fix with this level up notification is that our health is going down and when we level up it with we're
still losing health it would be nice if when we leveled up we got a health bonus as well at least that's
what I want to implement in my game and it's a great challenge for you to apply your knowledge of events
from a couple of lectures ago.
So I'd like you to have a go at the challenge to regenerate your health so add an on level up events.
I'd like you to add that in base stats and then in the health component subscribe to that on Level Up
events and use it to set their health to a percentage of its maximum.
Every time we level up we can set to a percentage of maximum or if you've already got more than that
percentage of maximum keep it as it is.
See if you can do that kind of behavior.
If you're not sure how to do this bit then do everything else and just set the health to maximum to
100 percent by using the base stats to get the number of health points that is maximum.
Pause the video and have a go at this challenge.
KAYE Welcome back.
So we're going to add an event now it should be starting to become a bit easy to do these events.
Well it's gonna look like is it gonna be a public event action because we don't need to take any arguments
we don't need to return value and it's going to call on level up like so.
And then on level up we are going to call on Level Up Where are we going to call it in wherever we have
done the level up so we got a level of effect after the level of effect has been spawned.
We'll call on level up which will call all the things that subscribed to on level up.
So we want to find our health components and subscribe as we said.
So we're gonna do that in start and we're gonna do this regardless of whether we have set the health
points or not.
So it's going to be getting the base stats and then we're gonna do on level up.
We want to subscribe a function what are we going to subscribe Well I'm going to create a function so
plus equals re Gen rate health like so and I'm not calling it because we are trying to subscribe it
and I can just go ahead and generate this method.
Private method regenerate health.
Let me move it down below the public methods.
So we've got Di it's more important.
Keep that up their experience reward them below that.
I'm going to have regenerate health and as I said the simple solution is just to set it to Max.
So that would be health points equals get component based stats and then based at health but we might
want to do what's the maximum between the current health points and some percentage of this.
So say we want to regenerate to 60 percent then let's have a sterilized ball field for the percentage
sterilize field
floats.
Read Jan Gration percentage.
And we're going to set it by default.
Let's have it as 70 percent regenerates to 70 percent health and then what we're gonna do is in our
regenerate health we're gonna get any floats called region
points like so and we're going to multiply our maximum health by the reed generation percentage divided
by 100 to make that into a fraction rather than a percentage.
So it's going to be point seven for example if it's a 70 like we've got.
So we got a region health points and we're going to set the health points equal to math f dot Max which
allows us to get the maximum two values that we pass in and that can be the maximum with the health
points.
So if we've got more health points than the region health points don't reduce it.
And otherwise we do at region health points and set it to that instead.
So let's see if this notification system is working and we are indeed regenerating our health points.
So notice we died down to about 40 health points when we killed that God.
Let's try it out now.
If we are killing the God I'm getting some health region so whack the God a few times like so and then
notice I have region by health back up to 70 percent which means that I don't get all the benefit of
having all the health and just leveled up to I would need health potions and so on to get there but
I have got a little bit of health region to help me go on through the level and if we want we can tweak
our regeneration percentage we go for 50 percent or 20 percent or whatever the regeneration percentage
you actually want to be is cool.
So to summarize what we've got now is a particle system spawning when we level up and we've also revised
our events and delegates to create an event for level up that we've used in our health script to provide
health regeneration in the next lecture.
We are gonna have the damage caused by the enemies and by the players change depending on their levels
so that if we are encountering a grunt when we have levelled up it's suddenly easier to attack them.
I'll see you in that lecture.