So at the moment we've got a bit of a design issue with Aggie your ideas.
If for example instead of dropping new enemies into my scene from the prefabs because I don't want to
necessarily every time have to go and find the prefab folder I wanted to do the following.
What if I took this enemy and just wanted to duplicate him around the scene a little bit.
That seems harmless enough surely I can do that.
At least that's what your designer might think.
And that designer might even be you but look at all these enemies.
If I select them all and have a look at their new ideas.
It's all identical each one of them has exactly the same year you I.D. overwrite and that is the same
override as the enemy I copied it from.
So that's what we're going to be fixing in this lecture.
Let's dive in OK so what we want to be able to do is figure out whether or not the idea that we have
generated here is unique because what happened when we were duplicating is that that unique identifier
was copied along with it.
Now it's no longer no.
So in update we don't have to worry or at least that's what our code thinks.
But it isn't unique because we've duplicated it from something else.
So what we really want to do here is on line 49 basically an update of the salable entity.
We want to say if it's null or empty Sure go ahead and generate a unique identifier but also if it is
a not unique thing.
So I'm going to create a method is unique because I generally think in positives I could create a method.
This is not unique but it's easier to write the methods usually in positives.
So I'm going to put a knot is unique and what we're going to do is we're going to pass it the property
dot string value.
Now this is obviously not being created yet so I'm going to use visual studios generate methods to go
ahead and create this saleable entity thing.
And what it's gonna done is it's created a is unique that returns bool private and takes a string which
is calling string value.
I'm going to go ahead and rename string value to candidate because it is the candidate that we're checking
for uniqueness.
Now I'm not gonna go ahead and fill this out just yet because I want to do an overview of the methods
we could take to solving this problem.
So what we've got is a scene full of salable entities or a world full of stable entities and we want
to check whether a you I.D. on a particular safe and entity is unique.
What's an easy way of doing this.
Well we could go ahead and do a find game object of type.
Get all the safe balances iterate through all of them and say hey all the ones that aren't me.
Do you have a different unique identifier.
If not I need to regenerate mine.
Now this is seems okay except that it's quite expensive to do a fine game objects of type to begin with
but also every saleable entity will be doing that every frame.
So we're going to have to do find game objects of type for every saleable entity every frame and it's
going to just get more and more expensive the more stable entities we have to check.
So this is not a good way.
What we want to be able to do instead is have a more efficient way.
So what I'm gonna do is introduce a dictionary components or a dictionary data structure where the salable
entities will register themselves.
They will put their new ideas in the dictionary and they will point back to the stable entity in question
so that we can check that things are up to date and check that we're not talking about ourself you know
who is this item in the dictionary and this will be much more efficient.
You can check this every frame no problem because the dictionary is quite easy to keep up to date and
very efficient.
So that's what we're going to go ahead and introduce.
Now where should this dictionary live now.
It could live on the scene but we're going to forget to put it in places and it's also could potentially
want to check for uniqueness between scenes.
So what I'm gonna go with as the simplest solution is to create a static dictionary which remember statics
live for the lifetime of the application.
So we have to be very careful with them.
They even live between scenes and we're going to see it as an issue with that later on.
So I'm gonna go ahead and create a dictionary.
It's going to be from the string type which is the unique identifier to the saleable entity which has
that identity to fire and I'm going to call this the global look up just for simplicity and I'm going
to do a new dictionary salable entity right at the beginning.
So we've got a dictionary to begin with.
And then what we're going to want to do with this static dictionary is we're going to want to update
it.
That's the first thing.
So have a little think.
There's not gonna be any big challenge just a few mini changes throughout this lecture by the way.
It's quite in-depth.
So have a little think where do we want to update this.
Now you could update it in a start method but what happens if the game designer just goes and manually
changes the serialized property that unique identifier.
Well then your start method won't update the dictionary and the dictionary won't stay up to date.
So I'm actually going to updated every single update and I'm gonna do this after an if statement that
has changed the value of the unique identifier just so that we have the latest version.
Basically we have the latest identifier in here.
So it's going to be the global look up and it is going to I'm going to add in a key the property string
value and set its value to this to point to the current saleable entity.
So now global look up hasn't got values in it.
We want to go ahead and implement is unique.
Now if you feel confident and want to try and implement is unique.
Do by all means go ahead and give it a go.
But basically we want to do a couple of things.
We want to have a first of all check that the key exists in the dictionary.
And if it does exist in the dictionary we want to check that it is not pointing to ourselves.
So those are the two main things if you do want to take this on a challenge.
Those are the two things to check in is unique.
And then there are some edge cases we'll tackle afterwards okay.
So let's have a go.
Now you may have had to look through the documentation to check whether a key exists in a dictionary.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to put an if statement in here and we're going to say that.
Does that does it exist in dictionary global look up dot contains key and this returns a boolean whether
that if the key exists.
So we're gonna check for the candidate key.
We're going to say there's this global look up contain the key.
What happens if it does contain the key.
Well if it does contain the key we want to go on.
But if it doesn't contain the key we already know that we can return.
So if it doesn't contain the key then we want to return true because we know that there is no other
key in this dictionary so no other saleable entity has got this key already.
Perfect.
Okay.
So we can return true.
And our default is going to be returning false.
Otherwise then we want to say is it pointing to ourselves.
If it's pointing to ourselves again we can return true.
Otherwise we're going to go on to return false.
So let's look if the global look up candidate is actually equal to this.
So is the current game object.
Then again we can return true because this just means that the candidate is US so there's nobody else.
It's just us which means that it's fine we are unique.
That's what we want.
So this is already a good system.
Hopefully if we go back over to our game and have a look at the enemies that we had duplicated and had
duplicate your ideas we have a look at each of them you can see that they you you ideas have actually
been saved.
Now there is a deficiency again with this approach.
If we go over to a second scene the sandbox scene then we got unsafe changes or combat.
Why that is in a second.
If I go back to the main site sandbox and don't save.
You'll notice that we've got changes here too.
And actually if you went through and looked through all these guards you'll see that they you you ideas
have changed for some reason why have all the guards changed their ideas.
That doesn't make any sense.
The reason as I warned you is because this dictionary actually exists for the entire lifetime of the
application and that includes between loading scenes.
So when we loaded the scene the sandbox scene the first time round the guards all put themselves faithfully
into the dictionary.
Then we unloaded the scene all those guards saved all entities got deleted but their allocations in
the dictionary did not go away.
They stayed in the dictionary which means when we loaded the sandbox scene a second time and the guards
are new saved balance fees that have been created.
They pop up all of a sudden they go to the dictionary and say hey my unique identifier is already taken.
What's going on I need to regenerate one but actually they don't realize that it has been taken by an
item by several entity that has been destroyed with a previous scene.
So an easy way to get around this is to check whether the item in this dictionary has been deleted already
and if it's been deleted we can remove it from the dictionary.
So how do we do that.
Well in unity it's quite simple.
All you have to do is check whether the item is equal to null and there's actually some special overrides
and magic going on to make this work in unity but we don't mind.
That's fine.
So we're going to do a global lookup candidate and if it's equal to null it means that it has been deleted
in in Unity's idea anyway it has been destroyed.
Which means that we no longer interested in it has been deleted it could be from a previous scene it
could be ourselves in a different iteration.
So what we're going to do is we're going to remove it from the global look up so global look up Dutch
remove candidate and then because we removed it is now empty in the dictionary so we can happily return
True from is unique.
We know that now it is unique because any objects that were in the dictionary were already know.
OK so that is hopefully going to fix our issue if I go back to sandbox 2 and then don't save and then
go back to sandbox 1 and don't save.
Now you can see there are no changes in sandbox 1 all the enemies have kept their original new ideas
that we had saved in the sandbox so I'm pretty happy that that is what we want now there is finally
one more thing.
Little edge case I don't know whether where or when this could come up but for example the global look
up candidate could in theory.
So the item the saleable entity that it points to could actually not have the EU I.D. that we're looking
for it could have got out of date and I think one case where this could happen is if you updated it
in the editor and then the global I.D. would go ahead and create a new global I.D. look up in the dictionary
table but the old look up would also still be there pointing to it.
So we can now clear that up.
We can say hey why don't we take this unique identifier once I get a method get unique identifier.
So we're gonna get the unique identifier of the item that we looked up from candidate and if it's actually
not equal to the candidate.
So something's gone wrong.
Look up is now not up to date it's not pointing to the right value.
Then again we want to remove it from the lock up because it is no longer this line of the dictionary
is no longer up to date.
We remove it and we can again return true because we know that it's free.
Okay.
So that pretty much covers it.
Now there is one thing I would like to do.
The AB player at the moment has a uniquely generated idea which is fine but what I'd like to have happen
is that the all the state of the player is shared between scenes.
So what we can do there is actually give him a unique idea.
So if I go to the player's prefab and where we currently don't have a unique identifier that doesn't
get generated in prefabs we can manually put in the player unique identifier which means that in every
scene that we put the player he is going to have the same unique identifier.
Just need to go over to the sandbox and revert his identifier so his identifies now player.
If I go over to sandbox to save my original sandbox and go and find the player again I want him to have.
He's already got a reverted unique identifier and now because no players are ever in the same scene
at the same time it doesn't matter that they're unique identifiers are actually the same.
So what's gonna happen is when you load sandbox 2 it's going to get the state the health and all those
kinds of things that were shared with sandbox 1 talking of health in the next lecture.
That's what we're gonna work on.
We're going to work on making health save itself as well.
See you that.