Welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be figuring out how close the player is to any given enemy so that if I move within
range of an enemy it starts printing that.
It should give chase.
And if I move in range of multiple enemies you can see that they all are saying that they should give
chase that will be the subject of the next lecture actually giving chase.
But in this lecture we are going to be figuring out that condition.
Let's jump in.
The most boring thing about these enemies is they just don't put up a fight.
I can walk up to them and punch their friend in the face and.
Well nothing happens.
He just carries on and they all watch as he gets punched to death.
So obviously that's no good we want to give them a bit of panache a bit of jazz.
So what we're gonna do is create in the control namespace a new script which is going to be create C
sharp script let's do that and it's gonna be the A.I. controller.
We've had the player control that.
Now we have the A.I. controller.
So let's open that up and I'm going to start by removing start and update we can always add those back
later if we want to.
And I'm going to cut this to put it in a namespace of RPG control.
Same namespace as the player controller.
And then we are going to take this A.I. controller and what was the first thing we want to do with an
A.I. controller.
Well I think that what we're going to need first is the ability for them to know whether they should
start attacking us or not.
Because if I'm over here walking down the path there's no good them attacking me already otherwise all
the enemies in the level are going to come up to me.
So we're gonna need to know at what distance they should start chasing me.
The chase distance hence the name of this lecture.
Well that's gonna be a parameter to start with.
So what distance should they do it.
Well let's do a serialized field to decide that it's gonna be a float because it's a distance and we're
going to have the chase distance and I'm going to start off with AIDS fault maybe a five meters like
so 5 unity units like so then what's gonna be the next thing we need we're going to need to check exactly
every frame whether the player is within the chase distance or not.
So this is gonna be every frame.
It's gonna be an update thing.
And how are we going to check with the player.
Well first thing is we need to actually get hold of the player and how do we get hold of the player.
Well there's a number of options for example you could do it by finding a object that has the player
controller on it.
For example you could look for an object that has the name player but both of these options are quite
expensive and unity builds in a way for us to do this more efficiently with the tank system.
So if we open up the player prefab because I want to do this Wherefore I include the player.
We can look for the tag next to the name just underneath the name and the inspector.
And here we've got a few options and in fact the player is one of the tags that's in there.
By default you can add custom tags if you want to but players already there.
So we're going to use it.
And you can see is an override here in the player variant.
That's what we want because we don't want it to apply to all characters.
So if we look at the enemies they are untaxed.
If we look at the player he's tagged with player so we can now get hold of his game object by doing
game object dot find with tag and then it's a string reference thing.
So you know go carefully typed carefully this case we can't copy and paste from there very easily.
So I'm just going to type in player and be very careful about it.
Okay.
So we've found the game object.
This is going to return a game object I believe.
Let's just check that can hover over to see what the expected return type is.
It wasn't giving me an error right now.
Yes it's a return type of game object.
So this is going to be the player game object like so.
And from this we can obviously find things like the player's current location.
So you're part of the challenge is going to be to figure out whether we should be giving chase or not.
By this I mean you need to calculate the distance to the player.
You've done a bit of distance calculation before so we can do it again between the enemy current enemy
and the player.
You're going to need to print if we should chase.
Oh and by the way before I forget.
This might trip you up.
We I control is not yet on the enemy prefab.
So if we open up the enemy prefab we can add in the A.I. controller as a script.
I don't want that to trip you up unnecessarily so we should print if we should give chase and a little
bonus for you that you can have a go at if you feel confident is to include the name of the enemy of
the game object of the enemy in that print statement so that you can distinguish which ones should give
chase.
So if I'm standing over here and I'm within the chase distance of this guy then the other ones aren't
printing that they should give chase and we can be able to see that all in the log what I mean is this
name here the enemy enemy one enemy too.
That's what we should be able to see.
Okay.
So without further ado I'll let you get on with that challenge.
Welcome back.
Hopefully that was an all right challenge.
Do let me know if things are a little bit too tricky.
I need to dial the challenges down and give you more hints so our player is the place we want to start.
So he's got a location.
How do we find the distance between them.
Well we've done this before it's a vector three dot distance like so just to show you in case you don't
believe me we've done this before in fighter that's how we've done it before and it's even been a boolean
to see whether we're in the weapon range or not.
So it's very very similar in many ways.
So we're gonna do the distance between the player dot transform dot position and the current transform
dot position which is gonna give us the position of the enemy.
And that's the distance and I could even extract this out into a function that's control plus extract
method and I'm going to call this the distance to play out like so and I can even put this find with
tag in there like so and because it's a cheap operation I don't mind repeating this a few times that
need then the name I don't need the argument being passed in rather so distance and then we can say
if the distance to the player is less than the chase distance well then we are to give chase is the
name of the game.
So we're gonna print saying should chase something like that like that and we'll figure out how to actually
give chase in the next video.
OK so let's just see what that's working then we can have a go at the bonus as well.
I hit play and country they're all saying that they should give chase.
Let's go to the end of the log.
And now they've stopped saying that they should give chase but clear the log.
No more coming in.
I got back in and they're all giving chase and you can see I can go in and out of the chase radius like
so.
So the next thing to do was the bonus to see if I could print out the game objects name so I can do
this by getting a hold of the game object of this particular component and then do dot name.
And that should pretty much do the trick.
So plus the string should give chase.
So if I gave play then in the console log if I go to the bottom again I want to make sure I'm all the
way at the bottom then what we see here is the enemy one enemy and enemy 2 should give chase but I can
move to just having enemy to need to give chase which is the closest one to me.
And you can see that that's working individually for each enemy.
This is often a useful trick by the way to include the name of the game object in a print statement.
If you've got multiple of those print statements clogging up the a log and you can't tell which one
you actually want.
And also if you ever want to debug something just a little tick a little tip is that you can always
say something like Game Objects dot name equals.
I don't know enemy if you want to only print stuff for that particular enemy or you could do a game
object dot tag equals player for example if you want to just print stuff for the player and that can
be very useful for debugging stuff.
Sometimes when you get loads of log messages for every single script so good job.
What we have done there is we have set up logic to decide whether we should chase or not depending on
the player's current position in the next lecture.
We will actually make that chase and attack start to happen.