High again in this video we are going to be instantiating a big old soda a little bit of a silly sword.
If I do say so myself in the player's hands so that we can run around with a weapon and start the whole
journey of putting weapons into our game.
So let's jump in and get started for our play to wield a weapon we need a concept of what in other words
what weapon and where in other words where is our playing and a hold that so going to start by jumping
over into my fighters script find a dot see yes and we'll give ourselves to new fields in here to new
serialized fields serialize field.
First off will be a game object.
And I'm gonna call that weapon prefab because our weapons will be prefect and I will initialize that
at no.
Just so if we don't have a weapon equipped the compiler knows that we deliberately don't have anything
in there.
For example if we're just doing unarmed and we don't want a weapon now.
Second we will serialize field.
This one will be a transform because it's a where we need to know the location.
I'm gonna call this hand trance form because I'm putting putting the weapon in the player's hand.
And again I'll initialize this at no save that up jump back over into unity.
Now what we need to do is to first of all identify where we are going to put that.
So let's go into our play a prefab click on the little Chevron arrow key thing to the right of the player
prefab and within here we can see we've got our character model I'm going to scroll through here I'm
using my arrow keys right arrow key expands and down arrow he moves the indicator down I'm just did
the data and looking for spine down right down right you can use a little clicky thing on the left here
if you want.
That's the official name for it but I find this is quick when I'm looking for something if he does hold
down right it just quickly expands out everything and then you can go off and find what you're looking
for what we're looking for here is the hand I'm going to put the weapons in the right hand for now.
Later on we will have some weapons in the left hand like the bow and arrow but for now we're going to
put it in the right hand and underneath my right hand I'm going to right click Create empty in here
I'm going to create a new game object this will be what's the weapon we're gonna use First I use a sword
first so I'm gonna call this e quipped sword is this a new game object make sure that the equipped sword
is at the 0 0 position which it should be if you've just gone right click and created an empty game
object now going to go and find within my Sinti asset pack here my prefabs burn where are we right down
the bottom this sword so S M weapons sword 0 1 Dragon to the hierarchy underneath equipped sword if
you're using your own weapon again make sure that it's reset to 0 0 0 if you've got some weird numbers
in here then you're gonna get all sorts of mischief when you try to rotate and s so make sure the child
is reset to being zeroed underneath the equip sword.
So now we can manipulate our sword within our equipped sword game object.
The reason I've done it this way and staggered it is that what I want to do is go into play mode move
around the positioning of the sword and have its position relative to the equipped sword game object
which I know is being childish right under the hand so it's going to be in its correct position you
can see our indicator here it's right under the hand now I can go in and monkey around with his sword
to my heart's content content knowing that it's going to follow around where the hand goes and importantly
what I'm going to do is jump out of player click on Play Now go back into play at this point we're working
on an instance of the player not the prefab itself when we click on play so as I go and find where is
the root hips to using my keyboard again the spine clavicle shoulder elbow hand Okay and here I will
find my equip sword These are all instances so changes here aren't gonna be applied back to my prefab
so I'm gonna have to copy the values so let's have a look where is it currently position not in the
best spot but we will while clicked on this sword I'm going to rotate it around properly click on pause
just so he's not wobbling too much rotated around get it into the right position I find we need to have
our weapons rotated quite a long way away from the player if you're having trouble seeing and if you've
got some clipping plane issues and click F to zoom out to focus in on your weapon and just getting into
a pretty good spot that you're happy with.
Okay now what we can do is on pause and as we run around these sword should be in the correct position
in the player's hand it's kind of chopping his face off a little bit there.
So what I'll do.
Click f just to get it into the right spot.
Does it rotate mine down a little bit so it's nearly touching the ground as he runs.
Okay.
Nearly bunks him in the head but not quite.
Awesome.
The other thing I'm going to do for my sword just because I think it looks funny and silly is to scale
it up so I will take my scale and maybe make it two to two.
Okay so is really dumb massive saw that he's running right.
It's too long now.
I think the scale what's at the X on the Y so I make the Y a little bit shorter I wanna make it kind
of this big fat final fantasy style sword that he's running around with that looks a little bit too
heavy for him clunk clunk nearly banging on the ground.
Excellent excellent excellent.
A dumb funny way.
Okay.
There we go.
So it's a little bit silly a little bit funny but that's the game that I'm going for here.
Now what we need to do before you can get a play mode and click out to play mode yet is to right click
on transform copy component.
Now we can click out of play mode and enter our play a prefab again find where we've got our equipped
sword and then click on underneath that find the transform of the the sword prefab itself right click
and paste component values and that should be there we go.
He's got his sword.
Now when I click on play again we can run around run around when we click on play.
It should all be copied in there as expected.
Okay excellent.
Now we need to make sure that is a prefab.
So again from within my player prefab I'm going to make myself a new folder game.
I will call this weapons create folder weapons and within weapons I'm going to drag the equipped sword
down.
Excellent.
And now that our sword is prefab if we're going to edit it I recommend that you click into the equipped
sword.
Now we're working on the prefab the sword itself.
You want to make any changes to it.
You can make some changes in here.
Make sure you're editing the sword itself.
So if you're wanting to change the position of it if you've got some new values change the sword itself.
Don't be changing the equips so we need to keep that at the 0 0 point sitting right on the head because
any changes we make at the child level will be propagated to all of the equipped swords out there in
the scene whereas if we make changes to the transform of the parent of the equipped sword it won't be
propagated.
It won't go and change any instances that we currently have in the scene or other swords that enemies
for example might be wielding.
Okay.
Hopefully that explanation made sense for you.
If I jump back out into my game you can see our player has the sword sitting his head.
But how do we instantiate this sword at runtime so we can in the future switch out our weapons.
Well that's gonna be the challenge for you.
What you instantiate the weapon in the hand create a spawn weapon method to instantiate a weapon in
the player's hand when the game starts.
And here is a hint for you instantiate takes you know what it takes in a way which has been what we've
been talking about until this point.
So in the fight did not see a script spawn a weapon in the player's hand and I'll see you back here
when you're done.
Right here.
So I'm going to.
From within my player.
I'm just going to delete this equipped sword point because we want to be instantiating at runtime so
we don't want him to be holding one already back out of player over into my script.
I'm gonna do this in the stop method.
We want to have this straightaway as the game starts so start just tidy up my parentheses here.
My what are these my curly braces.
Tidy them up a little bit and I'm going to create a new method spawn weapon parentheses semicolon.
This isn't created yet so click on it.
Control.
Full stop or control period will allow me to generate method and it's as simple as using instantiate
and then the what is going to be the weapon prefab and the comma where he's going to be the hand transform
and transform.
Okay semicolon save that up.
Now we've got a couple of thing I'm just gonna move this down.
Actually it's good coding practices we believe to have your start and update method right at the top.
So underneath method I'm just gonna paste that new method spawn weapon we just created such a little
bit tidier.
So we tend to go start an update and then we have our public methods.
Then we have our private methods back over into unity what do we need to do.
Well we need to click on the player.
Let's jump into the player prefab again as Sam has reminded me a gazillion times make sure we're working
inside the prefab then we know it gets applied the right level in the right way.
And if I clicked on the right thing just then on the player there we go.
Now we want to find the fighter script currently the weapon prefab well will drag in the equipped sword
from our game.
Game weapons photo and then we will find the hand which is sitting on the player I'm gonna grab the
hand itself.
Drag that in a hand transform and there we go.
And just a side note we're gonna be doing a lot more work with this will be using scripting all objects
so this is just to get us underway.
But in the future we'll be having this a lot more sophisticated.
We won't just be dragging in a weapon because we need it to change when for example the player picks
up a weapon.
Okay.
So let's click.
We'll see if the player has a sword in his hand.
Hopefully he does fighting.
Why.
There we go.
Shazam we got this big old sword.
And if I can drag my window over a little bit we can run over to the enemies and they don't have weapons
yet but can we still doing our old animation we're gonna change that in upcoming videos.
But we have our weapon.
If you wanted to you could go ahead and do exactly the same process and put the same weapon or other
weapons into the hands of your enemies and you may notice we're getting some red arrows.
That's okay.
That's because our enemies are instantiating weapons but they don't have any weapons yet.
That's fine we'll be fixing that in the next video.
So for now that's it.
We've got our first weapon.
We're well underway and I'll see you in the next video.