Hello again.
Welcome.
In this video we're just making ourselves a really simple second sandbox scene.
Say that quickly so that we have a place to load into and save from so that we can start working on
our scene management functionality.
So a little bit hard to do scene management with just one scene.
So again to make ourselves a second one let's jump in and get started.
You're probably gonna hear me use the words scene and level a little bit interchangeably when it comes
to what we're doing here because technically this is a level we interact you go through your exit.
It's also a moment because we've made this as a moment based upon all the things we've talked about
and unity names each of these things as a scene.
This is a scene file so we could also call it a scene.
So you know I'll probably be calling it is a level that's just what I have in my brain and what I'm
going to do is create a mechanism where I see this entry point and that exit point or that entry exit
point over there I'm going to pretend there's another level just in here.
So it's just going to be a small little thing with a play I can run from one end to the other.
And then as Sam is hooking up the save and load functionality will have a little portal here and then
we also have a little portal down there just so we can make a little bit of a loop the whole way through
which I think would be a little bit nice.
And the first thing I do is just delete my code over here.
My code that I've been using as prototyping thank you for that we don't need it more.
Now we have our sky back again and what I will do super quickly is before I jump into the next scene
is I'm gonna grab a copy or I'm going to duplicate the fence that I've got here moved the fence over
to this kind of entry exit point just so I can get a little bit of language to the player or to ourselves
as well that when we see these fences that means we're entering a different area or about to load into
something just to see if that makes sense if that's a good system
just quickly play make sure that looks okay.
Run run run run run run run run run run.
Okay.
And then that's around when that tree gets in the way that's around where we would want to load which
I think is cool.
Okay.
So we've done that little bit talking let's save that up now what we need to do before we go and jump
into our next scene is to make sure we've got the right things prefab so our player is prefab.
Make sure I had forgotten to do any overrides.
Yep that's looking good.
We have our one directional light that's probably gonna be the same our camera.
We haven't prefab down our camera.
When I say we I should say me because I haven't prefab the camera so I'm going to find my game and then
Cor in here we've got the follow camera.
That's the old flow camera which are going to delete.
Yes you can delete that.
So grab our current camera drop that in grab our follow camera drop that in.
We'll see if there's anything we need.
We've got our enemies our prefab.
Yes.
And cinematics we don't need to take our cinematics over.
So I think this is looking pretty good.
It's really just player and camera that we need to get in there.
So going to save this up and now we want to go to file new scene you've probably done this a million
times when you've been making games.
Now we will start by saving our scene Save As.
What do we want to save it.
Well into the scenes on call is sandbox to not the best name in the future we'll do a little bit better
without naming but for now fast and loose with our sandboxes so it's perfectly fine going to right click
Create a 3D object terrain drop that in make it way smaller than it wants to be at the moment.
Make this 100 by 100.
Just guessing that's an okay size.
Make sure we go on to liking and where are we.
He auto generate.
Turn that off so it's not sitting there trying to do the lighting over and over.
So my 0 0 looks like it's right in the middle if I drop it in a player.
So we'll go to our core characters.
They drop the player into the hierarchy then right click reset transform it's way up in that corner
over there.
So that looks to be at 0 0 corner which means I'm going to grab my train.
Move it to minus 50 and minus 50 on the X and on the z because I like to have my terrain my world right
in the middle if I've got something centered in my 0 0 side is reset the player back to 0 0 I'd like
to have it centered in the middle.
Now let's just quickly sketch out where we're going to do our level like before.
There's parts of this video I'll speed up if I think you don't need to see them and other bits where
I'll talk you through it.
So we need to bring in our terrain textures.
So over on terrain click the paintbrush paint texture edit terrain layers add layer.
Now because we've got these already we shouldn't have to go and create them from scratch.
So double click on dirt edit add layer green grass edit add layer like dirt hit it add layer light green
grass so you can see that they weren't automatically part of our scene because the terrain layers are
scene specific each scene you're gonna have to go on set up your layers all over again but if you've
already made them created them and tweak them then it's as easy as just going add layer as I did just
there.
And the challenge of coffee is to make a second sandbox level be clear on where the player can enter
and exit your scene and it's up to you how much polish you want to put into it.
I'll be making mine really quick and dirty I'm not gonna put a lot of time and effort into it I'm going
to make it so it's quite small so that when we're testing out our entrance and exit we don't have to
run a whole way through our level to do that.
So I'm going to create my See now I'm going to speed up the video so you can see all the action you
can create yours at the same time or watch me make mine and then make yours as well like say if you
want you can just have a flat ground plane and that's it you can be done you don't have to put a lot
of effort into it but if you do here's a good chance of flex your level creation muscles again I can
start off by just painting on the ground where I think my level should go through you can see those
two dots pretty close because I just wanted to be a close little sandbox level just trying a few different
brushes here to see what look I think looks good for my eyes sort of mountains around the outside to
sort of splash them around leaving not much space in the middle like I say this is really sand boxy
just so I've got a short path to go from A to B painting some stuff Brown you can see I'm accidentally
gonna make myself another terrain here I'll delete that later on.
Not sure how that happened I didn't see that as I was creating it to be honest okay.
Putting in some trees for the different sort of the other sort of tree that I've got the asset pack
you some of the trees are going to get in the way of the camera later on so might need to tidy those
up but just slapping them down putting the path along the pathway finding my fence so I can have my
language to the player this is where we enter this is where we exit just the same as I did at the end
of my other level and then what are we doing here duplicating putting the fences down the other end
became my terrain to sandbox to terrain so it's putting the cameras and see if this actually works properly
so where are we looking for that under core we're dropping our camera and drop in our follow camera
the follow camera we need to change the flow to be the player okay make sure navigation bake we take
our NAV mesh so that we do have one k now let's click on play see what happens here okay.
Run run run run it's kind of cool sideways that's not the way I'd intended it but not too bad so I'm
just gonna tidy up my trees the closed side to the camera now make sure this is all okay that our character
can move around yet through the gates and I'll just put a little bit more of an obvious barrier down
the end here that you've reached the end
okay.
It's looking pretty good.
One last final play to make sure everything's in order as we're expecting.
Looks my light is still baking or maybe I need to change up the sort of light I having in there.
I'll get rid of that one last tree but then run run run run run.
And then we have our other load area.
So super simple there's not much going on with this level.
The last thing I need to do is throw in a skybox.
So where did I bring in my skybox asset packs.
It was box phobic I believe skybox undamaged materials skybox drop the skybox in the same skybox.
There we go.
Probably a little bit silly me having all these trees in the level so I'm gonna go and get rid of all
these ones up the back here that we're never going to see okay.
That's looking a little bit nicer to save up my level while my video was posed my lights have finished
baking and then let's finish up with little bit to tidy up.
I'm going to create myself an empty.
I will rename this to be core as we did in the previous scene reset the transform on that grab the player
the camera the follow camera drag those into core the I've made a bit of a mess here I've got two terrains
let's see that terrain looks like that one there and the one that I renamed sandbox 2 terrain Sorry
that was actually some sort of mis click.
So the two I'm going to delete that.
Then the terrain I've got in my scene I will call this sandbox to terrain.
Click on assets I can see I've got these two terrains here one is new terrain that looks kind of like
what I've slept down in there and terrain data doesn't look like we need that one there so I'm gonna
delete that and this new terrain I'm going to rename sandbox to terrain.
So this terrain now should match this terrain in our scene.
And I'm going to drag this terrain into my scene a little bit messy I know but I think we got there
in the end.
It's got this one terrain.
Let me just reduce my photo size here so it's a little bit more civil.
This sandbox I'm going to drag in a sandbox too so that should belong in the right place.
The scenes we've got at this higher level so I can see them easily.
Great sandbox to terrain.
I'm going to drag into my environment.
Game Object.
Excellent directional light into my core main camera we don't need because we've got ourselves our fellow
camera everything in there should now be complete save that up zoom back in a little bit.
Click on play just a final check to make sure it works.
Yes it does awesome.
Okay.
It's pretty good.
That's it for me for now.
Back over to Sam So you guys can start implementing your scene management functionality.