Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're gonna be looking at importing our savings system module so you will get these
files in your project and we'll look at what those files actually are how it all fits together.
What's the architecture of this saving system and how we're ultimately going to use it.
See you in that so against this lecture you should have the following asset pack the saving module.
Now the idea here is that maybe you need to unzip it but we're going to bring this in and this will
be the saving system that we are going to use.
Now if you bring into unity you will see that it's going to add in to our scripts folder.
Now the reason for this rather than adding it to the asset packages because I want you to take ownership
of this saving system now that means that you might want to add to it but one might want to extend it
but ultimately you only want to do that once you understand it once you've taken the saving system section
itself.
So for now I would urge you to treat it just like an asset pack in the sense that you're not gonna touch
anything in here.
You know open up the files and you don't really need to understand how it works internally.
But we are going to learn how to use it as an API as if it were just a library provided by unity.
Because in my opinion we should have a saving system built in.
It just does not.
So let's go ahead and import these files and then we can talk about what those files are and how it
hangs together as a savings system.
So I'm gonna go down to the saving section and I'm going to have a look.
If I put this in a list view out what we've got here now the most important ones are the saving system
class which is the main one the saver Bill entity and then the Icesave Ebola serialized Bill back to
three will get to at some point and why that's there.
But first of all we'll talk about saving systems and how that fits into the big picture.
Let's start off by talking about how we're going to try and save game objects.
So game objects could be things like your player your enemy the enemy as many enemies in the scene you
ultimately have entities in your scene that you want to save some state about and we have the saving
system which needs to coordinate the saving of these different entities.
Now how we do this and how we note that a particular entity needs to be saved is by putting a special
component on it called a saleable entity.
So they go.
We've already explained two of these classes the saving system is the main class coordinates everything
and the saver Bill entity on the other hand is put on every single every single game object that we
want to have saved.
Now what happens then is the saving system coordinates finds all the salable entities in the scene and
makes sure all the state of those salable entities is properly put into the save file.
When we ask it to be.
So that brings up the question of how do we know.
How do we make the saleable entity and get all the information that it wants to from the different components.
So we might have a movement component a health component that both have information that we want to
store the movement component for example might want to store where you are located.
The health component might want to store how much health you've got your inventory component might want
to keep the items that you've got and the quests might keep hold of the active quests you have on a
particular entity.
Now how do we link these different components up to the same blends tea in a nice easy extensible way.
Well interfaces.
We've used interfaces before for this kind of inversion of dependency.
What happens is that each of these components the movement the health potentially question inventories
later on will inherit from the IceSave bill interface which basically gives the safe balance to a way
of generically querying these kinds of components for their data.
So it can say hey movement system give me some data and the movement system will return for example
its position it can say health system give me some data and it returns protected potentially the current
health and so on and it can get arbitrarily complex using this sort of system.
So that is the MET THE FINAL main component that we have introduced as the IceSave bill.
And we're gonna work these in and integrate them into our project.
Bit by bit.
Now first of all the subject of this lecture is going to just be the architecture but let's have a look
at the main API to our savings system.
So the main API is save and load.
But we'll see load in a second so save which you call on the save system component takes in a string
which identifies the save file you want to save too.
So you save the current scene state not another scene but this particular scene you save that to the
given save file if you give a different save file it'll be a different cipher so loading then you want
to load from the particular save file that you just save too and this time it'll be loading the current
scene state from the given save file not from a different save file it's going to be distinguished by
the save file you give it.
And finally this delete which deletes a save file entirely and obviously that's going to delete all
associated data for this safer not just this data for your current scene but any scene that you might
have.
These are the main API is that we're gonna be dealing with there is some one more function that we're
going to look at towards the end of this little mini set but otherwise this is the overview of that
saving system so if you haven't already go ahead and import the saving system and I'll see you in the
next lecture where we're going to look at how we can wrap that saving system and apply some key bindings
to save and load.
See you there.