Hello and welcome to this lecture where we are going to be civilising the health component it means
if I kill this god in this like lecture and this level rather go over into seem to then go back that
God is still going to be dead.
Fantastic stuff.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So this lecture might as well just be a great big challenge because what we're going to do is implement
the ice savable interface.
Now if you do want a bit of help with this then we can follow along.
If you think you can implement the IceSave bill interface for the health component and go ahead and
do that right away.
OK.
So what we're going to do first of all is inherit from the Icesave.
We're obviously not really inheriting from it cause we're gonna inherit from one thing but we are having
it as an interface against our health component.
So I'm going to need to include the using RPG saving namespace and then I'm still got an error here
because it's saying I don't properly implement this interface so I'm gonna go ahead and implement it
get it to implement it for me.
It's great.
Two methods one of which is the capture state which I'm going to stick at the bottom and the other one
is the restore state in here.
So these two methods are what we're going to work with.
And first of all there's the capture state.
What are we going to return out of capture state to capture the state of our health component may a
little challenge for you.
There have a little think what we're going to return is the health points.
So if we return health points is there any problem with that is health points something say realizable
it is a float.
So is the realizable by the C shop built in systems so we can just return health points.
Now the tricky bit is going to be here where we actually want to restore the state.
One thing is we've got to get the Health points out of the state so we might need to do some casting
first of all.
And then second thing is that if we are dead once we restore the state we need to cool add dying code
as if we had died in the level.
So that is a challenge for you.
Two steps.
First of all we want to restore the health points and then possibly die as well.
So that is our challenge.
Two steps for you post a video and have a go okay.
So first thing restoring the health points we want to use a cast here.
So health points equals and then we can do a cast because we know the type should be float of this state
is a higher level abstraction.
It's an object.
So it could be any sorts of thing.
But if we cast it down we can make sure it's back to being a float.
So we should get our health points out here and then possibly we want to die.
When do we want to die.
Well if the health points for whatever reason are less than or equal to zero up above we've got equal
to zero.
But I'm gonna have less than an equal to zero just in case something went wrong in the serialization
we had minus health points.
We just want to kill off the character we've got our die code here.
I'm just gonna go ahead and call that.
So that's pretty much all we have to do.
That's how easy it's gonna be from now on whenever we add a new components with some state that we want
to save.
We just need to implement IceSave bill.
Make sure it has a safe Bill entity on the object that has this component and then we are golden.
So if we give this a go I'm going to go ahead and hit play.
We've got loads of extra guards in the scene now.
I've got a rogue safe Falun Gong delete.
This one's been left over from my prototyping so it's just delete that save file and go and hit play.
Now we shouldn't have any save file at all so I'll go over and we've got lots of extra guards here I'm
just gonna go and pick one off.
Kill him and I want to point out to you see daisies.
I didn't mean to go into their attention maybe I'll kill them off too.
So I wanted to point out to you that the player's health is obviously going down quite low actually.
Hopefully I can kill this guy before I run out of health.
Okay.
Yes I did.
And I've got health points of 40 I'm gonna go over to the next scene to be lowered into our same sandbox
too.
And if I go and have a look at the player his health is still 40 points.
Why is that because they share the unique identifier between the two scenes.
So when we loaded Scene Two We loaded all the health of our character from Scene 1 so he's still down
40 points but if I go back into scene one go over to the bridge you can see that all the guards are
where they were and they're also dead.
Which is perfect because our code has told him to do that.
Fantastic so we've learnt how I say was going to make our life super easy.
And I just want to reassure you that if you start the level and all the state is loaded back in and
that's not what you wanted you can easily get rid of that behavior just by deleting the save file and
it will start from scratch in the next lecture.
We're going to look at how we can do proper reloading of the last scene.
We were in but first I want to show you a another issue that we have.
If I were to go ahead at this point and build my game we are going to get lots of errors.
You can try it out for yourself and the errors will be emanating from our salable entity particularly
where we are using these serialized objects and serialized properties because these came from our unity
editor namespace and they don't exist in the built game.
You can't have those objects around.
So what we have to do is we have to exclude them that exclude the code completely basically remove the
code.
In the case that we're building and we can do this by doing an if Unity Editor unity underscore editor
and this is a C saying if we're in the editor then you can include this code.
Otherwise remove it and then I'm going to do an end if a hash and if so you may not have seen the syntax
before but this syntax basically runs when your code is being compiled and can conditionally remove
entire blocks of code.
So we're removing this update because if it's in the built game we don't need this update to be running
at all.
Okay.
So that's what I wanted to do.
Now hopefully if you go ahead and hit build it should work for you.
You can create whatever builds that you want to.
So I'm gonna go ahead and hit build and pause a video and see whether it is going to successfully build
for me.
And here is what pops up if it has built yes it has.
Fantastic.
I'm just gonna go ahead and hit play in windowed mode and it pops up.
Here's my project loads up loads up in a very random location probably because of my save file which
we're gonna have a look at in the next lecture so I'll see that.