Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're going to be creating a flexible modify system which among other things is going
to allow our weapons to do different amounts of damage.
On top of the damage by that is dictated by the current level we're at.
So this fireball for example has done 13 damage.
But if I pick up the sword now this is a different damage bonus to my base damage stat and that is doing
18 damage instead let's dive in and see how to achieve this OK.
So what we need is a modifier system.
How's it's going to look.
Well at the moment base stats when it does get snapped it gets the stat for damage and it gets basically
just the base stat.
Well I'd like this to do is actually calculate all the additive bonuses and percentage bonuses that
apply for this particular stat.
So if we go to get stat and see where it's implemented you can see we're just getting the stat from
the progression and that's why I said it does.
But what I want it to do is also get the additive
modifiers for the particular stat.
So that is going to take in the stat and I'm just gonna use control plus to go ahead and generate this
method and it's going to be a private methods are going to move it down below the other public methods
like count calculate level and calculate the will should be private I'm not sure why it's public.
It's just probably a quirk of the fact that we've changed it from the public method.
And here we go.
We've got additive modifiers it doesn't do anything at the moment but it should return a float.
Basically all of the additive modifies and it is based upon the stat that we're trying to do we're going
to implement this as a challenge in just a bit.
But first I want to see how we can possibly use something like this because let's have a look at how
it's going to work.
We've got base stats down here and we've got fighter using base starts to get its damage that we've
got health using it to get health we might have mover using it to get a movement speed we might have
stamina we might have inventory and buffs.
Now this actually works the other way round right because we are depending on inventory and bots in
order to give us for example are additive modifiers but not just on things like inventory and buffs
know we might be depending on fighter because fighter has a currently equipped weapon.
And so we need to know if there are any additive modifiers that we need to apply on fighter.
And similarly we might have other dependencies within here move or help.
Who knows but there might be circuit dependencies basically and we don't like circular dependencies
the way to fix that is with interfaces at least in this case is going to be an interface.
So we want to have an eye modifier provider that's going to work very much like the save system interface
if you completed that section and what's going to happen is we are going to have fighter stamina inventory
buffs whatever it is that needs to provide.
Stuff is going to depend on the I modify provider and that way we can call to those things and we can
ask them what modifiers they've got without having to create any circular dependencies.
So let's go ahead and create this.
I modify provider so I'm gonna go and do this over.
Ian let's have a look which is gonna be the most appropriate script folder in stats and then I'm going
to go ahead and create a C sharp script I call it I modifier provider and then we can open up the script
and we are going to change it up to actually be an interface rather than the model behavior it defaults
to so remove everything in here and just do an interface called I modify provide gonna cut this and
put it into a namespace as well so it can be RPG stats not saving stats and then we are going to paste
on the eye modifier provider.
Okay.
So the I modify a provider what kind of method should it provide.
Well I'm going to call the method get additive modifiers set against return.
Essentially a list of additive modifiers for a particular STAT STAT STAT and what is that list going
to be we could just return a list but I'm gonna go.
We know how to use I enumerators now and we know that they can represent they can be more efficient.
Basically because we can do yield returns it will be easier to implement additive modify if we have
it as an iron numerator we can do yield returns or we can just return a list if we have got a list of
additive modifiers So let's return an eye in numerator and it's going to be of type floats.
We're going to enumerate over the floats like so and for this we're going to need to include system
collections generic like so now.
In this case we actually want to use an eye enumerable rather than an iron numerator.
Reason being it'll make it possible to do a for each loop over it.
Otherwise the eye enumerable is exactly the same.
And you can use it with yield returns in exactly the same way.
It just allows you to do this for each trick as well.
Now later in the video I'll be doing exactly the same thing because I will run into this issue where
I can't do a for each loop.
Now finally we want to implement our first I modifier provider which is going to be the fighter itself
because it's going to tell us about the modifiers applied based on the current weapon that is equipped.
So we're going to implement I am modify provider.
We're going to control dot to implement the interface automatically and then find where it's gone out
of this method it's gonna have it all the way down here.
I'm going to bring it up too.
Let's see.
I think just after stop attack is probably a good place to do it and now we're gonna see why it's so
handy that we made this an AI in numerator rather than making a list because what we're gonna do is
we're gonna say hey if the stat in question is equal to the stat dot damage.
So this is the damage that well in that case we do have an additive modifier to give it.
It's going to be an additive modifier from the weapon and it is going to be the amount of damage that
the weapon does.
So it's going to be a yield return current weapon.
Dots get damage so that's going to be an additive modifier on top of the damage that our character does.
But that's only if the stat requested was the damage stat.
Otherwise you can see we aren't yield returning anything which is basically the same as saying that
this AI in numerator is an empty list and that's pretty cool because it's allowed as very concisely
to say that we want to return something in certain cases but not in others.
But also you might find that you want to return more than one thing for example if you had two weapons
equipped you had two hands and you had two weapons equipped.
You might want to yield return first the damage from the first weapon then the damage from the second
so you could have to yield return statements as is allowed in an AI in numerator but we're not going
to do that.
We have single handed weapons but in the inventory it's going to be particularly useful because we'll
iterate over everything in the inventory and yield return any of the stats or modifiers that they have
there.
So you challenge this lecture is going to be completing this get additive modifiers that we've got over
and base stats.
So you're going to get the use get components basically to get everything of the AI modify provide a
interface and then you're going to for each over all the providers and then for each over all the modifiers
in the AI in numerator that's going to be a list of floats essentially so you can have a list of modify
providers which each has a list of modifiers and then I'd like you to return that sum so that when you
go ahead and play based on the weapon that you pick up you're going to do a different amount of damage
on top of the damage for your current level.
So pause the video and have a go k.
Welcome back.
Let's give this a shot hopefully.
The instructions were intelligible and you had a good shot at this.
Don't worry if you didn't quite manage it 100 percent.
So first for each loop we are going to be doing over the eye modifier provider like so.
And then this is going to be called the provider in my for loop and it's going to be a get component
components.
We want multiple of them of the I modify provide a type and then parentheses and then in order for each
body we want yet another for each loop.
This time the type where for each never is going to be floats because they are the modifiers themselves
and is going to be for provider and we need to get the additive modifier for this stat that we're looking
for the additive modifier stat.
Now you'll notice there's a bit of a problem here it's saying that hey I can't enumerate over an eye
in numerator which is a bit odd but what you need to have it's really odd that there's two different
things that are very similar in C sharp the eye in numerator and the IE in New a.
Now I enumerable basically just is exactly the same as the numerator except it allows you to use it
really easily in a for each loop.
So just go ahead and switch over from iron numerator to I enumerable as I have noted earlier in the
video you've probably already done this so it's going to be I enumerable in the I modify provider is
also going to be I enumerable in the fighter to make sure we are implementing the correct interface
and now you can see that for each loop doesn't actually complain so we're going to go on and add up
and modifies how going to do that we're going to have to keep track of the totals I can have a float
total that starts off at 0.
That is the total of all our modifiers then I'm going to do total plus equals.
So adding to this variable the modifier if let's make that singular for some reason I made it plural
so the actual modifier and then right at the end of the for each loop we return the total so that if
there was nothing there in the set for example there's no provider or the provider returned no additive
modifiers then the modifier total is going to be zero as is gonna be the case with the health it's not
going to find any modifiers for health so let's hop over TNT and see if this works I'll pick up the
spell First of all see how much damage that does hit him once and the damage done according to the console
was 13.
So does that make sense.
Let's just evaluate I've got in my progression that I do 8 damage at level 1 and I am at level 1 then
if I go to my weapons folder resources I'm gonna find my fireball and see how much damage that does
it does 5 so indeed 5 plus 8 equals 13.
Now if I go and pick up the sword which I think is a slightly more powerful weapon and see how much
damage we do with a sword.
Have a look at the console didn't actually finish my attack that's to finish the attack and the damage
done that was 18 so I would predict that the damage done by the sword is going to be 10 and sure enough
the weapon damage is 10 so you can see we've got this additive modifier system that is working very
flexibly because any of our components could implement the I modify provider so you can have your equipment
providing modifiers you could have passive items sitting in your inventory providing UV modifiers you
could have all sorts of things buffs and debug components that allow you to store the results of spells
on you and provide that to the stat calculation system now in the next lecture we're going to look at
how in addition to the additive modifiers we can have percentage modifiers that basically multiply your
current strength and all the things you currently have additives be applied I'll see you there.