Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We're going to be working on making sure that our weapon choice is saved between scenes.
So I've got a sword in my hand if I walk through the portal and come out on the other scene you can
see I still have that sword my hand if I changed weapons in the scene and went back the weapon that
I have will be remembered.
Let's dive in and see how that's done.
So we want to be able to save our current weapon which is a state variable in the fighter class.
So the way to do this as we know or if we've already seen is to use the I save a ball from the Save
namespace and that's going to allow us to tell it how to store the state of the current weapon.
But also how to restore the state of the current weapon so if we go ahead and try and include I save
a ball it's going to ask us to include the RPG saving namespace and it's going to ask us to implement
the interface.
So I'm going to go ahead and get the default implementation of the interface which should be somewhere
down at the bottom here.
And we've got our capture state and our restore state so capture state.
We just need to return something that tells us what the current weapon currently is.
Now the easiest way I think of doing this at the moment and bear in mind we will do this in a better
way in part to once we have full equipment.
We need to remember all the different things that are equipped or in your inventory.
But for now what we're going to do is we're simply going to return the name of the current weapon weapon
in our current weapon prefab.
So we're going to do current weapon and Dot name.
Now your current weapon could be no.
But usually that's an error because we should instead of having a null current weapon we should have
an unarmed current weapon.
So I'm going to go ahead with just assuming that current weapon is never none.
It might be unarmed but it's still a weapon.
Now that's basic going to say OK.
So I'm going to save the string which is the weapon name in to our capture state.
So the object and then when we load up the game again that's what it's going to give us in this state
object in restore state.
So we're going to have to implement that.
You're going to have to go ahead and do something with this state object which is actually a string.
It's just more general because we can't rely on it being a string in general for our interface.
So what we've got here is we've got the state which is the current weapon name and you've got to go
ahead and restore it.
So that's your to do using this resource load setup up that we've used before.
Go ahead and restore the weapon of your choice OK.
Welcome back.
So no challenge right there because I thought it was easier just to show you.
So we're loading this weapon here.
We're not doing it from the default weapon name.
So we're doing it from the state.
We're going to use the state as the best to cast that to a string and we're going to store that string
in a string called weapon name and then with the weapon name that's what we're going to load from our
resources load brings us up with the weapon.
And finally we want to try and equip the weapon that we found from our resources.
So that should do the trick.
And I want to also go ahead and just fix up what we've got in start because we do want it to actually
load at default weapon again not this string thing.
So going to remove the string and going to remove it from the serialized field as well.
So we're just loading it from a normal resource link.
But I do want to point out that we've got potentially a race condition we're going to see this in a
second when we go ahead and test test this out.
So I'm gonna go ahead and play and see whether we can save what we had in our hands.
So I've got my sword here.
I'm going to go ahead and save now if I go ahead and load the game again what I should have is that
I should appear back with the sword but it doesn't seem to have happened what happens if I go ahead
and hit L4 to load the game from the safe game that Gary actually has given me the sword.
So what's going on that why when I loaded it didn't give me the sword.
So we actually have a race condition because what's going on here is that the restore state is getting
called in start from somewhere inside the saving system but also we've got our start We're equipping
a weapon so we're overwriting the choice of the saving system potentially by equipping this weapon.
So what I want to do is just put a little guard in here that says that if the current weapon is not
equal to no or sorry is equal to no then we want to equip our default weapon.
Otherwise the saving system's already done its job and we don't need to do anything.
So that's what I'm going to go ahead and do if I go ahead and play at this point.
We should hopefully see that we appear there with our sword has remembered the sword with the equipped
thing.
And if I go through into the next world hopefully I should remember the same thing.
Yep and there I am with my sword in the next world.
So we're now successfully saving our weapon from world to world.
But I want to show you that there's still a kind of funny issue because our pickups we will have better
pickups by the way we'll be able to drop items.
But what happens if I can pick up the flower and I pick up the sword.
Well I can't go and pick up the flower again.
I didn't drop the flower.
It's not in my inventory I can't equip it or anything like that.
So what I would like to be able to do is just make these pickups respawn themselves automatically just
to hide that problem for now.
Later on we are going to have pickups that we are able to drop that we're able to put into our inventory
and so on and that will fix that problem.
But for now we're gonna have respawn balls which is gonna be the subject of the next lecture and I'll
see you there.