Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're gonna be going through lots of classes and evaluating them for their use of Awake
and Start based on our guidelines.
And we're going to fix them up and improve them.
So let's dive in and see how we're going to do it.
So one lecture ago I mentioned these guidelines and I said that we were going to evaluate our whole
code base on the basis of these guidelines.
So let's remind ourselves what they are again.
So it says don't call any methods in a wake.
And if they belong to a mono behavior or a scripts will object because these two types have their own
awakes that we could race with.
Then secondly in start we're saying at this point if there is any state it should be absolutely safe
to use so it should be safe at this point to call methods on other minor behaviors and other scripts
will objects because their state is set up.
That does mean that if there is something you need to set up in star you need to think about checks
for it as we did with the current level in base stats.
So we're going to go through and do a very systematic evaluation of our usage of Awake and Start.
And I'm also going to explain to you another set of callbacks that we can use as well.
So I'll show start off with an example and then I'm going to give it over to you folks to do even better
and go through the whole code base.
So the first example I'm going to give you is base stats.
So here in base stats it looks okay more or less but we do have something here that we're taking this
experience we use it again.
So maybe we decide hey let's take the experience out of here into an awake method to set it up and cache
it.
So I'm going to create a cache it's going to be what type experience.
So and we're just going to set it like this in a week.
Now why am I doing this in a week and not start because I want to be able to depend on that state being
set by the time other Start methods might be calling into this base that's going to take that out.
Next up we've got we're registering for this callback in starts now.
That's okay.
But actually the best practice for registering for callbacks is to do it in a message called on enable.
Now when does on enable get called it actually gets called at sometime around the same times that the
awakes are happening but always after it for the same method.
So we've not got an issue of racing because we aren't going to be using this we don't have any calls
coming in externally in on enable.
And we know that our own wake method has already happened.
But just be careful because it means that in on enable the same rules go as for awake you cannot use
any external functions because you don't know their state has been set up yet.
So we're going to do experience on experience gained and we're going to register for that now note.
You might think that.
Is that a external function.
It's not actually an external function you're not actually updating any state there you're just registering
a callback.
So this is safe to do on enable and similar to this which need to do an on disable as well as is just
good habit.
We don't really need it just yet.
But what could happen is if something disables base stats it could continue to get notifications from
experience when the experience is gained.
And just to prevent that from happening we're going to remove our subscription to this event by using
the minus equals operator on disabled.
So on enable we add our subscription again on disable we disable it so that we aren't getting callbacks
while we're disabled and when we get enabled again we register again.
So that's no problem.
Unlike awake on enable might get called multiple times on a single class.
So that's good.
We can remove that.
Now of starts and now star is just calculating this current level.
Now this is a kind of okay because current level is being set when it gets called as well in the getter
which means that we are doing some level of protection of this so that the current level could be accessed
in start and in fact it was getting access to in start.
However you will notice it's also being used in update level and although update level is only getting
called on this on experience gained and that's not currently being called in start.
Who knows at some point you might have experienced gain notifications coming through in start.
And that would not be a very good thing.
So ideally we would have some better protection mechanism but that's gonna be the subject of the next
lecture.
For now we're just going to leave some of the state being initialized in start.
That can't be moved to awake because we can't move it to wake.
Why.
Because calculate level it goes through and gets the experience component and actually gets experience
so in indirectly we would be accessing another class in awake if we tried to move this into a wake.
So that's why that is not possible.
Now let's have a look at another class.
We've got an A.I. controller here.
And you'll notice hey this state here the fighter.
What happens if another start method via a public method here on the A.I. controller was trying to access
our fighter.
Well that would be no good.
So what we want to do is move this into a wake so that this state here of these references is actually
all set up in time for any public methods that might get called from a start method elsewhere.
Now again we've got this state here this guard position which could at the moment is not being called
in a public method and it's definitely not being called in another start.
I have checked but who knows you know down the line you might forget about this and you might accidentally
expose the guard position for whatever reason that no piece of UI or something that you want to update
on start and then you will have yourself some problems.
So we are going to look as I said into a better way of doing this but for now just leave this kind of
state initialization that we can't do elsewhere in start again.
We can't do this in a wake because we are accessing the transform dot position.
Now why we're not using a jet component transform is a different mono behavior.
And we should not access it on awake.
So I'd like to challenge you to evaluate other classes in the same way as I've just been doing so search
for the start and awake uses that we've got up to this point and is in line with our guidelines from
the last slide.
Now what I mean by search you can use the search functionality for example in Visual Studio and I would
do something like a wake and then open brackets and that's going to give you the awake methods and you
can step through them one by one and just check that they conform with our guidelines you can do that
for both start and awake.
OK.
So I'm going to leave this guidelines on the screen for you to take a look at Paul's video and have
a go OK.
Welcome back.
Let's refer to these guidelines as we step through.
So first of all we have an enemy display.
It is not accessing other model behaviors as you can see here is just taking a reference to the fighter
or good there now awake in our control we've just done the persistent object spawner.
This is interesting.
So what's going on here we're spawning persistent objects which you can see is instantiating a game
object and setting it to don't destroy on load.
Now it's not actually doing anything with that game object until it has been instantiated in France
not doing anything with it even after it's been instantiated.
So we're safe that because it's not accessing a game object before awake.
Now the mover is just using awake to initialize components again.
That's perfectly fine.
And same with health display.
Now the fader yep just initializing components.
That's all good.
The saving wrapper.
OK.
This is an interesting one again it's starting a car routine.
So we have to ask ourselves what's going on in that car routine.
Whoops.
Looks like the first thing we're doing is we're finding an object and calling a method on it.
Now we know that we should not do until after awakes have taken place.
So what we're going to do there is we're going to cut this out and we are going to put it just after
we have loaded the scene.
Now this is okay because it still is going to be happening before the first frame and so before things
are rendering but it is actually safer because if you had just looked at the last thing was it the last
thing we were looking at was the object spawn.
Let's have a look.
Where was that persistent object spawner has an awake method and you can see that we're instantiating
objects in a wake.
So that is potentially a race condition here where we haven't yet spawned the fader and we could be
accessing it in a week.
So that's no good.
We can't access a fate that doesn't exist.
So that's why we have to find the object after the awakes have happened and obviously given it's a chance
to set up its state because if we had to look at the FAA has its own awake method that sets up its canvas
group.
So it wouldn't be able to access its canvas group if we called it too early either.
So that's all no good.
So that's so hopefully fixed up that race condition with The FADER in saving wrap are now up to base
Nance.
Yep that's all good.
We did that earlier experience display.
That's fine level display and then we're into stuff that's not on our own.
So then I just want to have a look at starts.
So our cinematic control remover cases is a good example to do on enables stuff again.
So just to recap we are adding the notifications on enable and removing them on disable that means you
don't need those in start anymore and start with taking this reference.
That's no good because that reference won't be safe to use in other start methods.
So.
OK.
We want to do this instead on a wake for best practices.
Again not necessarily everything that we're changing here is fixing a race condition but it's fixing
a potential future race condition.
So then we're going to go and have a look at fighter.
I don't like this very much.
We're trying to protect this current weapon that could be not initialized in start but we're going to
look at that in the next lecture.
Then we've got to transform that we're setting up in start here for the projectile.
This get aim location well that's calling methods on another component here so the capsule height.
So we can't move that to awake wake the A.I. controller again this guard position makes me a little
bit queasy but we'll figure that out later.
Got the player controller is getting the help.
This should be an awake method and we've been through the mover health.
Again we'll do an on enable and we're setting up these health points in this particular way which again
I'm going to fix in the next lecture and based that's as I said we're also going to be able to make
an even neater way of doing this in the next lecture.
So we've gone through and evaluated all our uses of awake and starts and made them conform to our guidelines
which should help us out in the future.
Now the final step of the puzzle is these things that we are having to initialize in start.
How can we make those safer so that we don't make race condition problems like our current level had
but we had to fix with our getter let's make sure that never happens again and I'll do that in the next
lecture.
See you then.