Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be adding a little health cheats to allow us to more easily play test our game so if
I'm running low on health as I currently am from all this volley of arrows I go and eat my pumpkin.
And you can see it added 20 to my health.
And just like all the other pickups it responds and at the moment it's a bit of a hack.
And we are going to do proper health once we do inventory which will be in a different course.
But here for now this allows us to play test and restore some health to the player as we are playing.
Let's dive in and see how to create this little hack
so one feature of the game.
We currently don't have is the ability to heal.
Now this is something that we're going to have more of once we have potions and inventory and stuff
that we'll do later on in future courses.
But for now I do want to put in a little healing cheat that allows us to get through the level even
when there is going to take a lot of damage from our plan.
Now the way I'm gonna do this is by changing our weapon pickup to allow us to also gain health when
picking up a weapon and potentially for it not to have a weapon at all.
So this will mean that we'll be able to create a healing pickup.
So let's go ahead and create that pickup first of all I'm going to go to the game pick up folder and
create a new variant off of my pickup and I'm going to call it the health pickup and then with this
health pickup I'm going to open it up and I'm going to find an appropriate mesh so the appropriate mesh
I want.
Let's have a look.
We go in the center pack and that prefabs.
And I think I'm going to use this pumpkin.
So I just dropped the pumpkin underneath my health prefab scale up a little bit because I think it's
quite small.
And then I can move my spear collider to the center of the pumpkin like so and maybe move it up a little.
Saying OK now I have got myself a prefab that I'm going to go and drop into the world as my health potion.
But we don't have anything that looks like a potion.
OK.
Now what I'm going to do is in this health pickup I'm going to remove the weapon.
So that's going to say basically I'm not going to be arming a weapon when I pick up this pickup.
Instead what we want to have is some health that it's going to restore.
So I'm going to find my weapon pick up a script don't say yes and I'm going to add a new serialized
feel to just before the respawn time and just after the weapon which is gonna be a float which is the
health to restore.
And by default this will be zero.
So most weapon pickups will not restore health but we can choose to have one that does.
And the reason I'm doing this rather than creating a new class is that I just don't want to deal with
having to recreate all of this hide for seconds.
Business especially when it is just both of these things that are a bit of a hack waiting for us to
have proper drops and inventory.
So I'm not going to go ahead and recreate it.
We're just going to get around it for the time being.
Now what I want to do is in app pick up instead of taking fighter as the thing that we want to take
in we're gonna need something more general because we also want to get to the health component.
So I'm going to take in the game object which is going to be the subject and this subject we can then
do subject dots and get component fighter for it when we want to equip the weapon.
And that means that in the place we're calling we have to change it.
Currently it's a collider so we can do other dot game object.
It's gonna be the subject of the pickup and when we are handling a recast it can be the calling controller
game object is the subject.
Now what we're going to do is let's see.
We want to make sure that we only equip the weapon.
If it's not no.
So if weapon is not know then we're going to equip it to the fighter then we are going to say if the
health to restore is greater than 0 well then we can do a subject dot gets components health and for
this we're going to have to include ourselves a new guy has to use the attributes but that's okay because
in the combat system we have use health before we've referred to health.
It's just the other way round that we're not allowed to do.
And then what we want to do is call a heel method which we don't currently have.
I'm just gonna do this optimistically as if we did have the heel method.
Again the heel with the health to restore.
Simple as that.
Now your challenge is to go ahead and create a heel method that most importantly will not let you heel
pass the maximum number of health points.
So pose a video and have a go.
So my first step is going to be to control dots to generate that health method.
And I am going to find where it has gone and done it that's gone and done it up here just above the
on enables.
I'm going to take it down to just below take damage.
Make it public rather than internal and what we're going to do is essentially exactly the same as our
take damage families remove this log message from take damage.
We don't need that anymore and we're going to be updating the health points to the health points plus
the health to restore plus health to restore and we're no longer going to be taking the maximum of this
and zero because we want to limit it.
So we're going to do the opposite.
We can take the men of this value that we're incrementing to and the max health points because we don't
want to go over the max health points.
So taking the minimum of those two which should keep us below the max health points now that should
do the trick.
Let's go over in two and a game and see.
So well I would expect is I currently have max health.
I click on the pumpkin and my health doesn't go up I'll go and get beaten up a little bit by this God.
So he does some damage to me and then I go and collect my pumpkin and.
Well I didn't have any health restore a set up in my health prefabs so let's set that to 20 like so
and try that again if I pick up the pumpkin.
I don't get any health increase because I'm a maximum health.
We're going to get beaten up a little bit so my health decreases past 20 lost and I'll pick up the pumpkin
and you can see it is just shot up by 20 health points so we've got.
And if I stay on the spawning spot you can see I can get keep getting that pumpkin to increase my health.
So that kind of leads to this mechanism where I can play the game by just diving in doing stupid stuff
get myself absolutely hammered but then I can go back and just sit on the pumpkin and wait for it to
spawn and have all of that health come back to me.
So it turns the game into a bit of a waiting game which probably isn't the mechanism you want.
You probably want to have to go buy health potions and then you've got a secret stash of them and you
have to keep reloading but that's okay for now.
This is just to allow us to play test more easily to come back here give ourselves health have it taken
away by enemies and so on and so forth.
Let's summarize in this lecture we've created our health pickup which is basically just a hack for now.
In the next lecture I'm going to be handing over to Rick who is going to be doing a little bit of designing
up this level and sprucing it up before we polish off.