Now that we have the start of our progression system how do we know what numbers to put in here what
makes sense what's going to make for a fun game.
Well I can be a little bit overwhelming so what I want to do is give you a couple of techniques that
will help out.
So what is it that I'm doing.
Well he is a spreadsheet with a bunch of numbers.
There we go.
Done.
Good luck.
Now I'm just Just joking just been an idiot.
So the first thing that I do is to find myself what I call like a soul number what's the soul of my
spreadsheet or what's a key stat.
The first case that that I've got that I think I've mentioned to you in the past is how many hits do
I think it should take the player to kill the enemy if if we're at the same level so he's made the player
he's an enemy if we're both level one and I run up to this guy on average it should take me I think
three hits like bang bang bang gong.
If he was a level all right level five then it should take me a lot more hits maybe it's going to take
me six or seven or eight and then also more relevant to what we've been doing in the let's see the levelling
up is how many kills do I think I should get before I level up.
Now there's again a bunch of ways that you can approach this the way let me just get my scribble a pen
so I can scribble some stuff here that looks decent.
OK.
So for me the approach that I'm going to is a very very standard RPG approach if this is my time.
So time is this way.
How long I've been playing the game for and this is leveling up level up in terms of how much experience
it takes to level up at the first level.
It takes a small amount at the next level a larger amount next level a large amount larger amount.
You could do it linear so each time I level up it takes a little bit longer it took me 25 kills and
then it took me 30 and then it took me 35 and it took me 40 and so on.
So you can do this in a linear fashion or you can do it something that's a little bit more exponential
exponential so slow slow slow and then it gets harder harder higher and then it's just crazy impossible
by the end is really really hard to level up.
I don't think that's so much fun.
You can also do it in a way which was I don't know is maybe at the start it's super easy takes nothing
to level out you can't see that yellow sorry let's do it in black.
So at the start it takes nothing to level up nothing nothing nothing with her first five levels and
then it gets crazy difficult to level up for a little bit and then it flattens off again and then it
peaks up so you can do your progression however you want.
Like I say I think I'm going to do mine more in a gradual at slightly more difficult at each level.
It takes a little bit longer to level up.
Now there's some other factors in this when I am level 1 and I'm fighting level 1 beasts.
I want my Level 1 beasts to have a certain amount of experience for example they give me just for example
50 experience.
Now when I'm level and I level 20 I don't want the level one beast if I happen to come across a level
one beast.
I don't want them to give me a different amount of experience that wouldn't make sense that would feel
a little bit cheapening so I still need them to be worth 50 experienced but when I'm fighting a level
20 beast I might want them to have a ton of experience so that it feels like a really big worthwhile
kill maybe they're worth 4000 experience for example.
So I need a way of managing just how many experience should a level 20 thing be versus how much should
a level one thing to be.
And then as you are tuning your game when the player is in the very first level you're gonna give them
a bunch of level ones to be fighting against these little ones that they're finding is maybe there's
a two that's a little bit of a challenge or the bosses are three level three gives them more experience
maybe 200 instead of 50 experience and so on they finish level one that was amazing.
Now you know because you've calculated.
Okay I've got my 25 25 kills to level up and I went and put in approximately 30 enemies in Level 1 then
I'm pretty certain that when someone gets to my level 2 is my level 2 Hopefully my scribbles here are
making sense when the plague is my level 2 I'm pretty sure they're Level 2.
So the play is going to be up against a bunch of Level 2 enemies maybe a level one to say Look how powerful
you are now and then some threes and maybe the bosses of five because they've progressed loan themselves
so show you the next page of my spreadsheet and while I do this I just make a point that I've given
you a link against this lecture for this particular spreadsheet or if you want to just type in this
you are Oh now go ahead I'm just joking with you being an idiot again.
So go find the link for that against this lecture and what you'll do when you open up you'll see mine.
You don't need to ask for permission I get a lot of people who are sending requests to edit like don't
edit this one this is mine what you want to do is got to file and to either download.
You can do that as an Excel spreadsheet or whatever else you want but the main thing you want to do
is to make a copy let me listen to what I've done in here first just a very simple piece of house spreadsheets
work in terms of calculations if you've never worked with a spreadsheet.
When you click on a cell you can put in a formula within that so you can type in a number obviously
and type in 27.
Or I could do something that I do a calculation the way I do that is I hit equals.
And then I can choose for example one of my cells I can choose.
The multiplier for my base health click on that and that is in Cell B so B across this way.
And 12 across that way.
And then I could multiply that by doing the asterisk sine I can multiply it by for example.
This thing just hit this cell 10 full and then hit enter.
And now that's gone and calculated that times that say three times ten equals thirty.
So you see that if you go and click on my my little formulas in here you see those sorts of things up
in the the bar up here you see that all the time.
The other thing that I'll add in my just very very quick and simple spreadsheet intro is sometimes you
see a dollar sign.
That means if I copy this cell somewhere else then don't change the the letter or the number that the
dollar sign is in front of.
So not small on my screen here that has dollar sign.
Be dollar sign.
Well that means this 150 is being generated by multiplying be twelve.
And that's b twelve which is this number just here.
This is my number of hits to kill at same level my multiplier.
It's multiplying that by G 8 and G-8 is my total damage.
So how much damage the played out spaces in this times that.
Because there's a dollar sign I can copy this.
Copy that and pasted in here and paste it in here and so on.
And when I pasted in there it keeps the beat 12 exactly the same it doesn't modify it but it progressions
along the H eight it moves it along a s smart enough to know that you were multiplying that and you
copied this.
So when you paste that in there I'm going to move this one along as well.
And the fast way to do it is if you have a formula set up here at the start you can grab this little
squared and the bottom is go drag drag drag drag and it will populate that for everything beyond that
point probably if I drag this one yes then it's going to continue along with whatever formula I had
in that previous self.
Okay.
So I just wanted to I know some people get a bit stuck on that so I wanted to explain to.
Now let me talk to you about my rationale and what I've actually done in this spreadsheet.
I've got the play details at the top that I have enemy details below that and I've got my l You means
level up.
And if you see the little top right triangle thing then that means I've inserted a comment against this
multiple means multiplier and was l You means how much is added when the player levels up and so on.
So the experience to level out this is what we want to know the player at level 1 they need 2000 experience
from level 1 to level 2 level 2 they need 3000 to get level 3 level 3 then a four thousand and so on.
And you can see I've got in here 1000 l you that means that I've got my fairly linear path but it's
getting a little bit more difficult each time.
So we might need to put in a new row in here which is cumulative.
I'll do that now and you can see me as I do it insert a row and what I'm going to say is to get from
level 1 to 2.
Okay.
Well that's the first time we've leveled up so it just equals that 2000.
Great to get from level two to three.
I need a further 3000 so I'm going to add 3000 onto my previous number so I'm going equals 3000 plus
the number just to the left.
And that should make 5000 now I've set up my little formula.
If I go drag drag drag drag all the way out to level 18.
That should work accurately.
Let's see.
And it's showing us to get from level 2 to 3 and a further 4000 on top of 5 which means a cumulative
total of nine cumulative experience.
OK.
Now when you're at level 1 I've said I want the player to have to kill around about 25 enemies to get
to level 2 and I know I've said well let's start with 2000 Experience Experience points you need to
reach 2000 to level up you need to kill 25 enemies to do that therefore how much experience should each
enemy give you.
Well that's going to be the let's see the experience 2000 divided by 25 equals 80.
So each enemy gives you 80.
And when you kill 25 of them you'll have gathered 2000 Experience points and for a moment I'm just gonna
set this number here to zero and you can see that gives me the experience per enemy is 80 forever even
when I'm killing a level 8 enemy I'm getting 80 experience then this consistent the whole way throughout
all the enemies are exactly the same.
They don't give you any more value you know super boring but what happens in that case if I'm saying
you need to get more experienced to level up instead of getting four you need five instead of five six
then the number of enemies you need to kill you can see the pattern here at level one is 25 then it's
38 enemies then 50 enemies in six 3 I don't know.
By the time you get to level 10 138 enemies feels like a lot.
And so what I want to do is make that journey a little bit smoother but also give the player a feeling
of reward when they kill a bigger enemy.
You could say 50 so if I kill level 3 thing then it's a whole hundred experience points more than that
level one guy and so on when I'm killing a level 10.
Thing it's 530 So if somehow I'm level 1 and I managed to find a level 10 creature then it's going to
give me a ton of experience.
However that means the number of kills I need to get is decreasing.
Well I could probably solve that by saying each time I level up let's add 2000 to this and see what
happens.
I get 25 31 33 35 that actually feels not too bad.
The number of enemies to that I need to kill to level up at flattens out a little bit which is quite
interesting as the numbers up here get quite huge.
The numbers down here aren't quite so huge big and see these levers have different effects.
They're not exactly linear in how they works I could changes to 40 additional experience each time I
level up and then it continues to make this curve a little bit steeper.
I could change this to eighteen hundred for example additional experience I need so that's something
for you to play around with for now.
I'll just leave it at 2040 and see how that feels.
Okay.
That gives me the number of creatures that I need to bump on the head to level up and base health it's
the same thing 40 some going from 200 to 240 to 280 seems okay but maybe I want the play to have a lot
more health.
They feel a lot more powerful each time they level up.
Maybe it's 100 each time maybe it's 200 each time from 200 to 400 to 600 and put that back to where
it was 40 for now just to see how that feels and have to play that and see how it works.
Similarly base hit.
I'm saying it starts off at 10 each time I level up I get another 5.
Now I've put in here a standard weapon bonus to acknowledge the fact that when I'm level 10 I'm going
to be finding these really amazing swords when I'm level ones and not so amazing.
Generally I'm saying they should be roughly the same value as the current players health so the players
damage.
So if you do 20 unarmed then if you find a cool weapon it should be roughly another 20 to do damage.
Okay.
These these are general numbers to help me make decisions when I say how much for my weapons be worth
and also how much damage am i doing therefore how many hits is it gonna take me to kill enemies.
Okay let's just quickly go through the enemies here.
I know this is a lot of content with taking a while with all these the base health.
Now this again as I said before as a number of hits to kill at the same level and I've got in here this
value of 60 which is let me look at my formula.
It's been 13 so it is my number of hits to kill times by D 9 which is my total damage so if I'm doing
20 points of damage and I want to have three hits to kill a same level enemy then and level one enemy
should be 60.
Like just a nice linear growth on the enemy healthcare per level and then likewise how many hits for
the enemies to kill the player I'm saying 25 at the starts.
That means the enemy is just a standard enemy needs to be doing 8 points of damage.
That's based upon the D6 divided by so D6 is going to be the player's base base health divided by how
many hits we want to have kill them.
So it's gonna be 8 when we're at level 1 and 10 and 11 13 14 and so on and then I've just gotten here
a functionality if we want to have the enemy do a big hit maybe it's a massive big slow hit or maybe
they've got a special ability that I've just given ourselves a mechanism for that we don't really have
that now code at the moment and then I've gone down and said well for a soldier or a grunt as Sam has
been calling it what would be the stats the different level I've got to multiply in here saying the
grunt or the soldier is the standard so a 1 multiplier on everything so basically whatever the base
enemy has the Soldier has exactly the same.
However if we say a heavy soldier on the heavy soldier to be more of a challenge I want them to have
more health I want them to hit harder.
They're still level 1 but there are more challenging level 1 and so their health is higher the damage
per hits higher and the experience you get from them should be a little bit more as well I think minions
let's see minions I've got in here is just a little creatures I'll put in there a point for slave less
health and do less damage and you get a little bit less experience for them and then I've just created
a few other categories.
We've got Archer in here for example again tweak the number and that will change the the values so if
I say Well no maybe Archer should have the same health as a standard soldier change that then it'll
change the numbers from from each of the levels.
That's my stat spreadsheet.
What do I do now will I get my spreadsheet I put puppet down in the corner over here rip him.
We open up our progression we say with our health for the player.
I'm going to put in 18 and you can see it's left a whole bunch of stuff in here to populate.
So I jump over into my stat spreadsheet I find the players health.
Where are we player base health at level 1 should be 200 and then back over here sorry about the flipping
and flopping but at level 2 is gonna be 240 so I copy that and I pasted in it is a little bit manual
there it's a lot manual but it's gonna give us a lots of flexibility lots of visibility lots of visibility
to know is that right compared to this compared to that and then we putting our numbers into our progression
so I think you've probably guessed it by now.
Create your own stats spreadsheet as I have just done or update my spreadsheet I guess and then populate
your game with your progression data so it makes sense that you could be playing your game from level
1 to level whatever you want.
I'm going to pause the video while I put mine in now so you don't have to watch that now just briefly
show you what I've done when I come back.
Okay.
Jump in take on that challenge.
Welcome back.
I've put it in my numbers didn't take too long actually and I've got my player's health damage experience
level up and then with the characters I've got the grunt with its health and damage and so on.
And then same with the Archer and I wanted to have all my fields entered manually so we know have it
correct but you might say Ha Man if I make a slight tweak in my spreadsheet is there a quicker way to
enter it.
Yes there is.
Thanks to the intellect of sand pit to see who reminded me we can do it this way.
If you open up visual studio code then you can go and grab your progression file drag it over individual
studio code drop it in place and that will allow us to see you smile.
That relates to our all about progression information you can see our character class 0 that's the player
stat 0.
That's the first time we've entered I have deliberately accidentally made a mistake which is I've gone
and entered my non cumulative when I should have ended my cumulative experience so what I'm going to
do is highlight all of my numbers here from 1 to 18.
Copy that jump over into my progression asset in Visual Studio code look for where I have that information
and it is step two.
Just here it's important through this whole process that you don't mess up the indentation you want
to keep those the same.
What I can do is highlight all of my numbers here blank and paste that's going to paste my numbers across
the page.
It's deleted the ones are in there across the page.
So if I highlight the space after my first number and before my next number hit control D that will
find the space space space space race between all the numbers until I get to the point where I find
the last one do I have the last one there.
I think I do.
Yep.
The last one I can hit Enter so it pushes all of those down on the page and then I can do dash space
that will do the indentation.
It looks like it's at the right spot I need to do it for the 2000 Dash Space.
It's kept it at the right level I believe you can see where the indentation is there.
If I save that up we could have done this first time round I just wanted to get the structure in place
and show you how you can update your numbers a little bit quicker in the future.
Now when I jump back over into unity let's have a look health damage experience to level up 2006 12
and the highest being 34 2000 is that looking correct.
Always right of me.
Yep.
There we go.
34 2000.
Okay says Just a quick away that you can make some more wholesale changes in the future.
Going in and editing the progression asset using the yellow visualization that we've got there now.
The other thing that we need to do in here is to make sure that we add in the appropriate weapon damage
so resources find the script of subject for say sword now sort of an interesting one Sam's given us
a bunch of flexibility.
Here we can have the weapon damage maybe put that at 2 it's not much but then percentage bonus of 50
so my character's currently doing 10 damage at level 1 then it's going to add an extra 5 based upon
the percentage.
So I think if this is a sword of Level 1 it's going to scale a little bit it's still going to be relevant
as well Level 3 and 4 and 5 but we're gonna be looking for a better sword that's giving us a better
percentage bonus as we go.
So I'd probably even put this lower I'd say a 20 percent bonus if I look at my spreadsheet again and
see that I winning generally wanting to add a bonus of weapons it's around about the same amount of
damage as our base damage but I don't want all of my weapons to be amazing.
So I think the balance between the damage and the percentage bonus is pretty important here as the weapons
get way cooler and better you might want to have more of it be about the percentage but at a lower level
have more to do with just the weapon damage itself so that you're not going and giving them a weapon
that scales really well level one weapon shouldn't scale super well.
You want to be looking for cooler weapons as you go make sure you change the fireball and the red and
blue projectiles as well.
Just some numbers that I've got in there for you.
Again putting what numbers works for you.
Give it your best shot.
Play the game see how it feels and continue to finesse and tune.
Update your spreadsheet if you've got any questions let us know.
And if you want to take a screenshot of your spreadsheet so you can see his hammer.
Show us how much love you put into it.
That'd be cool as well.
It's been a huge lecture.
Thanks for bearing with me and I'll talk to you again soon.