OK.
This is how my level is going to be looking by the end of this video.
I'm just starting the process of tidying up I'm doing a little bit of undulations with my my terrain
just tidying up my painting of the textures and putting in some nice water so we can get closer to having
this look show worthy.
OK let's jump in and start thinking our live a little bit more like I'm not gonna show you click by
click exactly what I'm doing here but I'll show you what it is that I'm trying to do.
And then I'll show you the result after I've done it so the first thing I'm gonna do is to increase
some areas of my elevation throughout my map to make some undulations in there so it's not just one
flat flat flat flat just a little bit of a side note on that.
It probably does make sense that the town is flat because towns tend to be flat but maybe over the backyard
it's a little bit higher.
And as you're coming into town maybe coming from up and then running down a little bit into the town
so I'm just gonna go ahead and do that.
So if you've got any elevation changes you want to make to your level now's a good time to do it.
I'm midway through the process just a quick update here I've got rid of my trees in the area I'm working
on they're easy to put back in but I find them a bit distracting I push my pickups out of the way I've
just gone and raised some areas I'm making these kind of stepped approach by going set height so selecting
set height of my terrain and then if you hold down shift and click that'll allow you to do the height
of things I'm just tidying things up.
I know the sand has been running down this side but here which wasn't really the purpose so I can put
trees there so you can't run down but I still want to be out to see into the river come from a little
bit higher down a little river deep up and up and over such just a bit.
Interesting.
Ups and downs and then after I've made my steps at the height I want them.
This is way too steep but just doing that for illustrative purposes you know to smooth height put it
at a very aggressive opacity and then just go up and wave it around like that that'll smooth this out.
So it's a little bit smoother and get to the point where if you're happy with it that's not too steep
then that's a good little undulations.
OK.
That's a midway I'll keep working on my thing and switch on the camera if I find anything else that
I think might be useful for you.
OK.
I finished editing my train and playing around with the elevation put a couple of light ups and downs
over here like I said before I think it's good if you've got a natural environment to have some ups
and downs.
I made a little ledge up here where we could put some sort of landmark like a church or you know they're
often up on a hill just imagine our camera the whole time thinking that way is my camera the camera
around here there's a little bit of interesting set dressing we can do up the back here put some sort
of interesting landmark I think then running down here then elevated this a little bit so up into the
town and up out of the town for both of the areas where my bridges will be a low elevation.
Okay.
The next thing I'm gonna do is tidy up where I've got my texture.
You can see the blue now because I've put some of this out.
Let me just change that so it's not going away.
I push some of my train.
I love it.
Now my blue doesn't really make sense in some of my paths aren't quite right.
So I'm just gonna go and tidy up my my painting of my ground texture.
Next I'll be back in a moment.
Okay.
Good good.
I've done a little bit of painting here just made it look like there's been people walking around on
this dirt a little bit more is gonna look different once we put our foliage over the top but I just
want to make sure I've got the underlying principles right.
We don't have the water the blue being painted all the way up onto there so it's pretty good.
Next what I want to do is just fix up my water.
The the actual water a little bit the water plane we've got in this let's find that click on water.
You can see you can just go to the albedo and change it around here maybe make it less transparent.
That's not so good maybe make it darker.
Few things we can play around with in there.
Actually I'm going to bring in a different water and my caveat on this is if you find that bringing
in a different water into your game brings errors and makes things go slow or makes your character do
weird things it might be that your computer is just not up for the challenge of having the fancier water
in there.
So by all means leave this water that's in here what I'm going to do is jump over the assets store find
the standard assets I've just searched for standard assets click on import it's going to take a little
bit of time I'm going to choose just the water assets I don't believe I had low river search for it
and I believe we've brought in the other water that I'm looking for in here so it's going to take a
little bit or just click on none I can just collapsed all of these and I found water under standard
assets environment and then water and do not work in VR.
OK cool thanks for that.
So water plane pro time day I think it's gonna be this pro day time I'm looking for to poop but I am
just going to click on all of the water and bring in all of the water in port all of that into my project
should bring it into an asset pack called standard assets or something similar to that that I was gonna
go through I have look for the water because I like the water that we get from the standard assets I
think it looks a little bit more fancy than the one that we've got in our level at the moment but totally
up to you I gonna grab my standard assets has been brought in drag it on two asset packs give myself
a little bit more space here I in the scene find the water what do we got in here standard assets environment
water water again lots of water and then prefabs I think it's going to be and water pro daytime just
drag that in there guy that looks a little bit different a bit more watery so I'm gonna say thank you
to my previous water.
Or is that delete that go back up to my other water I've just dropped in drop it onto environments and
then do a little bit of moving around drop it into place.
Okay and then just stretch it and get it so it's fitting underneath where my river is just using the
stretch tool it should all scale nicely rotate a little bit.
This is not a square one as the previous one was this is more of an SAT an oval as with any of these
things try to make it bigger than you need it down to it.
Okay so I just scaled and moved and rotated make sure it's fitting into all the areas where we needed
to fit just by doing a bit up and down knees again this way a little bit more that looks like it's fitting
in all the places I know what I want to show you one more thing just remembered with the water when
you clicked on your water you can go to the water.
Pro daytime shader open that up and I'm going to change my refraction color just to show you if you're
running around in a swamp you can maybe make it green and give it that greenish kind of tinge.
If it's you've got some sort of devilish volcano type thing then you could.
What am I trying to say here.
I don't know an evil level then you can have a red color.
I'm gonna have my more of a deeper blue just to simulate the fact that as you're running along you're
not gonna see through it when I have it a little bit blue a deeper richer in color.
Okay cool.
And then I make sure we click on place outlooks in the game.
It has inspired me actually as I run into my level I think I'm gonna make a little bit of a sneaky thing
around the corner here.
Put a tree in that bit just there.
So that playing can come in here get a health pack or a weapon pick up a piece of loot or something.
Then block this off with a fence or a bunch of trees.
That'll do two things One it gives the player a little bit of a secret thing a little bit of a side
track but not very far just like a five second side track but also gives them a chance to have a look
at the water that I'm pretty proud of that we've got now levels so they can appreciate Oh that's a river.
What are the implications.
The river runs through the level or through the town so they get a little of an anchor point about what
the town's about because they can see that there's a river running through it.
Okay.
So I think that's enough for this particular video I just wanted to make those additions to improve
the visual look and the terrain of my level in the next video.
I think it's time for us to start adding a few extra props and just playing around with the placement
of our houses making sure this all looks looked pretty cool.
So great work.
I hope your world is coming along nicely and getting a little bit shinier and I'll see you in the next
video.