In my previous video I mentioned that we were going to jump in and do scripted all objects very soon.
That was a little bit of a misdirection because we have one or two things I want to do before that the
first thing is to solve the problem we have of how to create different animations for our different
weapons.
So let's jump in and talk.
Animations and get our character when he's swinging his sword instead of what he's thinking how he's
doing his punch animation.
We want to do a sword swing animation so let's have a look at our animator if you open up your animator
we know and have a look at our animator controller.
You can see that we have locomotion attack death all these kind of good things.
What is happening at the moment is in our tax state we have our unarmed attack animation which is a
valid animation if we want to punch.
How are we going to go about creating a swing for our sword.
Well we could go and change in here and choose from our animation pack that we've brought in before
we could choose the sword attack.
That'd be cool.
But when we go and pick up a crossbow when we pick up a mace or a spear then each time we have a different
weapon.
We can't go and change in here beforehand and set up.
We want that to happen at runtime within the game.
Now there's a solution and the solution is the animator override controller.
I've given you a link to this unity documentation here so you can read up about it a little bit more.
What we need to do is let's find our game folder with weapons in it.
I'm just going to create another folder here which I'll call sword because we're going to need to do
this for each of our different weapons so we'll check out a clip sword they're going to right click
and create animator override controller.
Okay.
What does the animator rename it.
First of all before I explain what's going on this will be the sword over ride can roll.
Is what I'll call it.
AKA Excellent.
So what is it doing well with this override controller.
You can see here it's taking in an animated controller.
We've got the one at the moment which is our characters so let's go I'm fine in my photo game then characters
I've got my character animated controller so we put that in there and says Great.
This is what I'm going to override.
Now we get to choose which of the animations that are contained within our character animator controller.
That's what we've got just here.
Which of these we wish to swap at runtime when now or is it again just when our sword override controller
is being used and we'll write a little bit of code shortly that will say which animator override controller
we want to be using at what particular time.
But here we can say well when we're in this sword when we're using the sword override controller when
it's overriding our regular character controller we wish to change from an attack 3.
So to make an armed attack we want to find a sword attacks.
I've just got this sword attack R6 in here.
So I want to say use this particular attack.
We could change any of these we could change have a different death.
We could have different run and different Idol et cetera.
So that's what the override controller is at runtime.
It's going to swap out this particular animation for the original animation and obviously we're going
to have an override controller for each of our weapons that we wish to look different that we wish to
have a different animation for.
So let's go and create the code that will use the override controller and side note I've noticed my
errors that I said in the last video we'd fix in this video.
Well wait one more video before we fix those.
We'll we'll get to it.
I promise you.
But for now let's go and find our scripts.
We will look at our combat and fighter.
We can put all these things in fighter for now but in a couple of videos time we'll be creating a different
class which will be the weapon class not doing it just yet because that is what will be our scripted
object.
So we're getting there I promise you this.
There's method to the madness.
First of all we need to give ourselves an animator override controller variable so let's serialize field
this would be animator or override controller and we'll call this weapon override over.
Right.
Got to remember the two eyes in there.
And again we'll start this off.
No.
Now let's find where our spawning our weapon underneath instantiate I'll get a handle to the animator
and animator animator and that will equal get component and of type and a metal OK.
So just getting the animator and then what we need to do is set this animator animator dot run time
animator controller equal to saving and figure out the rest of this what will equal the weapon override
weapon override is the animator override controller we've just created and we're going to set the runtime
automated controller to be this weapon override.
Let's save that up and just now the little micro challenge for you see if you can complete the rest
of it.
Just pretty obvious change in the inspector here what do you need to do to finish this off.
Okay.
Well we go into play out.
Funny I play a I'm going to go into the prefab of the player and then on the fighter script we have
the weapon override the weapon override will be let's see in here the sword override controller.
Drop that straight in.
Excellent save that up I'll save it up click on play.
I'm so used to saying save it up and click on play in my script.
Let's run over this way civilly and find an enemy.
Click on the enemy and wait on the big swing with the sword.
Ha.
Then we go.
Awesome.
So we are changing the animation based upon our override controller.
Very cool.
Okay.
Just a straightforward video there introducing the animator override controller so that we have the
pieces we need for the next video where I promise you in the next video we will be jumping into the
scripting all object for the weapons.
Okay great work and I'll see you again soon.