Hello and welcome to this lecture on dependency is we're gonna be learning how to manage dependency
hell where you modify one class everything starts to break down and how we can keep that going when
we've got massive class hierarchies like this and keep the dependencies as low as possible between all
of our classes and all of our name spaces we're gonna be learning about names spaces how to use and
how to create them.
So let's dive in and see what this is all about.
So we have started to allow our scripts in these different folders under control core movement and so
on.
But there's nothing that actually keeps us honest to this in the code this is just for our organization.
I'd like to talk a little bit about something called name spaces and why we might want to use them.
You've actually used named spaces before you might not realize it but when you do using Unity engine
that is including the unity engine namespace and that's what allows you to use things like the Ray and
the ray cast and the camera and so on and so forth.
Basically all these names are included in the namespace it restricts the ability to clash basically
because if you had another module that required a camera it could use it as long as it was in a different
namespace to the unity engine namespace.
But why might we want to use these.
So the problem is that dependencies are evil we need dependencies in any program obviously because things
need to cooperate with each other you know it would be useless to have a perfect combat system if it
didn't communicate with movement and wasn't controlled by a control system.
So imagine we have this dependency structure between our different names spaces of our basically our
features as Chris call them features for now and we'll use namespace as later on.
Imagine we have this situation in movement we have our movement components and it has a script to move
move to which is shared between combat and control because combat uses it to move towards the enemy
whereas control uses it just to move when you point and click.
So this both of these makes sense but what happens if we make a change to movement we could do this
for example by changing the return type of move to now it might return a boolean and potentially fail
to move.
That means that now what could change as a result of that one change to movement.
Well we can go backwards along these dependency arrows to see what could change combat could change
for example we might need to decide what to do in the eventuality that movement fails control might
fail as well we need to show some affords when we fail to move to a certain location so the player knows
why we are failing to move now obviously not every change in movement is going to break something in
combat and control but it is a possibility and it's something we have to test so that's why dependencies
are evil and as much as possible we try and reduce the impact of dependencies if we can manage it not
always okay we're not going to be able to do everything but we don't want to have a situation where
movement depends on control and combat on core and blah blah blah blah.
Now if dependencies are evil then cycles are even worse.
So this is a cycle because it's a dependency cycle because if I go from control I can get into combat
and at the core and I can find my way back to controls I've created this cycle of dependency in fact
factors more than one cycle here I could go by movement I could go via movement core you know there's
there's cycles lots and lots of cycles.
Now what if I make that same change to movement what can be affected now have a little think maybe pause
a video and think what could be affected now in this well core and combat still the same as before but
now we can follow this dependency this circular defensive back to core which means that core can be
affected and funnily enough movement itself can also be broken by a change the movement in a way that
you weren't expecting so you change something over here but hey via that dependency on core that got
changed by the dependency on control something broke.
So this is obviously not great and this is how cycles can just propagate this problem of dependency
is further and further and further and just make your life a nightmare.
So what we try and do is without a doubt always try to avoid cycles and what happens interestingly enough
when you try and avoid cycles is you get something called layering.
So this is the layout structure of my prototype and obviously it's very complicated.
There's lots of dependencies but not as many as there could have been right.
You know the combat depends on five things it doesn't depend on ten things the movement only depends
on two things saving in core and so on.
Now what you'll notice here is that you can arrange them in layers where none of the modules reference
anything higher up so inventories doesn't mention anything about combat or special actions or UI or
control it doesn't rely on any of that because it's a lower layer dependency and the lowest layer dependency
have basically no internal dependencies within these modules they might depend on stuff in C sharp or
in unity but they don't depend on anything within our project is the lowest layer dependencies and interestingly
enough what happens here is that you have stability increasing as you go down the layers and that's
a requirement for stability.
So what I mean by that is that we need to change these classes less or if we change these classes it's
going to destabilise our project and you can kind of see this you know if I change the way my saving
system works I've got to think about everything because everything depends on my saving system.
I've got to think about how that affects questing and as a result how does that affect the dialogue
system in the UI.
How does it affect combat and control because these lines go all the way up to control so you have to
have the lower layers as stable as possible as unchanging as possible and the higher layers are the
ones where you can do lots of changing so control can change a lot because it has very little dependencies
on it.
So this is just a little bit of an overview of why we are going to be using namespace as it allows us
to really kind of see the picture of this stuff through the using statements because in combat I will
say in a combat namespace I will see that it is using.
Saving is using coins using stats is using inventories and is using movement and that allows me to really
kind of highlight the dependencies and be cognizant of them when I'm adding a new dependency when I'm
writing a new using line I'm having to think twice about doing that and is that really a dependency
I want to add to this graph.
Is it something that I want to add in terms of complications to my project so it allows us to essentially
firewall our features now a flip side of this is that within a namespace you want things to be as cohesive
as possible.
And what that means is that they should try as much as possible to be related to one another so they
probably need to be using each other's classes.
So here's an example of a not very cohesive namespace.
Right.
The combat system depends on damage text and health and the weapon conflict depends on damage range
but between these two you know they could kind of be separate namespace is right.
This one over here could be one namespace.
This one over here could be another namespace because they don't have very much to do with each other.
Now in reality this namespace is more like this where the combat system does rely on weapon conflict
and damage range.
And this is more cohesive now because everything relates to something else in the namespace.
And it's pretty much you know you can't pull any of this out.
It's not completely cohesive it's not as cohesive as it could be.
You know if I added in more dependencies like this there would be a really cohesive namespace.
We don't necessarily want to go for maximum cohesion within a namespace because all these dependencies
do add complexity and it means that if I change the health system I could damage.
Yeah I could change any of these other systems or C sharp scripts in here.
So you still want to minimize dependencies but you want to make sure that within a namespace you've
only got things that are really related to one another.
So with that said let's go and apply this in practice.
How do you create a namespace.
It's fairly straightforward.
I'm going to do it with our player controller first of all.
So the player controller if I go ahead and cut out the class definition because I'm going to stick it
inside a namespace I can use the keyword namespace and then I can name the namespace.
And now the way I'm going to do this is starting off with a prefix namespace as are hierarchical.
So you can have RPG dot and I'm going to call it control.
So this is going to match with the structure of the folders that we've got.
You could have RPG dot control dot something else as well if you wanted.
You can keep it hierarchical.
We're starting with RPG so that if we import anything else cool control it doesn't conflict.
If there's any other module you're using the fact that we started it with RPG hopefully will keep us
safe from conflicts.
So this is RPG control namespace and then you have curly brackets to define things that should go in
that namespace.
That's where I'm going to paste in the definition of our player controller.
So now whenever we want to use the player controller somewhere else in another namespace in the same
namespace it's going to be fine if you have namespace RPG control you can just use player controller
but if you are outside of the namespace you will need to do have a using statement.
So this is gonna be the challenge for you folks to namespace the remaining two classes that we've got.
So each class should be in its own namespace name it appropriately as we have with our folders at any
using statements you need to use you might find that you already have some dependencies between these
different name spaces.
And what do the dependencies look like.
Get out a piece of pen and paper and map out all the dependencies between your name spaces pause the
video and have a go at this challenge okay.
So welcome back.
What we're going to do is we're going to go into the next one is a follow camera.
It is in this core folder so I think it's gonna be in a core namespace.
I'm gonna cut out the class and again use namespace and there is actually a snippet here and visual
studio.
I'm going to auto complete in a kind of pop pops in some of the boilerplate for me.
It's going to be RPG prefixed again because it's everything relating to our project is going to be under
this RPG namespace.
And then instead of control which is trying to alter complete form you're going to create a new namespace
called core.
You'd actually declare namespace as anywhere if you use one.
It's created it and then in the body of namespace I can paste that follow camera class back in.
And finally in the movie script I'm going to go ahead and cut out mover like so and I'm going to add
a namespace as you might have guessed it's going to be RPG dot can you guess it movement as then as
the folder I'm trying to keep it the same as the folder.
And then in the body I can paste and move a class back in.
Now I am getting a little red thing here in Visual Studio.
KERRY Let me can just check this over in unity as well.
I should be able to go to the console and see that it's saying in the player controller class I go over
to that player controller class Whoops it's opening up in a different place the player control class
got a red squiggly under move here and why is that.
Why do I have this red squiggly if you click on the little show fixes button we little light bulb it
it'll say that you need to be including using RPG movement you go.
So we've got our first using statement in here saying using RPG movement which is including our own
module called movement and we can see now that there is a dependency between our control module and
our movement module as we might well expect.
So let's have a look.
If I were to draw out my dependencies I've got three modules or three name spaces called control movement
and core and that is the dependency.
That's the only dependency we've currently got.
We're going to hope to see more dependencies ones between movement and Core for example or when we add
in a combat module we're expecting to see a Lisa dependency between these two so we've got control and
combat and combat depending on control depending on combat basically.
So hopefully that elucidate is why you might want to use namespace as why dependencies are evil and
we want to reduce them as much as possible.
I know it's early at this stage we've got very like three classes but trust me an RPG becomes big very
quickly and you were going to want to have this in the back of your mind while you're doing it so that
we don't get ourselves into a dependency hell.
Hopefully you enjoyed this lecture let me know what you think over in the discussions and I'll see you
in the next one.