Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to set up some triggers that allow us to switch scenes so when I walk into
this switching area this portal area I end up being taken to Rick's new lovely corridor scene so hopefully
this is going to be a little bit of revision for you folks on how we load scenes in unison.
Let's dive right on in so as Rick mentioned in the last lecture we want to create a portal between these
sets of gates.
How are we going to do that.
Well the key is going to be triggering some code.
So we're going to want a trigger very much in the same kind of setup as a cinematic.
So we're just gonna rush through this quickly.
We're going to go ahead and add an empty I'm going to rename it to portal and on here I am going to
add some components to add a rigid body because we need that to deal with getting our events to make
sure the trigger gets events.
So we're going to use a switch of gravity.
Add is kinetic so that it doesn't try and move around with physics and notice that we adding in rigid
body to the triggers here.
You could add the rigid body to the player instead and that might be something to think about doing
in future.
For now we're not going to I'm going to add a box collider here as well.
Now notice this is not showing up because it's in some random location a great way to sort that out
is to make a prefab of our portal.
Now where is a good place for this.
I think it's quite core to have a portal so I'm going to put our portal prefab into the game core folder
and then I'm going to remove my scene and bring it back into the scene by dragging on to the scene view
so that it is positioned in a good place now I'm just gonna rotate it and modify the size so that we
can't help but go through this portal when we walk between these gates which is the idea after all.
So there we go.
That's nice and big and should do the trick.
I'm going to save the scene and we're going to leave those sized parameters not applied to the prefab
but other stuff we're going to want to apply directly to the prefab so I'm going to open up the prefab
so that we don't forget to apply it basically because that's always a problem.
Oh yes.
One more thing we're going to want is to add the letter to be ignore recasting on our portal prefab
and then we're going to want to add a script for us to call saying going to create a new folder here
called Scene management.
And in that I'm going to create a new model behavior called portal C S and I'm just gonna skip over
the bit where I write out the boilerplate code which you know has to do by now Model Behavior call portal
in the scene management namespace reflecting exactly how we've set up our scripts.
Now in here I want to do an on trigger on trigger enter in particular is that's where we're going to
trigger off a loading up of the next scene.
So here I'm just gonna put in a print statement which should tell us whether our portal has been triggered
or not.
And I'm going to not forget to add this portal component to our portal prefab go back up to the scene.
Let's hit play see what's going on.
Can we trigger off this portal by walk into it.
It is not showing me Day has triggered.
So why is that.
Have a look at the portal check a few things.
The box collider is not in fact a trigger.
So let's go into the prefab and make it so is now a trigger and let's try it one more time.
I am noting some other errors will get to these in a second okay it did get a portal trigger notification
so that seems to be working as we would like getting a portal trigger each time we step inside that
portal.
Cool.
So the next bit is going to be a challenge to you.
But before we do that there is this reference script unknown on this behavior.
So what's that.
If I go to the intro sequence you may have worked this one out for yourself.
But when I deleted whatever the fake I think it was the fake playbill director I forgot to remove it
from this game object.
So it's called Broken reference.
We're just going to go ahead and remove this components again.
And that should make that error go away.
Let's just try one more time.
Yeah.
No such problems this time.
Now notice that we are also getting triggers when it's not the player going in we know how to deal with
that.
So time for your challenge to load the correct scene.
So fill in on trigger enter and the player should be the only thing that sets it off otherwise we're
going to be switching scenes all the time and I'll be absolutely no good.
Try and keep your dependencies to a minimum so don't try and include that basically try and include
no name spaces if you can get away with it.
And if you're thinking cool I know how to do that then go off and do that and maybe you can do a little
bit of YouTube a little bit of Google research YouTube research whatever to see how to load scenes if
you've gone a bit rusty on that if you don't and aren't quite sure wait for the tip and the tip is that
you want to be using scene manager dot load scene pulls a video and have a go at the challenge okay.
Welcome back.
So as we said we want to check that where the players.
Let's put an if statement in here.
I'm going to just check that the other object were colliding with DOT tag is in fact equal to plan.
And if that's the case then we can proceed to try and change the scenes.
That's going to be seen manage.
What was it scene manager dot load seen.
Now you might have to include a namespace for this.
It's going to be a unity engine dot scene management.
And that will now work.
And then we've got a few overloads followed seen that we could choose from so we could get the one that
does it based on the scene name as a string.
We could do it.
That's another string one more string ones but there's ones that have the build index.
Now I'm kind of of a mind to go for the build index ones because we then rename a scene.
We're not going to have issues with having to rename everywhere.
OK.
So I'm gonna add a serialized field that allows us to configure the portal as to which scene it's going
to load.
So it's going to be an int and it is going to be seen to load like so and by default we will start with
a minus one which should throw us some errors if we haven't decided what to do with it.
What we haven't actually configured our portal.
So that should be basically it's almost there.
We need to set up the scene indexes so to do that we need to go to I always forget where this is so
it is a file build settings and then we can drag in the scenes from the project view.
So if I go to my scenes folder and grab the first sandbox scene then sandbox too so you'll see that
sandbox one has got the index zero sandbox to go index 1.
That's what we want to know because now when we have our portal selected we've got this scene to load
and we want to make it seen one said we load Rick's a lovely scene so I'm going to go ahead and save
that and see if when running into it we're going to trigger it to load a scene bam we have.
So to recap we have created a portal game objects way of handling the trigger event and loading a scene
of the back of it using a build index.
The next lecture we're going to work out how to make things a little bit more sophisticated than this.
But first we're going to need to know a little bit more about coatings or do a recap at least.
So I'll see that.