In this lecture we're talking about the player experience.
And I'm going to challenge you to come up with an experience that you want to give your player in your
game.
So what do people like playing games.
Well what they'll say to you is it's fun you know I like it because it's fun.
No I'm good at it or the graphics look great.
That's what they're saying.
What's really going on.
I think what they actually mean is it made me feel a certain way or it gave me an interesting experience.
And the best games give a player a consistent experience throughout the game.
And I think the most important high level design tool or design technique you can have in your in your
toolkit is to create a very specific and consistent player experience that you then have every aspect
of your game support.
Let's talk a little bit about how you come up with a player experience.
So I've got three ways here that you can express your player experiences more I'm sure.
But let's talk about these three the first one is to make the player feel like a particular type of
person.
His couple of examples if you look at the Elder Scrolls series I'm looking at Skyrim just here.
The game creators want you to feel a particular way like a something and I think they want you to feel
like an adventurer you're going off on these big quests across faraway lands you're having to scale
mountains and battle monsters and discover things and and find allies and kick down doors.
It's all about being an adventurer and a lot of memos give you this kind of or open world games give
you this sense of being an explorer and adventurer going off on a grand quest.
But if we look from the same studio Bethesda the Fallout series in particular we're looking at full
out for here.
The experience that they're giving the player is different it's not an adventure but it's as a survivor
it's post apocalyptic.
You have to scrounge for materials you have to you're running around as a lone wolf trying to survive
from mutant monsters jumping out at you to unravel what's going on and just just stay alive just survive.
And if we look at a different game Assassin's Creed This one's great.
It's right in the title.
They want you to feel like an assassin you're running around with a hood over your face he slinking
through the shadows you trying not to to be seen or get caught it's all about this secretive assassin
bad ass fighter kind of guy dropping on your enemies from the rooftops your you're sneaking around you're
shooting arrows just everything about this game makes you feel like an assassin.
There's another way to express it is to make the player feel a certain emotion.
So what I mean by that couple of examples here God of War I love this series within God of War.
How do you feel when you play that well you feel powerful you feel like a god you feel like you can
smash things you just bust through walls and and command great surging power.
It's one of those games that just everything says we want the player to feel powerful.
If we look at a game like five nights at Freddy's or many the other scary games you could say I want
the player to feel scared.
That's okay but I think it's more you wanting the player to feel tense.
But it's all about the anticipation waiting something's going to happen something's going to happen
and then you get the jump scare at some point of you know the scary payoff but it's that that tenseness
is why people love it.
Similarly I'm so scared but I love it.
So the the experience doesn't always have to be one of pure joy.
It can be one that's a little bit painful the player but you know in a way that makes them want to keep
going and playing through the game flour if you've seen the game flour or played it I think you could
say this is where you control the wind and you moving around petals of flowers.
You could say well want the play to feel like the wind.
But what's the downside of that.
If I say the wind to you it might mean something.
I might be thinking a gentle breeze.
You might be thinking a hurricane so we can't just say we want the play to feel like the wind.
I think here the what the developers were going for is to make the player feel peaceful.
When you say peaceful you like Ah I know what sort of wind will have the play I feel peaceful there's
there's a powerful ness to it but it's rustling through the grass and and swooping around and if you
look even the artwork even the title screen has a peacefulness to it blue sky and green grass it's not
it's not a stormy day with a thunderstorm that wouldn't be peaceful would it.
Okay.
And another way you can express it is to give the player the same feeling as doing a certain activity.
So a couple of examples on this Minecraft.
What do you think what activity does Minecraft feel like.
I think Minecraft feels like playing with Lego.
So if you say I want to make a video game that feels like playing with Lego people we like aha I know
what you're trying to make here and when you're making decisions on your games team you know does this
make the player feel like they're playing with Lego.
Yes or no.
If it's yes you do it.
If it's no you don't put it into the game.
Similarly fortnight how do you feel when you're playing fortnight and also pub G and the other battle
royale type games.
I think it feels like playing a game of tag or sometimes playing a game of hide and seek.
But there's a whole bunch of us in a playground running around.
I'm trying to tag you you're trying to tag me or in this case you're trying to shoot me while I don't
even know where you are and I get frustrated and quit the game.
Okay enough about me but it's that feeling you get when you're playing that game of tag with a whole
bunch of friends running around in the schoolyard.
So having a player experience makes your decision making easier.
I've alluded to this the best games create a consistent experience in every aspect of the game within
the art within the gameplay within the audio within the story within their marketing.
Everything speaks to that.
You don't sit there and say what should I do in my marketing promo art piece you like.
Well I need to create peaceful.
All right I need to create powerful and so you know how to go about doing it.
It helps you make decisions.
So if you're in doubt what should I do.
Do whatever will create the experience that you're aiming for for your player.
That's how you make decisions.
So I have a challenge for you and that's to decide what's the player experience you're creating for
your player.
Now you might need a little bit of time to think about it.
You might want to put down an answer and then say I'm going to think about this a little bit more over
the next couple of days so that's cool but I want you to put down something now so you've made a start.
Just go with your gut your gut reaction might be powerful or or frantic or an adventurer like you might
already have a feeling of what your game that you've got in your mind is going to be.
So think about what's the experience want to create.
Write this into your one point five page DDD.
And also please share your choice with the community.
Let us know what you've come up with and so you have it as a point of comparison here is what I'm doing
for mine.
I'm going for the joy of laughter going for funny is a little bit.
I've wrestled with this a lot funny is not really an emotion funny is a is an approach so we wanted
an absurd funny game but what is funny if someone's laughing Well it's the joy of laughter.
So that's the experience I'm looking to create for my player.
The joy of laughter through absurd absurd comedy and humor so there's your challenge.
Take that on come up with your player experience and after you've done that I'll see you in the next
video.