We've talked about tuning combat a lot in this video.
I'm going to show you a little bit of my final combat tuning to make my moment my five minute moment
exciting and interesting and a good gameplay experience.
My challenge for you I haven't given you many challenges lately but I have a final combat training challenge
for you which is to train your combat moment so that it is a fun five minutes.
Don't worry about how it fits within your overall game.
That's something that you would tune when you've got your overall game for now.
Just wanted to make a fun five minutes and tune the combat so it's cool for that.
And then if you haven't done so already have someone other than yourself play your game.
Give me feedback give me thoughts and celebrate the fact that your game is awesome.
So there's your challenge.
Show you a little bit of what I'm doing for mine and what I had been doing the last kind of half hour
or so I've put a couple of guys up in here just to break up the moment so it's not all about this moment
down here on the bridge although that's delivered to the start of the show starting my player off unharmed.
So I'm kind of pretending like this is the start of the game but you know at the start the game is going
to be quite different to this because we have a little bit of tutorial but this is a five minute moment.
So I want to have a little bit of progression in my five minute moment.
I'm unarmed I run over here I hit these guys I've had to choose my own arm a little bit to give them
a little bit more of you know what I'm gonna do while I'm here is hang on a sec I'll kill these two
guys finish my thought I've got the flame thrower fireball over here picked it up I put a light on it
so it stood out a little bit more now I've got the fireball one thing I wanted to show you is you can
see that my enemies have got the weed kind of border on their on their health by here I'm going to pause
the game going to scene and just show you probably enough to go on the scene but I'm going to show you
here if I grab let's see scroll down if I grab canvas and click that off so click off canvas all those
go away all that outline that I had there also my players got some little audio things around him so
I think what I'm going to do is just grab all of the 3D icons and just shrink them all down to pretty
much zero that way those things aren't going to get in the way I find I don't look at the gizmos so
much but when you're back into building game mode like playing around with your construction of your
game you can go back and increase that up again oh that's what all those things are.
OK so that is just a footnote there and then unopposed I've now got my flamethrower thing here in my
window when I get more content in my game this is where I could have a quest giver or some loot or some
some other weapon or arm or even a shop over here could go over and do a little bit of inventory stuff
sorry just a footnote for that that I can still use this this kind of moment later on when I add more
features and functionality than up here I've got this moment on the breezeway Oh goodness me this guy
shooting at me I've kind of drawn the aggro of this soldier here I'm going to pick him off with my fireball
shouldn't take as many have gone in done a lot of tuning on my weapon so my fireball was a little bit
weak so I've gone into my script to all objects here my bow my SO MY BLUE Bow that I give to the player
the red I give to the enemy make sure that the distance so the range is consistent and the fireball
what I mean by consistent is that the enemy should be out of out shoot the player so you can see here
the weapon range is twenty whereas what the player is gonna do is just sit just a little bit out of
range and pick off the enemy which we don't want to have happen.
So the player I give the blue projectile which has a range of 18 and the enemy I have the red projectile
which is 20 so the enemy can shoot me a little bit fireball also 18 I increase the specs on that increase
the damage because I wanted it to be a bit more powerful and then sword I increase the damage on that
as well I've dropped the sword later on in my scene over here near the fireplace just there before I
get to my difficult battle at the end here with the stronger guy and Sam made us our little health cheat
here I put that just the other side of the bridge to create this interesting moment where I can run
run run run and get that health and then running the way again if I want to be shooting at this guy
and have a little bit of a standoff shooting sorry let me show you that I've got my projectile weapon
now I can run up here to the bridge Oh I see a guy over the bridge I can shoot he shoots me I shoot
him I run away I dodge dodge his weapon he's not clever enough to dodge mine which is kind of cool shoot
reload shoot again.
Come on do it.
Just standing there doing nothing that's not the way to shoot OK.
And then I get him who I can't I can run over and get a little bit of pumpkin action this guy standing
here with the massive sword shoot at him a couple of times.
Side note I think there's a bit of room for us to add more feature work so that when you shoot them
they come running at you I think that's a little bit lacking at the moment.
So that's one example of kind of a last minute feature bug tweaking we might do might might make another
video too on those sort of things so if you find anything that you say Hey Rick can Sam this is really
busted can you do a video on this then let us know we'll add another video or two into the course.
So then I'm not gonna fight these guys with guys patrolling make sure you update your patrol routes
make sure that the world looks lively and alive as you're coming through then as I said before I would
have picked off these guys I probably would have gone and got this sword which I won't have enough damage
on it.
So sir.
OK.
SAVAGE I really don't die but enough damage on it so that I can pick off these guys and have a really
good last battle with the last guy so probably another health pumpkin or two along the way so I don't
die but I'm pretty happy with that.
I think if I'm making this five minute moment where the player has to figure it out you don't want them
to do it first time.
Oh that was easy done.
And you don't want them to fail miserably.
I've got no idea.
But you know you have to figure out that oh I can pick up that fireball thing here.
Oh I can get the health from there and like I say if I go and duplicate this and put that another one
down in there to so I've got a couple scattered around then the player knows I'm trying to get to the
end.
And when you're giving this to someone else to play what you want to say to them hey trying to make
it all the way through town or whatever your objective is so that they know what they're trying to do.
You don't have to give them all these details you know all you can click on the flower or you can do
these and whatever.
Just tell them enough so that they know what am I trying to do in this game.
And then as I mentioned before the challenge is for you to change your combat moment so it's a fun five
minutes.
As I've been doing here June how many enemies you've got in spots how much damage they do and how much
help the player has chewed it all so you get this really cool five minute moment.
You can show it to people.
It looks good and it plays good.
So that concludes ask creating our five minute moment.
I'd love to see what you come up with and I'll see you in an upcoming lecture.