Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be fixing the bug where we are able to move our character around when
we die.
No longer can I move it around and the same is not true for the enemy.
They're not going to be following us while they are dead and other things like that we're going to be
disabling generally a lot of behavior when the health component tells us that a character is dead.
Let's dive in and see how that works.
At the end of the last lecture we saw this bug where if I am dead I'm still able to control my character
and run around which is just not really okay.
So what we're gonna be doing is disabling control from the player but also we're gonna be disabling
control from the enemy.
So if I take these enemies I'm going to move them slightly away because at the moment they're making
it very hard for me to do anything.
So let's go and focus on them with FC and then move them out of the way.
So I've only got one enemy to deal with and let me just check what his health value is.
I think it should be fairly low.
Yeah.
Health points eight.
So I should be able to go up to him and give me a good thwack.
Looks like it's taking a while to start attacking and our attack time is very long.
So let's just fix that quickly.
So why is it taking a long time to start attacking because if I go to our fighters script then the time
since last attack.
Right.
The beginning is zero.
This means that effectively when we start the game it's as if we just did an attack.
That's not what we want.
We want this to be as if we did an attack a very long time ago.
So the way we're going to do this is by using math f library of unity and doing math f dot infinity.
So that's basically going to mean that when we do our comparison further down that time since last attack
is greater than the time between attacks that's always going to be true if we use infinity nicely that's
going to mean that we can attack straight off the bat.
So hopefully that's going to work.
Yet we can both attack straight off the bat and then the other problem is that the time between attacks
and Rick changed to try to fix a bug.
We're going to revert that back to the time between attacks that we had before.
As the default for our players are now he attacks a couple of times and the enemy is dead.
But if I move around he's still trying to chase me.
He's still trying to attack me.
If he could.
So that is not good either.
We're going to have to both those are gonna have to change and then there's some other things that gonna
have to change when we're dead.
So what we've got here is a quandary about how should we do our dependencies.
Because we've got control we've got combat we've got movement or potentially want to know when we're
dead and want to change their state when we are dead.
Which way round should these dependencies be what's your gut feel.
Tell me what you think maybe positively and have a little think.
So the way round I'm recommending is that we have control depend on health combat depend on health movement
depend on health so there's a lot of dependencies this way.
But the alternative would be for health to depend on control combat and movement which is going to get
problematic.
The reason being that health is going to have basically have to depend on a whole load of named spaces.
If we ever want to add any more things that depend on health it's gains you're gonna have to go into
the health file and modify that just generally not the best way to have things depend if we do it this
way round then everything has to depend on health it makes health have to be a more stable dependency
we can't go changing its interface all the time because it might mean we'll have to change lots of different
classes but this way round is a little bit better and to me makes sense health is a very fundamental
concept to our game and as such it probably doesn't belong in combat.
We don't want all these things depending on the combat namespace in order to do their job probably better
is that health goes in core.
So that's what we're doing going to move it over to the core folder over and Visual Studio code.
In fact actually movement is probably best done in the Unity project review just because that's going
to move the matter files as well on the file system.
So just a little bit less cleanup for unity to have to do so in the combat folder I'm going to move
it over from health is going to be moved over into the core folder of scripts and I just need to make
sure you can see that the TAB stays open in Visual Studio code when I've moved something.
So just be wary of that.
You need to close that tab and open it again in order to get the new location of the health component
otherwise if you save you're going to be writing back to the old location and that can cause you some
weird bugs.
Okay.
So now we have got a health component in core where no not in core because we haven't changed the namespace
so let's change the namespace over to core and then is there anything that's currently referencing.
I think there is because I just went or went read here the combat Target for example was depending on
it being in combat.
So I'm going to be using instead the RPG Doc core namespace in the combat target.
And I can have the required required component of type health.
The fighter does the fighter require a health.
I think it does.
Yes it does require health but I think we already had a dependency on core.
So that's all.
Okay so quickly before your challenge.
One exception to the rule of the health everything depending on health is.
I think health needs to know about the action schedule.
So I think what it needs to do is try when it dies to cancel any currently running action.
So actually this is pretty straightforward.
We can just do a start action of null and that's going to cancel the running action because of the logic
in here you can think it through.
Pause video if you're not entirely convinced about that but I think that's a bit messy.
So just in case that is that behavior change at some point I'm gonna create a new public void.
Cancel current action like so and it's not going to take any parameters and we're just going to internally
make that call to start action no.
Which will do the same thing but it just means that if we change anything about how this start action
works we can then change the body of cancel current action and that's all against all work.
So then in health what I want to do is get components of type action scheduler and we're going to call
on this cancel current action which I think makes sense right.
We are dying.
You set the trigger to die and you cancel the current action so that the anything that was running now
knows it should have stopped running and then going on from there we can stop further things from happening
by modifying our controllers so that they do not trigger anymore actions but we know that the current
action has stopped.
So that's gonna be your challenge to disable control.
So the A.I. shouldn't move when debt and the player shouldn't move either.
If you've got this canceling action stuff in place as well then this should be fairly straightforward
and we've done similar stuff to this before.
When checking if the player is dead or not so pause the video and have a go at this challenge.
Welcome back.
So we're gonna get to the AI control and this is pretty straightforward really.
We're going to add a reference cache reference to the health component is the first thing data in start
and we're gonna need a dependency on core which we don't currently have in the controller so we can
add that I did that with control plus and then the health we can check at the start of update.
So if at the start of update the health dot is dead.
It's true so our current player War II is dead then we're just gonna return out of update.
We're not gonna do anything.
An update and this logic is gonna be exactly the same over in the player controller.
We aren't going to do any recasting at all.
If the player is dead I am going to have to add in and start method in here to take a cache reference
of it.
So I'm going to start.
Health equals can get components.
Health and then we are going to have to have a variable to store that cache to reference at the top
of the file and we're going to need to include the namespace of core.
So that should do the trick.
Let's give it a go.
I'm going to go ahead and play in the game so it comes and beats me up.
I beat him up.
I go.
He's dead.
He no longer follows me round the map which is good.
Now let's see if they can kill me could give him a helping hand by setting my health down a little bit
low a go now I'm dead and I can't move around.
Now there's one more bonus thing that I just want to do here while we're dealing with this death stuff.
If I beat this coming up until he's dead you'll notice that if I try and run over his body I'm kind
of getting stopped by his nav mesh agent because if I select is now my agent is still active and preventing
me from moving.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go to the movies see a script and at the beginning of update I'm just
going to disable the nav mesh.
If the player is dead so the is enabled I think is what I need so nav mesh agent die enable because
that much agent is the component we can just disable the component entirely.
If our health component is dead so health let's take our reference here again.
I just skipped over that bit because you don't need to see me do that.
About a million times so it's enabled if not health dot is dead.
So that's I'm not doing any statements here because actually we want a boolean and what we've got here
is a boolean so we can just do a little Boolean operation every update that's gonna disable the nav
mesh agent as soon as our player is dead so let's see if that is going to work going to restart the
game and go and attack our enemy A.I. so attack attack attack and you can see that his capsule or his
nav mesh agent is now great out and I can walk straight through it.
Fantastic.
Hopefully now you've got a good idea of how you can disable things on death row nicely decoupled way
by making everything depend on the health component in the next lecture.
We are going to be learning about gizmos these little things and how to create our own so that we can
visualize the chase radius and we're going to be using it later on to visualise patrol paths as well.
Very useful tool so I'll see you in that lecture.