In this video we're gonna make sure we know how nav mesh works by looking at the different values that
we can change and setting up a little scenario where we implement a nav mesh obstacle.
We change our buildings to static.
We have some trees.
We have the player effortlessly figure out how to Pathfinder through the obstacles and up a slope to
get to the target.
So let's jump in and more deeply understand our nav mesh.
To start with a quick reminder that one of the best places to get information is the unity documentation
and I'm showing you here the advance nav mesh base settings which we'll be talking about a bit in this
video.
It's a great place to go to read if you have if I've said something that you haven't quite understood
or you want just more depth to what we're talking about.
This is the best place to go to for pretty much anything if you go into Google and search for unity
docs and then whatever it is you're interested in for example nav mesh obstacle.
We're going to be talking about in this video a little bit then unity docs unity manual nav mesh obstacle
find that there and then it gives you a whole bunch of information on that so obviously you can surf
around through here through the the navigation system within the unity manual but just such a rich rich
place to get information is in the unity docs and many lectures I will give you links to the topics
we've been talking about.
I'll give you the link to the unity Doc against the lecture.
Just something to have a look out for.
But pretty sure you know how to use google to search for yourself if you can't find a link for me.
Okay so let's have a look at our NAV mesh.
I'm going to click on my terrain and then navigation and you can see we've got the bits of blue we've
got jagged edges and we've got bits where the blue is not there.
So let's talk about that.
If you click on the bake button you can see a couple of values.
The agent radius which is literally how close or how far the nav mesh is to the obstacles in your world.
So if we make this really high but probably like that re bake then you can see the distance from our
obstacles is quite massive it makes this kind of odd little shape in the middle here.
I put it back down to just control undo if I put it to say point 1.
That's control Z not control undo There's no undo button if you click back on it's at point 1 then you
should see it's gonna take a little bit of time and then you can see when we can look at our building
it's really really close.
Which means that our player is probably gonna call it a little bit into the building so we want to have
something since we play around with it wait until you have your character actually complete so you can
see how fat your character is and how wide the arms are so it doesn't actually look like it's walking
through the building so it makes sense.
Okay.
Now why is it that these buildings have the nerve mesh correctly calculated but these buildings do not.
It's because these buildings have been flagged as static so click on Inspector click on the building
you can see up in the very top right corner of the Inspector there's a tick tick box against static
if you click on the little pull down next to the words static you can see these are the things that
can or cannot be static or you can turn on and off static so navigation static is the one we're interested
in but usually it's holistically everything's static or nothing static seeing like on nothing and then
none of these things will be static sorry.
Or you can click on everything and it's all static and things like lighting and what else we got in
here patching and reflection promos of these we don't even need to worry about at all but static means
it's not moving.
It means we just want it to be a static not moving blob in the world and that way the never net navigation
mesh will say well it's never going to move so I can bake it into the navigation mesh so these ones
here this building you can see that static is not clicked on so it's going to click on that.
That's one way to do it and then back to my navigation window click on bake and then you can see around
here we have our navigation mesh he's taking that into consideration and we can't walk in this bit just
in here.
Interesting little artifact on the top which I'll talk about in a moment.
Now if you wanna make sure that all of your objects are static click on all of the things that we need
to have static and don't don't I'm just hung now control while I click through these.
So I think all of my world assets then I can back on the inspector.
You can see how it's got next to static here it's it's got this little dash which means some things
are static and some are not to click that so it's a tick and now everything should be static back over
to navigation when we click on break all of these including the trees will have a appropriate navigation
mesh calculation been made to it.
Awesome.
And the other couple of things I wanted to show you in this video you can see over here on my mountain
that we have some navigation mesh and some not navigation mesh and that's changed by the slope.
So you see here the maximum slope.
And as I move this the little angle indicator he goes up and down have it really low.
It means that only very gentle slopes can be worked up so if I bake this all of this mountain you can't
walk up it because it's too steep for the player.
I couldn't possibly walk up that hill if you put it all the way up to maximum then you can nearly walk
up the side of a cliff.
So most of these particularly this one over here you can see it is now walkable despite the fact it's
pretty steep.
I put it back to 45 and then back again you can see part of that there is too steep for the player to
walk up you're going to advanced a couple of settings in here.
The voxel size is just going to show how detailed things are.
And you don't play around with it too much but basically the more voxel as per agent radios the more
fidelity the more finesse you had to so free.
It's currently set to a default.
If you click on the manual voxel size the higher the number here the less fidelity we have.
So if I put that to one you can see here it's now showing point five voxel per agent radius based on
that and it makes everything just a little bit more macro which is not too bad in a way I think it simplifies
it a lot.
It's it's saying here's a nice big smooth edge when we're having lots of little fiddly diddly bits but
if you want to have more and more fidelity like over here for instance now if we try to walk there the
player could not make that if I put my target over this side of the building and I put my player where
are you player put my player over here.
You can see when I click on play.
Hopefully it'll show up on the camera might have to click back to scene view.
Yep.
It's gonna go the whole way around the house because it can't get through this bit here.
But if I change my voxel size back to the point one or so that it was actually a point one 555 so point
1 7 7 7 I think it was looks pretty good.
And then click bake.
Now you can see that there is a path there because of the fidelity of our vessels per agent radius and
then the other important thing in here you can see we've got these weeds sort of on top of our buildings
that's because there's a flat part that the player could potentially walk on but you can see there's
no way to get up there and we don't want to have any sort of weird accidental clicking on the top of
the building and what's happening there is that it's saying that the the space is large enough for us
to have a region.
So the minimum region.
So the minimum region is smaller than whatever this region here is.
So if I put this up to 10 and bake we'll see how that goes.
Then it gets rid of that as saying whatever size this was was too small to have nav mesh on top of it
can they see some other areas like on the top of this hill over here house put up say 30 as the minimum
region back again then that is no longer there.
That was too small an area and generally if you've got a world that's mostly continuous then you're
not going to have any problems having a pretty high minimum region area but it'll cut out some of those
just little fiddly like if there a little bit of a spot in there that was okay and a little bit of a
spot in there it'll cut those out just kind of makes it a little bit cleaner.
So I gotta put this back to say 20 I think that's not too bad and then re bake.
Okay.
There's another thing that's really super interesting if you see my box just here it is currently when
we click on inspect it it's currently flagged as static.
But what if I wanted my box to move.
So what if I wanted to as the player walk through a trigger volume down here the box I don't know falls
off the roof and lands in the way of the player in the player then has to go random or the enemies have
to run around it.
So I'm going to click off static because it's no longer static.
If I was to rebate my nav may she could see that it wouldn't impact the nav mesh because it doesn't
think it's something that is is statically baked into the scene.
And if I go onto Mike Craig click on my quite add component and add a nav mesh obstacle.
This one's really cool nav mesh obstacle and click on the carve carve means that it will carve a chunk
out of the nav mesh.
I've clicked on carve and go back to navigation doing you have to click on bait.
You can see that as I move this around underneath the crate there's gonna be a gap in the nav mesh.
So this is an area that if I was to say you know what I want to have the crate there the play is going
to avoid that.
You know I'm going to have it here let's make it dramatic size this by having it even bigger so we can
see this effect as I move it around so I move it to there and then move my target all the way over to
here.
Click on Play this through this dynamically back into scene I get going around that way.
Now you can look which while you're trying to go see how the player is readjusting where it's trying
to get to.
As I move that nav mesh obstacle which is really fun and really cool.
Lots of great stuff that you can do that.
So speaking lots of great stuff let's create an interesting pass I want you to double the speed of your
player if you can remember how to do that create a path where the player walks around a static object
avoids another mesh obstacle that you've placed in its path you can move it around and manually if you
want to be sneaky to walk through a clump of trees to make sure that we've got the Fidelity right and
to walk up a hill to make sure that your slope setting is as you want it.
So just take a couple of minutes to play around with your sandbox to set that up and I'll see you back
here when you done OK.
Move our target over somewhere where we've just put on the navigation.
OK.
I do want to change the slope of that hill there.
I'll put it just here.
This is a good one.
See what happens if we've got those two little weed navigation bits here.
That one's obviously too steep and that's too steep as well.
Cool.
I could fiddle around my voxel size to get rid of those but I want to see how the play goes when we've
got a little bit of difficult situation for it.
He's so moved the house there go through the trees.
This is cool.
Another tree just there.
Maybe give the tree to make one more.
And remember always we need to go back to base click on bake again.
Great.
Now let's see.
Actually I'll change the camera.
Change the camera.
So find the camera.
Main camera.
Game Object align with view.
And I mentioned doubling our speed so I'm going to click on my player back a bit Inspector scroll down
to nav mesh.
Agent change the speed to seven you can make yours whatever you want.
I'm making mine seven.
Click on play.
You should walk through the trees.
Yep.
Around that box they're just out effortlessly through the trees and up the slope to the target that
we got.
So we've got our nav mesh.
I'm pretty happy with this.
We'll have to do some fine tuning when we have our enemies in there and when we have a whole bunch more
obstacles.
But for now I think we've gone through nav mesh enough it's time to get to the next type of functionality
where we can click and move our player.
So great work in this video and I'll see you again soon.