Hello and welcome in this lecture we're gonna be fixing our recasting logic so that it makes sure that
the available action to us is the one closest to us the component closest to us.
So if I hover over my enemy here you can see that is the attack action I see not the pickup action even
though there is a pickup right behind him.
And if I move my mouse just a little bit I can use the pickup.
But if in as it currently stands and again that is not the case as we'll see in just a second.
Let's dive in.
OK so here's a little problem for us now.
When we go ahead and hit play.
If we have got no objects aligned with each other everything is just fine.
But what happens for example if I take my pick up flower and I place that pickup flower in front of
the enemy such that their colliders get in each other's way.
Let's go and see this.
So the collider here for the pickup is just fine.
It's in front of the enemy.
And as I mouse over it I get the pickup as the thing that I would click on which seems just fine.
But what happens if I move this pickup behind the enemy instead.
So I then go over to the enemy and mouse over the enemy and oh it's wanting me to do the pickup.
Now the reason for this is that the pickup is the first thing that is returned in the right cast.
So if we go over to our player control of C.S. and it's just close down this side bar for now what you
will see is that our recast all is returning an array of hits and we are going to simply return with
the first recast bill that we are able to interact with.
Now in this case the right cast all is not returning things as you might expect by the order of depth
within the scene.
No instead is returning things based on some arbitrary order.
Now we don't actually know what that order is but I'm guessing it's something to do with the hierarchy.
But who knows in a different version of unity it might be completely different.
So what we wanted to hear is actually get a sorted list of recast hits instead of the default.
And we want them sorted by the distance.
So that's what we're going to do we're going to introduce a function that allows us to get that sorted
list and I'm going to call that function right cast all sorted.
So right cast all sorted now.
I don't actually need to take any arguments because we've got this get mouse Ray already on this current
object and the return type is going to be this list of hits of the recast hits.
So that'll be the return type and in the body.
For now I am just going to go ahead and return the result of doing this Ray cast all.
So it's going to return recast all like so and with Ray cast all sorted in place of the hits.
Now obviously this is not what we want to do what we want to do is take the result of these hits and
then sort them and then return that so that's what I have written out in pseudocode for us here get
all hits sought by distance and then return.
So how are we going to do that sought by distance.
Well there are about a million ways you could sort a an array in C sharp.
Now I think the simplest for us to use that uses the fewest new language features is this static function
here array dot sort which takes in two arrays one array is going to be the key by which it is comparing
the elements and the other array is going to be the actual items.
So how does that actually translate.
Well that means if you've got an array of recast hits the first item the first array is going to be
an array of keys which is going to be the distance because we're sorting by distance and then the second
array is going to be the recast hits themselves and it's going to rearrange that second array.
So when we're sorting by distance we're going to have to essentially first build the array of distances
and then we're going to have to sort the hits basically.
Okay.
So we've got a an outline let's do the first bit getting all the hits we've got this already it's essentially
what we've been returning up to this point.
So let's just pull it out into its own variable it's going to be a ray cast hit a ray that I'm going
to call hits and it's going to be got from that right cast.
So I can remove the comment.
Pretty straightforward don't need a comment for it.
Now sorting the distances first of all we need to build the array I need to basically build an array
that is exactly the same length as the length of the array of hits.
So what we want is a float array called distances which we are going to fill or create a new array containing
the right amount of space.
So it's going to be a float array of length hits dot length like so.
So that basically creates as a brand new Array.
That is the same length as I break past hits.
Now as for populating it that's going to be part of your challenge.
So I'm going to let leave that one there for you and remove some comments.
Now we're going to have to sort our hits now.
Again this is done using a ray dot sort like so.
And as you can see there are many many many overrides.
And the one we want is essentially the array of keys and arrays of items which is this one here.
So the key is first is going to be the distances and then the second one is the items which is going
to be the hits.
So again it's going to rearrange this second one based on the first one and you can see that has no
return value so it's actually rearranging the hits array in place.
So now the hits array should be in order so we can return it.
We can return hits like so so your challenge is to build up that distance array.
So for each element of the array we want to correspond between each element of the array and the distance.
So we'll have the 0 element of the hit array should be the or rather the other way round the zero earth
element of the distance array should be the distance of the 0 earth element in the hit array.
Similarly the fifth element of the distance race should be the distance of the fifth element in the
hits right.
That's how this sort function is expecting things.
That's how we have to build that distance right.
And then use a four rather than a for each loop just because it's gonna be easier to work with those
indices and make sure that the elements are actually corresponding pause the video and see if you can
achieve this.
OK.
Welcome back.
Hopefully you didn't get too stuck with that let me know how the difficulty of that challenge was.
So we're gonna have to build up this empty array at the moment we have created the new float to but
has no elements or values in it so let's do a for each loop to populate it.
So I'm going for a standard for loop here rather than a for each loop because I want to deal with the
indices directly so I can create that direct correspondence and modify both of the arrays essentially
well hit the distances right anyway.
Now the length of this array is we could choose either of the links because we've basically made them
to be exactly the same length.
And then what we're going to do is set the distances eye so the current element I to correspond with
the hits element I dot distance.
So the hit value has a distance to the right cast and the distance we're going to be putting it back
into the distance array which just means the sort function knows what value is supposed to be sorting
relative to.
So let's try that out go over in to unity now and see whether we have fixed our bug.
So let's go ahead and hit play and move our flower in front of and behind.
First of all we want to put it in front and check that it's still working as it should do when the flower
is in front.
So go back to the game view I hover over and sure enough the flower is blocking the guard.
And now if I move the flower behind the guard go back to the game view and hover over the guard you
can see that the guard is the first thing that's coming up because he is the closer of the two right
constables.
If I go away from the guards capsule I can still use that pickup.
But the first thing that's going to be the action available to me is the first thing in front of the
camera not things behind it and so on great stuff.
So in this lecture we've learnt a very useful and transferable skill of how we can sort an array of
certain objects based on some value within those objects or even some value that you calculate any of
how we've just figured out how we could sort those arrays which is a very useful skill not just for
recasting but generally everywhere loads of places and need to know how to sort.
Now there are certain places in the world that we cannot currently go well we do not really want to
be able to go to.
But at the moment we can get there.
So for example the river we can walk through the river.
We want to make certain areas off limits and not walkable in our level so that's gonna be the subject
of the next lecture.