So again in this video we're going to create ourselves a second weapon.
Technically it's not a weapon it's the unarmed weapon as a scripted object and we need to rearrange
our scripts a little bit so that we have all of our relevant tweaking and tuning variables on our scriptural
object so that we can be easily updating our data for our various weapons if we want to change the damage
on sword we can do it there if we want to change the damage for an unarmed hit we can do it on unarmed
range et cetera.
So let's jump in to get started.
Let's continue with our scripted object by bringing the other things from house fire a script over you
can see that we don't have the damage and the range.
I think it is let's look in our fighter script and say yeah we've got weapon range and weapon damage.
Want to have all of these within my weapon scripts so we've got all the weapon things in one place.
And I also need a way for my fighter script to still be calling and getting that information.
So still be accessing range and damage so let's start off with a challenge voice should be reasonably
straightforward where I want you to move range and damage to the weapon class from the fighter class
and also to create to public getter methods.
Just very simple methods that return the value of damage and return the value of range and then to update
update fighter don't see us to call those public methods in the right place.
So to make sure that we can still access range and damage from fighters so those who challenge champion
take that on I'll see you back here when you've given it your best shot OK.
First of all in fighter let's go and grab our weapon damage variable cut that out and then cut that
out too and then over to our weapon paste that in.
Cut that out.
You two seems to be what I say to my kids a lot of the time.
Stop fighting back ever in a fighter.
We find range cut that out then over two weapon and paste that in as well.
Now we need to make a couple of public get to methods pretty straightforward we have public and then
we're looking for a return type of what is weapon damage.
It's a float and we'll call this get damage parentheses curly braces and we will return in here.
Weapon damage easy peasy.
Now let's copy get damage because we're gonna make a very similar method for get range rename this from
get damaged to get range and from get a story from weapon damage to weapon range.
Okay.
Clean my spaces up a little bit save.
And then over into fighter we need to find where we were using those we should have some red squiggly
lines somewhere.
Okay.
Weapon damage.
And within range these are no longer variables from within this class.
So we need to be accessing weapon Dot.
Get what's his damage.
And then over and Burns's parentheses at the end and then weapon range you might get is in range method.
I will change this to weapon don't get range.
Mark I say that I'm pretty straight forward.
Hopefully that has been straightforward for you.
Back over into unity let's see what's going on.
When I click on play K you can see the sword has been updated.
We now have damage and range.
Let's run run run over.
There'll be a problem but that's cool.
Problems are things we can fix the problem is that our enemies aren't really really doing much anymore.
That's because we've broken them.
They have an unarmed but we're not really set up for an in a very clever way.
Hey while I'm here I'm just gonna change damage on sword.
All right tend to a bit more than it was and give ourselves a mechanism for creating an unarmed weapon
while an unarmed weapon is not really a weapon is it.
But we'll create a script rebel object so that we can change things like the damage and the if we do
wish to override the current default animations and the range and so on.
So new folder within our weapons folder create folder.
We'll call this an armed and unarmed right click Create weapons.
We've got our contextual make new weapon script table object.
This will be an armed an armed weapon damage.
We'll make this.
3 just to make sure it's a little bit different.
One is fine.
Weapon prefab.
We don't have a weapon prefab an animator overall.
We don't wanna override the animator but what we do want to do is to jump over into our weapon class
and just to make sure that when we instantiate and when we're doing our override that we're not getting
into trouble if we have any no situations.
So what I mean by that null situation is that the terminology right in if weapon prefab does not equal
now.
Then we want to instantiate I'm going gonna come back to weapon prefab in a moment not happy with that
naming it loops then we want to instantiate the weapon.
If we have a weapon is what we're saying.
If there is no weapon then don't go ahead and try to create a weapon.
Pretty easy just protecting against that.
No scenario.
Nelson area.
I think that might be better.
Okay if animator override does not equal now.
Same deal put out rack.
Now statement in our curly braces hey presto.
Okay.
With prefab I mentioned I'm not happy about that.
So let's rename this from weapon prefab to we'll just call this equipped prefab which is really what
we're saying here.
If you don't have a prefab equipped then don't try to instantiate that equipped prefab and it may be
a weapon or it might be something else.
Just trying to map out terminology so it's really clear we're talking about what you have equipped here.
K we'll save that and then a couple of things we'll need to tidy up.
We would need to find our player make sure that our player still has what the player needs to have on
the player does the player have a sword.
Yes the play does cool and then our enemies are going to give the enemies an unarmed weapon as we've
created here.
So let's go and find our enemy's enemy enemy.
I won't go into the enemy prefab and then over where we have weapon I will click on the selector This
is in the fighter scripts weapon we will provide that unharmed which is excellent and what we he will
also give it a hand transform because technically it's not a weapon but you still are punching with
your hand.
So if we want to have any hit effects we want to do that when we're punching so scroll down find right
hand and under right hand click on that backup to the enemy level.
And now I can drag the right hand into the hand transform.
There we go.
Exit back out of enemy just click that check that all that enemies do have that behavior.
Yes unarmed and right hand click on play now what we want to see when we run over there is the player
has the big old sword which the player doesn't.
We've broken something there.
Let's have a look and see what we've broken with the player's weapon.
I think it might be because of my rename over here of equipped prefab so we'll click on our swords scripted
all object fun sword in here yet you can see a quick prefab has disappeared so click my selector and
search for equip sword so equip sword goes into a quick prefab Yeah but a naming there I think.
Click on play make sure the player's got his sword.
Oh soon I'm going to have to implement the player's secret weapon.
I'll tell you about that when we get to it a little bit of suspense.
What's the secret weapon.
And they're punching as they should do and he's got his sword as he should do and it's just check that
the players damage health is going down whereas his health before he dies healthy is going down.
Yep it's going down as they punch him.
Excellent.
Okay so now we've got an unarmed weapon we could equip that the player as well if we wanted it contained
within our scripted object and we have gotten rid of our errors that we've had there before.
So thanks for your patience with patients with those errors.
I know it's taken a while.
Great stuff and I'll see you in the next video.