Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We aren't going to be doing something massively impressive but we aren't going to lay the foundations
for being able to transfer information between seen so if I walk through this gateway here you'll see
that there is a scene loaded message being printed and interestingly enough that scene loaded is being
printed from the portal which was a game object in the previous level not from this game object not
the game object in this level but one from the previous level.
So that's what we're going to be able to do get notifications of when we've finished loading a level
and keeping and game objects alive across that level load.
Let's dive in and find out how.
So at the moment we've got a way of going from Scene 1 to scene 2.
However we don't have a way of going back if I play at the moment in our sandbox to the corridor level
then I can try and go back this way the way I came in and nothing happens.
The reason for this is at the moment we do not have any kind of portal.
So let's go and find where our characters at.
Harry is and I am going to put a portal in here.
So I'm going to get a game core find my portal and drop the portal into the level and then reach scale
the collider so that it will catch everything and there we go.
So let's try this out.
So I need to hook up this portal needs to load.
Scene zero.
Let's go ahead and play and walk through it.
Sure enough it takes me to see in zero but not to the place where we went through.
Right.
We wanted to come out here where the gates are if I go through the gates I want it to take me back to
where I started which currently it isn't doing and of course not because we're just loading the scene
and our character is ending up where it ends up.
What we want to do is remember which portal we came from so that we can then say which portal we should
move our character to now to do that.
We need to know when the scene has finished loading and transfer some information into the new scene.
Now a really neat way of doing this is actually with Chi routines and asynchronous scene loading.
So what we can do is all in one method we can load a scene.
So I'm going to do this by creating a new car routine method here a private's returning AI in numerator
which I'm going to include the right namespace for and I'm going to call this scene or just transition
transitioning to the new scene basically.
And this is where we are going to put this scene load right in here.
And I forgot to include the right namespace which is using System collections.
And we've got this transition which is complaining not all code path return of value.
So that's because we aren't doing any yield returns inside our in numerator.
So for now I'm just going to put at the end of it a yield return null to get rid of that error and what
we want to do is when we enter the trigger we want to call start co routine with our transition code
routine.
So remember as of the last lecture you know that what this is doing is it's putting that Christina directory
and it will be running the code up until the yield return and then it will pause and let unity decide
when to carry on running this code routine.
So what we want to do is figure out when the scene is finished loading and to do this we can actually
just use a different function on scene manager.
So if I have a look at what's available to us if I start using the autocomplete I can look for loads
seen async operation and in here you can see that the return value is return value of async operation.
We can give it the same basic like the build indexes and load scene mode as we've done before.
And I think that is basically what we're going to do we're just gonna pass in the load index but we
want to find out when this is finished and it returns as async operation which actually if we just yield
return that is going to do what we want.
Basically it's going to say hey unity run up until this point and we load async the level then it's
going to return the async operation to unity and unity is gonna go.
Okay I know what to do that I I know what to do with that I need to call this code routine again when
the scene has finished loading.
So that's what we're going to end up with and what I want to do is just for this lecture I want to get
to the point where we are printing out scene load it like so.
So that's the only idea.
But there is something that is going to stop this from happening and that's the fact that as soon as
we load this new scene app portal game object the one which has the code team gets destroyed and so
does the code routine itself.
So this is the challenge to you to not destroy this portal unloading the new level.
Hopefully you already know how to do this you can Google around a little bit if you don't so keep the
portal around make sure that the print happens when you load the next level I should expect to see that
scene print happening in the console log and then make sure the portal is actually destroyed after the
print has happened.
So pause a video and have a go.
Okay.
So hopefully you can run this yourself and see that you're happy that this print statement is not working.
But if we do a don't destroy on load and we call it with at Target to be the game object.
So we don't destroy the portal game object at all at this point.
Then we can go ahead and yield return this.
And we're coating will still be around to print the scene load it afterwards and then just to be a good
citizen I'm going to destroy my portal and not leave it hanging around afterwards because well it could
be confusing for one thing your character could walk into it again and that would be really weird.
So we're going to go ahead and get rid of the object as soon as we've printed out.
Now don't destroy and load only works when your game object is at the root of the scene so it can't
be under any other game objects.
Now we will find a way of getting around this in later lectures but for now just make sure that your
portal is at the root of the scene.
So let's give this a go.
I would expect that if we walk through this portal we are going to get a log message on the other side.
So walk in.
Have a look at the console and sure enough the scene loaded was printed and it's not by a monarch behavior
that's any more in the hierarchy.
So to recap what we've got here is a code routine that runs between scenes.
Here is before the scene load here is after the scene load and allows us to transfer or lays the foundation
for us to transfer information into the new scene from our current portal which we'll use to reposition
the player.
Good stuff.
See you in the next lecture.