Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be making it so that when we change what's in our file and we go back
to our project and we load from the file we can actually print out the text value even though the file
contains binary we can convert it back into text so we're gonna learn about how to convert back to text
and how to read from files.
In this lecture let's dive in so before we go any further I would like to point out how error prone
it is to open a stream and have to remember to close it.
And it's even more error prone because any of the code in between opening the stream and closing it
could throw an exception.
For example if there is no way of converting this particular string into this particular encoding they
might throw an exception and that would circumvent the closing mechanism and the stream would not get
closed and we would get a leaked file handle which could potentially lead to problems.
So how do we avoid this.
Well C sharp has a system built in.
And if you use using by using keyword in this way not like the way we've usually used at the top of
the file but using then followed by round brackets around the statement you want to protect which in
this case is this file open and it needs to have the whole line the assignment in as well.
Because if you think about it if we tried to pull this file open out of here it would no longer be protected.
And then what happens is after this we can have this basically behave like an if statement or a full
loop and we can put the code we want to use the stream in here.
In fact you can see the streams no longer accessible outside of these using statements brackets and
the cool thing about this is that once you leave the using statement whether it's because you came naturally
to an end or you returned out of it if you did an early return in here for example at the beginning
it would also call close.
Basically anything you do to exit this using statement is going to call close on the file stream.
So we can't forget to do it.
It's just good habit.
Whenever you're using a resource like a file stream you do it inside a using like this so that we know
it will get cleared up.
It also makes it easier to check for correctness when you're coming back to read this later on.
Now what we can do for loading is very much the same as what we do for the opening a file stream the
file stream can be used for both reading and writing by the way.
So that means that there are methods on there to do reading as well.
Now I'm going to give you as a mini challenge to open this file for reading.
For that you might need to look at the documentation from last lecture on the file mode and what file
mode you might need to use.
OK.
So I'm going to go ahead and do this.
And basically it's almost an exact copy I'm going to use the using statement this time.
So we don't forget to close it the path we're going to copy that up from the saving as well and we can
use that in our print statement like so and what's our file mode.
We don't want to create the file we don't want be overwriting it.
We want to open and not open or create because we might be we don't want to be loading from an empty
file.
We only want to be loading for a file that already exists.
So I'm just going to use file mode open which unlike create is not going to overwrite the file but instead
will allow us to read what's already there and then we've got access to reading methods like this.
We could read one bite at a time like we did before.
Or alternatively we can do this read method which is a bit interesting looking this read method basically
takes a byte array in and an offset and count so it looks a lot like the right method we had about above
but this time what it's gonna do is it's going to write into this byte array so the byte array is what
is known as a buffer and a buffer is basically a piece of allocated memory memory that we have created
for something else to fill in and it's quite common when dealing with file operations so I'm going to
call this the byte buffer and we are going to create a new byte array and we need to think about how
long should this byte array be.
Now typically you would allocate the byte array to be a certain size a specific fixed constant size
and then you would iterate over the file in chunks and do whatever you need to do with it in chunks
because think about it a file could be multiple gigabytes in size and your memory might not be able
to fit all of it in.
Which is why we need to use buffers and write to it a little bit at a time and often we can use I enumerators
to lazily do operations on bits of this file but in our case our file is going to be small enough because
we've just writing small messages into it so we can just get the length of the whole file stream streamed
at length and that's going to tell us how many bytes are in the whole file and that's great.
That's a good start.
And that's going to be the size of our buffer which means that we can read into the buffer we can pass
in that buffer and we can tell it hey why don't you start at 0 start reading into it at the offset 0
at the beginning of the buffer basically and finish reading into it at its length which should be the
same as the land.
So buffer dot length like so now you'll notice that actually the Reid operation does return an integer
actually tells you how many bytes it successfully read in our case it should be exactly the same number
as this stream length and the buffer length because we're trying to read in the whole file.
But if you had given it a buffer with a smaller length then it might be the length of the buffer.
Or if there wasn't enough data left in the file it might be even less than that.
But this is all out of interest at this point because we are just going to be reading it all in one
go but it's just a justification of why the API looks like this.
And that's also why the right API looks like that because often we are reading using a buffer that we've
been reading from another file and writing out from that buffer into another file and so this is why
the API is tend to look like this.
And there are quite low levels so that's okay.
I just noticed that I cut the path variable from the Save method and we shouldn't have cut it.
So hopefully now we have got a buffer which is the right length that has read from the file but it is
in bytes and not a string.
So this is going to be your challenge to convert the bytes that we got back from the file into a string
so explore again that encoding UTF 8 API eyes and see what you could possibly use to convert the other
way.
And what is the print result.
So just take the string and print it out and that should be a good good start and you could even type
something else into the file and make sure that you're reading that back rather than just what you had
written into it at the beginning.
After all this is just a text file so you can open it up with a text editor and write into it.
Pause the video and have a go okay.
Welcome back.
So we are going to explore this API we've got encoding the DOT UTF 8 and we're going to do dots.
Now let's get bytes which we have already used but there is also a get string down here which takes
in some bytes.
There's a few overloads here one is a byte array perfect so I'm going to pass in the buffer as I buy
to write and what we get back should be a decoded string.
So we are going to go ahead and just print out the decoded string and see what we get.
And for testing purposes I'm going to change the text in here to Hello world like so.
And if I go over to our project and this time I'm going to hit load when it's reloaded I should see
that hello world is printed out and I just want to show that this is in deed what's coming from that
file if I hit lots of exclamation marks and hit load again it reloads the file and it loads the new
contents there off.
Okay great.
So we can write strings and read strings from files.
But in general our game data is not strings it is things like floats and vectors and so on and so forth.
And that's what we want to be saving into this file not strings.
How can we convert those into binary.
That is going to be the subject of the next lecture.
So I'll see you there.