Hello again in this video we're going to use one key game design metric so that we can figure out how
many hit points our player should have and our enemies should have and how much damage they should do
when they hit each other.
So let's jump in and get started.
Now we need to make a meaningful contest between the player and the enemies how do we do that we've
got some tuning values that we can play around with if you have a look at the player we've gone our
damage that the player is going to do we've also got our health.
So over 100 health and 5 damage we have similar numbers on our enemies.
Let's talk about some game design and the game design problem specifically how many hit points do we
give our player do we give our enemy do we give tougher enemies do we give weaker enemies.
And how much damage is dealt by the player and by enemies.
And here's the solution that I'm gonna use for this game design problem.
I'm gonna link my decisions back to one central metric that metric is hits to kill.
So in other words how many hits should it take to kill something.
And I link all of my tuning back to that.
In the future we're going to be making ourselves some nice big old spreadsheets.
But for now we just want to come up with one number that feels good.
And then once we've got that number we can modify it with simple formulas for things like what's the
player's current level so if I'm at level 1 What should my hit points be if I'm at level 2 what should
my hit points be.
Also taking into consideration the enemy's current level so I like to think of it.
If I'm at a particular level and the enemy is one level higher then how many hits should it take to
kill them then if they're two levels higher.
How many hits three levels and so on so we can come up with a mechanism for saying this is a tough enemy
because it takes for example 20 hits to kill or is this is an easy enemy because it takes just one hit
to kill and we can also take into consideration with our formula the bonuses for buffs.
In other words if you give yourself extra boosts or spells also for weapons and so on.
But as I mentioned or that spreadsheet goodness is gonna come later on in the course we just want to
get our moment feeling good.
So here's the process I recommend you go through first of all play your game and see how many hits feels
right for the player to kill the enemy.
That's what we gonna do right now in this step one.
So I've got my player.
It currently has or he currently has weapon damage of five.
I'm gonna put that to tend just to give it a nice even number.
Now if I want to run up and take let's see four hits to kill the enemy then how many hit points the
enemy need.
Or how much health IT needs.
40 so 40 points and 10 points each.
So it's going to take four hits to kill the enemy.
So I'm going to find out as grab my enemy bring it over he will have this fight on the breach so I don't
have to keep running in every time and have you guys watch me run all the way.
So we have 40 hit points on this particular enemy.
Health points I run up.
Okay.
He's come back to his patrol point that worked well Rick.
One two three four.
That felt okay for.
For punching for fists I mean if we haven't had a sword it might be different there's so many variables
that we're gonna be playing around with later on but for justice point of the moment how many hits to
punch someone to death for seems okay.
I'm going to go with for for the moment now.
The next step in the process is to play your game and see how many hits feels right for the enemy to
kill the player.
If I was to put the number of hits to kill the player at say 10.
Then after fighting two and a half enemies I'm going to be dead.
Do I want that in my moment though I want to create a moment where the player has to run the whole way
through the level and avoid fights.
Probably not.
So I think at this point I'm going to say I think around about 20 hits to kill the player.
I don't see how that goes.
Step three is to pick a starting health for our player and when I say starting health I mean just a
health.
Now while we're playing around with it while we're prototyping this could also be the health of your
plan at level 1.
But for now just pick a health level for me I'm going to go back into my character find the player and
give the player 200 health points.
If the enemies are also doing 10 points of damage to me then 200 means 20 hits.
He's going to kill me and then step four is to set enemy damage based upon how many hits it should take
to kill the player and then step 5 is to repeat steps 3 and 4 the health points for the enemy.
So how many health points should they have and the damage that the player does when the player hits
the enemy.
So I rush through those last couple of little bits because I didn't want to give you all of my solutions
in one go.
I want to give you a challenge to tune your combat determine your hits to kill and then set the health
points for the player and for the enemies and then to set the damage down and for bonus points you might
want to have a tougher enemy in there.
That's cool.
And then to play test and remember these numbers will change.
I'll absolutely change when we give the player a weapon it's all going to change when we change armor.
It's all going to change.
So for now it's just a starting point to get into the flow of how we can go out shooting this moment.
So it's a cool moment.
So jump in combat and I'll see you back here when you done okay.
Let's wrap up the last couple of BTR so weapon damage for the player 10 it's already done.
Health points 200 are already done.
I'm going to click on my enemy here and let us see.
Health points 40 yes and then damage dealt.
To put that up to 10 in the future I might make that different but it kind of seems logically okay.
They punch me for 10 I punch then them for 10.
That's okay.
Now I'm going apply some of these back to the prefab so I'm going to apply the fighter scripts yes apply
that to the enemy the health.
Apply that to the enemy as well not to the character.
Character because that would change the player.
But we're going to apply it to the enemy prefab and the enemy II controller.
Okay.
That's got to do with the chasing so I don't want to change that at the moment so that should have changed
if we just go click on our enemies they should all now have ten and forty ten and 40.
Okay cool.
It's going to put my enemy back where he belongs and I think I will create a slightly tougher enemy.
So I'm going to find just my first enemy duplicate that first enemy drag that enemy down the end here.
Okay just f to focus in swinging around a little bit.
Okay.
We haven't developed our system just yet for how we are naming our enemies who they are.
Are they soldiers is this big soldier.
For now I'm just doing it fast and loose where we'll take this one enemy.
I'll rename it in here.
But notice how I'm not creating another prefab variant just yet.
I'm just gonna say tough enemy and I'm going to change his color so go into Sinti materials let's see.
Just scrolling now is control and scroll wheel to scroll in and out zoom in and out here so texture
black.
There we go.
Just so he looks a different color.
So says I'm a slightly different enemy and how shall I make it a different enemy.
How did the kill or hurt the player more.
You know I'm going to give this guy just double the number of hip points 80 he points and same weapon
damage.
So if the player was just a blip but up the middle here he's probably not going to arrive with enough
hip points to kill the enemy which is cool that's kind of encouraging you to either find a better way
to hit them without them hitting you or to go around the track so save that up.
Let's just quickly check that works.
I'm going to run past my initial enemies.
Which side note.
That's something in our design that we need to make sure the player doesn't just run past everyone and
say I don't care who is going to run to the end of the level this guy's doing some wondering which I
don't want so I have to change that.
Okay.
Fighting fighting fighting.
All good and it feels like staying bit too long to kill that guy but all in all pretty good.
I've got a tough enemy.
I need you just change his patrol routes.
We'll do a little bit more on the patrol routes in the next video and tuning where the enemies are moving.
But for now we've got our hit points and our damage figured out.
Hopefully you had good success with yours and I'll see you again shortly.