Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're going to be positioning our character so that when he walks through a gate he
will be at the corresponding portal rather than the default spawn location.
So let's dive in and see how that's done.
So at the end of the last lecture we were able to print out scene loaded which meant that we know when
it is time to update our player's location but at present we are not able to do so.
So if I load up the transition scene and go through the portal we end up not in the correct location
in fact where is it that we want to end up.
We haven't really specified this.
If I have my character here.
That's obviously not the right choice.
We want him to have it somewhere near the portal but not actually inside the portal otherwise he'll
teleport straight back.
So we need to specify that location so I'm going to open up our portal prefab and I am going to create
a game object underneath this great big empty game object.
I'm going to call this the spawn point and the idea of the spawn point is that it's going to be separate
from the portal and not inside it so that we're not going to end up teleporting straight back so this
is our portal.
This is the portal spawn point.
Now it's hard to visualize at the moment the spawn point so I'm going to change the representation of
the game object you might not know you can do this but on the dropdown in the inspector next to this
little cube icon you can select a different type of icon you can select the capsule which tells you
that this is the spawn point.
I'm going to have this little diamond because it's just smaller and easier to see.
And then when I've got the portal selected you can see that I could move this diamond wherever I like.
Outside of that portal.
So that's going to create as a spawn points.
And I'm gonna go and find the portal in the level and we can see that it's spawn point is not correctly
located outside of where we want to be.
So I'm gonna move that spawn point forward a little bit and they'll go if we walk into this capsule
into this collider we will be transported but when we come back we'll be just outside of the collider.
So that we could walk back in if we wanted to or go on with the rest of the level.
So that's the idea and we're gonna have these spawn points I'm gonna have to update that spawn point
also in the other level.
So in seeing in just the sandbox scene and I go and find my portal zoom over to the portal.
We go and I've got to find the portals spawn point which is here get to move it out just in front of
the gates like so.
Okay so that's that's the idea.
Now we need to have a link to this in the script.
So we've call our portal script open here.
Just gonna close my sidebar down and what I'm gonna do is I'm adding another serialized field here which
is going to be of type transform and I'm just gonna call this the spawn point.
Like so obviously we're gonna have to set that over in our prefab.
So let's open up the portal prefab and I'm doing it directly on the prefab so don't forget to apply
any of this stuff and spawn point game object I can just drag into that transform.
So it's getting the transform component of that.
Game Object.
So when we move it in each scene it's going to be a different location.
So what we're going to want to do is instead of print scene loaded we are going to want to do two things.
Firstly we want to get hold of the other portal because when we enter the level we are a portal in that
level but there's also another portal in the level that's where we want to end up spawning too.
So for now I'm just going to create a empty function to do that and that's gonna be part of your challenge
to get that other portal.
And then we want to do is we want to update the player and we're going to be doing that with the result
of the other portal so we gonna use the other portal to update the player.
And again I'm going to generate an empty method for that.
So we'll update it from the other portal.
But you need to do some stuff to find the player and update it in the first place.
So that's the general crux of how this is going to work and I'm going to leave out to you in a chat
to move the player.
So you're going to find the portal that's the first method you going to fill out.
Remember that performance isn't too important.
We're doing this once when the scene loads not every frame.
So you might be able to use that to choose your methods for convenience rather than performance.
And don't forget that the current portal still exists.
So you don't want to return the current portal otherwise that's not going to work as it know going to
spawn in the right location and then you want to update the player.
So have a think about that.
How are you going to set the position and rotation from our portal.
Pause the video and have a go okay.
Welcome back.
So we're gonna give this a shot first of all getting the other portal.
Well I'm just going to do a find game objects or find objects of type in fact and we're going to want
to find them of type portal.
I'm doing this in the wrong method aren't I doing this in the update player I want to do this instead
in get other portal.
So this is going to return as a list of portals of which we can do a for each loop over.
So for each portal portal in portals and then how we're going to check where we are.
We don't want it to be this portal so I'm just gonna do a quick if portal equals this.
Then we're just going to continue.
Remember that just means we going to skip over the rest of the for loop and otherwise we are going to
return the current portal that is being examined because that is the other portal fairly straightforward.
And notice it's still giving me an error here because not all code pass return value as because if we
go through the hole for each loop and find no portals because there are no portals in the scene what
are we going to return.
Well I'm just going to return null because we couldn't find a portal now updating the player's location.
How are we going to achieve that.
Well first of all we need to get hold of the player and we've done this many times before.
We're going to call game object up find with Tag player and that's going to return as the game object
player.
Now we want to update this player's transform.
So I am going to do.
Player dot transform dot position is equal to the other portals dot spawn point dot position.
And similarly for rotation.
So just copy it over.
It's going to be the rotation.
So for both of these.
Okay let's give that a shot.
Head over into the editor hit play and see if we can spawn into the right location.
So I'm going to go through the portal and seen the sandbox scene that takes me here.
That could have been just right by accident.
Let's go back through.
Nope.
That wasn't right by accident.
Here I am at the right spawn point when I go through so I'm noticing that the rotation of the spawn
point isn't quite correct.
I'm facing in the wrong direction not facing towards the world so let's quickly correct that this spawn
point.
I think the Z is the forward axis so we want to turn it round so it looks a little bit more like that
and Z is now pointing forward if I hit play.
Let's try one more time.
Yep sure enough I come back through I'm facing down the path ready for action.
So Sam from the future here to give you a little bit of an update if your player is not updating correctly
for whatever reason.
Sometimes this can be because you have multiple terrains in a scene.
Then the reason for this is actually because we are updating our player transform directly but there
is also a nav mesh agent that is simultaneously trying to update the position and these two can sometimes
conflict and your character can end up in completely the wrong place.
So if this is happening to you there are two ways around it.
In both cases we're going to have to do a using Unity engine dot A.I. and then we are going to have
to use our players nav mesh agents so we can do play dot get component nav mesh agent and one way we
could do it.
Which is fairly simple is enabled equals false and then re enable the nav mesh agent just after you
have set the position and rotation.
That's one way another way which is a little bit nicer than doing this is just to tell the nav mesh
agent where you would like it to teleport to where you'd like it to warp to.
And there is a function called warp which does just this.
You give it the new position you want it to go to and it will automatically not conflict with the nav
mesh agent because you're telling it what to do.
So what we're going to do is warp to that position not set the position transform the rotation does
not conflict with the nav mesh agent so we can just go ahead and do something like that.
That's probably the simplest solution.
It's not going to be reflected in the future videos but if you go ahead and do this now then it's not
going to be a problem.
We do work around with the other solution later on though however.
So be aware of that.
Now of course this is all going to break down as soon as we have multiple portals in the level we're
heading to and that is going to be the case because in sandbox 2 less safe sandbox 1 and go over to
our portal and I'm going to create another portal over here between these two sets of gates and that's
in core just drag our portal and I'm going to re scale it and I'm going to move this spawn point and
finally just set the scene to load to be the scene index 0.
So what's gonna happen now is that when we come into this scene which is going to be the portal that
we actually get moved to so I'm going to go over into the original sandbox then back and you see that
it's kind of not even sure where it took me.
Now the reason for that is actually pretty odd and it's something to do with the nav mesh agent.
And basically if you try and reposition right at the beginning of the scene with the nav mesh agents
enabled sometimes it doesn't work.
So I'm going to have our player have his nav mesh agent disabled by default.
Now remember that the nav mesh agent is enabled in health when you are alive.
So in the first update our character is going to have his nav mesh agent enabled anyway.
So I'm gonna go ahead and hit play and now hopefully what we should be able to see is if I go through
to the main scene and then back to the corridor then I get positioned at this gate but not at the other
gate.
What if I wanted to be positioned at the other gate.
Well then we are going to have to have some way to identify these two gates and that's going to be the
subject of the next lecture.