Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be adding in a river and we're gonna be making it so that you can actually walk on that
river say as you can see if I hover over the river I get a little X cursor and there is no nav mesh
there and basically anywhere where there is no nav mesh I get a little X cursor saying I can't walk
that which makes sense if there isn't enough mesh.
So let's dive in and see how we can do that.
So as you can see here with the navigation switched on it and the navigation pane we have got nav mesh
down here in this valley where we can move to.
And that's not really what we want.
We don't want to be able to navigate through the lake.
We want that to be off limits.
So how do we do a lake that is actually off limits a piece of water or something that we can't pass
through.
Well the hint is with these buildings over here.
And so these buildings are in fact static I believe.
Yes they are.
And if you make anything static essentially punches a hole through the NAF mesh.
If it is not itself something that is walkable or the working conditions are that it would be higher
up.
So for example you might be able to walk over the top of this building but that doesn't really help
because you can't get up to the top of it because the slopes are too steep.
Now we want to do the same thing essentially at is to have the lake the water level down here.
Be not walkable.
So the way we're gonna do this is under the environment I'm going to create a new 3D object and create
a plane and the plane is going to be our water plane.
So let's see where that plane has got to.
I think it's quite small.
I'm going to double click on it.
Try and focus in and it's yes it's it's quite small indeed.
There we go.
That's our plane.
So we want to expand the size of that plane.
So having it selected I'm going to scale it up initially I'm going to scale up by 100 in x and z and
let's see if that does the trick.
And it seems way over large.
Okay.
So that's not what we want.
Let's see where the 10 is more like it's and then what we're gonna do is we're going to bring that plane
up until it intersects with our train and you can see that it starts to fill out those areas of land
that we have been digging down or Rick has dig dug down into to create our lake or our river.
So now I want to show you that if we make this static.
First of all then we go over to our navigation and we get to bake and we bake in the nav mesh you can
see obviously the nav mesh is trying to go over it by default.
That's because this particular piece of terrain has been marked as walkable.
We want to make it not walkable.
And then if we go and bake again.
So that was going over into the object tab you can make it not walkable from there.
If you've got the plane selected and if you bake now you can see the nav mesh avoids it it knows that
is impossible to walk over that piece of scenery.
So we're going to rename the plane to water.
And we're also going to give it some nice look because at the moment it is looking very plain haha.
So if we go to our asset pack there should be a water asset in here somewhere.
I'm just going to search for water.
And we have the water material from the polygon adventure pack.
So drop that on to the water object and you can see that it has this nice translucent effect.
So that's good enough for now.
But I want to show you that actually I can still I still get the cursor to move to that part of the
terrain even though I can actually walk.
You see the character tries to get as close as possible but can't actually make it there.
Now I want to give some performance that you can't walk onto water.
How can we disable movement to an area that doesn't have a nav mesh.
Well it's not actually that straightforward as you would hope because you can't recast to the nav mesh
directly but you can try to project a particular point onto that NAF mesh and try and find the closest
point that is on the navigation.
That's what we're going to attempt to do.
So what we're going to do is we'll have a look in our interact with movement of the player controller
script and currently what we've got is a method.
We're doing a rate cast and we're doing has hit in here and based off of that we are then able to say
okay if we've able to hit the ground then go ahead and try and move to that location.
I want to add in a bit more complexity here where essentially we're saying are we hitting the ground.
And that bit of ground is near some nav mesh so that we are essentially ruling out areas that don't
have a bit of nav mesh near them like this bit here like these steep slopes of the hills.
These are places we can't walk to because there is no NAF mesh.
So in order to do that I'm going to introduce a new function that's going to be private is running and
we calling it in this interact with movements.
It's going to return bool because it is going to be true or false depending on whether we are hitting
something that is near the nav mesh and I'm going to call it very much the same as our recast.
I'm going to call it right cast nav mesh and what I want to do here is as well as returning the ball.
I want to also return an out parameter that will give us the location that we should start moving to
it's going to find the location on the nav mesh rather than just the location that was hit.
So this is going to be an outer parameter we've used our parameters before here in the recast declaring
them is very much this almost the same as using them we have to use the out keyword and then you have
to type very much the same as you would have the type of return type or the type of a parameter in here.
So it's going to be a vector three basically and it is going to be the target.
I'm going to call it OK now.
Within any function that has a return value obviously you need to return something.
So we're going to return true.
Just for now and then we're going to fill this out as part of the challenge.
But you will notice that this gives us an error still.
It says Hey you've gotten our parameter that needs to be assigned to before you return.
So this is just a safety.
That C sharp is putting in place for us it's saying that essentially you've got two things that you're
trying to return out of this function one is a boolean and one is a vector three and you've forgotten
to update that to three.
So we do need to set the target to something we can just set it to any kind of new vector 3 and that
should do the trick.
So basically what we're saying is that Target is just a default vector three at the moment but we want
this to actually end up reflecting a position on the nav mesh which we can talk about in a second.
But let's think about how we're going to use this broadcast nav mesh.
The point is you're going to use it as if we're using it like this broadcast.
So I'm going to comment out the right cast and the recast hit at the moment and I'm going to replace
that with a bool and we're going to set the has hit from our right cast nav mesh like so.
And we're also gonna need to have this out parameter.
So let's declare a vector three cold target.
So and that's what we're going to pass in to our right cast nav mesh.
So it's going to be out target like so and then this target can be used instead of the hit points.
So we've just abstracted away all that detail that we had in doing the recasts.
Now we are recasting to the nth affirmation.
If we hit some point on the nav mesh then we are going to move to that point.
That's the idea.
So let's talk more about how we want our recast map mesh to actually work.
Well the first thing we're gonna do is just a straightforward recast and that's going to hit the the
terrain so to terrain so recast to the terrain and then the next thing we want to do is try and see
if there is a nav mesh point that isn't nearby.
So find nearest nav mesh point and then basically we only want to return true if we're able to find
that enough points
so return true if found.
So these are the basic steps that we're trying to go through app to aid us in this quest.
We have got the NAF mesh dot sample position sample position does exactly this second step to find the
nearest nav mesh point.
So what you do is you provide it with a position and it will try and find the nearest position and the
parameters you give it are essentially the maximum distance that it should try to find that position
over.
And also an area mask.
Now the area mask is a little bit on the confusing side but if you just go with the default that's given
here in the example nav mesh dots all areas then you'll be absolutely just fine.
And this configuration this is more of a configuration parameter that the max distance that you want
to be able to go.
And as you can see it also has an out parameter so it's very much like the recast nav mesh and a recast
method in that it simply returns a boolean but it also gives us more information in that NAF mesh hit
out parameter and as you can see we click on that nav mesh hit our parameter.
We have got stuff like the distance to the points the hit the position that we hit on the nav mesh as
well which is going to be useful for setting the target.
So here's the challenge for you to disable when we are not on the nav mesh so implement the pseudocode
that I've outlined there.
Move over the recasting code that we've commented out because you're gonna need that in the first half
of the pseudocode.
If that fails then the whole method needs to fail so return early and try to use the sample position
for the second step.
See if you can figure it out from the API how you can get the closest position on the nav mesh using
that API.
And if it succeeds then you want to be returning the target and that should basically by filling out
that method help you.
And basically allow it to disable when we're not hovering over the nav mesh.
Pause the video and a go okay.
Welcome back.
Hopefully those instructions helped you through.
Let's give it a shot.
First thing I'm going to take there's commented out code and replace the first comments with it because
that's essentially what it's doing.
It's taking that recast.
Now if we have not hit if not has hit then this is where we want to return.
Nice and early basically saying false hate.
We did not get any sort of useful information here.
Now notice even if we return false.
We need to set the target of the OUTFRONT.
So I'm just gonna use that default vector 3 to set it right up at the top.
Next step is our second comment to find the sample point in the meat really here in the challenge.
So the nav mesh dots sample position we're going to have to do on these and nav mesh.
We might need to include something we might need to include a unity engine A.I. hopefully you've figured
that out nav mesh dot sample position and we're gonna take the source position which is going to be
our hit dot point and we're going to have to pass an output round which is gonna be a type nav mesh
hit.
So let's create a nav mesh hit to fill here.
I'm going to call this the nav mesh hits to distinguish it from the hit that we had above.
We're gonna pass that in as an output ounces prefix it with the out keyword and then we wants to configure
it with a max distance.
So I'm going to go ahead and create that as a configuration parameter to our player controller.
So it's going to have a serialized field.
It's going to be a float and I'm going to call it the max nav mesh projection distance.
That's a very long one.
Watch that default be I'm going to go with about one F as defaults lead and then we're going to use
that in our sample NAF mash.
Down here on line one hundred and 111.
And then finally that area mask as I said let's just use NAF mash dot or areas by default.
Nice and easy.
And then we have got a return value from here.
So it's going to return a boolean.
So let's store that boolean and it's gonna be let's think the result is essentially going and tell us
whether it has cast to NAV mesh nicely was it close enough.
Now we're getting a really long line so I'm just going to try and split things out a little bit like
so to keep things all visible on the screen at same time.
And then I'm gonna do it.
If not has cast now finish then we need to return False again.
Basically we still have not got a valid point here we should not be displaying the pointer to be able
to move here because we are not able to find any nav mesh near the point that was hit by the cursor.
So okay that's fine.
So we're turning false in this case.
Otherwise we're returning true but we need to make sure we remember to update our target so that we
move to the right location and the target can be updated by using the nav mesh hit dot position that
gives us the position on the nav mesh that we have cast too.
So let's go over into unity and see whether this is doing the trick.
So I'm just gonna make sure I have my scene saved just because I don't want to forget to committed to
version control later.
And as you can see when I hover over our little river here you can see I get that little X cursor saying
no you can't move here because there's no nav mesh nearby.
Now I start to move closer to the nav mesh edges and sure enough it is projecting to that now mesh it's
cast into the NAB mesh and it is giving me a point on the nav mesh that I want to move to.
They go it's give me a point on the map to move to try and move these trees.
Well they're okay because that that one meter of leeway is allowing us just to move near the trees.
But we really want to avoid is being able to click on a hill here and having the player not at all know
where they're going to end up.
So that was quite an action packed lecture and what we have found out how to do is how to sample positions
on a NAF match.
We get one position and we try and find the closest position on that nav mesh and that's enabled us
to disable the cursor reference for movement when we're not actually hovering over any nav mesh.
Now he's a little weird piece of funniness.
If I go and click on this tiny piece of nav mesh up here at the top right.
What kind of routes are going to take me on.
You don't really know.
It's a long route and so it is a little bit odd and unsure as to where it's going to take us in this
case it was trying to send us in this sort of direction but if I had clicked on there it might have
taken us all round the houses all the way around here.
We want to avoid that and that's going to be the subject of the next lecture.
So we'll see you.