Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be getting a rudimentary saving system in place so that if I hit save he has saved to
a save file and there some incomprehensible binary gobbledygook in our save file but I then move away
from that location.
I can actually reload the save file and boom it takes me back to where I saved.
Fantastic.
How are we going to do that.
Let's dive in and see.
So how do we actually store something useful for a change rather than all these strings about hello
world.
Well we want to be able to serialize something for example like our player position.
Now I use the word serialized there and that's just a fancy way of saying I want to take the representation
of some state and turn it in to binary which is basically what we're doing here with this string.
You could say that we are serialize in this string into binary and then going backwards we are DC realizing
the string.
Now we can do that with many data types we want to serialize for example floats and ints and vectors
and in fact whole things like the player movement and the health state and all those kind of things.
All of that we want to serialize.
So how are we going to do that.
Well I'm going to create a couple of private methods in here.
One of them is going to be to serialize the vector so we're going to return a byte array and we'll call
it serialize vector Mike.
So and obviously it's going to take a vector three as its input have just something called that vector.
So whatever the vector is it's going to serialize it and then we're gonna do some stuff in there to
return a byte array and we want the inverse of that which is going to be decentralized which will take
a vector 3 and decentralize it a decentralized vector and it is going to take a bite array as its argument
and we'll just call this the buffer as we have called it before so how are we going to implement this.
And what's the point.
Well the point is that here when we are saving to the file we are going to use our serialize vector
method.
Let me show you how.
Instead of trying to serialize this string which is pretty useless let's go ahead and get the transform
of the player.
So I'm going to have a transform variable in here called the player transform and how we going to get
that well I'm just going to do a get player transform and create that method.
So again can generate the method and where's it gone.
It's gone up here when I move it down below our public stuff at the very least.
And then we can do a game object find with Tag and we know how to do this now the player and we're going
to get the players transform and that's what we're going to return OK So whoops I start to close that
file.
There we go.
Control shifty reopens it by the way.
So that's got to play a transform.
And then we want to somehow serialize that into an array of bytes.
So we're going to have a bite array.
So I'm going to call the buffer and we're going to assign from that the serialize or two that we're
going to assign a serialize vector.
And it's going to take in the player transform dot position like so.
So that gets us the data which were then going to right into the file.
I'm just replacing out where I had bytes with buffer.
So we're writing the buffer out into the file which is going to write out the vector which means on
the other end you can then read it out and that's going to be part of the challenge for you.
But how do we actually do this serialization.
Well we can use the methods in bits converter so bit convert a dot and then you can use a few methods
in here.
One of them is the get bytes method and that allows us to take in various overloads of primitive types.
So you can use boolean chars doubles shorts ints floats and longs and stuff like that.
Basically all these primitive types they can take in and turn them in to a set of bytes for you into
a byte array and that's what we're going to be doing for our vector.
So we can take our vector and split it up into the state that actually contains the X Y and Z and that's
going to return as a byte array here like so now we want to put all these byte arrays together.
So the way I'm going to do that going to cause I'm going to have more than one go have a bite array
for X Y and Z and the way I'm going to do that is by introducing a byte a right at the top which I am
going to call the vector bytes and it is just going to be an empty one new byte array and we are going
to make.
How big how big should it be.
Well let's think about.
There are three floats that need to fit inside this byte right.
So it's three times however big a float is in bytes.
How many bytes does a float take up.
Well you could google it but generally speaking is four bytes.
So that should give us enough space to store our floats in.
And then once we've got this vector bytes we need to copy in the byte array that we've got back from
our converter.
So I'm going to do the get that and do a copy too.
And then you can paste in the array that you want to copy it to and the index you wanted to start copying
at.
So the first one we're going to put an index 0.
So at the 0 bytes it's going to start writing in and then the next one where are we going to put that
little challenge for you have to think about where is that going to go well if each float is for long
then we want to start at four because that will be after the vector x and then we can do another one.
So what you gonna end up with is a chunk of vectors basically of four bytes each.
We're gonna get a total of 12 bytes over all filled with float information so we've got three floats
in those eight 12 bytes.
And so at the end of this state I am going to return the vector bytes to complete our sterilization
effort to go the other way is quite similar this time we have to read in our bytes.
So we're going to do a bit converter and see what we've got.
We've got big converter and we can do a two.
Now it doesn't have a to float but it does have a two single that is a single as opposed to a double.
And that's what we want.
So a two single.
And it takes in notice it takes in the byte array and a start index.
So this is perfect.
What we can do is pass in the buffer and we can say hey the first one that comes back from index 0 is
going to read in 4 bytes of a single or a float and then that's going to return the float value.
So we need to create a vector we want to store.
So I'm going to have a vector three that's gonna be the result.
It's gonna be a new vector three like so.
And then this result we can say result dot X it should be equal to this first portion from position
zero.
Now I'd like you to just go ahead and fill out as a mini challenge the rest of this.
Function OK.
Welcome back.
So I am going to just pretty much do the same thing so why is going to come from the offset for as we
did over here and then Z is going to come from the offset eight makes it going from eight to twelve
in byte array and then we're going to return the result of the vector three the new vector 3 that we
d serialized from our buffer.
So your challenge is to restore the player position.
Now we've saved it already in our save function.
So what you need to do is update your load function to get that player position from the save file and
then make the player go to that safe location.
So now what should happen is if you walk around the world and save and then move to a different location
when you load your player should jump back to location at which you saved it so suppose video and see
if you can get this to work.
Welcome back.
So we're going to start off with updating our load function which is basically what we're doing at this
challenge so instead of doing this string conversion from the buffer we know the buffer now contains
a vector rather than a string.
It should do anyway.
So what we're going to do is we are going to D.C. realize the buffer instead into the vector and basically
in one fell swoop we're going to assign it to the player transform so I'm going to grab the player transform
using the function we've handled created and then I'm going to set the player transform dot position
to be equal to the D serialized vector and we are going to pass in the buffer as the input.
And we should get the vector coming out that we have built using our bit converter.
So hopefully let's see that if that works go ahead and hit play over and the editor and I'm going to
run over to a location that wasn't our start location and hit save.
Now I want to show you that the save file has now been updated with stuff that is incomprehensible because
they are bytes that aren't part of the unicode encoding or if they are part of the unicode encoding
they don't really make any sense because they are just floating point numbers they are locations in
space that aren't getting rendered properly.
So we are then going to move away from that location that we saved.
And if I hit load bam I go back to location I saved.
Obviously it's also remembered where I wanted to move to from the before the load.
But that's okay.
We're definitely getting the saved location of the file if I can save again you can see that it's overwritten
it and now that new save location is where I will load back to no matter what I do.
So we've got the rudiments of a very very basic saving system here.
And the Points of all that was to really take you over and give you an understanding of what serialization
and d serialization is all about now in practice.
We wouldn't go around doing this for every single one of our classes manipulating byte arrays and using
bit converters were all the basic types.
Now there are better ways and more automatic ways of doing this in C shop and that's what we're going
to learn about in the next lecture.
So I'll see you there.