Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We're going to be learning how we can discard parts that are just too long.
So for example I'm up here on the Hill.
I wanted to go down into the valley.
You can see that even though I'm hovering over a nav mesh I can't actually move to that tract of marriage
because the path to get there is too far.
Basically saying try and tell me which path you want to go down.
I'm not going to do all the work for you.
This is consistent with games like Diablo that don't let you try and come down from a very obscure location
into a valley and let the nav mesh do all the work for you.
The player has to remember the way down to the Valley it's more fun that way is more manual.
We're also going to look at how we can make certain portions of the nav mesh that are basically unreachable
also not react to having the cursor over them.
So here we've got a nav mesh on top of a building.
But seeing as I can actually walk there there's no point me showing the walking cursor so I don't let's
dive in and see how that's done.
So the end of the last lecture I gave you pretty rubbish example of the kind of routes we don't want
to take.
Imagine we are here on Long this river bank and what I want to do is get over to the other side of the
river bank.
Now it's not completely obvious what route I'm going to take and I'm going to get back on myself and
I'm going to go round here in these situations in the game really what we want to do is have the player
decide the route by going and taking us there.
If you play a game like Diablo won't let you do big round about loops like this.
So what we have to do is exclude certain lengths of routes because what happens if I click here is it.
It's kind of go and take me a very long way round because the nav mesh can find the way you can see
the way there.
And in fact I shouldn't have taken me there because of this gate.
So let's remove the gate or have the gate there but actually have it blocking the way.
I think the reason the gate wasn't blocking away is because it wasn't set to static.
So if we set it to static and then bake you can see it cuts off that little bit of the route.
And now the situation is even worse.
So if I go and stand by the edge of the river and then I click on this bit of river over here it's going
to take me I might have thought that there was a route there but there isn't because of the gate.
So it's going to take me right through all the enemies probably in the process getting me killed nearly
get me killed as I get to this particular little patch of land.
So what we want to do is exclude routes of more than a certain length.
Now to do that we have to query the nav mesh for the path that is calculating for a particular point.
Now the bit of documentation for this is under nav mesh dots calculate path the way it works is as follows.
You give it a source position and a target position and it's in return calculates a path.
Now I know this is a bit weird because essentially what we've got here is a path that is an outer parameter
but it's not labeled as an outer parameter.
The reason being is a little bit complicated.
If you want to look into this for yourself the reason is that the nav mesh path is actually a reference
type rather than a value type it's essentially a class rather than a struct.
So it is actually points the same thing and the method can modify it's a bit ugly and I don't like this
way of doing things but it is one possible valid way.
So anyway the point is that what you do is you create a nav mesh path and then you pass it into calculate
path which then modifies it.
Again we have that area mask thing which we can treat as before and calculate path is going to return
a boolean.
So it is going to be saying whether or not it has managed to calculate a path or not.
And in fact here it says true if either a complete or partial path is found.
Now we don't want partial paths.
So we are going to have to find out a way of discarding those.
But let's dive in to our code and see where we want this in the first place.
So we'll do this in the player control where we are right casting to the nav mesh because what we want
to do is basically avoid certain things we want to avoid certain positions from being returned here.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to add in another condition just after we have checked for sampling
the position on the nav mesh we have this position that we could move to.
But now what we want to do is essentially work out whether or not we want to use that position based
on the path that we have got.
So I'm going to keep the target as that position because we might want to use that later on.
So I'm just gonna put the code in between the target and the return and potential gonna return False
if the path is too long.
So we want to calculate the path so it's gonna be a nav mesh dot calculate path and we're gonna have
to take our current position.
So transform dot position we're going to calculate a path to the target position then we're going to
use the area mass like we've used before the nav mesh dot all areas and then we're going to have to
pass in a nav mesh path.
So let's create a nav mesh path.
Now unlike the other stuff so nav mesh path is what I want I'm going to call it path.
Now you might be tempted because it's an out prance just to pass it in like this.
I believe it's going to give you an issue here it's going to say use of unassigned local variable path.
So saying hey you haven't assigned it and actually we do need to assign this.
It's just a different way of doing out parameters which in my opinion as I said is not as nice.
So we have to do a new nav mesh path like so.
And for those few interested basically a reference type in C sharp can be no in the sense that it is
sometimes not actually an object at that location whereas something like a struct which is not a reference
type it is a value type can never be known.
It always has some default value.
So if you create a NAF mesh hit there is always a nav mesh hit.
There can never be null it has a default value.
If I create enough their path however that could be set to null and that's the difference here.
Basically I want to give it a value it needs to give it an object so the calculate path can modify that
object and that's what's going on.
So here what we can do is take a boolean and it's going to be has path basically and if we do not have
a path.
If not has path then indeed we are going to do what we've done all the time before here and do a return
false.
But there is another situation in which we might return false.
And this is if the path that has been calculated so it's going to be path dot status here.
Path dot status has a few potential values as we can see here.
It's a nav mesh.
Path status which I believe is an enum.
Yes.
And it could be complete.
Could be partial or it could be invalid.
The only case we are interested in is if there is a complete path to this.
So we want a nav mesh.
Path status dot path complete based that's what we want it to be equal to and if it is not equal to
a complete path then again we return false.
So if not a complete path then return false and we're not going to use the result of this recast and
we're not going to be able to move to this location if we can't make a path to it which makes sense.
So now what's going to happen is if you've got two bits of NAV mesh that are completely separated from
each other and that there is no way between these two bits of nav mesh then you are not going to see
the cursor to be able to move to that nav mesh which is basically what we want that where would you
be seeing this.
It might seem like an odd thing to be suggesting but for example here on top of these buildings we've
got a little bit of nav mesh because hey if my player was on top of there he could walk around it but
there is no way from this nav mesh onto the top of the building so we shouldn't show a cursor that says
that you can move to the top of the building even though there's an avalanche there and this bit of
code just here achieves that.
So the final test we want here is to see whether the length of this path is too long.
Now there's not actually a method for calculating the length of this path.
You have to basically make your own which is kind of funny I find.
So the way we're gonna do this is I'm gonna write a get path length method and we're going to pass in
the path and we're going to say if this is greater than the max nav path length which I'm also going
to define then we're going to return false.
Now let's first of all create that variable that's gonna be yet another configuration variable on our
player controller and we're going to do a serialized field again it's gonna be a float Max path length.
And through experimentation I've found that 40 is a good value in my game.
In your game might be different depending on how far out your camera is and what you feel is right.
But you can obviously tweak that as Eat to your heart's content.
And finally what I want to do is create this get path length to generate the method.
Indeed it has correctly intuited that it should return a float and that we're going to look at how we
might want to implement this get path length.
So to understand how we can calculate this length we actually need to understand a little bit better
how a path is stored.
What is that path.
So if I go ahead and hit I might need to actually return something from the path length.
So initially I am going to return in a really short path to zero so that we're always a correct path
if we go ahead and hit play now.
Then what I would expect is I want to see actually is how that path looks I'm going to select our player
so we can see his nav mesh element and I'm going to click off in that really distant location over here
if I get bit closer.
That would go and then I'm gonna pause OK and we can have a look at his path elements in the scene.
So what you've got here is it's calculating a path in a straight line segments.
So it's saying move from here to here.
Then there's a corner then it is going in another straight lines to hear where there is another corner
and it's trying to take the shortest route through these corners then it gets a corner here and now
it's not quite calculated to the end but presumably it would draw another corner to here and then a
corner to this target location at the end.
So this is actually what unity stores in its NAV mesh patter.
We have a look at the nav mesh path where is that.
Here's the nav mesh path you can see that it has this corner's property in the nav mesh path and it's
a read only property if you have a look at it.
It is basically just a list of vector 3s.
So you've basically got a list of all these points along the path.
So what you have to do is find the distance between each of these individual points and then some of
them together and you have got yourself the path length.
I know it's a bit involved.
Why didn't unity provide a method for that.
I don't know but they didn't.
So it gives us a little bit of an opportunity to flex our muscles.
It is a bit more of an advanced challenge so if you don't feel like you're able to do that something
of the path corners then don't worry.
Just watch me do it instead.
But for those of you who are feeling like a challenge and want to see if you can whip out your for loop
skills and total up the total length of all those different corners then give it a shot.
Now KAYE Welcome back.
So what I'm going to do is I'm gonna to start with an accumulator variable which is going to be our
float total and it's going to start off at zero.
The accumulator is going to be what we actually return here at the end and something we have to first
of all cancel I basically consider is the case where we have got a path that it's got fewer than two
corners which is not very useful.
So if the path dot corners dot length is a less than two well we can't calculate the distance between
anything that is less than two so we're just gonna go ahead and return the total which is zero at this
point.
Now on the other hand we might want to do a full loop over all the bits between the corners now because
we are always going to be comparing two corners in the array.
I'm going to do a for loop which includes the index rather than a for each loop so that we can be comparing
two elements from the array at the same time to find the distance between them.
Now as it happens we don't want to go up to the full length of the corners that length because if we
were to go up to the full length we are going to basically over run because we want the gaps between
them.
Imagine if you are looking at a fence post for example and you are trying to count the gaps you're always
going to have one less gap than you have the fence posts themselves.
So now what we're going to do is try and calculate the distance first of all so float distance here
between these two points is going to be a vector three dot distance and it calculates the distance between
two different variables.
So we're going to calculate the distance between the path dot corners of eye and the path dot corners
of eye plus one.
Now is eye plus one safe.
You can have a little think about this do you think that's safe to do.
I plus 1 I think it is because what we're going to do.
I've actually talked about it but didn't actually do it is that we're going the eyes only going up to
the length minus one in fact one less than the length minus one which means that we should always be
safe to do this.
I plus one here because we're always going to one less and that's part of the reason why at the beginning
we did that check to see whether the length is less than two in which case this wouldn't this loop basically
wouldn't work.
So we have got the distance and with that distance we basically want to sum to the total.
So actually I think it's going to be easier if I just do total plus equals that distance and I think
that should be it.
If you want to try and tweak your distances then I do recommend at this point to put it in a print statement
of your total I'm not going to do that because I've already tweaked my distance I know that 40 is a
good one for me and we should go ahead and try it out now.
So if I go ahead and hit play and I want to see that basically I can't try and navigate across the river
as I was doing there.
So it's basically giving me an X when I'm trying to navigate too far here I can navigate too because
that's quite close.
Here is already too far so I can't get there and you can see that basically if I try and navigate up
hills and things like this then that's also not going to work.
If I try and navigate across the river from up here the top of the hill you can see it's all basically
got the little cross saying I can't move there because it's just too far and it can't really see the
route there that we the player might want to take.
So it's been quite an in-depth lecture we've seen a few things we've seen how to calculate or force
the nav mesh to calculate a path between two points and also how that path is constructed so that we
can calculate the path length I'll see you in the next lecture.