Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we aren't going to be adding two things.
One is automatic checkpoint thing when we go through a gate.
So as I go through this gate and out the other side I have automatically saved in this location in the
new level.
And this becomes obvious when I stop playing and start playing.
You will see the other thing that we're gonna add which is loading up the last level that we were in.
So it's automatic.
Even though as in sandbox one it's automatically loaded up sandbox to because that is the last level
that was saved.
That's what we're going to figure out how to do in this lecture.
Let's dive in and see how so in order to be able to load the last scene we need to know a little bit
more of a piece of the API to the saving system namely this function here the load last seen function
which seems to be exactly what we need.
Now it takes again the save file and its job is to load the last saved scene and then load the state
in that scene.
So it does both loading the scene and loading the state into that scene and it returns an iron numerator
in exactly the same way as loading an async scene takes time.
Well loading the last scene.
Does does that as part of its job.
So it takes time as well so we have to run it as a numerator.
So the way we're going to do this is we're gonna call this in start and we're going to call this in
start from the saving ramp up.
So let's have a go in our saving wrapper.
We are going to introduce a start method.
Now one thing you may not have known about Start methods is that actually they can be or they can return
I in numerator.
And if you do this essentially start becomes its own code routine which is automatically started in
start kind of makes sense doesn't it.
So the iron numerator is what we need and what we can then do is with AG Get component saving system
we can call to the new API that we know about which is the load last seen.
So dot load last seen and we want to load from the defaults save file so figure out what was the last
scene that was saved into that save file and then we want to go ahead and yield return the result remember
that in an iron numerator you can yield return another iron numerator and that basically waits for that
co routine.
So what we're going to end up doing here is on start it's immediately going to try and load up the last
scene and basically wait until that's done and obviously will end up in a new scene.
So let's go over into unity and give this a shot.
So I'm going to hit play and let's see where it loads up.
I actually loaded us up in two scene two but then you saw that the last place that we were in scene
2 was actually at the exit portal because we saved just as we were exiting.
And that meant that we then got portal through into scene 1 which is all a bit confusing and a bit wrong.
That's not really how it should work now.
The way I would like it to work is that I go over into scene two and at this point I've loaded into
a new world use this as a checkpoint.
It saves here so that if I exit the game and come back to the game again it's going to reload me here
rather than going through reloading me into scene one then back in Scene 2 through the fact that I'm
going through a portal change et cetera.
No.
It should just come straight to this point.
So for that we're going to have to make a modification to our portal class and just have a think about
it it's a mini challenge really for you to pause video and have a go and think where abouts are you
going to call an extra save in the seat this sequence of events in order for us to load directly into
that level and have checkpoints after we've gone through the portal pause video and have a go okay.
So hopefully you saw the behavior that we wanted from the beginning of the video and have been able
to replicate it.
If not then let's talk it through.
Basically what we want to have happened is we have loaded up the data so perhaps the health from our
player and then we are getting the other portal and updating the position of the player as well.
At that point is where we can then do a save before we fade in but we've got the position of the player
that we want to keep track of.
And we've got all the other data from the load so we can go ahead and save again right after we have
loaded up the player.
It sounds a little bit wasteful and counter-intuitive but it's all right.
It's a good way of doing this I think is to checkpoint at this point.
Once we have loaded up and gone through the portal.
So if we do that let's see how that actually goes and looks.
So first things first I'm gonna go and play it's going to be a bit weird and funky this time around
but we've gone through here gone through the portal it should have done a checkpoint thing save at this
point.
So if I quit and open up this time I should go straight into sandbox 2 as we do.
Fantastic and it loads me up and in the right place basically where I left it.
Now we did see in that instance that it was a bit jarring it all happened very quickly and suddenly.
So what I would like to add to this is that in our saving wrapper after we have done our start and we
have done our load last scene I would like to add in a fade in basically so that we always start with
a fading.
And it hides any of that jarring jumping about from the initial scene load.
Now the way I'm going to do this is I'm going to go to the fader and create a new method in The Fader
that allows us to instantly switch the fader to faded out.
So then we can fade in.
So I'm gonna create a new public void because it does need to return a thing called fade out immediate
and it doesn't need to take any parameters.
OK.
Now in the body of Fader immediate all we have to do is set our canvas group Alpha equal to 1.
So it's not going to be transparent.
It's not gonna be visible through that alpha then using fade out immediate.
We can go over to our saving wrapper the first thing I'm gonna do in start is get a reference to the
theta so that we've got something to work with.
So we'll get the fader doing a find object of type as we've done in the porthole.
Again this isn't happening very often it's only happening the first time we start the game and then
using the fader we're going to instantly fade out so the fade out immediate so that it's all opaque
and then we're going to load up the last scene.
It's gonna be that twang that we saw as the camera adjusted and we're fighting in so we're gonna do
a yield return Fader top fading and we need a time for that so I'm going to make that a civilized field
configuration variable.
It's gonna be a float called the fade in time and I'm gonna set that to a very small point to a second
and that's going to be what goes into our fade in.
So let's see that in action.
So if we exit the game we should be loading back into our sandbox to when I hit play yes indeed we did
and it faded in as well.
So you gonna adjust the fade in time to your liking to try and cover up the camera trying.
I think it's better now.
I don't want to put too much fading in either cause is going to annoy me as I prototype but now you
can see that if I go back in sandbox one and hit play it's going to have remembered that the last scene
I was in was sandbox one and it remembered my position and everything.
And hopefully if I killed guards they'll remember that too they go we got that God who's still dead.
So it's remembering all the state automatically for me.
So I don't need to remember to hit save and hit load.
I can use that for debugging purposes now but automatically when I go between levels it has check point
in my progress and put it in the save file so when I come back I'm gonna go back to the last level I
was in great stuff.
So in this lecture we have seen how we can automatically load and save on check points and also load
up the last scene we were in and that basically wraps it up for the saving system.
So hopefully now you are confident with using that saving asset pack you can try bringing into any other
games that you have that you want to implement saving and it should be generic enough to use in anything.