In this video we're going to add a an actual mesh for our player.
We're going to add a blend tree.
We're going to set it up so that we can preview what happens when our character is walking.
When our character is running so let's jump in and get started on some asset packs for us to download
first of all so if you want to find against this lecture there's two asset bags zipped up and so download
those and unzip them into a folder of your choice.
One is the animations unarmed walk and run and the other is the polygon student sample Cindy studios
two point one.
So what I'll do is unzip those and first of all drag the animations over into my project and then you
need to click import.
Excellent as that comes in that's pretty quick.
And then the other one is the polygon pack so drag that over on top of assets as well and import all
of those.
Now this the second pack is an expansion or it's more assets from the existing assets that we have already.
So it should go nice and neatly into the same folder the Sinti polygon student sample pack.
I want to take a moment just to talk to you about what these assets are and where they came from.
There's a replay that shows the usage rights and it says this has been provided by Sinti studios and
I'm going to show you some details on them in just a second.
And you can use these for non-commercial use.
So you're not allowed to sell these assets and you're not allowed to put them into a game.
There's efficient finished game that is selling for money but you can put them into your student project
and you can share it with your friends and you can use it to improve your skills and obviously go through
this course with us if you want to use them in a finished project then you need to go ahead and buy
the pack that they came from the packs that they came from from the provider.
And that is Sinti studios they're awesome.
They've helped us out a bunch in the past and they're really good folks are love supporting them.
Here's some of their assets I'm using if you so I give you this link to their Facebook page in the resources
against this lecture.
And also I'll give you a link to the asset store where you can find in the unity assets store the place
of all greatness I love the asset store where you can find all of this city studio assets I'm using
the polygon assets and there's tons and tons of different packs and if you're making a professional
game I think these assets look really slick and they're a pretty good investment I reckon.
And from time to time we get cool deals and discounts from these guys.
So if we do I'll have them as a link in the resources against this lecture as well.
So hopefully you've downloaded now the assets and installed them or imported them into our project.
Excellent.
Let's go ahead and use them.
You can see a couple of things first.
I've got some new layers.
This was from when we created our terrain there floating around a little bit I'm just going to rename
this new layer as green grass just so I'm not confused in the future and I'm drag it down into my terrain
textures I think also in our prefabs folder which is the one we're interested in in this new asset pack
the Sinti polygon student sample pack you can see prefabs I've got a bunch more we've got a couple of
characters and drop them in the scene just so we can have a look at them there's a cool one there's
a cool one and I was saying before I've got a couple of these new layers that was from when we created
the terrain textures earlier on yours might not be in here I don't know why mine ended up in this folder
but I'm gonna go ahead and rename them to something sensible and to drag them into the terrain textures
folder grass layer and drag that over into terrain textures and the final one which is what's that kind
of like dirt like dirt layer OK.
They weren't in the.
The asset pack they just happened to be saved in there for some reason.
OK.
So what I've done I've grab my two characters I'm gonna choose this character on the left which is the
night or two I think he's looking pretty nifty and we need to go ahead and instead of having our egg
head driving around we're going to have our character.
So it's delete my character and the scene.
Okay ready for action.
So go ahead and find your player.
He's a play here for us.
First thing I'll do is reset the transform the place a right click reset just so I know that all the
values are at 0 0 there's no wackiness going on double click on player in your hierarchy that'll zoom
you straight to it.
Now get a phone from my Sinti prefabs folder I'm going to grab character night soldier 0 2 you can use
0 1 0 0 2 dragon on top of player which will child that to the player so the player is parent and the
character with the mesh.
In other words the geometry of how it looks and its materials is now the child can go ahead and get
rid of the egg and so by clicking on player will find the capsule right click on capsule remove component.
I'm also going to remove the capsule collider if we need a collider we'll put one on in the future but
right click remove component and then we have the nerve mesh agent.
If I'm clicked on that you'll see it's also kind of underground.
That's because our base of set was changed because of the capsule so click says one and change that
to zero.
Now it's at the right height I want to make it a little bit skinnier so the radius I'm going to change
to point three just so it hugs where the players outline is.
Cool stuff I'm going to click on player and I want to update the prefab for the player so up in the
top right you'll see the overrides button click on that and I'm going to apply all which means all of
the changes I just made to the night into the capsule collider etc are now part of the play a prefab
so you can see that the night remains a prefab and the player is a prefab and this is code nested prefab
so prefabs within prefab and it's something that Sam and I are going to go into a lot more detail later
on in particular when we're making changes to prefabs within prefab.
So for now let's just apply the changes to our player and keep moving on with our basic movement.
But rest assured we are going to spend a lot of time exploring nested prefabs in upcoming videos.
Okay.
What next.
Well we need to make our player walk and run and move around general locomotion.
So I'm going to show you a couple of pieces of terminology.
This will be a reminder for some of you it'll be a new introduction for others of you if you're new
to unity.
So what we need to do is add an animated component which assigns animations to game objects through
an animator controller.
We'll talk about animator controller in a moment but just a reminder that when you have any game object
these things that we attach to the game object are components and components give behavior to our game
object.
So we have a transform component.
We have a mesh renderer component I'm just clicking on them.
That's why they're opening and closing.
We have a nav mesh agent component and we're going to add another component right now which is an inmate
or I can click on the animator that's now added an animator component and you can see the very top line
is controller and is looking for a runtime animated controller.
What is that.
Well an animated controller is an arrangement of animations and transitions so a transition is going
from one state to another and we can think of this as a state machine.
I'll show you that in just a moment.
We also need to be implementing animations.
We downloaded a couple of animations in that asset pack that I just showed you and gave to you and they
are specific pieces of motion.
Obviously that's what animation is and we're gonna be implementing a blend tree y a blend free well
that allows us to have multiple animations and for them to be blended together smoothly so we can blend
from Idol which is just kind of standing around and wobbling a bit on the spot through to walk through
to run based upon a value that we use to say how fast the play is going so if the player is currently
at at zero then there'll be an idol if the play is currently at five they'll be running.
So let's implement all of these things we've just been talking about.
We have our animator.
We need an animated controller so within our assets directory over here I'm going to right click Create
folder and characters ruin the surprise by already having it in there didn't I.
Okay.
Of our characters folder double click on that in here and going to right click Create an animator controller
halfway down the middle.
And this I will call character character and we're gonna use his character animator controller.
The thing that drives the animations for probably for the player and for the enemies and for the NPC
is because there's a lot of commonality everyone needs to walk and move and and run for example.
So we've got a couple of windows that you might not have yet.
We give ourselves a bit more space.
Go to window and animation and find animator and then move it wherever you like I've got mine down in
the bottom here.
Just a reminder if I haven't told you this already to move you hold a tab.
You can move it and snap at different parts of the screen.
I'm guessing you already know that already.
And we also need our animator window so window animation animation I might be in a slightly different
spot unit he likes to update.
This is updated recently in the version I'm using so it is loaded with me saying hang on I mean it was
that window that used to be just there.
So animation takes over animator and animation and you get the same set up as may make sure you clicked
on the parameters tab not the latest tab and in the animator you can see you've already got a couple
of states that don't really do much or me much at the moment.
Entry just means this is the very start when this game object and when this animator comes to life we
we are starting off this entry point and going somewhere in the moment is no effort to goes to so we're
going to right click and create state and we'll create from new blend tree.
So this is creating a blend tree and you can see here if we click on blend free we have an opportunity
to rename this I'm gonna rename this locomotion.
Look everybody doing a brand new dance now locomotion that's an old song reference for those of you
who are old like me locomotion.
Okay.
Doesn't look very interesting just yet but if we double click on locomotion we go inside to the blend
free where we can add some cool stuff.
So when I click on blend free can see I've got this preview tab window it might be down the bottom few
it snaps down they can drag it up a little bit.
Currently there's nothing going on that's because we don't have any motions we can click our button
here and add a motion field now it's gonna go through on your show you all this but I want you to go
all the way of discovery how to do this yourself.
So here's a challenge for this video to add our motion fields so add three motion fields and I just
showed you here you can click on the plus button add motion fields so add three of them and then using
the selector button that's the little circle with the dot in the middle.
Add an idol a walk and a run to these fields and then the preview window click Place.
This is a preview window that I'm showing you just here before and then slide the blend value seating
and find the blend value to see what happens within our preview window.
Okay.
So it's a pretty simple one in terms of there's not a lot of coding there's no coding.
It's pretty straightforward but just a little bit of finding where things are in the interface because
having you do it instead of following along directly with me.
So get it to a point where you have a character that has three states that you can blend between by
sliding the slider up and down.
OK.
Hopefully you did that challenge I know is a little bit of a different one to the sort of challenges
we do usually but let's go through it together so you can see what I did adding one adding two and adding
three motion fields click on the selector.
And these are the three animations we downloaded from our asset pack.
If you don't have these make sure you download the asset pack that I've given you and add Idol and then
selector again add walk and then for the third motion click on the selector and I'm going to add humanoid
run.
So I have my window here and I click on play at the moment not much is going on just standing there
idling.
Just a note up in the top right.
You can change the speed with which the preview happens you can make it really slow.
That's just changing the preview of the animations and drag this up to once that's playing at the proper
speed.
And I'm found my slider just here on the blend as I drag this up.
He's moving from from Idol to walk to run if you want to see what's going on up at the top here we've
got the blend where one animation is decreasing and the other one's increasing.
So this point right in between.
So it's going to be eight point seventy five which is halfway between the walk and the run.
He's doing a blended walk run.
So this is taking the animations and blending them together which means we're not pumping we're not
just walk walk walk and then all of a sudden pop into run and then pop back to walk walk walk and then
popping into run this blend allows it feel a lot more organic which is really cool means you create
three animations that you get this massive variety this organic feeling to the playoffs.
Okay.
So that's it.
That's that's what I want to show you in this video in terms of setting up a blend tree stunning our
animation characters not going to do anything yet if you're going to click play is going to be a little
bit broken because we haven't hooked up this relationship in code to say when the player is at zero
speed and when the player is at a greater speed.
That's what we'll need to do in upcoming video.
So great work and I'll see you again shortly.