Hello and welcome in the next handful of videos we are going to be looking at how to add damage text
that spawns above our player's head when we take damage or above the enemy.
So if I go and attack this enemy you can see that we've got damage coming up fading off kind of vapid
writing off the enemies and it is coming up and spawning and always facing towards the camera.
Now in this lecture we're going to figure out how we can create text like that in game UI that faces
towards the camera at all times.
Let's dive in so we want to get some health text over the top of the player's head.
So how we're going to do this we're gonna go open up our character prefab and we are going to start
off with adding in some text why.
And we're gonna do this by right clicking on the character going that's the you I objects and selecting
just a text object.
Now you could do this with text message probe.
I don't want to complicate things more than they need to be.
Now one thing we're going to change right off the bat is this canvas is currently in screen space overlay.
That means that if we go ahead and hit play is going to show over the top of the screen as you can see
here this new text is showing right in the middle it's a little bit faint maybe we will change the color
over to Red a nice kind of vibrant red like this just what we're probably gonna want to use anyway.
Let's go ahead and hit play and they go.
You can see it's hovering over right over the top.
In fact it's quite a few copies of it are hovering here because one is there for each character.
Now what I want to do with this text is make it into world space so that it follows the characters around.
We do this on the canvas itself.
So get to the cameras find the camera's component the render mode.
We want to switch over to world space like so.
Now if we go ahead and hit play it's going to be completely out of whack.
The scale is not ready there if we show gizmos you can't even see it it's just really hard to see and
you might be see and seemed I'm not going to fart around what we're going to try and do instead is bring
this into line because basically what's going on when you do world space is suddenly these width units
are height units they're all in meters which is obviously huge.
So let's bring this down to one meter by one meter.
Now let's try and get our text into that canvas so you can see it's going to be a bit of a stretch because
the text is getting pixilated already.
As I scroll in so we can fix this by looking at our Canvas Scaler and we want to change the dynamic
pixels per unit because if you increase this you can see the sharpness of the text goes up and that's
what we want to be doing and it can keep increasing increasing increasing and eventually it's going
to start scaling the text down.
And that's what we're going to want to do.
So let's give that a shot.
Let's see if we can get this down.
I think I found that about a thousand.
This seems to work and we want to position our text so that it is inside our canvas rectangle so let's
do that by changing the width of our text element.
And if we zoom in now you can see that we are in much more sensible territory.
It is not quite right still but it's much more sensible.
Now all we have to do is center that canvas.
So at the moment it's in an odd position that's central.
0 0 and have a look over in game if we go ahead and hit play then we should be seeing would expect to
be seeing some canvases at their feet.
Let's try bringing the canvas a little bit higher okay.
Now we've got the text hovering above their heads.
So that's the kind of thing that we want to have except that we want the text to turn towards the camera
rather than be turning around with the character.
So that's not quite right that particular aspect.
Also the text in there is going to be a number.
So perhaps you do 100 damage that would be a representative example and you can see didn't quite apply
to the prefab service save.
Also sent the text while we're at it and hit play and have a little walk around and you can see that
now we have got the text 100 floating above our characters had in fact all the characters heads.
Now obviously that's not all going to want.
Eventually we want this to turn towards the camera and we want it to only show up when we take damage.
But for now this will do.
So what I'm going to do is create a camera facing script over in in Corso script core and create a new
C sharp script called camera facing and this component is what we are going to use to rotate out our
text component our canvas so that I could give you a little mini challenge of your feeling confident
to go ahead and fill out the camera facing script so that it updates the position of that text about
the rotation particularly of that text so that it faces towards the camera.
If you feel able to do that it's a little bit of a tricky challenge.
And don't worry if you do it a different way and my way is better than to take my way if you do it a
different way and your way is just as good.
Then do it that way instead.
Now I'm going to go ahead and plough on.
So if you want to give a go at this challenge pause video.
Now OK.
Welcome back.
So I'm going to first of all stick this in a namespace.
So I wonder if you forgot to do that.
So it's gonna be RPG dot core and then paste that class back in.
And I don't need to start method all I need is update to update the rotation of the text every single
frame.
Now one way we can do this to update rotation is actually by setting a transform dot forward vector
so you can tell.
You can set the forward vector and at 10 essentially says this is the way that this particular object
should be facing.
So what way do we want it to be facing where we want it to be facing the same way as the camera.
So I can do the camera dot main so get in the main camera and then get it transform and Gates forward
vector as well.
So if we set our forward vector to the camera's forward vector the canvas is going to be facing the
same way as the camera at all times.
That's basically what we want.
So let's have a go and add this on to our canvas and then we'll make a prefab of this to clear things
up.
So going to add a component is going to be the camera facing script like so.
And if go ahead and hit play now what we should see is that all of those canvasses are facing towards
us like so.
So as I said the last thing I want to do is just clear up this canvas I'm going to change it in to giving
it a different name.
It's going to be the health the damage text like so and I'm going to make a prefab of it in to the game
folder and particularly under UI and I create a new folder in here for in-game UI.
So create folder in game and then inside that folder I'm going to just drag out damaged text as it is
and that's just going to the damage takes prefab that's just to clear things up we're gonna make modifications
to damage text prefab in that prefab and the character prefab might link into it might use it for other
things.
And in fact later on we all going to be spawning this damage text prefab from a damaged text spawner.
So it does make sense for us to put it in a prefab at this point.
So a word of warning to those of you who might be using a newer version of unity if you've created your
prefab and it's got this canvas environment as the root this kind of weird black Great out thing and
you cannot see your text that's the most important thing because we're gonna need to be animating it
in the next lecture if you cannot see your text then follow these steps.
We're going to go back to our character we've created our damage text prefab and just right click and
unpack the prefab completely.
I'm also going to go ahead and delete that prefab that we just created because we want to go ahead and
create one a new.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create just a empty game object that we will use as the basis
for creating a damage text I'm just gonna call it damage text and pull it over and then we can copy
this damage text in fact cut this prefab.
Well I think you might have to copy it go into the damaged text prefab and paste it in here and we can
then go back to find our character and remove the extra set of damaged text now you'll see that in this
prefab while you've got an extra parents in here you now have a canvas that should be working and you
should be able to see your text.
Cool stuff.
So in this lecture we have looked at how we can use a canvas act to turn and face towards our camera
as you can see here.
I've got our number 100 is facing towards the camera no matter where we are in the world or how our
player is rotated and we have made that into a prefab.
Now in the next lecture we're going to be looking at how we can animate it so that it floats off into
the distance and fades out.
We'll see that.