Hello again in this video and making a projectile fly at the player which is using a debug mechanism
of just dragging in and saying the target is the player and also just dropping a projectile in the world
we're not spawning it from the bow yet we'll do then in upcoming videos.
But now we can have an arrow bam shoot at the player and then do some weird wiggly things because it's
not not destroying itself yet and not decreasing health.
But this will be the start of our Arrow Functionality.
Let's jump in to get started.
Let's start first by grabbing our arrow asset that we can use for our project.
I've given you this as a download for this lecture grab simple arrow drag it on in.
That should be going to game dev TV assets import.
We can see simple arrow piece there get a simple arrow head on.
Doing well thanks Rick.
Okay first sign of insanity talking to yourself.
But we have our arrow that we can use for our creating our game object.
So I'm going to jump over into game scroll down a little bit here make myself a new folder.
So create folder for Jack tiles.
Now scene I'm going to make a new game object create empty we will call this arrow proof Jack dial.
Excellent dragged that down to make it a prefab into my projectiles folder open up the arrow projectile
and let's see where is the arrow we just brought in this the prefab the simple arrow prefab drag that
under arrow projectile and we have ourselves a simple arrow now it's pointing up in the air I think
I want out.
Well first of all let's learn our lesson by resetting the transform and I can see my senior fly zoom
in side note I'm going to change my camera in a minute when we get back into the scene but I want to
have my arrows starting lying down so do it at a minus 90 I think there were guys so just generally
laying flat in the scene Okay we have our projectile at scroll down to our scripts folder find combat
right click Create a new C sharp script I'll call this projectile excellent and then click on Arrow
projectile again drag over our projectile script so that since there is a component on the prefab good
looking pretty sharp now as the arrow in our scene welcome arrow I mentioned camera a second ago I haven't
been out to put my finger on it my friends but finally I have it's so hard to show you what's going
on with my character because we're so zoomed out so it might not be best when we finally play the game
but I'm going to turn my camera distance down to say it live and maybe even ten okay so that when I'm
demonstrating to you what's going on in the build and in the game while we're teaching you can actually
see it we don't have to squint at our screens to see that there is an arrow there after all.
I guess so how we gonna go about making our arrow move.
Well you might know the answer already but I'll just recap First of all we have two simple steps and
we need to do on each frame an update the first step is to make the projectile look at the target so
it's heading in the correct direction and then we move it in the forward direction so if its forward
is this way because it's pointing at the target in this case the player is going to move in that particular
direction each frame and this is going to be the structure of the challenge I have for you now that
we have our projectile scripts sitting on our projectile I would like for you to move the arrow projectile
so use transform don't look at to look at the target who is the target well you can make the target
whoever you like I suggest you make it the player for the moment and then to use transform dot translate
to move to the target and remember a couple of things here don't forget to use time not delta time so
that we have frame rate independent and to expose a variable so that we can tune the speed mostly for
our play testing so we can have the arrow going super slowly so that we can see that it actually works.
So that's your challenge.
Give it your best shot and I'll see you back here when you're done okay over into our projectile script.
Fire that up have a look at what's going on here I think I'm going to get rid of stocks I don't need
that but we will keep update and expose a couple of variables top serialize field and this I'm going
to make a target so the target needs a trance form and I'll just call this target we've done this a
few times read our code already know initialize that at now just so we know that there is none at the
start and the compiler doesn't get too cranky with us if we forget to put something in then we need
a second serialized field this will be for our speed of the projectile I'll make this a float and we'll
call it speed and we'll initialize that one now with an update we are going to do a couple of things
in here first of all I'm just gonna protect against null so that if we don't have a target we don't
get ourselves into a situation if Target equals equals no we simply return okay protect against now.
Now we want to say transform dot look at as I showed you in the challenge and we look at the target
dot position and second we are going to use the second thing I told you transform dot trends late and
here I'm going to use vector three dot forward and if you're not familiar with vector three dot forward
you can have a look at the Unity documentation for that essentially manipulate a game object's position
on the z axis of the transform in world space and move it forward on the z axis is the description that
we've got here for vector three forward and then I'm going to multiply that.
Remember this is per frame by speed and then multiply it per frame by time dot delta time okay.
How do you go with that did that challenge make sense maybe the vector three forward threw you a little
bit or maybe you did it in a slightly different way which is totally cool.
One of the important things is to get the job done and not get hung up on doing it exactly the way Sam
and I do.
If we do it slightly differently that is fine.
So let's see if this works.
Now jump back over into our game we've got our arrow projectile that I've dropped into the world.
It currently has no target.
So we've set the target to be player boink and speed of one should be nice and slow my camera zoomed
in so you should see me as I run around let's see if it actually chases me okay it's going backwards
for a start.
So that's something which is noteworthy we rotated it the wrong way but it's moving.
Let's go back into my prefab that I thought I so cleverly rotating but I was not very cleverly rotating
was I arrow projectile.
You can see from our vector three forward it was saying what in terms of the blue.
Let's see what in terms of the blue it's saying the blue axis of transforming world space so basically
we just got that back to front.
I had it correct on the right axis but pointing the wrong way.
So it's click on our simple arrow.
So instead of minus 90 we want to do that well probably plus 90.
Okay.
See how that goes.
Save this up back over into our game click on play we'll see which way our arrows pointing this time
okay.
It looks like it's pointing towards us success.
Once it's shot it's gonna go very fast out at us it's gonna look I think pretty good.
Just grab the arrow projectile move it away a little bit over there see what happens if we change the
speed to say we'll make it eight and then click on play just to make sure it's behaving like an arrow
should and bounce yes it does it shoots straight at us now it shooting straight at our feet Why is that.
Well if you click on the player click on the player and see that the players access here it's point
of interest it's pivot is at the feet.
So that is the transform information that's been given to our arrow it's looking at our feet.
So let's resolve that by saying we want you to look at where probably in the middle of the player you
know right in the chest.
So it's good kind of what's that critical mass.
No it's solid mass Central Mass Central Mass.
I think that's the terminology.
So I want to aim for the guts basically.
So how are we going to do that.
Jump back over into our script here and so you know update instead of target position let's return.
We need to get the position we're going for and get the location.
So I'll create a new method called get a location jump down below and create this would be private.
Now we need to return a vector three because we need a particular point in space that we're aiming at.
So to be evicted three and this will be called Get aim location.
What is in here.
First of all we want to use what.
To know how to attack a particular entity the player for example so the player I've clicked on here
already has a capsule collider and we know the capsule collider is most likely going to be the same
height as the player or the enemy or whatever entity it's on.
So we use the capsule collider we'll make ourselves a new variable which be a time capsule collider
that we'll call target track it target Capshaw.
I think that's built right and that's going to equal target don't get component which component we're
looking for.
It's the capsule Collider.
And then once we have that capsule collider we need to return our vector 3 so let's return the target
dot position and we're going to add to this.
We're going to add to this the high.
But I'm going to halve the height so be the height of the capsule collider divided by two so we get
in the middle here.
I easily have shorthand again use vector 3D Dot up and if you wanna know what vector three dot up is
I've given you a link to this as well.
It's just a shorthand way of saying vector 3 0 which is on the x 1 which is on the Y and 0 which is
on the Z.
So basically it's giving us an upwards of 1 a y value of 1.
We write it vector three up in shorthand and we multiply this by the target capsule dot height divided
by two.
So we want to get it roughly in the middle.
You can make a little bit higher a little bit lower if you wish.
So this is adding just on the y axis.
This is why we're placing a vector three so it's adding on the y axis.
We're not adding one we're adding whatever 1 times the capsule height is divided by two.
So let's just quickly look at this I know some people be asking I'm not exactly sure what's going on
here.
So we click on the player we see the height is one point seven nine.
We're getting half of that value because we're dividing it by two and we're adding that to the to the
y value of the targets vector three that we're interested in using as our aim location.
And lastly to make sure we don't have any issues if the target doesn't have a capsule collider let's
protect against that.
If targets capsule equals equals.
Now then we'll just return the position because we might not know the capsule Collider.
We don't want that to break the whole projectile or just return the target dock position as we did before.
If it does have a capsule collider then we're gonna return target opposition.
Plus this offset to increase it based upon the capsule colliders height.
Right now it's safe that jump back over into Unity have projectile here I'm just gonna turn the speed
of the projectile down again so we can see it in slow motion.
Make sure we know exactly what's going for it down to 3.
Click on play and we'll see where the arrow brb.
Bam right in the guts.
Okay.
Pretty happy with that.
It's not really intended to be a homing missile but you could make it that if that was your desire.
But we have a projectile that we can give to our archers so that I can shoot at us which will be doing
an upcoming videos actually launching our projectile blink so we can shoot at each other get great work
and I'll see you again soon.