Hello welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be creating waypoints as you can see here and we are going to be having ways to manipulate
said waypoints and be able to visualize them.
So let's dive in and see how we can visualize waypoints so we're gonna need waypoints which are effectively
just a set of points our transforms around the world so they don't necessarily have to be transforms
that's just an example but they you want a series of vectors you want to say first go to this points
then to this point then to this point then return back to the first points and so on.
So you end up with this loop of points.
Now one easy way to do this in unity is to create a parent object.
So I'm going to create an empty game object.
I'm going to call this one the patrol path and this is going to be the route of our patrol.
Then we can create a new empty sub.
Game Objects and this can be the first waypoint like so.
So we've got this waypoint and we can then take this waypoint and we can duplicate it and we can move
that point.
So what we're ending up with is waypoint here waypoint they're duplicated again and got another waypoint
here.
And this will work.
We can use this in our code to set up a waypoint system but the problem is that it's really hard to
visualize.
When you click on this patrol path you cannot see the waypoints that the character needs to be following.
So good but also not good enough.
So how can we make this a little bit better.
Well with a bit more gizmo visualization like we've already been doing.
So the idea is that you'd have points to visualize each of these different game objects and in between
them in the next lecture that will be dealing with this.
You would draw lines to show you that that's how they're connected because if you've got a group of
waypoints do you go from this one then that one then that one or which order do you do them.
So it's important to be able to see that from the device designer's perspective and you can always add
more waypoints to the path by just adding more empty game object by duplicating these waypoints.
So that is the idea let's start off by creating a new script in control and we're going to create a
C sharp script and this is going to be the patrol path script.
Now let's open it up in Visual Studio.
Code and I'm going to pop it in a namespace song and cut it out.
Create the namespace RPG.
We've already got one for control so just auto complete it and then paste that class back in.
So we do we need start do we need update.
Probably not.
Probably not at the moment.
All we need to be able to do in here is to draw the gizmos for these waypoints.
So we are going to need an on draw gizmos.
And at the moment do we want to do it when it's only when the path is selected.
Well probably not for right now just to make it easier for us to visualize the waypoints that are in
the world and then what do we need to do.
Well there's two possible approaches here.
You could have a script that we put on every single waypoint and each waypoint is responsible for visualizing
itself but that doesn't give you the full picture because it doesn't tell you about the relationships
between the waypoints and we do want to fundamentally know the relationship between the waypoints be
able to progress waypoints know which one is the fault next waypoint and so on so forth.
So having a script on patrol path itself is going to be the easier way in my opinion because then an
enemy can have a reference a patrol path and that automatically gives it the whole set of waypoints
and that's gonna be easier to manage.
So what we're gonna have to do in on draw gizmos is we're going to have to cycle through all the waypoints.
Now I'm going to do this in the typical kind of int for loop.
You may need to use the arrow keys to select a different entry here it might not be the first for you
it's kind of an order of most frequently used.
And if this menu ever disappears for you you can bring it up with controlled space.
There are two for loops as you probably know there is a for each loop which goes over every item in
the collection you can do this for iterating over all of your children in their child game objects.
But I am going to use the integer one because we are going to want to be able to reference the previous
waypoints as well as the current one in order to draw this line.
So I'm thinking ahead to the next lecture so we're going to do this for each loop.
What's the length going to be.
Well we can access the children and everything about children through the transform because the transform
is what manages this parenting hierarchy.
So the transform knows how many children it's got it knows how to access the children and so on and
so forth.
So if I do transform dot I think it's called child count.
That tells us how many children there are.
So now there's full loop is going to go from zero to the child count minus one.
So in our case it's gonna be 0 1 2.
And you can see there even numbered this way.
We've got a waypoint zero waypoint one waypoint to that kind of makes it easier for us automatically
and if we duplicate the waypoint one more time we've got waypoint 3 and the child count will be adjusted
accordingly.
Now if we want to get hold of a child in here I'm not quite going to tell you how to do that but the
hint is that you can do it from a function of transform dot so you can do transform dot and then have
a look through the options there have a look in the unity documentation to see what your options are.
So it's challenge time to draw the waypoint gizmos.
I'd like you to get the child transform and that's what I'm hinting at here how do you get hold of the
zero child the first child so on and so forth then draw a gizmo for each I'll leave that up to you you
can revise your knowledge of gizmos from the previous lecture and as a hint coming so if you want to
try this challenge without the hint pose a video now and here's the hints that transform dot get child
is what you want to get hold of to get hold of a child transform and you can see that there isn't going
to be an argument in here and I'll leave that to you to figure out what to put in that.
Okay so we're going to do gizmos dot draw and this time I'm going to draw a sphere and not a wide sphere
because they're going to be smaller so we're gonna draw a sphere what does that require requires us
to know what the center of the sphere is gonna be and that's gonna be the position of the child transform
so we're gonna transform dot get child as mentioned in the hint and the index is going to be eye from
the for loop so the zero.
First second third child and so on.
Then we need a vector so we're gonna get a position of this.
And then finally we need to know how what the radius of this sphere is going to be.
Now we don't like having magic numbers so I'm going to create a contest float up here which is going
to be the waypoint gizmo radius.
I'm gonna set this to point three f the moments and you could play around with that obviously see what
works for you.
Now let's see whether we've got some gizmos over in the world okay.
I'm seeing things they're a bit transparent because I think they are underground.
So what I'm gonna do is I can pull it up so there above the ground and we can see the gizmos.
That's great but I'm also going to create a prefab for this should I bother with a prefab.
Probably yes.
I think if we were to change this we don't want the same file to necessarily change.
So I'm gonna go over in two.
I think game characters and I can bring the patrol path in here as a prefab and if we have multiple
of these we can just drag in a patrol path over here and it's given us a starting point of a few waypoints
to go for.
That's the first patrol path.
Let's get the second one drag it down to the bottom here and then we are going to we can drag around
these waypoints separately which is going to create an override compared with the prefab parents.
But that's okay and they'll get it we've got ourselves some waypoints.
We've got some visualizations of these waypoints and we'll soon be able to get our enemy to follow them.
But before that I want to complete the visualization by putting these lines in and that's gonna be the
subject of the next lecture.