So next, we're going to talk about a service called AWS CloudTrail.
And according to AWS, CloudTrail is a service where you can log,
continuously monitor, and retain account activity related to
actions across your AWS infrastructure.
Now,
one of the great things about this is no matter which
interaction method you're using,
whether that's the console or whether you're using the CLI
or whether you're working within the SDKs, CloudTrail is
going to log all of those actions.
So when we look at CloudTrail,
first of all you need to know that it includes this information into
an S3 bucket, or you can even utilize CloudWatch,
which we'll talk about later within this module. And it logs events
in the regions in which they occur. Now one of the good things about
CloudTrail is that it meets many different compliance requirements
for infrastructure auditing.
So in terms of even just general best practices,
you want to know who is initiating actions that change your infrastructure.
But for some of you,
you might be in environments where that's not just a like to
have, that is a requirement based on different compliance
standards, and for many of those standards,
CloudTrail will meet that. Now as a best practice, it should be enabled on
every AWS account. Now if you have your own personal development account and
you're the only one that has access to it and you don't want to deal with the
cost of storing this information in S3, you could choose to forgo it.
But for any other situation besides that,
you want to be sure that this is turned on. And you can consolidate this.
So if you are using AWS Organizations,
you could utilize the organizational trail to get
information across all of your accounts.
Now, let's talk about some general use cases for using CloudTrail. First of all,
and we've alluded to this already, it might be a compliance requirement.
So if you want to be able to track information
specifically for compliance purposes, CloudTrail can meet that.
It could be that you're using this for forensic analysis.
So if you have already had a data breach and you want to go back and
see what actions were taken against infrastructure,
you could utilize it for that.
Also, you could use it for operational analysis.
So if you're looking to determine who potentially changed
infrastructure that caused a crash or caused an outage, you could go in
and analyze the users that perform that and then work with them to make
sure that that action isn't taken again.
You also can do it generally just for troubleshooting. So you could
go back and look at when a specific bad configuration was injected
into the system and use that to fix any issues that are happening within your infrastructure.