Hello everyone.
My name is David Tucker, and welcome to the course, Understanding AWS Core
Services. I'm a cloud consultant that helps organizations plan, build, and
implement custom software solutions in the cloud. I have over 15 years of
experience in software architecture and development,
and during that time, few things have fundamentally changed computing
like the cloud. AWS certifications add value for both technical and
nontechnical resources in today's digital world.
In this course,
I will walk you through the services from AWS that you will need to know
before you take the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner exam.
First,
I will review the ways that you interact with AWS services. And
next, I will review the major categories,
including compute, networking and content delivery,
file storage, databases, app integration, and
management and governance services.
And finally, I will provide an approach for preparing for the certification exam.
When you finish this course,
you will have a clear understanding of these core services, whether you want
to take the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner exam or just have a better understanding of the services that AWS provides.