So next, we're going to be talking about Amazon VPC and Direct Connect.
Now when we're talking about a virtual private cloud, or VPC, really what
we're talking about is a logically isolated section of the AWS cloud, and
this is where you can launch your EC2 servers in that area and know that
it is just your slice of the cloud.
And this is a virtual network that you define and you can configure.
Now when we're talking about VPC, there's a couple of things to note here.
First of all, it does enable you to have a virtual network in AWS.
Now, let me ease your mind for a minute.
You don't have to be a networking guru to be able to pass
your Certified Cloud Practitioner exam,
but you do need to understand what a virtual private cloud is. But
for those of you that want to dive a bit deeper,
let me tell you that within a virtual private cloud,
you can support both IPv6 and IPv4 addresses, and those are just
different standards that we have for the addresses that our
computers have on the networks that they're on. And you can
configure an IP address range, subnets,
route tables, and network gateways. Again, you don't have to
know all of those details for the exam, but if this is an area of interest,
you should know that you can configure all of these
things within your VPCs. Now, in addition,
it does support both private and public subnets, so if you want to
have areas that can't communicate or can't be reached from the
internet, you can do that. If you want to have areas that are
accessible to the internet, for example if you have a web server
that you want to be available,
you can do that here as well. Now if you do have private subnets,
you can use network address translation, or NAT, for those private
subnets, and there are multiple ways that you can actually
establish a connection to your datacenter,
and we'll talk about one of those in just a minute. And, you can connect VPCs
to each other. So you can have what we call peering connections or use
transit gateway to be able to connect multiple VPCs.
You also can have private connections to many AWS services.
Now let me explain why that's important.
If you want to be able to make sure that your sensitive application
doesn't have to send traffic through the internet, that can just stay
within your VPC, there's a way to do that,
even when you're using specific AWS services. Now next,
we have AWS Direct Connect.
Now this is a service that makes it easy for you to establish a
dedicated network connection from your datacenter to AWS.
So let's say, for example,
you have a business application that uses application data
that's stored within your datacenter, but the application
itself is running on AWS.
Well,
it would be ideal to have a high‑speed connection
between your datacenter and AWS directly,
as opposed to having to send it through the internet. And that's what AWS Direct Connect provides for you.