So now that we have a good understanding of AWS as a whole,
we're going to be looking at how we leverage the services
that are included within the platform.
And when we're talking about interacting with those services, we're
really looking at three different approaches.
The first of these is the AWS Console,
and we used this when we set up our initial AWS account
in a previous course within this path.
Now, in addition to that, we also have the AWS CLI,
or Command Line Interface,
and this is what allows you to access those same AWS services,
but just from the command line on your machine.
Now,
if you want to program access to your AWS resources, this is
when you would look to leverage the AWS SDK,
which is supported across a variety of languages.
Now let's take a look at each of these in turn.
First of all, we have the AWS Management Console,
and as I mentioned,
we have used the browser version of this earlier in this path.
But there also is a mobile application that goes along with this. Now, it
provides access to most all of the 150+ AWS services,
and in this case, all major browsers and mobile operating systems are supported.
Now, you'll probably primarily use the web‑based interface,
but it wouldn't hurt to download the mobile version
and explore that on your own.
So here's an example of the browser version of the console.
We can see here that we're logged in, I'm logged in as myself, and
we can see that I'm using the Northern Virginia region. And you can
see a list of some recently visited services that I have had here on
this version of the console.
Now, we'll dive into the console later on within this module.
So next, we have the AWS Command Line Interface,
or CLI, and this is a tool that allows you to manage your services
from the command line, and this works on Windows,
Mac, and Linux. And most everything you could do in the browser
with the console, you can do with the CLI.
So as an example,
if we wanted to list the current users for our specific AWS account,
we could run aws iam list‑users.
Now, for those of you that maybe have some experience with the platform,
you're noting that this is just limited to IAM users and not the root user,
which is totally true.
And we'll cover more of that in a later course within this path.
Now, the next thing we have is the AWS Software Developer Kit, or SDK.
And this is what allows us to use a programming language to actually
script the process of how we interact with AWS.
Now,
this is great because it can allow us to automate
many things within the platform.
And as we look at the different languages that are supported,
we do have quite a range here, and this includes Java, .NET, Node.js, JavaScript
in the browser, PHP, Python, as well as Ruby, Go, and C++.
So for most developers,
you're working in one of these languages, and that is supported with an AWS SDK.
Now, let's talk about when you would use one of these approaches versus another.
So, first of all,
the console is a great method for testing out AWS services. So if
you want to leverage a service for the first time,
if you want to spin up a virtual server and maybe you haven't used EC2 before,
or maybe you're looking at testing out a new service that AWS just announced,
the console is a great way to do this.
However,
if you have repeated tasks, you might want to look at
using either the CLI or the SDK.
If we require a person to log into their browser and go and
perform tasks, that can be very cumbersome.
But if we're going to be doing these tasks continually,
this becomes a great case for automation,
and both the CLI and SDK can enable that automation.
And next, the SDK enables automation of AWS tasks within custom applications.
So if you have a custom application that you're running on AWS and you want it
to automate some way of interacting with an AWS service,
the SDK becomes a great choice for that.
Now, it's important to note here,
most all services and actions can be performed in any of these three.
Now, there are some exceptions to that rule,
and we'll cover a few of those within this course. But at a high
level, just know that for most services, you'll be able to use
either the console, or the CLI, or the SDK to perform whatever tasks you need when using these services.