So next, we're going to be diving in and taking a look at Amazon DynamoDB,
which is a very exciting service on AWS.
So first of all, it's important to note here what it is.
It is a fully managed, NoSQL database service. So fully managed in this case,
this is a Software as a Service option.
Not only do you not manage the underlying infrastructure,
but you also don't even manage the database layer, you simply use the database.
And in this case,
it is not a relational database, it is a NoSQL database approach,
which gives you some flexibility in terms of your schema,
but also provides some other limitations depending on how
you build your applications.
And it provides both key value, and it also is a document database.
And one of the great things about it is that it does enable
extremely low latency at virtually any scale.
Now you might be wondering how they were able to achieve that.
Well, if you think about it, they have some great challenges to work with,
including supporting amazon.com.
And so DynamoDB was built with that kind of scale in mind.
and so they were able to build a database that could
perform extremely efficiently at a very,
very high scale.
And it does support automated scaling based on configuration,
so you can choose to have its scale based on the predicted need
that you think you're going to have, but it can also scale
automatically based on your usage.
And there's also several other additional features,
like the Accelerator, or DAX,
which gives you an in‑memory cache that you can use alongside the database.
Now we can handle more than 10 trillion requests per day and can support
peaks of more than 20 million requests per second.
And so this gives you just the scale that you can't get with many other
databases, and it's provided here in a way where you don't have to
manage any of the underlying infrastructure.
So let's talk through some of the use cases on when you might leverage DynamoDB.
So here we have scale without excessive maintenance.
Now, this is critical.
If you have ever tried to scale a database in the cloud,
it can be quite challenging.
So if you have run up to an issue where you've had difficulty
scaling, DynamoDB could be a great choice.
Also,
if you're embracing a serverless architecture, DynamoDB
fits into that nicely because, again,
you're not having to manage any of the underlying
infrastructure or even the database layer.
Also, if you have implementations where low latency is key,
you want to be able to get responses quickly from the
database, DynamoDB is a great use case. But also, if you
have data models without blob storage,
so big bits of binary data within your database schema, if you have that,
it's not going to work well with Dynamo, but if you don't, this could be a great fit.