So next, we're going to talk about a service called Elastic Load Balancing.
And this might be a term that you're familiar with because we did
introduce earlier the concept of elasticity.
And just as a reminder,
it is the ability for infrastructure that's supporting an application to grow
and contract based on how much it is used at a point in time.
Well,
one aspect of that is how we actually route users to the correct infrastructure.
And that's where Elastic Load Balancing comes in.
So what Elastic Load Balancing does, in essence,
is that it can distribute traffic across multiple targets.
So at a really high level,
if we have users that are coming to our web application and we have two servers,
it can choose to route the users between those two different
servers based on the load of each of those servers.
So by default, it will integrate with EC2,
ECS, which we haven't yet talked about, but this is AWS's container service,
so for running Docker containers, and Lambda.
So it supports one or more availability zones within a region.
So you could say, for example,
we want to have our customer website running across
three different availability zones,
and we want to have servers that exist in each availability zone.
And then we can leverage Elastic Load Balancing to distribute users to the
right servers in one of those three availability zones.
Now there are three types of load balancers.
We have Application Load Balancers, or ALBs, Network Load Balancers,
which you'll hear called NLBs, and we have Classic Load Balancers,
and in some cases,
those will just be referred to as either classic or ELBs. Next,
let's talk about the process of scaling, specifically with Amazon EC2.
And we will be diving down into this quite a bit deeper in a later
course within this path, but at a high level,
we have a couple of choices when we need to scale our servers on EC2.
So the first here is what we call vertical scaling.
This is when you scale up.
So note here that vertical scaling and scale up are
talking about the same approach.
We scale up our instance type to a larger instance
type with additional resources.
So let's say we were using a t3 medium instance type, and let's say that we just
noticed that our users are hitting that server pretty hard,
and it's not responding as quick as it needs to, and it's even
dropping the connection for some of our users.
Well that's not a good thing, we need to address that.
And sure,
we could go in and say that we want to get a larger server, we could
do something like an m4 xlarge, but if we do that,
we're going to have to shut our server down,
and then we can add those additional resources to it
by changing the instance type,
spin it back up, and now we're able to meet our customer's need.
However, that's usually not the best way.
The best approach is what we would call horizontal scaling, or scale out.
And again, remember here that horizontal scaling and scale
out are talking about the same approach.
This is where we leverage Elastic Load Balancing and we add additional
instances to handle the demand of the application.
So in that case, maybe we have a t3 medium server,
and maybe then we just add two more t3 medium servers, and then we rely on
horizontal scaling with the Elastic Load Balancer to actually handle the
process of routing our users to the correct server.
Now as I mentioned, in a later course within this path,
we're going to tie this together with EC2 and talk about how
you can leverage auto scaling groups alongside Elastic Load Balancing to make this work.