Now next,
we're going to walk through some scenarios to see how well you've
absorbed what we have covered within this module.
So our first scenario has to do with Ruth, and she started a nonprofit
that assigns volunteers to open opportunities to serve.
And recently, their database server went down, so when users went to sign up,
it wouldn't let them do anything, so they actually lost some people
that could have volunteered for some opportunities.
Now, while they have improved their database server,
they're still not able to guarantee that there won't be downtime in the future.
So she really wants to explore an AWS service that
could prevent these lost user signups.
So in this case, what service would you recommend to Ruth?
Okay, next, we're going to talk about Jessi,
and she created a list of onboarding steps for new customers for their app.
Now,
these steps have a lot of integrations with things like their
CRM, they want to send out an email to users, they want to
integrate this in with analytics.
Now, Jessi's a bit worried that it's going to take her development team a
long time if they have to build all of this from scratch.
So is there an AWS service that can help with this approach?
Okay, let's look at our third scenario, and this one has to do with Roger.
And his company is an ecommerce company that's building a custom ecommerce
platform, so they're not using one of the ones off the shelf. Now they're still
adding some new functionality into their platform, and he wants aspects of the
platform to listen for some key events, like orders and refunds.
But, they don't yet know all the elements that need to respond to
the events because they're still building it out.
So, is there a service that would allow current and future parts of
the platform to listen for events like these? So here in the next clip, we're going to walk through the answers.