So up to this point,
we've been focusing on Amazon EC2, but now we're going to look
at a different compute option that is available on the platform,
and that is AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
So at a high level, Elastic Beanstalk automates the process of
deploying and scaling your workloads on EC2, but the difference is
instead of dealing with those servers directly,
which we would call Infrastructure as a Service,
this is more of a Platform as a Service type approach.
Now because of that, it does support a specific set of technologies.
So unlike EC2 where you can really do anything you want,
as long as you can get it up and running on a server,
you can do that on EC2. Here, Elastic Beanstalk
works within a set of technologies.
Now it does leverage existing AWS services,
and you only pay for the other services that you leverage, and so this
brings up kind of a new category of services for us on AWS,
and these are services that really just make it easier to
use other AWS services. So in this case,
we're still theoretically running all of our compute on EC2, but
the process of managing those servers and handling things like
provisioning and load balancing,
scaling, and monitoring are all handled automatically
through the work of Elastic Beanstalk by connecting other
services into the overall platform.
Now you might be asking, well,
what platforms does it support, and that's a great question.
So here, we're going to be looking at a lot of the usual suspects here,
like Java and NET. We also have PHP and Node.js, as well as
Python, Ruby, Go, and then interestingly enough,
it also supports Docker.
So the good thing here is even if you weren't using
one of these other platforms,
but you still wanted to use Elastic Beanstalk, if you could configure a Docker
container with whatever framework you wanted to leverage,
you could still find a way to support it on Elastic Beanstalk, but with
just a little bit of extra work. Now you might be saying,
well,
I get that, and I get that all of these different technologies are
supported, but why would I choose Elastic Beanstalk?
What are the features that it has that would be an
advantage over using EC2 directly? Well,
first of all,
one of the great things about Elastic Beanstalk is it does
have integrated monitoring included,
and again, it's using other services that we'll talk about later to
pull that monitoring information in. Now here,
deployment is critical.
You might just think well I'm just copying some files
to a server, how hard can it be?
But in reality, in production, deployments aren't that easy,
especially when we're talking about load balanced environments and you're
dealing with multiple servers and trying to figure out how to appropriately
deploy things onto servers and make that available to end users, and Elastic
Beanstalk manages all of that for us.
In addition, it also handles scaling.
So if we want to be sure that our web application that's used
within our business as an internal application,
if we know that there's going to be a huge demand upcoming,
we can trust that Elastic Beanstalk is going to be able
to handle that scaling appropriately,
and we can add some configuration to that so that we
can best handle upcoming demand.
But it also allows for EC2 customization.
So here is the one area where it kind of starts to maybe stretch beyond
just a little bit, the Platform as a Service approach,
it does give you the ability to add some customizations to those
servers that it's actually going to be running on.
So why would you want to use Elastic Beanstalk?
So, if you want to deploy an application with minimal knowledge of other
services, so let's say you know Elastic Beanstalk,
but you're not familiar with really administering EC2 servers or
auto scaling groups or getting metrics from CloudWatch, setting
scaling rules, these are things that you can simply rely on
Elastic Beanstalk to do for you.
In addition,
if you want to reduce the overall maintenance needed for the application,
this can be a great choice.
So if you can fit into the specific use case that Elastic Beanstalk has,
you can avoid having to deal with many of the other administrative
tasks that are simply taken care of by the platform.
In addition,
this makes sense if you're not looking to completely
customize the environment that you're in.
And if you say, well,
I want to use this specific AMI and it has to have this specific package
and I don't want it to upgrade to this other version of the package, you
can get really specific about those things.
If that's you, you probably want to look at using EC2 directly.
But if you say, you know what,
I really don't need to customize it, I can take what it gives
me by default, then Elastic Beanstalk can be a great choice and one that will save you time, especially over the life of the application.