So next, we're going to talk about Elastic Block Store, or EBS.
But before we get too deep into EBS,
let's take a look at some different approaches that we have for file
storage within Amazon EC2. The first is Amazon EBS,
which is persistent block storage for use within Amazon EC2,
and that's what we're going to be covering within this clip.
But the next option is Amazon EFS, or Elastic File System,
which is a network file system that is designed for Linux‑based workloads,
and we'll be covering that within the next clip.
So at a high level, EBS is block storage that's designed to
be connected to a single EC2 instance,
and it can scale to support petabytes of data and also support
multiple volume types based on what you need.
So let's quickly give a high‑level overview of EBS.
So first of all, it does enable redundancy within an availability zone.
This way,
you can make sure that your data is durable. Now it also
allows users to take snapshots of its data.
So if you have data that you want to have on a drive
attached to your EC2 instances, but you do want to
periodically take backups of this data, EBS can be a compelling choice.
Now it does offer encryption of its volumes,
but it doesn't necessarily encrypt things by default.
You do need to make sure that is a step that you take if you're
leveraging EBS. It also provides multiple volume types,
including General Purpose SSDs, Provisioned IOPS SSDs, Throughput
Optimized hard disk drives, and Cold hard disk drives.
And we're going to review each of those volume types at a deeper level.
So first of all,
your General Purpose SSD is a cost effective type that
is designed for general workloads.
But if you have a more intense use case,
you might want to take a look at Provisioned IOPS SSDs.
So this is a situation where you're looking at high‑performance volume,
but you really need a low latency. Now we also have
Throughput Optimized hard disk drives,
and this is designed for frequently accessed data.
But, if we have situations where we have less frequently accessed data, we might want to consider the Cold hard disk drive volume type.