So next, we're going to run through a few scenarios to see
how well you've done at absorbing the material we have
presented within this module.
And so the first scenario that we're going to look at has to do with Jennifer,
and she is an IT executive in a financial services company.
Now they're transitioning their data warehouse to AWS to take advantage
of some of the great analysis features that are there,
including some machine learning features they want to
take advantage of in the future.
Now their data warehouse would need to support up to 2 PB of
data, so for Jennifer and her company, which approach would you recommend?
And so next, we're going to be talking about Sam, and Sam
is a DevOps engineer at a tech company,
and he needs to launch a MySQL database for a new web application
they're going to start building next month.
Now in this case, because of some of their security needs,
they need to have direct access to the virtual server that MySQL is running on.
So, what approach would you recommend for Sam's company?
And so next we have Frank, and he is the CTO at a gaming company,
and they are trying to determine how to store real‑time user analytics.
Now they need really low latency and the ability to scale to handle up
to a million players for this new game that they're getting ready to
launch that they know is going to be a hit.
He also wants to minimize the amount of time it takes to maintain the database,
because in the past, they've worked with some very complicated
databases to be able to get this level of performance.
But in this case, he wants to look at AWS first for a solution.
So which AWS approach would you recommend for Frank?
So in the next clip,
we're going to be walking through the answers to this scenario and take a look back at all the things we've covered within this module.