So next, we're going to talk about how you actually get
large amounts of data onto the AWS cloud,
even if you don't want to put it over the public internet. And one of the
ways that we can do that is by leveraging the data transfer services that are
provided with AWS. Now the first is AWS Snowball,
and this is a service where you want to physically
migrate petabytes of data onto the cloud.
But if that's not enough,
there's even another service called AWS Snowmobile, and this is a service if you
physically want to migrate exabytes of data onto the cloud.
So let's compare these two options.
First of all, we have AWS Snowball,
and it is designed for large‑scale data transfer, and as we mentioned,
it supports petabyte scale in terms of data.
Now in this case,
it is going to be a physical device that is delivered
by AWS to your office location,
and you can actually connect this to your network and then upload your
data from within your network. Now when you return it,
it's going to be returned by a local carrier back to
AWS, and then when they get the device, they're going to load your data into S3.
And so that's how AWS Snowball works.
Now, AWS Snowmobile is a little bit more intense.
First of all, it is also designed for large‑scale data transfer,
but in this case it supports exabyte scale.
Now it is a ruggedized shipping container,
and it is going to be delivered to your location.
Yes, a shipping container like one that's pulled by a tractor‑trailer truck.
This is rather large, and this is for some more extreme type scenarios.
Now, AWS will be there to set up a connection from your
network to that shipping container,
and then it actually loads your data onto the Snowmobile, and then AWS
will work to be sure your data is then loaded into S3 when that
shipping container is received back at AWS and they can do multiple trips to get, again, exabytes of data.