So we've covered a lot of new AWS services here within this module.
Let's quickly give an overview of what we've learned,
and then we'll dive into the scenarios that we discussed in the previous clip.
So first of all, we introduced virtual private clouds on AWS.
We also understood the purpose of AWS Direct Connect,
which gives you that direct connection between your datacenters,
your office locations, and AWS.
We examined DNS with Amazon Route 53.
We understood what DNS does and how Amazon Route 53 can help
us build highly available applications.
And then we reviewed Amazon CloudFront, as well as API Gateway.
And then finally,
we introduced Elastic Load Balancing and the different scaling
approaches that you can take when you're leveraging it.
Now let's look back at our scenario with Jane.
So Jane's company has two different corporate datacenters,
and they're looking to have their datacenters work closely with AWS.
So, what service from AWS would you recommend for her company?
Well in this case, AWS Direct Connect is a great fit.
They can build direct connections between their datacenters and AWS,
which means that that traffic does not have to go over the public internet.
That also means that a lot of this communication it can
happen behind the firewall for them.
Next, we're going to talk about Tim,
and his company serves content through their site to users all around the
globe, and they really are looking to optimize performance.
And they want to leverage a CDN,
or content delivery network, so what service would
optimize that performance globally?
Well, in this case,
this would be Amazon CloudFront. That is the content
delivery network that is present on AWS.
So any time you hear a question on the exam talking
about a content delivery network,
think about Amazon CloudFront and how that could help the
users that are leveraging that service.
So next we have Ellen, and her company is running that internal
application on an EC2 server and they're having the downtime.
So which scaling approach would you recommend?
Well, in this case,
we would recommend horizontal scaling, or scaling
out, using Elastic Load Balancing.
This is preferable over using just bigger servers because it can
handle whatever future load you can throw at it.
However, if you get bigger servers,
it's possible you're just going to have to take those
servers down again and make them even bigger.
We went to limit downtime,
and we're going to do that by taking a horizontal scaling approach.
And by using Elastic Load Balancing, we can make sure that we are routing users to the best server for them to use.