So we have looked at several different services over the course of this module
that have to do with both file storage and data transfer.
So, let's quickly review what we've covered before we dive
in and take a look at our scenarios.
So first of all,
we were able to review the different storage services that are available on AWS.
As a part of that, we examined Amazon S3 and its capabilities.
We also implemented a static website on Amazon S3. We then explored the
archive capabilities within Glacier and Glacier Deep Archive.
We reviewed EC2 storage, leveraging both EBS and EFS.
And then, we also examined the large‑scale data transfer
services that are available on AWS.
So now, let's review our scenarios.
So first of all,
we had Elaine, and she was trying to determine how she could
reduce her S3 costs while maintaining durability.
Well, what's the answer for her?
Well in this case,
it would be to use S3 lifecycle rules with S3 Standard‑Infrequent Access.
So let's break that down.
First of all, she could use S3 lifecycle rules because in this case,
the assets are only popular within a week of when they are released, so she
could define a policy that would change storage classes for the data after seven
days of when they are placed inside of the S3 bucket.
And then we could choose to leverage the S3 Standard‑Infrequent
Access storage class because that data is not frequently accessed,
but we would want to stick to this storage class and not one zone
Infrequent Access because we do want to maintain the durability of
the data. Now next, let's look at Esteban.
And so what approach would you recommend for him to get 2 PB
of user‑generated content into the cloud?
Well in this case, it's going to be AWS Snowball.
Now if we look here, we're looking at 2 PB of data.
If we were looking at exabytes of data, AWS Snowball wouldn't work. We
would need to look at AWS Snowmobile. But because we're still dealing
in petabytes, this would work just fine.
So next we have Emily, and Emily was looking for a shared file system
that would work between eight different Linux EC2 instances and would
need to support up to 1 PB of data.
So what approach would you recommend?
Well in this case, it would be Amazon Elastic File System, or EFS.
But note that there are a few conditions that need to
be true before we can choose EFS.
First of all, it needs to be for Linux instances,
and in this case, it is. Also, it needs to be in petabytes of data or less,
and not in exabytes of data.
So it seems like both of these criteria are met, and EFS would be a great candidate for Emily.