Have my students I want to give us some tips before you start this course.
The first thing that I want to tell you is you should make goals.
Why.
Because when you make goals you're telling yourself exactly how you're going to get there.
You making a road map you're telling yourself you know what I want to get here by this specific day
and going to get there by doing this every single day.
Make goals for yourself sit down and put a check mark every time you finish do something every single
day towards that goal that you have.
Even if it's not this course you're doing all the courses do anything in your life make sure that you
do something every single day and you will get there sooner than you think you want to keep motivated.
Think about the results.
Think about the things that you will be able to obtain once you finish.
For example a specific course once you finish a course.
One of the things that you can get.
You can get a better job right because you're going to have more knowledge and more knowledge equals
why more money with money.
Now I'm not going to say that money is everything but with money you can do a lot of things you can
help people with money you can help yourself you can make yourself very comfortable and you know eat
right exercise right.
Buy a new car buy a new house give poor people money.
Right.
So more knowledge equals more money.
Always remember that.
Leaving yourself if you don't believe in yourself nobody else will believe in you.
I learned the hard way.
If you put yourself down.
All right people are just going to put you more down and down you need to pull yourself up.
Believe in yourself you can do anything you set your mind to right now this is a proof right now that
you're watching this video right here.
All right.
If you were able to get in your computer and watch this video you can watch a hundred more videos and
get a hundred times more knowledge to get to where you want to go.
Make every minute of your life count.
Your day will leave.
It will be over in a couple hours and your day will be gone.
It will never come back to you again.
You will get older.
Make sure that every minute that you have in your life is doing something to get you to where you want
to go.
You have that specific goal in life whatever it is to make more money to be healthier.
Make sure that you do something every minute every hour every day towards that goal onto you accomplish
that goal.
And when you accomplish that goal make sure that you remember everything that you went through and celebrate
it because it feels wonderful to do.
I hope this tips really get to your heart because these tips really helped me achieve a lot of great
things in life things that I never thought that I would achieve.
And I want to give you that knowledge to you in this lecture so hopefully you take it very close to
your heart and use it.
Thank you so much for watching this lecture and I wish you the best in life.
See you in the next lectures.