All right welcome back my student.
Now this is Edwin from the future so you might see some files in this lecture that you don't have yet.
Don't worry.
I'm here because I'm adding lectures to the course.
I think it's very important for you to find out exactly how to code Ajax with pure javascript.
I want to give you the foundation so that you can understand how things work and how to even do it with
javascript even though most of the time you're not going to be using javascript you're going to be using
Jake where we or something similar to it because he's easier and is very compatible with a lot of browsers
out there.
All right.
It's a lot of stuff that goes behind the scenes that sometimes if you use just pure javascript you're
not going to get it working in all browsers.
But anyway so in Ajax we have something called the red states and these red states are coming from the
server.
These are responses that we're getting when we're trying to communicate with a server.
So they're ready stories.
There are four red states now as you can see right now 0 is requested by initialize.
One is server connection stablish to request received processing requests and four is the most important
one when the request is finished and the response is ready.
All right.
And then we have statuses We've got 200 and 400 which are the most important thing.
If you don't have that file for some reason the server cannot reach it will give you that for for now.
Found page error on the screen and you probably seen that before that 200 is the one that we care about
which is everything went OK and you're going to see the functionality happening or the web page right.
So that's what two hundred and four do is just way everything is ready and everything is good to go.
We were getting this responses for 200.
I want you to know that because later on we are going to be using that right.
So I made a file.
I want you to create a file called javascript up BHB and another one javascript DML mail.
All right let's go to javascript Deitsch the mailing list create some boilerplate or some ex-teammates
skeleton if you want to call it that.
And here I'm going to try to do everything on this lecture so this lecture might be a little longer
than the rest.
So in order for us to initialize Ageod's right to to have everything work and we need to create an object.
All right.
So objects is like a blueprint for those of you that don't know what an object is.
In programming it's like a blueprint so it can be something like this.
Let me show you this is how you can do an object in BHB and most languages objects are the same and
you have a language programming language so let me give you a little introduction here so you can create
an object called user.
All right.
And then here you would have functions this would be an example function.
And then you can just execute whatever you want in here.
Right.
Of course it's a function.
Well this this is that object because it's a blueprint.
This is like the container of method.
Now inside a class or inside an object right inside this blueprint.
This is called a method instead of a function even though this function is called a method.
So that's a method and I want to show you properties and this would be a property.
This is using BHB but just don't mind the way you write it the user name.
All right this just do a javascript.
All right.
So this will be a natural view.
Some people call each of you some people call it properties or right or variable a class or a blueprint.
Now down here is where you create the object.
So you've got the blueprint with the methods and propert and you can have as many as you want.
And down here is where you create this new object you say new and you use the object name parentheses
and that's it.
You created this object and you assign it any name you want object 10.
There we go.
And now here in this variable you are going to have all the functionalities of your functions inside
methods and all the properties available.
And every time you want to use that object all you have to do is use the name of that object dot whatever.
It depends on what language you are using.
All right so that whatever function you have like this and that will add to Q function because you are
using the object now to add to queue whatever is inside that class or that you know blueprint and you
can access it very well and you can assign them different values as well.
All right so that user name and you can assign this different.
So now you create an object and you can create as many objects as you want.
You can create object 12 in Object 12.
You can assign the user name property to something else like Maria.
So now this object has a different property value.
You see what I mean.
So you can can create on limited objects.
Now this is not a object class or anything like that.
I just wanted you to have some type of idea on what object and method and properties are before we start.
All right.
So I try my best Hopefully you understand.
If not rewind the video and try to understand it.
You don't need to understand it to follow along.
But I just wanted you to know that.
So anyways how how do we initialize agents.
Very simple we create an object and the object name is already defined.
It's in mail H.
TTP requests and you can see right here right.
It needs to be everything exactly the way I'm doing it right now.
And then the parentheses.
All right.
And then we can assign it to a variable that we can assign it to let's say whatever variable I want
the object I'm going to call it the object.
And of course we need a timing operator there and that's how you initialize everything.
And now you start using this object to access methods and properties of the agents of Ageod's so that
where you can communicate with the server.
All right.
This is all the final ready for you.
You don't have to do anything special here you don't have to do custom's objects or anything like that.
All right.
So now that I explained to you how I worked on the next lecture I'm going to show you this working and
hopefully we can finish in the next lecture.
Everything that we have to do we can finish everything we have to do.
All right.
So again if you do not understand or worry about it you don't need it.
But I want you to know it and you can always rewind the video and watch it a hundred times if you need
to.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.