Hi my students Welcome back.
It's really a pleasure to have you here.
I hope your day is going good.
My day is going wonderful.
I can feel the keyboard in my fingers.
I can't even field the energy right now inside of me wanting to live and live in live.
All right.
I'm alive right so that's why math matters right.
Well in this case you are alive.
You're watching me so feel good.
All right.
It's a great day.
You're learning something really valuable here right.
So now on this lecture we will be creating an in that hd a male page.
We're going to be linking to Jake where we were going to be also link it to bootstrap and making sure
that everything works just right.
All right.
If you don't know up again I have a really good cause I bought it for beginners.
Well actually for developers and I also have a course in javascript window that's not it's not the same
same same thing about Jake where we will help you understand Jake we're a little better.
I might have a course in Jake where we laid on.
Not sure yet.
So you might want to check on my house by the time you're watching this.
All right.
If you don't know it that's fine if you don't know Jake where.
Just follow me and you should be fine.
All right.
This course is not about Jake where we so we won't go into details or body right.
No.
Those are major tools that every developer should have.
All right.
So just make sure that you have it.
So now let's go ahead and get a right click here.
And I am going to create a file called index that age the e-mail.
Right.
And then you are just going to create a simple markup for our HD L5 document.
And I am also using a plugin called Emma which helps me write things faster.
So E M M E T Emett.
And that's a plug for this editor here.
A lot of editors have that plug in so if you are develop it you can go ahead and look it up online and
find out how to use it.
You saw how I did it.
I just put a question exclamation and tap and bang.
All right.
I just like teaching your stuff every every minute I guess.
I like teaching you stuff so make sure you grab all of that information in your brain and write it down
to them for good.
So I'm going to go to the Jay Querrey download section there.
Go to actually let's link bootstrap first.
So let's link this first one.
Here's first link and that's it.
You can see that you are all here get Bushrod that come.
And the next one is this one Jake.
Let's just make sure that Jay Square is below this.
All right.
Perfect.
So now the next step is for us to check this out to see if it works right.
He's got to make sure that he works.
I'm going to save it with my keyboard control as will command s and let's Gricean Jake where we put
our script tax for javascript for Jake where he basically is a library for javascript just to make things
easier for us to write and he has a whole bunch of I think well you should probably know that already.
So let's just create a simple function here from Jake where we and just make sure there are this is
this whole thing is working right.
All right so the document out ready is going to help us do that.
And I'm just going to learn something in the stream and I'm going to say this is great.
All right perfect.
There we go refresh.
I saved my document and I get that this is great.
So that means Jake where he's actually working.
This is beautiful right.
We got it working out our first try.
So anyways if you got this done great.
If you didn't don't worry about it I'll wait for you.
Well actually I won't wait for you.
You could just pause the video and you know copy it yourself.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture.
I hope it was enjoyable for you as it was for me.
Now CNN that's all right.
Take care.