I will come back my students.
I hope you have a great day.
Now on this lecture here we're going to be start writing our markup for our male page here.
Now we already tested that and saw that Jake where he's actually working right.
So we don't have to worry about that any more.
So I'm just going to take that alert off and start writing our markup down here.
So what I really want to do is create a div element and what we run to do right.
This is what we want to do.
Because I know you want to do it.
I'm going to create a container here a different class of container and I just like creating IDs so
we might not even use this idea later on who knows.
Right.
But anyways I'm going to also create an H-2 here called search database.
All right.
Another thing that we might want to do here is just going to what I'm going to do.
Very simple here.
I'm going to.
As a matter of fact I'm going to put it right here I'm going to put it in a class here and test center
there.
Now you might be wondering why in the way is he doing I'm going to show you right now let's go to the
left side right here and you can see that I already got into the center of the page.
This is used in that framework that I tell you about bootstrap right.
So if you don't know about it I get a great course that would teach you all than that would introduce
you to the framework and teach us some tricks.
So anyways
now the next thing for us to do is I'm going to also create another class here just to make this certain
size access and it's going to be sets.
That means it's going to have six columns.
For those of you that have made greats before you know how that works and call heads as set just copy
them on doing it like I said I'm not going to go into details about this because this is not a Bush
Shrub course this is just basically we'll just build and what we need it for our page.
Right.
So if I right click on it and I check it you can see that that's right there in the center.
Now bots.
All right.
Perfect.
All right so what is our next step.
Search our database.
Actually let's just say our database actually won.
There you go.
Our next step is to actually to create an input here and if I just leave the input like does
refresh digest looks like that would square the input to just one little simple input right.
Well I don't want to leave it like that.
I want to create is nice input that's why we've got this framework working for us right.
So I'm just going to make sure that this this class form control
right.
And so you see that form control makes it looks like that perfect that's looking a lot nicer than what
we had before.
And now let's also apply some attributes here and you're going to put this one is going to be called
name.
Let's just make sure that we are enclosed in raising apostrophe's the right way.
So this is going to be called search is going to have a search name their name also an ID of search
and as a matter of fact we're also going to be putting a placeholder there.
So let's do a placeholder this place holder is going to say search our inventory
right.
I think we are done with this and I'm just going to put some BE OUR TAX down here.
And we are also going to be creating a another day if you're actually engaged to element with a class
of Fiji set says
Id resorts result is fine.
All right.
All right so make sure you copy all of this down.
See that.
All right.
So there you go.
Daniel's going to refresh and I think a placeholder is not working let's just make sure that it is spelled
correctly.
And there we go.
All right so we have this castrato.
He is looking pretty pretty good in my opinion.
It's very simple.
You can put a bag around here if you want or you can you know it depends if you want to just put in.
Put this into your website.
That's fine.
And anyway I think we are done here right for this lecture here.
We don't want to make this too long so anyways.
Copy this down make sure you have it down packed correctly.
All right.
Thank you again for allowing me to teach you this.
And I'll see you the next lecture.
Keep it up.
Good job.