All right welcome back my dear student.
So one thing that I want to actually do in this small application here is that I want to go to search
and I want to take this out of here I want to take the connection out and then I'm going to cut it out.
All right and I want to create a separate file for our connection to our database is going to cold is
going to be called divi BHP.
All right.
And I'm going to paste that in there.
Whoops.
What did I do with it I do.
It's not good.
The BHB enter
Roy and then pasted in there.
Sorry about that guys.
Make sure that you pull your BHB tags of course and I wish the editor had that BHB tags.
Hopefully by the time you're watching this it does have some type of plug in that we can you know do
that fee and then tap and we create a BHB tag automatically that would be nice.
I haven't really I should actually researched it but probably is already available.
But anyway so we have the connection here.
What we need right now is to include this in our search just to make sure that
it's working.
That would be nice.
I think you could do require that to include and see how that works.
And we own the B.
B.
All right.
And let's try this out to see if it works.
Be all right.
So he's still working.
Beautiful.
So we're going to do the same thing for sure.
We haven't created it yet.
All right we're going to be creating a different file for our code to add the cars.
All right.
We could if we wanted to put it right here if we it but we're not going to do that.
We're going to send this information somewhere else.
So I'm going to create a separate file and I'm going to call this at the car that BHP Antar and we're
going to include.
That's right ph feedback for first right.
We do
we include the database of course the be that BHB.
All right.
So we have this file ready here to go.
Let's go to our end there and see what we gotta do here.
So basically what we're going to be doing here is picking up all this information with Jake wari and
communicate it like we did here but we're going to be using some different functions to communicate
because I just want to show you a different way of doing it.
You're right you learn that Ageod's function and that's when you're going to learn that that post function
is going to be really cool.
All right.
So let's actually make sure that we have the correct.
So we're going to start writing a call right here.
All right but let's go to a form to the forum first and put an ID here because one is selected and we're
going to say at car form that's going to be the idea right.
So in the next lecture we're going to select the form get all the data out of there and submit it to
the database.
Hopefully we got time to do that.
The next one.
Take care keep active keep playing around with the cold.
It's really exciting to learn something new and I promise you this course is going to give you some
some of the foundations that you're going to be using in really really nice application with agents.
Thank you and I'll see you in the next lecture.