All right welcome back my students.
So we are actually making a lot of improvement here since we are starting to write these cold and that's
going to be a great thing.
All right.
You're going to organize my call a little bit here.
Right.
All right so why is the next thing the next thing would be to actually create the while loop right to
make this fetch.
So let's actually use a variable here and use the function Maia's you lie fetch array.
That's best.
And that Querrey which is the query.
Let me just copy this.
Real quick.
I don't want to actually write it down make a mistake and then you know go crazy trying to find out
what's going on right.
So just because we have a table I'm going to relate in that to you.
We have a table down here right where we're going to be catching that data.
We do we need a TR And we need some on cells right.
So let's go back to the split cars.
And so the first thing that I want to do is echo a TR
we go.
The second thing would be to call a TV
with some information right.
So we could say and it's put in brackets actually we can use it this is the only way we can use arrays
here when we have double quotes.
Right.
That's why I like to use double quotes because you can use arrays.
So we want to pull out the ID.
So first thing you want to pull out of them is sure make sure that you put these single calls around
and then we close that the like does.
And we can just copy this and provide the name of that car which I think is cars that's the way you
can bring it out of the database.
And then make sure that this is the same there.
We can actually get this from here close a TR Guidice beautiful and we save it.
All right so this is looking really nice and next thing to do is to try this cold and see if it works.
But anyway we're going to do that in the next lecture.
If we find a bug or anything we'll fix it.
You're welcome to try the cold if it works for you.
Great.
If he doesn't don't worry we'll get it working on that net lecture.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.