All right.
So let's make some improvements to our application.
One of the first things that I want to do is to be honest with you is change the name of the table that
we have now the table the table column cars right in the database.
So I've got to go to ph from my admin and I hear oops I don't even know why my computer are-I So that's
just because I've got a huge monitor in my right hand side and left hand side.
That's why my window is huge.
But anyway I want to change this column name.
I think it's not descriptive.
This should be like Tide or something like that.
All right.
So I'm going to go to a structure
right here structure and then change.
And we're going to change that's a title that we go save right.
And you need to change it everywhere you have BHB of course.
So that's go to display cars and right here instead of that it should be title saving.
Right.
Let's see if it works.
Refresh.
All right.
There we go.
So it's working.
All right perfect.
So we fix that now.
Let's go.
And I want to fix I want to make this feel require I don't one I don't one users or myself to be able
to add cars unless I put something in there.
So because right now we try to add a car.
I would do without putting anything in would send an empty space to the database.
I don't want to.
Right.
So let's do it the easy the easier way without using it be less useful.
H the m l 5.
So let's go to in that age the amount and what is a field at a car
right here.
All right.
Let's add something called the required.
I think this is the input right here.
Let's.
We should actually also put a label here on this input so that way we know.
All right.
So as a label here real quick to label for car name
car name and then add a car or something like that
safe.
Let's check it out real quick.
Refresh prices at a car and I need to make this one 500 millisecond because I think I got it where you
sense every three seconds that requests.
Yes.
So I'm going to make it 500
I'm back here.
Refresh.
There we go.
So out a car and now we try to send it like this without writing anything it would give us this year
so we can do it.
All right.
So we kill like two birds in one shot.
Right.
Actually three because we put a label we require this and we change the database column name to title.
All right so we're making good improvements.
And then next lecture we'll continue doing so.
All right hopefully I'll make some more lectures too.
To keep adding functionality to our little application so that way you can learn a little more.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.