All right welcome back my students.
So that makes this lecture super easy.
We're going to add a band here that would close the box whenever we want so that way this thing is never
it's not open all the time.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do that real quick let's go all the way to the top and right here we've got and
we Empress's that BHB by the way.
Let's use.
Called his bun close.
I don't know.
That's a bull.
I haven't used it.
But
that's it.
All right.
And there you go all the way to the bottom here.
We don't need to actually
write all that if we don't want to have a whole bunch of different ways that we can do this but we can't
even attach it to the send button.
Close by.
There we go.
And I need to be honest.
Just this click event here
tag right here.
You can remove it from the Dohm if you want it to.
Would a function.
But we can also hide it.
So
between is ID.
So let's check it out real quick to see if it works.
All right.
We need to take these we're hello out of there.
This is the lead.
But anyway this barn right here with click click it and it's closed.
All right.
So
there we go.
What else
oh hello word.
All right.
Beautiful beautiful.
Click it.
Gone we go.
Actually
we're computer guys.
Computer update record was updated.
It can go to Friday's update as well on the fly and we can search our database for that specific Honda
winking at it.
Lamborghini intercessors.
You spell it.
Maybe not.
There we go.
Can select it from here and delete it.
Of course we might want to work on this here because it's actually being shown right now.
But we can take that off and fix it.
All right.
Anyway I'm not going to work them out right now.
I'll work on them on that next lectures.
All right.
Meanwhile just remove this wants you.
You'll show it.
It should be easy.
Or when you actually close it down.
You can remove the anyway.
Thank you so much for watching.
When the next lectures and hopefully I'll make some more lectures and make more there's more events.
Bye Bye bye.
Now this course is finish.
You know I did what I promised the cross functionalities here and whatever comes after this is really
really really extra lectures that I haven't even promise you yet.
All right.
I just say I might make some more and actual lectures and I like doing that to all my courses.
Thank you so much for the support.
If you are happy with the course don't forget to give me some reviews.
I love seeing my students reviewing my course and again it's a pleasure and I'll see you in the next
lectures or courses.
Take care.